<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tomato Free on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/tomato-free/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tomato Free on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/tomato-free/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Turkey and Sweet Potato Stew</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/turkey-and-sweet-potato-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/turkey-and-sweet-potato-stew/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a recipe to use up your turkey leftovers after Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will need a slow cooker or an oven-proof cooking dish.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About four portions of cold turkey, torn into bite-sized pieces&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 sweet potato, chopped into small slivers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 carrot, chopped into small slivers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 onion, diced&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 cloves of garlic, diced&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 tsp mixed herbs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 tsp smoked paprika&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;20g butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;50g diced chorizo&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 chicken stock cube mixed in about 700ml water (see method)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;method&#34;&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Melt the butter and fry the onions on a medium heat until golden.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the garlic and fry this mixture for a further thirty seconds.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the diced chorizo and continue to fry, adding a little stock and turning down the heat if things get a little too sticky.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fold in the cold turkey and mix into the onions, garlic and chorizo.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add half of the stock and bring to the boil.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the carrots, the sweet potato and the remainder of the stock.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Transfer to a slow cooker or the oven proof dish. If you&amp;rsquo;re using a slow cooker, you need to make sure liquid covers the contents of the pot.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use the default high setting of your slow cooker, or cook in the oven at 160C for about two hours.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Check on the pot when about 30 minutes of cooking time remains. If you need to thicken the mixture, stir about a tablespoon of cornflour into about 20ml of water and then add this to the pot, stirring it in well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serve with rice and a green vegetable.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beetroot Bolognaise</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/beetroot-bolognaise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/beetroot-bolognaise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We cook this version of bolognaise with beetroot due to Ingrid&amp;rsquo;s tomato allergy. This recipe is an attempt to capture what we do on the fly. The key to it is using the wine, the Worcestershire sauce and the herbs to even out the sweetness of the beetroot. If you can manage that, it&amp;rsquo;s super tasty. The sauce usually ends up being an unusual but pleasing pink/purple colour, as you will see from the pictures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
