<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Getting Stuff Done on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/getting-stuff-done/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Getting Stuff Done on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/getting-stuff-done/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>In Praise of Pulling Everything out of the Shed...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-pulling-everything-out-of-the-shed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-pulling-everything-out-of-the-shed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I pulled everything out of our shed and we took the stuff we didn&amp;rsquo;t need down to the dump. No one likes going to the dump, but it was strangely cathartic. It&amp;rsquo;s due in part to letting go of things from the past, but also the fact that I haven&amp;rsquo;t felt up to much lately. It ended up being a sunny afternoon so it was a pleasant walk back after we dropped off the hire car.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Garden</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-garden/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, we transferred our Christmas tree to a new pot. Being root-bound as the tree was, it took ages to get it out of the crappy pot from the store and into the new, bigger pot. And I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure it&amp;rsquo;s a bit wonky, which might make the baubles a bit lopsided next Christmas. It looks excellent next to the new bird bath.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, it was nice to get another plant into a pot with the hope of keeping it around. Currently, our garden is mostly bulbs erupting from pots. We covered what used to be the lawn in plastic sheeting last December to kill off the grass (and more importantly, the weeds). We had a look underneath it all last weekend, and it&amp;rsquo;s doing the job. It should be possible to continue the next phase of redoing the garden in March (depending on the weather). But it does mean that plant life is currently pot-bound, except for the shed-hugging Jasmine that Ingrid brought back to life a couple of years ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
