<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 17:55:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bob Mortimer, The Satsuma Complex</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bob-mortimer-the-satsuma-complex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 17:55:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bob-mortimer-the-satsuma-complex/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A hardback book called &amp;ldquo;The Satsuma Complex&amp;rdquo; is all that remains of a mysterious young lady that young lawyer Gary is chatting up in the pub one night. It&amp;rsquo;s a book that everyone reckons is &amp;ldquo;a bit sh*t&amp;rdquo;. But Gary&amp;rsquo;s moping about after the Satsuma lady doing a runner while he was in the loo will have to be put on hold when his friend turns up dead.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed this book. It&amp;rsquo;s not going to win any prizes for quality of writing but it is both fun and funny. There are a few repetitive phrases and at one point beers magically become lagers in the space of three paragraphs. The writing is very colloquial but there is a point-of-view shift at the start of part two that deploys some writerly skill. (This short-lived though as the new point-of-view soon collapses down into one similar to the main character.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tade Thompson, Rosewater</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/tade-thompson-rosewater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/tade-thompson-rosewater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rosewater is an exciting science fiction novel set several decades after first contact with an alien called Wormwood, that has established itself as a large biodome in Nigeria. The novel follows Kaaro, a thief whose extra special abilities are forged from an unlikely connection with the alien. The whole thing is part sci-fi adventure and part spy novel.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The novel is set in multiple timelines with whole sections of the story told in flashback. This gives a sense of hopping through Kaaro’s memories and helps us explore this strange futuristic vision of Nigeria. It also really helps with pace, first by throwing us into the story and then helping to explain the relationships between the characters we are introduced to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>John Irving, The Imaginary Girlfriend</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-imaginary-girlfriend/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-imaginary-girlfriend/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Imaginary Girlfriend&lt;/em&gt; is a short autobiography by American author John Irving. In it, he explains the interwoven roles of writing and wrestling in his life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As always with Irving, the book is absorbing from the off, and it&amp;rsquo;s tempting to use the anecdotes here to explain why most of his novels seem to have an underdog narrating them. It&amp;rsquo;s because he loves the work of Dickens so much. I kid. It might be because it is a role he has created for himself, and maybe he likes to write what he knows.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laurent Binet, Civilisations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/laurent-binet-civilisations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/laurent-binet-civilisations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Civilisations&amp;rsquo; is a counterfactual historical novel that attempts to extrapolate the future course of history after changing one pivotal moment of the timeline. I usually find novels like this are great fun, another entertaining example is &amp;lsquo;Making History&amp;rsquo; by Stephen Fry. The novel, originally written in French, won some big awards in France last year. I read the translation by Sam Taylor.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In &amp;lsquo;Civilisations&amp;rsquo;, Binet makes the pivotal point of his tale, the migration of Erik the Red to America in the late 900s. The idea of the novel is that as the vikings move down the coast of north and Central America, they bring exposure to (and therefore some eventual immunity from) smallpox and the ability to work with iron. This equips and prepares the indigenous people ahead of Christopher Columbus&amp;rsquo; arrival in 1492.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amal El-Mohtar &amp; Max Gladstone, This Is How You Lose the Time War</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/this-is-how-you-lose-the-time-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/this-is-how-you-lose-the-time-war/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Is How You Lose the Time War is a short novella about two members of opposing factions (Red and Blue) engaged in a &amp;rsquo;time war’: that is they travel in time and attempt to erase each other&amp;rsquo;s existence. Except that one day Red decides to taunt Blue with a letter, and a correspondence emerges.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The book is entertaining by virtue of wit and brevity. However, the elements that are skipped over that end up being more interesting to reflect on later. Clearly these are two talented writers bouncing ideas off one another, but you get a  sense that this whole fictional universe might have developed into something more. I was more interested in individual episodes than in the correspondence and its results. Perhaps the writers have ended up constrained by their witty idea.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Italo Calvino, If on a Winter&#39;s Night a Traveller</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/italo-calvino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/italo-calvino/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I started to write a review of Italo Calvino&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;If on a Winter&amp;rsquo;s Night a Traveller&amp;rdquo;. I read it while we were in Germany for Christmas. We&amp;rsquo;d visited Bremen and also undergone the bizarreness of Christmas in another language - the same motifs played out in different words and different customs. I&amp;rsquo;d tried to write the review in a similar structure to the book but, in a testament to Calvino&amp;rsquo;s writing I couldn&amp;rsquo;t pull it off. Here&amp;rsquo;s the opening paragraph:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Richard Powers, Orfeo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/richard-powers-orfeo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/richard-powers-orfeo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The mind may give up its desire to improve on creation and function as a faithful receiver of experience.&amp;rdquo; John Cage&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After enjoying &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/the-overstory/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Overstory&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I wanted to read more of Richard Powers&amp;rsquo; novels. &lt;em&gt;Orfeo&lt;/em&gt;  was also long listed for the Booker prize. Perhaps more of his novels would have been had the prize been opened to American authors earlier.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Orfeo&lt;/em&gt; is about Peter Els, a seventy year old composer who accidentally alerts Homeland Security to the existence of his home laboratory, in which he has been trying to recode the genetic material of a bacterium to include a piece of his music. He ends up on the run, which provides the catalyst for a narrative in which we ponders the past and returns to it. Woven throughout is a history of contemporary classical music, most real and some invented.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>George Saunders, Lincoln In The Bardo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/george-saunders-lincoln-in-the-bardo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/george-saunders-lincoln-in-the-bardo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I read this book on holiday in Belgium last year. Having forgotten to pack a novel I scoured almost every book in the Waterstones at St. Pancras station before settling on this Booker prize winning novel by George Saunders.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lincoln in the Bardo&lt;/em&gt; fictionalises a period in Abraham Lincoln&amp;rsquo;s life immediately after the death of his son Willie. The story alternates between factual accounts of what happened at the time and the observations of ghosts in the graveyard where young Willie is buried. Lincoln visits the grave several times over the course of an evening, something that causes costernation and intrigue among the ghosts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isaac Asimov, Foundation and Empire, Second Foundation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-rest-of-the-foundation-trilogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 21:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-rest-of-the-foundation-trilogy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I managed to read all of the foundation novels since I &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/foundation&#34;&gt;wrote about the first one&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, I’ll write about the next two, which covers the original trilogy of ‘novels’ created from the original short stories. I’ve tried to avoid spoilers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;foundation-and-empire&#34;&gt;Foundation and Empire&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Foundation and Empire comprises two novella length stories. The first story (“The General”) picks up from shortly after where the last of the five short stories in &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/foundation&#34;&gt;Foundation&lt;/a&gt; left off. While the Foundation has expanded its influence by using its monopoly on technology to control trade, the once great Empire begins to notice. One particular person who notices is a brilliant young General who is determined to crush the Foundation and restore the former power of the Empire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four Recipe Book Recommendations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/four-recipe-book-recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 11:39:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/four-recipe-book-recommendations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-a-z-of-cooking-by-felicity-cloake&#34;&gt;The A-Z of Cooking by Felicity Cloake&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book is for more luxurious and experimental recipes. There are 26 chapters, one for an ingredient beginning with each letter of the alphabet, but you probably guessed that already. Ingrid and I have been (very) slowly working our way through the chapters, making a couple of recipes from each one - we’re currently up to G for Garlic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My favourite so far has been the bread dumplings in parmesan broth because it gives us a use for our many many parmesan rinds. Mind you, the red spiced pork belly that we made over Easter has come pretty close.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Richard Powers, The Overstory</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-overstory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-overstory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Overstory&amp;rdquo; by Richard Powers piqued my interest among the novels shortlisted for the Booker Prize. And &lt;a href=&#34;satin-island-tom-mccarthy-review&#34;&gt;once again&lt;/a&gt; the book that interested me most did not win. One year I will succeed in my prediction!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I found &amp;ldquo;The Overstory&amp;rdquo; an enjoyable read. Its accessibility surprised me. Often people view Booker nominated novels as stuffy or over-intellectual. This novel however is a genuine page turner, full of emotion and heartbreak, not to mention plenty of science and awe of the natural world. Perhaps in another year it may have won.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isaac Asimov, Foundation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/foundation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For our &lt;a href=&#34;the-same-but-different&#34;&gt;first anniversary&lt;/a&gt; we decided to exhange books. What better way to &lt;a href=&#34;https://ideas.hallmark.com/articles/anniversary-ideas/anniversary-gifts-by-year/&#34;&gt;celebrate a paper anniversary&lt;/a&gt;? Ingrid bought me the entire Foundation saga, most of which were &lt;a href=&#34;https://abcoverd.co.uk/archive/designers/topping-mike&#34;&gt;reissued in fancy new paperback designs by Mike Topping&lt;/a&gt; in 2016. All save for 1993&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/7lueju/asimovs_forward_the_foundation_published_in_2016/&#34;&gt;Forward The Foundation&lt;/a&gt; that is, but Ingrid got me a copy anyway. Hence, here is a new series of blog posts!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Foundation novels detail a galactic empire in decline. A mathematician named Hari Seldon, using a novel science called psychohistory, realises that this is happening and formulates a plan for humanity, one that will reduce the time between empires. This, he reasons, will minimise human suffering and prevent an extended period of barbarism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. D. Vance, Hillbilly Elegy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hillbilly-elegy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hillbilly-elegy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/27161156-hillbilly-elegy&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hillbilly Elegy&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is the autobiography of JD Vance, a self-professed hillbilly made good who graduated from Yale Law School. I read it because reviews touted it as illustrating the economic conditions leading to Brexit and the implausible election of Donald Trump. As &lt;a href=&#34;space-between-this-and-that&#34;&gt;I wrote in an earlier post&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;m keen to learn about why Brexit happened. However, I think this book fails to provide an explanation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I enjoyed the book. It gave me plenty to think about. The story Vance tells is entertaining, but falls short of presenting a meaningful social and economic analysis of the plight of the white working classes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matt Haig, Reasons to Stay Alive</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/reasons-to-stay-alive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/reasons-to-stay-alive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After I read &lt;a href=&#34;hello-america&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hello America&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;like-a-mule-ice-cream-sun-manyika&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Like a Mule Bringing Ice Cream to the Sun&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; to Ingrid, it was her turn to read something to me. We settled on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.matthaig.com/reasons-to-stay-alive/&#34;&gt;Matt Haig&amp;rsquo;s memoir of anxiety and depression &amp;ldquo;Reasons to Stay Alive&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, which is as uplifting and life-affirming as its title suggests.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The book begins with its author standing atop some cliffs in Ibiza, crushed by depression and anxiety and determined to die. Fortunately he doesn&amp;rsquo;t go through with it and eventually this book detailing his experiences of recovery came out of it. It&amp;rsquo;s an honest warts-and-all account of what it&amp;rsquo;s like to be a depressed person and, perhaps even more crucially, what it&amp;rsquo;s like to live with a depressed person.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sarah Ladipo Manyika, Like a Mule Bringing Ice Cream to the Sun</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/like-a-mule-bringing-ice-cream-to-the-sun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/like-a-mule-bringing-ice-cream-to-the-sun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Like a Mule Bringing Ice Cream to the Sun&amp;rdquo; is a novella by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sarahladipomanyika.com&#34;&gt;Sarah Ladipo Manyika&lt;/a&gt;. Of all the books nominated for the 2016 Goldsmiths Prize, this looked like the most interesting to my eyes. I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed previous Goldsmiths nominated novels including &lt;a href=&#34;acts-of-the-assassins-richard-beard&#34;&gt;Acts of the Assassins&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;satin-island-tom-mccarthy-review&#34;&gt;Satin Island&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The title comes from a poem by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.poets.org/poetsorg/poet/mary-ruefle&#34;&gt;Mary Ruefle&lt;/a&gt; called &amp;ldquo;Donkey On&amp;rdquo;. You can read it &lt;a href=&#34;http://thegreatnothingof1987.blogspot.co.uk/2014/02/donkey-on-by-mary-ruefle.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Like a Mule&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; is set in contemporary San Francisco and takes the form of multiple first person narratives, centred around Dr. Morayo da Silva, an elderly Nigerian woman who is approaching her 75th birthday. The novel explores old age, memory, and how we use those things as a filter through which we perceive ourselves and others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alistair Reynolds, Revelation Space</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/revelation-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/revelation-space/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://approachingpavonis.blogspot.co.uk&#34;&gt;Alistair Reynolds&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; 2000 novel &amp;ldquo;Revelation Space&amp;rdquo; has long been in orbit of my science fiction &amp;ldquo;to read&amp;rdquo; list, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until one sleepless night (post &lt;a href=&#34;command-and-control&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Command and Control&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;) that I came across it in Ingrid&amp;rsquo;s audiobooks. I was instantly drawn in as I listened to the opening scene about an archaeological dig facing evacuation ahead of an imminent &amp;lsquo;razor storm&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Revelation Space&amp;rdquo; is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sf-encyclopedia.com/entry/hard_sf&#34;&gt;hard sci-fi&lt;/a&gt; set in a universe where the speed of light cannot be exceeded. Most of the action takes place in the 26th century, with the narrative also recounting earlier events as the story progresses. Humanity has expanded to five or six systems beyond our current solar system, using huge colony ships that travel at 99.9% of the speed of light. This means that &lt;a href=&#34;http://science.howstuffworks.com/science-vs-myth/everyday-myths/relativity10.htm&#34;&gt;relativistic effects&lt;/a&gt; play an important role in the narrative. A lot is made of the difference between sleeping away the decades between star systems and subjectively experiencing them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, Hello America</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-america/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had low expectations for &amp;ldquo;Hello America&amp;rdquo;, the next in &lt;a href=&#34;j-g-ballard&#34;&gt;the series of Ballard novels&lt;/a&gt; that I started reading over seven years ago. However, it turned out to be a hoot. A couple of years ago, this novel would have been a wig-out bit of standard Ballard weirdness (a bit like &lt;a href=&#34;the-drowned-world&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Drowned World&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;the-crystal-world&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Crystal World&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;) but given recent events &amp;ldquo;Hello America&amp;rdquo; is starting to take on an eerie prescience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hello America&amp;rdquo; (1981) is set a hundred years from now in an alternate time-line where oil production peaked in the late sixties. Without a viable energy supply the North American continent depopulates and the Russians dam the Bering strait in order to turn Siberia into farmland to feed the American refugees. Meanwhile, the continental United States turns into a desert wasteland due to the resulting climate change. The 44th president (President Brown) was the last before America depopulated entirely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eric Schlosser, Command and Control</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/command-and-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/command-and-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Command and Control&amp;rdquo; by Eric Schlosser is about the history of nuclear weapons and their safety. This might not seem like a thrilling subject, but it&amp;rsquo;s absorbing from start to finish. I started it three years ago but only finished it more recently as the subject of nuclear weapons has become more pertinent to current affairs&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. There are many people who would stand to gain a great deal from reading this book&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Richard Beard, Acts of the Assassins</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/acts-of-the-assassins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/acts-of-the-assassins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.waterstones.com/book/acts-of-the-assassins/richard-beard/9780099592938&#34;&gt;Acts of the Assassins&lt;/a&gt; is an interesting novel by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.richardbeard.info&#34;&gt;Richard Beard&lt;/a&gt; that retells the story of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apostle_(Christian)&#34;&gt;the apostles&lt;/a&gt; and their deaths. It uses a modern crime genre style and a contemporary setting. The author himself refers to it as &amp;ldquo;Gospel Noir&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Cassius Gallio, a Roman CSI-type referred to as a speculator, investigates the murders of the apostles following the crucifixion and resurrection of Jesus. Gallio, charged with guarding the body following Jesus&amp;rsquo; death and greatly undermined by the disappearance of the body, views the resurrection as the greatest conspiracy of the age.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Unlimited Dream Company</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-unlimited-dream-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-unlimited-dream-company/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/high-rise/&#34;&gt;I last wrote about a JG Ballard novel nearly three years ago&lt;/a&gt;. That one - &amp;ldquo;High-Rise&amp;rdquo; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/film/2016/mar/20/high-rise-review-ben-wheatley-jg-ballard-tom-hiddleston&#34;&gt;has since been made into a film&lt;/a&gt;. The subject of this post is &amp;ldquo;The Unlimited Dream Company&amp;rdquo;, my favourite among his novels: a silly romp through suburban sexual repression that glitters with sinister wit. Even after many read-throughs I still can&amp;rsquo;t work out whether it is a crazy masterpiece or something light that we&amp;rsquo;re meant to throw away after reading.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paul McAuley, Something Coming Through</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/something-coming-through-by-paul-mcauley/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/something-coming-through-by-paul-mcauley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Something Coming Through&amp;rdquo; is a science fiction novel set in the near future. A few years after a brief nuclear war known as &amp;ldquo;The Spasm&amp;rdquo;, an alien race known as the Jackaroo introduce themselves to humanity. The novel is funny, thoughtful, and politically charged. I found it to be a good read.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The aliens have given humanity fifteen &amp;ldquo;gift&amp;rdquo; worlds and an automated way to access them. Think of the Docklands Light Railway but with space shuttles. These worlds contain artefacts and remnants from their previous occupants. Movement between the worlds has also changed the Earth: it suffers from incursions by invasive species brought back from the other worlds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Satin Island by Tom McCarthy: Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/satin-island-tom-mccarthy-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/satin-island-tom-mccarthy-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As much as I wanted it to, Satin Island by Tom McCarthy did not win the Booker Prize. Having read it all I realise it was a long shot. However it is an interesting book that deserved consideration, even if it does have some flaws.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Normally I promise that there will be no spoilers. Not this time. There are some spoilers here. Because it took me so long to work out what I thought Satin Island was actually about, I want to use this post to explore those ideas. I promise to keep the amount of plot exposed to a minimum. Given that at first glance the novel appears plotless, I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have too much trouble. &lt;strong&gt;However, please read the novel before you read this review, unless you don&amp;rsquo;t intend to read it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Booker Prize Pick 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/booker-prize-pick-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/booker-prize-pick-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theatlantic.com/entertainment/archive/2015/10/man-booker-shortlist-2015-satin-island/408784/&#34;&gt;Satin Island&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; is my pick for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://themanbookerprize.com/man-booker-prize-2015&#34;&gt;Man Booker prize&lt;/a&gt;, announced tomorrow. I&amp;rsquo;ve not managed to read all of it yet. Also, I&amp;rsquo;ve only glanced at the others on &lt;a href=&#34;http://themanbookerprize.com/news/man-booker-prize-fiction-2015-shortlist-revealed&#34;&gt;the shortlist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My prediction record on selecting the winner of the Booker from the shortlist is pretty good, though all I&amp;rsquo;m ever doing is guess the outcome of a 1 in 6 chance, like the roll of a die. Often it&amp;rsquo;s a book that I really hope will win rather than one I know will (except &amp;ldquo;Wolf Hall&amp;rdquo; and its sequel). I still think the world is a worse place for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/culture/books/fictionreviews/3665324/Man-Booker-2007-Prize-Darkmans.html&#34;&gt;Nicola Barker&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Darkmans&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; not winning the prize back in 2007. I was delighted when &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/uk/2006/oct/11/books.bookerprize2006&#34;&gt;Kiran Desai&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Inheritance of Loss&amp;rdquo; won the previous year&lt;/a&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s part of my affection for &amp;ldquo;Satin Island&amp;rdquo;, it&amp;rsquo;s a book that will make people go &amp;ldquo;huh?&amp;rdquo; if they&amp;rsquo;re driven to reading it via a prize win.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ben Elton, Time and Time Again</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/time-and-time-again-by-ben-elton/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/time-and-time-again-by-ben-elton/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Time and Time Again is a ridiculously stupid novel by Ben Elton. A shadowy sect (established by Isaac Newton no less!) recruits a soldier to go back in time and prevent Franz Ferdinand&amp;rsquo;s assassination in Sarajevo in August 1914. I wonder if it all goes to plan and everyone lives happily ever after with no weird timey-wimey after-effects?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Needless to say &lt;strong&gt;this novel makes me wish that time travel were a real thing so that I could travel back in time and slap myself in the face while in the queue to buy this tripe.&lt;/strong&gt; I usually try to see the best in the books, albums and movies that I write about, but the most fun you can have with this novel is to rip it to shreds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eric Schlosser, Gods of Metal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gods-of-metal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gods-of-metal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Y-12 is the United States&amp;rsquo; most secure weapons-grade Uranium storage facility. It is known as the &amp;ldquo;Fort Knox of Uranium&amp;rdquo;. In 2012 it was infiltrated by three elderly peace protesters, sparking a major scandal about the safety of US nuclear sites. &amp;ldquo;Gods of Metal&amp;rdquo; by Eric Schlosser tells the story of that break-in alongside a history of both the anti-nuclear movement (in particular &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plowshares_Movement&#34;&gt;the Plowshares movement&lt;/a&gt;) and nuclear security in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Andy Weir, The Martian</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-martian-by-andy-weir/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-martian-by-andy-weir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I received a copy of The Martian by Andy Weir for Christmas. This week during some annual leave I managed to finish it. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those novels that just flies by once it gets going. I&amp;rsquo;ve stayed up incredibly late to read it as it is full of those &amp;ldquo;just one more page&amp;rdquo; moments. It’s a readable and enjoyable story of an astronaut trapped on Mars.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mark Watney is believed to be dead following an accident during an emergency evacuation in a dust storm. With his life support readings at zero and unable to locate his body to be certain, his crew reluctantly abandon him on the red planet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jodorowsky&#39;s Dune</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/jodorowskys-dune/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/jodorowskys-dune/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1935156/?ref_=fn_al_tt_1&#34;&gt;Jodorowsky&amp;rsquo;s Dune&lt;/a&gt; is a documentary about outlandish Chilean director &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alejandro_Jodorowsky&#34;&gt;Alejandro Jodorosky&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; attempt at a film adaptation of &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dune/&#34;&gt;Frank Herbert&amp;rsquo;s Dune&lt;/a&gt; in the 1970s. As a big fan of the novel and of science fiction in general, I was very interested in this film. It does not disappoint. It gives a great insight into the mind of a little known (if slightly batty) director and shows even an artistic failure can lead to shock waves that can be felt in later work by others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ned Beauman, Glow</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/glow-by-ned-beauman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/glow-by-ned-beauman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Glow is about a guy called Raf, a Londoner whose life is going nowhere in particular; a state of affairs not helped by “Non-24 Hour Sleep/Wake Syndrome”. One night while experimenting with a new ecstacy-like drug that’s apparently derived from a social anxiety medication for dogs, Raf meets a beautiful girl and then loses her to the crowd in a blink-and-you-miss-it moment. From there a conspiracy evolves involving the titular dog-medication-derived drug, Burmese dissidents, corporate espionage, pirate radio stations, and urban foxes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iain M. Banks, Feersum Endjinn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/feersum-endjinn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/feersum-endjinn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Feersum Endjinn is one of Iain Banks&amp;rsquo; few non-Culture sci-fi novels. Like the Culture novels, an existential crisis drives the plot: in this case the action takes place on Earth in the far future and the sun has aged to a point where it will grow and swallow the earth. This is referred to as the Encroachment. The characters are divided between the good guys who seek to find a solution for the greater good and bad guys who use the Encroachment to consolidate their power and influence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evie Wyld, All The Birds, Singing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/all-the-birds-singing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/all-the-birds-singing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently finished reading &lt;em&gt;All The Birds, Singing&lt;/em&gt;, the second novel by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eviewyld.com&#34;&gt;Evie Wyld&lt;/a&gt;. It’s about a woman called Jake who lives alone on a farm with a dog called Dog on an island somewhere off the coast of Britain. She has sheep to look after but something keeps coming in the middle of the night to kill them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, as the narrative on the island moves forward in the present, a second narrative peels off backwards to explain her past. This takes place in Australia. Jake is still working with sheep but there is a confrontation with a fellow farmhand who threatens to expose a secret from her past. As this second strand unfurls, we begin to see why Jake is jumpy and convinced that the deaths of her sheep represent ill-portent. However, because this second story rolls backwards in jumps, we have to wait until the end for the terrible events that set her on this path.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haruki Murakami, Colorless Tsukuru Tazaki And His Years Of Pilgrimage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/colorless-tsukuru-tazaki/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/colorless-tsukuru-tazaki/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Colorless Tsukuru Tazaki And His Years Of Pilgrimage is the latest novel by Haruki Murakami. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/books/2014/jun/19/haruki-murakami-marketing-publishers-stickers&#34;&gt;It comes with free stickers&lt;/a&gt;. Perhaps that tells you everything you need to know about this book, which is slimmer than Murakami&amp;rsquo;s recent efforts. The plot begins with an intriguing premise. Tsukuru is part of a group of close friends and is one day expelled from the group for no reason. Unfortunately, the development of the plot is uncontrolled and by the end  of novel too many holes have developed for it all to hold together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clarice Lispector, Hour of the Star</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hour-of-the-star-by-clarice-lispector/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hour-of-the-star-by-clarice-lispector/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.penguin.co.uk/nf/Book/BookDisplay/0,,9780141392035,00.html?strSrchSql=hour+of+the+star/Hour_of_the_Star_Clarice_Lispector&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hour of the Star&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a short novel by &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clarice_Lispector&#34;&gt;Clarice Lispector&lt;/a&gt;, a Ukrainian-born Brazilian author with an interesting life story. This is her last novel and is a remarkable book: inventive, funny, and sad, all at once. I found it in a special selection at the local library dedicated to Brazil because of the World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First some biography. Born Chaya Lispector in Chechelnyk, Ukraine, in 1920, her family escaped the pogroms and emigrated to Brazil in 1922. She was given the new name Clarice as the family settled in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lonelyplanet.com/brazil/the-northeast/maceio&#34;&gt;Maceió in north-eastern Brazil&lt;/a&gt;. Later she and her family moved to Rio de Janeiro&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and she started law school there in 1937. Her first published short story appeared around 5 years later.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, High-Rise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/high-rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/high-rise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a few false starts I managed to finish &amp;ldquo;High-Rise&amp;rdquo;, the next in &lt;a href=&#34;j-g-ballard&#34;&gt;my collection of JG Ballard novels&lt;/a&gt;. For a book that I had trouble getting into, it turned out to be a pretty good read - even if it was also a pretty unpleasant one. Published in 1975, &amp;ldquo;High-Rise&amp;rdquo; is perhaps ahead of its time in exploring the effects of social breakdown in stylised and artificial situations where people are in close contact. You might think the plot, about a luxury high-rise that goes to hell, is in some way political or sociological but it really isn&amp;rsquo;t. It&amp;rsquo;s just a big playground in which Ballard throws around some of his most twisted ideas, all the while remarking on the very artifice of the situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neil Gaiman, The Ocean At The End Of The Lane</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-ocean-at-the-end-of-the-lane/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-ocean-at-the-end-of-the-lane/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Ocean At The End Of The Lane&amp;rdquo; is the new novel by Neil Gaiman. I was so intrigued by it that I bought the hardcover, which is unusual for me because I prefer paperbacks. I&amp;rsquo;d been excited by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/books/2013/jun/10/extract-ocean-end-lane-neil-gaiman&#34;&gt;reading the first chapter online at the Guardian website&lt;/a&gt; and from reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://amandapalmer.net/blog/20130618/&#34;&gt;a blog post about the novel written by the author&amp;rsquo;s wife Amanda Palmer&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;d not read any of his novels before but they had long been on that &amp;ldquo;to read&amp;rdquo; list that is typically as long as your arm. I also enjoyed the movie adaptation of &amp;ldquo;Stardust&amp;rdquo; though I have no way (yet!) of knowing whether the film is as good as the original book.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don Delillo, Point Omega</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/point-omega/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/point-omega/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There were no mornings or afternoons. It was one seamless day, every day, until the sun began to arc and fade, mountains emerging from their silhouettes. This is when we sat and watched in silence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today I finished reading &amp;ldquo;Point Omega&amp;rdquo; by Don Delillo. I have wanted to read one of his novels for a while and though this is a slip of a novella, I certainly enjoyed it. I accidentally came across it when I looked at the wikpedia page for &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Teilhard_de_Chardin&#34;&gt;Pierre Teilhard de Chardin&lt;/a&gt; last week as part of research for another post that I am writing. &amp;ldquo;Point Omega&amp;rdquo; seemed short and in keeping with what I wanted to write about, so I used my usual quick-draw finger on amazon and bought the thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Michael Frayn, Skios</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/skios/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/skios/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week I read “Skios” by &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Frayn&#34;&gt;Michael Frayn&lt;/a&gt; (who was born in Mill Hill). It’s another book from now customary pile of books that tends to develop around this time of year. &lt;a href=&#34;hawksmoor&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hawksmoor&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;the-marriage-plot&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Marriage Plot&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; were on the same ever-increasing pile. “Skios” is something of a change from what I normally read: it’s a comedic farce about stolen identities set on the (fictional) titular Greek island. Amusingly, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Skios&#34;&gt;the wikipedia page for the novel&lt;/a&gt; currently reads “Praise for Skios was entirely misplaced”, probably thanks to some curmudgeon who doesn&amp;rsquo;t like the novel. Cue a ‘misplaced’ blog post about it, something that most people would consider to be business as usual for my blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peter Ackroyd, Hawksmoor</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hawksmoor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hawksmoor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Peter Ackroyd&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Hawksmoor&amp;rdquo; was first published in 1985. I bought a recent reissue that forms part of Penguin&amp;rsquo;s decades collection whilst on a spree in Waterstone&amp;rsquo;s. It appealed to me as I recently realised that despite growing up in the eighties and nineties, I had read very novels that were either written or set in the eighties. Happily &amp;ldquo;Hawksmoor&amp;rdquo; is both of these, sort of. It also appealed to me because it is (again, sort of) a detective story and I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself getting into those lately. John Squire&amp;rsquo;s excellent artwork for the cover and the nice binding also helped to seal the deal: you don&amp;rsquo;t get that with an iPad or a Kindle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jeffrey Eugenides, The Marriage Plot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-marriage-plot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-marriage-plot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Marriage Plot&amp;rdquo; by Jeffrey Eugenides is a novel about love and growing up set in the privileged world of US academia in the early eighties. The main plot concerns a love triangle involving two guys and a girl. Madeline Hanna, the girl at the apex of the love triangle, is the main focus of the novel and the majority of the novel is told from her standpoint. I think her sections are incredibly well written but I&amp;rsquo;d love the thoughts of a female reader, in case it is actually all a horribly male way of seeing through a young woman&amp;rsquo;s eyes. In love with Madeline (and the guy that we meet first) is Mitchell Grammaticus, an overly deep guy who is terribly concerned about whether he is doing the right thing in the world. He thinks that religious studies is for him but later finds that it is harder to live up to your ideals than you first imagine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Love On The Road</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-i-love-on-the-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-i-love-on-the-road/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was fifteen when I first read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/70401.On_the_Road&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;On The Road&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jack_Kerouac&#34;&gt;Jack Kerouac&lt;/a&gt; and recently, after twice as much lifetime lived, I was able to watch &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0337692/&#34;&gt;the film version directed by Walter Salles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The only people for me are the mad ones, the ones who are mad to live, mad to talk, mad to be saved, desirous of everything at the same time, the ones who never yawn or say a commonplace thing, but burn, burn, burn like fabulous yellow roman candles exploding like spiders across the stars. (&lt;strong&gt;Jack Kerouac&lt;/strong&gt;, &amp;ldquo;On the Road&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iain M. Banks, Consider Phlebas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/consider-phlebas-a-picaresque-in-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/consider-phlebas-a-picaresque-in-space/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A while back, I decided I was going to write about the Iain M. Banks sci-fi-novels (mainly as a respite from having to read and write about &lt;a href=&#34;j-g-ballard&#34;&gt;J. G. Ballard novels&lt;/a&gt;, but I only got as fas as writing about the excellent “Against A Dark Barkground” and re-reading the first of the Culture novels “Consider Phlebas”. WARNING: Some plot spoilers follow (but not too many).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure why it has taken almost two years to write about this novel. Perhaps it is because I couldn’t find myself a proper explanation for the title. The following is my own theory, feel free to add your own in the comments. The book takes its name from the epigraph, an extract from T.S. Elliot’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bartleby.com/201/1.html&#34;&gt;“The Waste Land”&lt;/a&gt; (which is also on my “to read” list):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Pynchon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-pynchon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-pynchon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The existence, or impending existence, of a new novel by &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thomas_Pynchon&#34;&gt;Thomas Pynchon&lt;/a&gt; was &lt;a href=&#34;http://dealbook.nytimes.com/2013/02/25/pynchon-takes-on-silicon-alley/&#34;&gt;announced today&lt;/a&gt;. I have all his previous books (seven written over a period of about fifty years, a pace that I definitely approve of), though he’s a hard author to get close to: I’ve only finished three and started four up till now. The unfinished one is, of course, Gravity’s Rainbow (GR) and somewhat perversely, I have two copies of the thing. Of the three unstarted, both Mason &amp;amp; Dixon (MD) and Against The Day (ATD) seem too dense and intimidating, while Vineland just begs me to read The Crying Of Lot 49 (L49) or Inherent Vice (IV) one more time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jon McGregor, Even The Dogs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/even-the-dogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/even-the-dogs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over my holiday I read &amp;ldquo;Even The Dogs&amp;rdquo; by Jon McGregor. I&amp;rsquo;ve not quite finished it yet but that will at least prevent me from giving away spoilers. I am not sure I would want to give any spoilers anyway because it is unrelentingly grim so far. Perhaps there is a happy  ending but both you and I will have to read it to find out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was introduced to Jon McGregor by the book group I was part of during my PhD. I think &amp;ldquo;If Nobody Speaks Of Remarkable Things&amp;rdquo; was the first book I read for the group. At that time of my life, about eight or so years after finishing my English Literature A-level, I had not had to read a book that I had not chosen for myself for quite a long time. I found it to be a complete shock. I can still remember reading about half that book straight out of the amazon packaging.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nick Harkaway, The Gone-Away World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-gone-away-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-gone-away-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Gone-Away World” is a novel by Nick Harkaway. It’s about a world slightly askew to our own in which the powers-that-be have deigned to unleash a weapon that simply wipes the enemy out of existence. Unfortunately the enemies also have the same weapon and there are terrible consequences to the extent that the very fabric of reality is threatened. If you don’t already know what reification means, you will by the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another Reading List</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/another-reading-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/another-reading-list/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/other/June-2012-Bookstack.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;More books to add to the “University of life” course list&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More books to add to the “University of life” course list. From top to bottom: I picked up “Generation X” for 50p in a charity shop in Tintagel. “Everything Is Going To Be OK” is a picture book full of inspirational mottos. “The Happiness Hypothesis” is the most useful and interesting book that I have read in a long while. I decided to read “How To Write A Sentence” as an alternative to Strunk and White’s “The Elements Of Style” which, while useful, can be a little stuffy! “The Marriage Plot” is a novel with interesting reviews, it was also (ahem) well-priced. After love I decided to go after music as something else I wanted to read about, hence “The Music Instinct” which comes highly recommended. “The Gifts Of Imperfection” is a manifesto for embracing life in a wholehearted way. And “Gonzo”? Well, &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/gonzo-a-graphic-biography-of-hunter-s-thompson/&#34;&gt;I have written about that one already&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Helen Fisher, Some Lessons In Love</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/some-lessons-in-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/some-lessons-in-love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As indicated by my &lt;a href=&#34;articles/reading-list-mid-april-2012&#34;&gt;reading list&lt;/a&gt; posted a couple of months ago (which has since been added to &lt;a href=&#34;articles/another-reading-list&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), I’ve started to try to read more about the things that I felt that I did not understand so well. Most notably perhaps is this book “on love” by Helen Fisher. Lest there is any innuendo it is not a book about technique nor does it attempt to explain love to those who have never known it, instead it assumes that we have all been there. In fact, the book attempts to explain the neurological mechanisms of love (specifically romantic love) and describes how science has helped reveal these mechanisms to us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Bingley and Anthony Hope-Smith, Gonzo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gonzo-a-graphic-biography-of-hunter-s-thompson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gonzo-a-graphic-biography-of-hunter-s-thompson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another book from the “university of life” pile (though &lt;a href=&#34;reading-list-mid-april-2012&#34;&gt;not in the picture&lt;/a&gt;), “Gonzo” is the biography of Hunter S. Thompson in graphical form. In case you don’t know his work, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hunter_S._Thompson&#34;&gt;Hunter S. Thompson&lt;/a&gt; was a journalist who invented the so-called “gonzo” style. This was basically to rock up at some major event and become embedded within it, usually writing up a long form piece from an outsider perspective. He was particularly famous for his work on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hell%27s_Angels:_The_Strange_and_Terrible_Saga_of_the_Outlaw_Motorcycle_Gangs&#34;&gt;Hell’s Angels&lt;/a&gt; and Richard Nixon’s campaign for presidential re-election in 1972.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading list, mid-April 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/reading-list-mid-april-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/reading-list-mid-april-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/other/April-2012-Bookstack.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A hefty reading list that should keep me occupied into the summer.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A hefty reading list that should keep me occupied into the summer. A friend on facebook asked “What course is that for?”, to which I replied “It’s for one of the modules I am doing at the university of life.” This response was quite popular.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sam Selvon, The Lonely Londoners</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-lonely-londoners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-lonely-londoners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Lonely Londoners&lt;/em&gt; by Sam Selvon was written in 1956 and tells of the experiences of West Indian men moving to London for work. It has been described as the definitive novel about the experiences of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nationalarchives.gov.uk/museum/item.asp?item_id=50&#34;&gt;Windrush settlers&lt;/a&gt;. The narrative centres on a man named Moses who was one of the first to come to London and finds himself the first port of call for many subsequent immigrants:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It look to old Moses that he hardly have time to settle in the old Brit’n before all sorts of fellars start coming straight to his room in the Water when they land up in London from the West Indies, saying that so and so tell them that Moses is a good fellar to contact, that he would help them get place to stay and work to do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Never Mind The Ballards</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/never-mind-the-ballards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/never-mind-the-ballards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;j-g-ballard&#34;&gt;Ages ago&lt;/a&gt; I set out to write a post for each of JG Ballard’s novels. In fact it is the oldest post on this blog. Most of the novels (I don’t have the two autobiographical novels &lt;em&gt;Empire Of The Sun&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;The Kindness Of Women&lt;/em&gt; and the late period novel &lt;em&gt;Milennium People&lt;/em&gt;) are sat in a row on top of my broken bookshelf, part of the weight there that bowed outer frame of the unit and made the inner shelves collapse. Had I known that it would be a task unfinished nearly eighteen months later and destroy a piece a furniture that I did not yet own, I may have been less ambitious.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mark Rowlands, The Philosopher And The Wolf</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-philosopher-and-the-wolf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-philosopher-and-the-wolf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I saw that a friend had ‘liked’ this book on Facebook and reading about it on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Philosopher-Wolf-Lessons-Death-Happiness/dp/1847081029/&#34;&gt;amazon&lt;/a&gt;, I was curious enough to give it a go. It is the autobiography of the philosopher &lt;a href=&#34;http://rowlands.philospot.com/&#34;&gt;Mark Rowlands&lt;/a&gt;, specifically the experiences and lessons learned from raising a wolf, Brenin, from cub to maturity and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The book addresses different aspects of philosophy including the nature of evil and the interaction between humans and other animals. As you might expect, the book pays particular attention to our interactions with wolves and dogs. There is also a lot of explanation of the difference between wolves and dogs. Rowlands appears often to disparage dogs, though remembering my experiences of our Labradors while growing up did make me nod in agreement quite often.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frank Herbert, Dune</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dune/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dune/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A week or so ago, I finished reading &lt;em&gt;Dune&lt;/em&gt; by Frank Herbert. It tells the story of a revolution within a Galactic Empire that takes place on a harsh and unforgiving desert planet called Arrakis. One central theme is how destinies can be shaped despite being intertwined around many axes. Another is the importance of adaptation in the fight for survival.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I came to &lt;em&gt;Dune&lt;/em&gt; via the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0087182/&#34;&gt;David Lynch film&lt;/a&gt; and then &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frank_Herbert%27s_Dune&#34;&gt;the Sci-Fi Channel’s mini-series&lt;/a&gt;, which I was able to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lovefilm.com/film/Dune-Part-1/161663/&#34;&gt;stream through LoveFilm&lt;/a&gt;. Of the two filmed versions, I found the latter to be more enjoyable and this is almost certainly because it runs to nearly six hours. The 1984 film runs to over 3 hours and yet still feels rather rushed. The Lynch version is to be praised though as in my opinion it develops a unique aesthetic for the Dune universe that I did not detect so much in the book.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, Concrete Island</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/concrete-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/concrete-island/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;no-man-is-an-island-not-any-more&#34;&gt;No man is an island (not any more)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You are tracked pretty much everywhere you go. CCTV, the GPS on your phone or the signals sent by your more primitive model to the masts to keep in touch with the network. Your cash withdrawals, your purchases in Tesco and your journeys on public transport all add to the picture of where you are. If you drive, your sat nav will hold clues to where you have been and, if you disappear, where you might have gone to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Favourite Culture Ship Names</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/favourite-culture-ship-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/favourite-culture-ship-names/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned before &lt;a href=&#34;more-books&#34;&gt;I am re-reading the novels of Iain Banks&lt;/a&gt; and this weekend I managed to finish &lt;em&gt;Consider Phlebas&lt;/em&gt;. A little post about it will be coming up soon. One of my favourite things about the Culture novels is how the ships are named and having found &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_ships_(The_Culture)&#34;&gt;a list on Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;, I thought I would share ten of my favourites with you!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;You’ll Clean That Up Before You Leave&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ravished By The Sheer Implausibility Of That Last Statement&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;All Through With This Niceness And Negotiation Stuff&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prosthetic Conscience&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Of Course I Still Love You&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Size Isn’t Everything&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hand Me The Gun And Ask Me Again&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dramatic Exit, Or, Thank you And Goodnight&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;We Haven’t Met But You’re A Great Fan Of Mine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Anticipation Of A New Lover’s Arrival, The&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Great names all I am sure you would agree. Not all of them appear as fully developed characters. In fact (and I will mention this again later) the ships don’t get nearly enough time as characters in the novels apart from &lt;em&gt;Excession&lt;/em&gt;, which is almost entirely devoted to them. In that novel, one ship is central to the story and is probably my favourite, an eccentric GCU (General Contact Unit) called &lt;em&gt;Grey Area&lt;/em&gt; that has been shunned by the other machines for “non-consensual mind reading”. It turns out the ship is somewhat morbid and likes to confront the perpetrators of genocides with their crimes. It is known by the other ships as “the meatf***er” and is totally badass.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More Books</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/more-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/more-books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;never-mind-the-ballards&#34;&gt;Never mind the Ballards&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have been writing about books by &lt;a href=&#34;j-g-ballard&#34;&gt;J.G. Ballard&lt;/a&gt; pretty much to the exclusion of all others. Gradually the posts have tricked out about four novels and ground to a halt. I’ve got a fair way through two other books but I am getting very tired of reading his novels all the time, much as I love them. The mistake I made was that I hadn’t read enough of them in the first place. The project for the site was get the books, read them and then write something. In terms of writing regular posts, this was a bad idea!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, Crash</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/crash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/crash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;form-and-function-deformation-and-dysfunction&#34;&gt;Form and function, deformation and dysfunction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think we should get one thing out of the way first. For me, there is nothing erotic about a car or a motorway. The place in popular culture of the car in particular as sexual icon has always bemused me. In fact, I’m really rather ambivalent about cars. This matters when discussing &lt;em&gt;Crash&lt;/em&gt;, the 1973 novel by JG Ballard that resumes this strand of posts about his novels. (You can read about &lt;em&gt;The Drowned World&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/the-drowned-world/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Drought&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/the-drought/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Crystal World&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/the-crystal-world/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Crystal World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-crystal-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-crystal-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;crystallising-the-world-the-body-or-the-mind&#34;&gt;Crystallising the world, the body, or the mind?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At last, Ballard in full flow. The Crystal World (TCW) is definitely the most enjoyable of the early trio of apocalyptic novels. It takes the successful elements of the first two and embellishes them with new details and ideas. At time of writing, TCW is definitely the best Ballard novel that I have read in its entirety.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The book begins with a steamer travelling up a river in Cameroon carrying the novel’s main protagonist Edward Sanders, a doctor at a hospital for lepers. He is hoping to meet some friends, Max and Suzanne Clair, who are also doctors and run another leprosy hospital in a town named Mount Royal (also the name of the main city in “The Drought”). His motives are not entirely clear and we are given introspection into his doubts about the reasons he is making the journey. The inference is that he had an affair with Suzanne Clair and may well still be in love with her.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Drought</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-drought/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-drought/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-world-created-by-nature-versus-the-world-constructed-by-humans&#34;&gt;The world created by nature versus the world constructed by humans&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On to The Drought by J. G. Ballard in &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/j-g-ballard/&#34;&gt;my ongoing quest to read and review all of his novels&lt;/a&gt;. This is his second novel, if we assume his convention of never acknowledging “The Wind From Nowhere” as being his first novel. “The Drought” itself was renamed from “The Burning World” and additional content added later on. This was quite common practice in SF in the 50s and 60s where novels were serialised in magazines like &lt;a href=&#34;http://philsp.com/mags/amazing_stories.html&#34;&gt;Amazing SF&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://ttapress.com/interzone/about/&#34;&gt;Interzone&lt;/a&gt;. It is evidence though of Ballard finding his voice as he wrote and from The Drought it is easy to see that he is iterating his thought processes and subject matter with each novel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Drowned World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-drowned-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-drowned-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;does-science-fiction-have-to-be-believable-to-be-meaningful&#34;&gt;Does Science Fiction have to be believable to be meaningful?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Should science fiction have predictive power? In plotting the vast unknowns of the future, should authors aim for prescience? Will people be able to say of the best SF novels in five hundred years time that some novels were right about some things and that these novels are better than the ones that didn’t?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I would say no, otherwise we would be remarkably unfair on an awful lot of good writing. That said, I doubt that SF is read for the futurology. As with all literature, SF is at it is best when it has something to say about the world around us now, no matter when it may be set. And if SF has any kind of predictive record, it does better when the psychological issues arising from continued technological development are considered over the mere technology of that advancement. In the long run, a fictional account of space dog Laika (does one exist?) that rings true emotionally will probably endure longer than a pulp novel entitled “Dogs In Space!” (though that is a great title!).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/j-g-ballard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/j-g-ballard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading &amp;ldquo;Crash&amp;rdquo; at 17 left me in a state of numb shock. It got me hooked and left me with &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/J._G._Ballard&#34;&gt;J. G. Ballard&lt;/a&gt; as one of my favourite authors. I then devoured a short story collection called &amp;ldquo;Myths of the Near Future&amp;rdquo; around the same time. You may recognise it because the Klaxons appropriated the title for their debut album. Those stories captured my imagination, in particular the eponymous story of a world gone to run amid &amp;ldquo;space sickness&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
