<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bolivia on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/bolivia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bolivia on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/bolivia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>South America, Part 12</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-trip-part-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-trip-part-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;uyuni-to-tupiza&#34;&gt;Uyuni to Tupiza&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We left Uyuni the night after the big storm, having stopped just a day or so to visit the salt flats. Our next stop was a strategic stay in Tupiza, a large town encircled with red hills. It resembled many towns that I visited in South America: low buildings arranged in a grid pattern. Not much greenery and plenty of dust billowing about. The reason for our stay was strategic, it&amp;rsquo;s only a short distance to the notoriously fussy border between Bolivia and Argentina. We would leave at 5am the next morning so we would reach the border early in case of a long delay, which can happen at this border.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South America, Part 11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-trip-part-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-trip-part-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;la-paz-to-potosi&#34;&gt;La Paz to Potosi&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/south_america/part_11/01.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We left La Paz, this time ascending the rim of steep hills around the city in a slightly less clunky &amp;ldquo;Death Bus&amp;rdquo;. Perhaps it was because we were travelling uphill or because it was daylight, but it didn&amp;rsquo;t seem so bad.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/south_america/part_11/02.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/south_america/part_11/03.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We set off to Potosi through strange towns with weird monuments (see the pictures) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lonelyplanet.com/bolivia/the-southwest/oruro/travel-tips-and-articles/76305&#34;&gt;Oruro where great festivals happen around Ash Wednesday each year&lt;/a&gt; that are famous throughout the continent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South America, Part 10</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-trip-part-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-trip-part-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/2014/05/south-america-trip-part-9/&#34;&gt;Picking up where I left off&lt;/a&gt; at Machu Picchu, we headed down into Aguas Calientes (trans. “hot waters”) by coach and by the time we got there it was torrenting down with rain. So much for exploration. We waited out the downpour in a pizza place and deliberated over whether to buy souvenier snaps from the tour guides. Ironically for a town named after hot waters, it was bitterly cold. One of those places where the sound of running water follows you wherever you go, the best thing about it was the huge trains that ran down the middle of street - big clanking hulks pulling huge passenger trains.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
