<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>June on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/june/</link>
    <description>Recent content in June on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/june/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Oh heck it&#39;s June</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/oh-heck-its-june/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/oh-heck-its-june/</guid>
      <description>White rabbits and all that.&#xA;Even more than during the pandemic, I&amp;rsquo;m feeling these days like the days, weeks, and months are all blurring into one another. It&amp;rsquo;s getting harder to figure out what year something happened, how the old the cats are, and just how overdue all my promises are. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely getting harder to look at this blog and wonder whether it will ever get back to its heyday of regularly posted updates.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2016</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-june-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-june-2016/</guid>
      <description>Album Digest June 2016 is a poppy batch of albums. We have the return of my long-time favourites Roxette and the heroes of my South American tour Tegan &amp;amp; Sara. There&amp;rsquo;s some dance music in the form of Flume&amp;rsquo;s album &amp;ldquo;Skin&amp;rdquo;: an Australian presence ahead of the new Avalanches album next month. Finally there is the first of two new albums by Islands - both were released back in May but one gets reviewed this month and the other next month.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2015</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-june-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-june-2015/</guid>
      <description>To reboot this series, Album Digest June 2015 features five fantastic albums from Hot Chip, Jamie xx, Blanck Mass, Holly Herndon, and The Orb. I could pick loads more as I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to a lot of albums since February but I decided to focus on the more electronic material. This means that I have no excuses for not continuing next month with a rockier theme.&#xA;Hot Chip &amp;ldquo;Why Make Sense?&amp;rdquo; Hot Chip seem to be settling in to a pattern with their album releases, alternating between messy experimental affairs and then a state of the art correction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2014</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-june-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-june-2014/</guid>
      <description>Watter are a &amp;ldquo;supergroup&amp;rdquo; composed from various members of Grails, Slint, and other bands. I did not know anything about Hundred Waters before this month: &amp;ldquo;The Moon Rang Like A Bell&amp;rdquo; is their second album. In fact second albums by bands I know nothing about are a something of theme because &amp;ldquo;Sunbathing Animal&amp;rdquo; is Parquet Courts&amp;rsquo; sophomore effort and I don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about them either. Meanwhile, I&amp;rsquo;ve meant to write about &amp;ldquo;The Four Seasons Recomposed&amp;rdquo; since April.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2013</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-june-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-june-2013/</guid>
      <description>Just two albums this month as I am still enjoying last month&amp;rsquo;s albums so much (and I spent loads of time getting reacquainted with Boards Of Canada at the start of the month). I listened to a few more albums but not often enough to write loads about them so there is an &amp;ldquo;honourable mention&amp;rdquo; section at the end of the post that briefly discusses a few more albums.&#xA;Without further ado, the two albums are:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2012</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-june-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-june-2012/</guid>
      <description>Three fantastic albums for Album Digest June 2012:&#xA;Saint Etienne Words and Music by Saint Etienne Liars WIXIW Hot Chip In Our Heads This month is a curious selection in that the albums are all by bands that I already own a few records by. When there is so much other directly related material that you can write about, it makes focussing on the album in hand quite difficult. I am always thinking up rankings and comparisons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another Reading List</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/another-reading-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/another-reading-list/</guid>
      <description>More books to add to the “University of life” course list. From top to bottom: I picked up “Generation X” for 50p in a charity shop in Tintagel. “Everything Is Going To Be OK” is a picture book full of inspirational mottos. “The Happiness Hypothesis” is the most useful and interesting book that I have read in a long while. I decided to read “How To Write A Sentence” as an alternative to Strunk and White’s “The Elements Of Style” which, while useful, can be a little stuffy!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2011</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-june-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-june-2011/</guid>
      <description>I have had the sort of month that is not conducive to listening to much new music. Therefore this month’s post is only going to consider two new albums and two albums that I have bought behind time. Because of various bits of stress and poor mood, I have ended up going back and taking refuge in some old favourites and not listening to new stuff. At other points I have also gone back to the Fleet Foxes’ album that I wrote about last month, which has grown on me even more since.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
