<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nelly Furtado on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/nelly-furtado/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nelly Furtado on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/nelly-furtado/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2017</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-september-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-september-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note: Recent months have been very busy, so this album digest combines a review of the new album by The National with a couple of reviews left over from earlier in the year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written a few more album reviews in the past months but I&amp;rsquo;m so far behind (February and March have already been published on a considerable lag) that I&amp;rsquo;m just going to pepper forthcoming digests with additional reviews of older albums.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, January 2013</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-january-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-january-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Only one of this month three albums was actually released this month. Nelly Furtado&amp;rsquo;s Mi plan was actually released over three years ago - I only discovered it last year when I wrote &lt;a href=&#34;album-digest-september-2012&#34;&gt;the September album digest&lt;/a&gt; following the release of &amp;ldquo;The Spirit Indestructible&amp;rdquo;, or it might have been when I wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;uc20&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Folklore&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; at around the same time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I guess these are albums that I bought with my Christmas gift vouchers!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2012</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-september-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-september-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had a bit more time to listen to this month’s albums because I was on holiday for two weeks. I didn’t manage to write about them while on holiday though! In fact I bought and listened to a few more, but I will save them for next month. The albums I will discuss now (in order bought) are:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Four Tet “Pink”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The xx “Coexist”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nelly Furtado “The Spirit Indestructible”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grizzly Bear “Shields”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s quite a diverse collection and, Four Tet apart, quite song based.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #20: Folklore by Nelly Furtado</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s rather spooky but shortly after deciding to write about Nelly Furtado’s “Folklore” as the next &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;understated classic&lt;/a&gt;, I found out that she has a new album out this week. As a result, I have been listening to a lot of her music while writing this post, and I’ve been enjoying it too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As always with these choices of mine, “Folklore” is a record that I can link to particular events and emotions in my life and so I guess my perception of it is coloured by that. Nevertheless while re-listening to the album I tried to examine whether my feelings for it were &lt;em&gt;entirely&lt;/em&gt; centred on those memories and emotional responses. I think the answer is not a simple one, because in recent weeks I’ve felt very unsettled in many aspects of my life and so I probably have found it difficult to tell.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
