<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The National on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/the-national/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The National on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/the-national/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #4: The National, &#34;First Two Pages of Frankenstein&#34; and &#34;Laugh Track&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-04-the-national-frankenstein-laugh-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-04-the-national-frankenstein-laugh-track/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s probably no surprise that as we reach the top four (or five if you like) we also&#xA;&lt;span class=&#34;marginfigure&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/the-national-first-two-pages.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of First Two Pages of Frankenstein by The National&#34; /&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Cover of &lt;em&gt;First Two Pages of Frankenstein&lt;/em&gt; by The National&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;get to the two albums The National released in 2023. The first, “First Two Pages of Frankenstein”, was trailed with a big reveal early on in the year, while the second, “Laugh Track”, was dropped all of a sudden in October. Once I got to know both albums, I swung between liking each one more for a while, hence putting them both at the same point in the list and not considering each separately.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the purposes of this list, we can consider both albums as one homogeneous collection of songs, though some reviews did pick out that “Laugh Track” has more live drums and the songs on that latter album are looser and longer than their “… Frankenstein” counterparts. I think there are songs that are similar to one another on both albums, and that for those tracks, the song on the first album is a bit better than the one on “Laugh Track”. Some of the songs on “Laugh Track” are almost invisible on the first few listens, songs like “Dreaming”, “Hornets” and “Tour Manager”, though the latter of those three has become one of my favourite songs on both albums.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note: Recent months have been very busy, so this album digest combines a review of the new album by The National with a couple of reviews left over from earlier in the year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written a few more album reviews in the past months but I&amp;rsquo;m so far behind (February and March have already been published on a considerable lag) that I&amp;rsquo;m just going to pepper forthcoming digests with additional reviews of older albums.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, May 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2013/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
