<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Indie on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/indie/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Indie on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/indie/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Parquet Courts Sympathy For Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/parquet-courts-sympathy-for-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/parquet-courts-sympathy-for-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./images/parquet-courts-sympathy-for-life.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover art of Sympathy for Life by Parquet Courts&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Getting back to my occasional album revisits, I&amp;rsquo;d like to consider the 2021 Parquet Courts album &amp;ldquo;Sympathy For Life&amp;rdquo;. This is partly because I own it on vinyl and put it on the other day while I was doing some rather humdrum data downloading at work. It&amp;rsquo;s that kind of album, quite loose and jam-based.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recorded just before lockdown, first in New York then at the Real World studios in Box, the album seems eerily prescient of what was to come later in the Covid pandemic. These are songs about constantly being watched by AI and the sort of coddling of the modern mind that results from this. It&amp;rsquo;s not quite as good as the previous album &amp;ldquo;Wide Awake&amp;rdquo; but is probably better than &amp;ldquo;Human Performance&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s so relaxed and different to the previous album that you might have expected it to appear under their Parkay Quarts alias.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Albums of the Year #2: Waxahatchee, Tigers Blood</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-02-waxahatchee-tigers-blood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-02-waxahatchee-tigers-blood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Tiger&amp;rsquo;s Blood&amp;rdquo; is a glorious bundle of songs that writhe with brains and heart, with love and friendship, and many other complements and opposites. The music is mostly alternative AOR with a distinct country twang. The lyrics were pretty impenetrable to me, at least until I looked them up online (and they&amp;rsquo;re also on the back of the poster that came with the LP), but they&amp;rsquo;re mostly songs of hope and happiness. It was satisfying to listen to an album this care-free, even if there is a hint of darker times in the background.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Albums of the Year #4: Adrianne Lenker, Bright Future</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-04-adrianne-lenker-bright-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-04-adrianne-lenker-bright-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One album that&amp;rsquo;s lurking in the periphery of my &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;understated classics series&lt;/a&gt; is &amp;ldquo;Dragon New Warm Mountain I Believe In You&amp;rdquo; by Big Thief. &amp;ldquo;Bright Future&amp;rdquo; is the latest solo album by Big Thief singer-songwriter Adrianne Lenker and it is just as good. Intimate and intricate, it draws the listener in as Adrianne sings live with a very small band. At times you can hear breaths drawn and the sound feels like a small space that you are cocooned in: this could be sound engineering (spatial audio would have us believe anything is possible) but it&amp;rsquo;s most likely equipment set up intelligently in a cosy studio.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Albums of the Year #7: MGMT, Loss Of Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-07-mgmt-loss-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-07-mgmt-loss-of-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know very much about MGMT these days. I haven&amp;rsquo;t read any interviews about their albums. The video to the single &amp;ldquo;Nothing to Declare&amp;rdquo; was brought to my attention by the YouTube channel Justin Hawkins Rides Again. In it he points out how melodically interesting the song is. To be honest I was more than a little bit in love with the video.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After that I added the album to my library and heard a few more singles in the run up to the release of the album, including &amp;ldquo;Bubblegum Dog&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Mother Nature&amp;rdquo;. The album itself is crammed with similarly interesting songs and has a circular structure, beginning with part 2 of the title track. I&amp;rsquo;d love to know what poem is being read or sampled or cut up on &amp;ldquo;Loss of Life, Pt. 2&amp;rdquo;. Other highlights include &amp;ldquo;Phradie&amp;rsquo;s Song&amp;rdquo; and a song called &amp;ldquo;Nothing Changes&amp;rdquo; which goes a bot bonkers in the second half, completely undermining the title of the song!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Albums of the Year #9: Cassandra Jenkins, My Light, My Destroyer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-09-cassandra-jenkins-my-light-my-destroyer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-09-cassandra-jenkins-my-light-my-destroyer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first time I listened to this album, I was still off work sick with Covid, but well enough to go out for a walk on what was too hot a day to stay inside the house. I remember it well, recovering from illness does tend to make these things more vivid, but more because I thought it was brilliant, but all out of order. I was, of course, completely wrong.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Albums of the Year #10: Yard Act, Where&#39;s My Utopia?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-10-yard-act-utopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-10-yard-act-utopia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yard Act are a post-punk band from Leeds. &amp;ldquo;Where&amp;rsquo;s My Utopia?&amp;rdquo; is their second album. I first encountered Yard Act in a review of this album, which sent me to look at the excellent video to their non-album single &amp;ldquo;The Trenchcoat Museum&amp;rdquo;. I enjoyed the metatextual references both in the video and the song, so I eagerly added &amp;ldquo;Where&amp;rsquo;s My Utopia?&amp;rdquo; to my library.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, the album took a while to win me over. Fourth-wall breaking asides and meta references are fine in a single song, even one as long as &amp;ldquo;The Trenchcoat Museum&amp;rdquo;, but combined over the length of a whole album, it can be a bit off-putting. Nevertheless, WMU? rewards repeat listens (especially on headphones) because it&amp;rsquo;s genuinely funny - I think comedy is an underrated quality in Indie music - and the songs themselves are ace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #4: The National, &#34;First Two Pages of Frankenstein&#34; and &#34;Laugh Track&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-04-the-national-frankenstein-laugh-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-04-the-national-frankenstein-laugh-track/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s probably no surprise that as we reach the top four (or five if you like) we also get to the two albums The National released in 2023. The first, “First Two Pages of Frankenstein”, was trailed with a big reveal early on in the year, while the second, “Laugh Track”, was dropped all of a sudden in October. Once I got to know both albums, I swung between liking each one more for a while, hence putting them both at the same point in the list and not considering each separately.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #5: Nation of Language, Strange Disciple</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-05-nation-of-language-strange-disciple/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-05-nation-of-language-strange-disciple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/nation-of-language-strange-disciple.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Strange Disciple by Nation of Language&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It would be remiss of me to claim that this is a placeholder for any number of (quite different sounding) song based albums that came out this year (Yves Tumor, Wilco to mention two) but it feels that way. This album came high up my list of listens because it&amp;rsquo;s a very good breakfast album, one to listen to while getting the Day started - though there are also some bangers on here too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
