<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>In Praise of Pomme Fritz</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-pomme-fritz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-pomme-fritz/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ian MacDonald, Revolution in the Head</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ian-macdonald-revolution-in-the-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ian-macdonald-revolution-in-the-head/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ian MacDonald&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Revolution in the Head&amp;rdquo; is a book that I&amp;rsquo;ve read parts of dozens of times and even all the way through once or twice. I picked it up again today and thought I would write about it. It&amp;rsquo;s a detailed analysis of every Beatles song ever released, along with the details and events of their recording. I own a copy of the second edition which was updated to include the anthology material. Today you can still get hold of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.waterstones.com/book/revolution-in-the-head/ian-macdonald/9780099526797&#34;&gt;a 3rd edition on the Waterstones website&lt;/a&gt; (not sure that I like the new cover though).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Albums Matter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/albums-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/albums-matter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having recently completed my review of 2024&amp;rsquo;s best albums, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reflecting on what a strange year it was for me in terms of the music I listened to. According to my Last.fm annual report, I listened to 51% &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; music in 2024 compared with 2023 (and 2023 was itself a peak listening year). Moreover, I listened to 709 artists, of which 37% were new discoveries. I listened to over 2 albums a day apparently, with &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/posts/2024-albums-03-acopia/&#34;&gt;Acopia&lt;/a&gt; being the album I listened to most often. Apparently I was the 11th top listener on Last.fm of my number 1 album of the year &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/posts/2024-albums-01-bolis-pupul-letter-to-yu/&#34;&gt;Letter to Yu by Bolis Pupul&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parquet Courts Sympathy For Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/parquet-courts-sympathy-for-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/parquet-courts-sympathy-for-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./images/parquet-courts-sympathy-for-life.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover art of Sympathy for Life by Parquet Courts&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Getting back to my occasional album revisits, I&amp;rsquo;d like to consider the 2021 Parquet Courts album &amp;ldquo;Sympathy For Life&amp;rdquo;. This is partly because I own it on vinyl and put it on the other day while I was doing some rather humdrum data downloading at work. It&amp;rsquo;s that kind of album, quite loose and jam-based.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recorded just before lockdown, first in New York then at the Real World studios in Box, the album seems eerily prescient of what was to come later in the Covid pandemic. These are songs about constantly being watched by AI and the sort of coddling of the modern mind that results from this. It&amp;rsquo;s not quite as good as the previous album &amp;ldquo;Wide Awake&amp;rdquo; but is probably better than &amp;ldquo;Human Performance&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s so relaxed and different to the previous album that you might have expected it to appear under their Parkay Quarts alias.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Albums of the Year #6: Total Blue, Total Blue</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-06-total-blue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-06-total-blue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What do you think of when you think of the colour blue? The sea? Perhaps the sky? Maybe it makes you think of blue stones like sapphires, or flowers such as forget-me-nots? Maybe the colour blue is the glow of a phone screen on someone&amp;rsquo;s face (maybe yours) in the dark? Blue gathers at the edges of the harsh white LED light that has come to dominate our night time existence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums: Honourable Mentions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-honourable-mentions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 13:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-honourable-mentions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A quick list of ten other albums I considered to be among the best of last year. I either listened to these less, or in the cases of &amp;ldquo;Transmission Three&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Be Opened By The Wonderful&amp;rdquo; considered them to be ineligible as they are compilations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;yves-tumor-praise-a-lord-who-chews-but-which-does-not-consume-or-simply-hot-between-worlds&#34;&gt;Yves Tumor, &amp;ldquo;Praise a Lord Who Chews but Which Does Not Consume; (Or Simply, Hot Between Worlds)&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Great album, recommended to me by Apple Music slinging the first track into my discovery feed back when that featured was added. Lots of earworms and a really good headphone listen. My top 10 was pretty dance heavy and putting this in might have added a few more guitars. Highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #1: Sofia Kourtesis, Madres</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-01-sofia-kourtesis-madres/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-01-sofia-kourtesis-madres/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/sofia-kourtesis-madres.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Madres by Sofia Kourtesis&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sofia Kourtesis is a Berlin-based Peruvian dance producer, &amp;ldquo;Madres&amp;rdquo; is her debut album which follows on from a 2021 EP &amp;ldquo;Fresia Magdalena&amp;rdquo;. It was trailed by several singles, including the title track which caught my attention back in May. The album is dedicated to her parents and there are also songs dedicated to the surgeon who performed life-saving surgery on Kourtesis’s mother. The whole album is a heady mix of positivity and dedication to both music and to family.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #2: James Holden, Imagine This is a High Dimensional Space of All Possibilities</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-02-james-holden-imagine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-02-james-holden-imagine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/james-holden-imagine.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Imagine This is a High Dimensional Space of All Possibilities by James Holden&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cool artwork! No, we don&amp;rsquo;t have it but it&amp;rsquo;s coming in next week.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cool artwork! We haven&amp;rsquo;t had a copy in but I can order it for you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Me picking it up a week later: &amp;ldquo;Cool artwork!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Imagine This is a High Dimensional Space of All Possibilities&amp;rdquo; is definitely album title of the year, made all the more topical with the intrusion of Chat-GPT and the like into the cultural conversation. Large Language Models (LLMs) like Chat-GPT work by absorbing large amounts of textual data (i.e. this blog, helping to make all those instant album reviews you can write now just a tiny bit more shit) and breaking them down into tokens, with each token having a meaning and a grammatical role and so on. These meanings and roles form higher dimensional spaces in which the tokens are vectors, where the rules of the LLMs help determine which tokens live near to one another and which pairs are likely to sit together in &amp;lsquo;meaningful&amp;rsquo; sentences etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #3: Barry Can&#39;t Swim, When Will We Land?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-03-barry-cant-swim-when-will-we-land/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-03-barry-cant-swim-when-will-we-land/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/barry-cant-swim-when-will-we-land.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of When Will We Land by Barry Can&amp;rsquo;t Swim&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some albums you come to one way: a good review on a blog you respect, a track appearing on a playlist by someone whose taste you trust, etc and so on. And sometimes you get directed to something multiple times. This is what happened to me this year with the irrepressible “When Will We Land?” by Barry Can’t Swim. Anyway, tracks by &amp;ldquo;Barry&amp;rdquo; appeared in mixes a lot this year and the album kept popping up in eagerly anticipated lists.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #4: The National, &#34;First Two Pages of Frankenstein&#34; and &#34;Laugh Track&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-04-the-national-frankenstein-laugh-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-04-the-national-frankenstein-laugh-track/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s probably no surprise that as we reach the top four (or five if you like) we also get to the two albums The National released in 2023. The first, “First Two Pages of Frankenstein”, was trailed with a big reveal early on in the year, while the second, “Laugh Track”, was dropped all of a sudden in October. Once I got to know both albums, I swung between liking each one more for a while, hence putting them both at the same point in the list and not considering each separately.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #5: Nation of Language, Strange Disciple</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-05-nation-of-language-strange-disciple/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-05-nation-of-language-strange-disciple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/nation-of-language-strange-disciple.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Strange Disciple by Nation of Language&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It would be remiss of me to claim that this is a placeholder for any number of (quite different sounding) song based albums that came out this year (Yves Tumor, Wilco to mention two) but it feels that way. This album came high up my list of listens because it&amp;rsquo;s a very good breakfast album, one to listen to while getting the Day started - though there are also some bangers on here too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #6: Grails, Anches en Maat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-06-grails-anches-en-maat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-06-grails-anches-en-maat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/grails-anches-en-maat.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Anches en Maat by Grails&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Grails are one of those bands who always get played a lot at my house. There&amp;rsquo;s something about their slow incremental instrumental pieces that my brain just loves to get lost in. Anches en Maat, their first album in six years or so, and the first with the entire band in the studio together since 2008, is their most Grails-y album in a long time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #7: Maara, The Ancient Truth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-07-maara-ancient-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-07-maara-ancient-truth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/maara-ancient-truth.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of The Ancient Truth by Maara&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There isn&amp;rsquo;t a great deal I can write about The Ancient Truth without sounding vague and anodyne. While I try to come think about different forms of music and go into some analysis of what makes one album more interesting than another, sometimes you end up just saying &amp;ldquo;this album is great because I like it and I always have a good time listening to it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #8: Everything But The Girl, Fuse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-08-ebtg-fuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-08-ebtg-fuse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/ebtg-fuse.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Fuse by Everything But The Girl&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you get older nostalgia becomes an ever important part of listening to music. It often feels like the business relies on convincing an aging population of fans to part with their money on new versions of old material. It&amp;rsquo;s nostalgia, the feeling of recapturing something you loved in your youth, that often makes this acceptable. Of course it&amp;rsquo;s also nice to get &lt;strong&gt;new&lt;/strong&gt; music from your favourite bands, especially when it&amp;rsquo;s as good as &amp;ldquo;Fuse&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #9: Fever Ray, Radical Romantics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-09-fever-ray-radical-romantics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-09-fever-ray-radical-romantics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/fever-ray-radical-romantics.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Radical Romantics by Fever Ray&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Radical Romantics, the third album by Fever Ray was released in April. I bought a copy on red vinyl which is a beautiful sight to behold. I listened to a lot when it was released but eased up a bit until listening to it a couple more times while writing this list. It&amp;rsquo;s a great collection of songs, probably better than their second album &amp;ldquo;Plunge&amp;rdquo;. The cover art is just as scary though.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #10: Wata Igarashi, Agartha</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-10-wata-igarashi-agartha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-10-wata-igarashi-agartha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/wata-igarashi-agartha.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Agartha by Wata Igarashi&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Agartha is the debut album by Japanese electronic artist Wata Igarashi. I don&amp;rsquo;t really know much about him, but I do know that I enjoy releases on the German record label Kompakt and I have really enjoyed Japanese techno in recent years. Over lockdown I discovered Haruomi Hosono&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Polyharmony&amp;rdquo; album and re-discovered the work of Shinichi Atobe, particularly their album &amp;ldquo;Love of Plastic&amp;rdquo;. Both of those albums could be future understated classics and while both are by Japanese artists working in electronic music, there the comparison ends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year Preview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/albums-of-the-year-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/albums-of-the-year-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another year (nearly) over and so starting from tomorrow, I&amp;rsquo;m going to count down my top 10 albums of 2023. The rules are:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;They have to have to have been released in 2023.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;They need to be albums. I&amp;rsquo;m defining this as either more than 7 tracks or songs, or more than forty minutes in length.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To make the top ten, they need to have been played the most times. I admit that I don&amp;rsquo;t have a precise measure of this, as I do still buy vinyl and about four of these albums will have had play counts missed by not being captured through a streaming service.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Compilations are not included, whether they feature multiple artists or a retrospective of a single artist.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s pretty much it. Have I done any prep work? Well no, not really. I made a preliminary list at the start of October and not only was the number one album not out at the time (!) but I also had mistakenly included two albums from 2022. So yeah, this is not a pro operation. 😂&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ellie Goulding - Bright Lights</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ellie-goulding-bright-lights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ellie-goulding-bright-lights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So today &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/how-random-should-things-be/&#34;&gt;my random album script&lt;/a&gt; picked out &amp;ldquo;Bright Lights&amp;rdquo; by Ellie Goulding, an album I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure I&amp;rsquo;ve ever listened to. I looked in my music library and there it was! As a result this is not so much an &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tag/album%20revisit/&#34;&gt;album revisit&lt;/a&gt; as an album _&lt;em&gt;visit&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this album was released in 2010 and did quite well. In fact, &amp;ldquo;Bright Lights&amp;rdquo; is a reissue of an album that was originally released as &amp;ldquo;Lights&amp;rdquo; (February 2010). This version adds seven extra tracks, which explains why it&amp;rsquo;s an exhausting seventeen tracks long. &amp;ldquo;Lights&amp;rdquo; was a successful debut and a few of the singles went top 20, which is what led to its re-release with all those extra songs in November of the same year. (I think this is why it is in my collection, I think I bought it for my mum or for a sibling as part of a Christmas present, and ripped the CD out of curiosity&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabric 44 by John Tejada</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fabric-44-by-john-tejada/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fabric-44-by-john-tejada/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is one of my more played Fabric mix CDs so I decided to go for it when my random prompter plumped for this earlier today. One constraint of these posts was to write it in roughly the amount of time it takes to listen to it. You&amp;rsquo;d think that for a mix CD that would be ok. After all, this mix is a full CD and 74 minutes long.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How random should things be?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-random-should-things-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-random-should-things-be/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to extract my music library, including all the albums I&amp;rsquo;ve added to streaming, as a CSV file and write a routine in R to select an album at random. The plan is to write about that album for the blog in roughly the time that it takes to listen to that album all the way through. I already did this yesterday for &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/goldfrapp-black-cherry&#34;&gt;Goldfrapp&amp;rsquo;s Black Cherry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But I have to level with you. That was not the first album that was picked. Nor is the album selection process entirely unbiased. I got to a working situation and stopped there. Essentially, I smoosh together artist and album title, so that albums like compilations, or albums where the lead artist collaborates with multiple other artists, are slightly over-represented. I say slightly as the pool was already pretty large with just unique albums. I might do what I did yesterday and ignore singles or compilations, especially as the code takes almost zero time to give me another idea.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goldfrapp - Black Cherry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/goldfrapp-black-cherry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/goldfrapp-black-cherry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the first in an unplanned series of &lt;strong&gt;album revisits&lt;/strong&gt;, I will write a post explaining the process soon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Cherry_(Goldfrapp_album)&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Black Cherry&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is the second album by Goldfrapp, released in 2003. I bought the lead single Train while I lived in York and also the single of the title track because by then I&amp;rsquo;d discovered M83 and they&amp;rsquo;d done a remix of it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Black Cherry&amp;rdquo; finds the band faced with following their successful and chilled out debut album &amp;ldquo;Felt Mountain&amp;rdquo;, which back in 2000 had sounded notably weird. But nobody wants to sound like a kook forever, sometimes people want to let their hair down and just dance. That&amp;rsquo;s very much what the first two tracks anyway, especially the pulsating &amp;ldquo;Train&amp;rdquo;. To my ears, I was definitely pleased when I first played the single - I love that relentless synth riff that sounds like it&amp;rsquo;s being fed through about seventy FX pedals. I vaguely remember the single&amp;rsquo;s B-side &amp;ldquo;Big Black Cloud, Little White Lie&amp;rdquo; and the Village Hall Remix being pretty ace too. Fortunately they&amp;rsquo;re also on streaming, so I was able to check. I think I liked the B-side because it sounded very much like a &amp;ldquo;Felt Mountain&amp;rdquo; outtake - twenty years ago I likely appreciated the familiarity but today it serves a reminder that while &amp;ldquo;Felt Mountain 2&amp;rdquo; would have been nice, &amp;ldquo;Black Cherry&amp;rdquo; definitely benefitted from changing things up a bit. The Remix is mostly instrumental and adds even more Glitter beat stomp to Train, pleasant enough I guess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Orb, Live at Brighton Concord 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-orb---brighton-concord-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-orb---brighton-concord-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Went with my friend Nick to see The Orb at Concord 2 last night. The last time I&amp;rsquo;d seen the Orb was back in 2004, at the start of their relatively dry spell. That night, they&amp;rsquo;d been a bit lacklustre despite playing (some of) the hits and a relatively decent album in &amp;ldquo;Bicycles and Tricycles&amp;rdquo;. I left feeling that I&amp;rsquo;d seen the past rather than the future, something that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t glimpse again in their records until 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #39: Lifeforms by Future Sound of London</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-39/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-39/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lifeforms&lt;/strong&gt; is the 1994 album from the Future Sound of London. A double album (just), it also features the talents of Robert Fripp, Ozric Tentacles, Talvin Singh, Toni Halliday, and Liz Frazer. It reached number 6 on the UK album chart and went silver.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have wanted to write about the &lt;strong&gt;Lifeforms&lt;/strong&gt; album for a long time. In 2012, I even tried learning how to tell the tracks apart from one another. It was not a success. Ten years later, I know some of them but not all. I know all the music, of course, but the album as a whole resists my trainspotter-like urge to identify the margins and components of every track.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics Or Not?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-or-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-or-not/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the new year, thoughts and spare time for writing point me toward writing some new posts for my understated classics series. Expect some new ones soon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I also reflected on my previous choices and thought a bit about how my music tastes have changed recently. Some of this has to do with streaming and the frustrations I wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/a-pox-on-both-their-houses&#34;&gt;in my last post&lt;/a&gt;. Some of it is just down to getting older: I have less time to listen to new music, and much of the &amp;rsquo;new&amp;rsquo; stuff I listen to is me investigating the stuff I missed first time around. Who knew Art of Noise were so good? Not me, but I do now!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A pox on both their houses</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-pox-on-both-their-houses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-pox-on-both-their-houses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How hard is it to just listen to music these days?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spotify has crammed in all sorts of crap in to the app lately. Lyric videos, those weird interactive art things that are turned on by default, podcasts (so many podcasts), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22798338/spotify-netflix-hub-exclusive-audio-extras&#34;&gt;Netflix tie-ins&lt;/a&gt;, and audiobooks. It wants to be the app that opens when you plug in your headphones (not that we’ll be doing that for much longer the way things are going). But I just want to listen to music!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If anything, make it weirder</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/make-it-weird/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/make-it-weird/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I listened to &amp;lsquo;Cloudbusting&amp;rsquo; by Kate Bush for the first time in a while. What a gloriously strange song it is. Best of all, it&amp;rsquo;s one of those songs that obscures what it is really about. It&amp;rsquo;s not a song about a change in the weather, but about &lt;a href=&#34;https://wilhelmreichmuseum.org/about/biography-of-wilhelm-reich/&#34;&gt;Wilhelm Reich&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Orgone&#34;&gt;orgone&lt;/a&gt; accumulator, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cultofweird.com/medical/radium-girls/&#34;&gt;fluorescent yo-yos&lt;/a&gt;, and a son (rather than a &lt;em&gt;sun&lt;/em&gt;) coming out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Cloudbusting&amp;rsquo; is from &amp;lsquo;Hounds of Love&amp;rsquo;, Kate&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;comeback&amp;rsquo; album following the commercial failure of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/understated-classics-19&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;The Dreaming&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;, an album I wrote about in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/tag/understated%20classics/&#34;&gt;understated classics series&lt;/a&gt;. It features four UK top 10 singles and some of her best work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #38: Trance Nation (Various Artists)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-38/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-38/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, but lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been in need of some music that:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Blots out the outside world&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Helps me to concentrate on my work&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Makes me feel a bit less anxious about the state of the world&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, allow me to submit the compilation Trance Nation for your consideration as an understated classic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But Matt I&amp;rsquo;ve heard trance music, I hear you say, and it&amp;rsquo;s one of the least understated forms of music possible. Yes, dear reader, we &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; talking about that borderline obnoxious musical form with the thudding beats and the tinkly high synth lines. Indeed, it is a genre that has grown and eaten itself, and the rest of pop music along with it. The &amp;ldquo;give it a drop or go home&amp;rdquo; mentality that infects modern pop musics originates in Trance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve listened to music in slightly different ways to normal in the last nine months, but it’s still been a decent year for music. When I checked out my Spotify Unwrapped and my Last.fm reports, I had listened to more 2020 music than I thought.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;december&#34;&gt;December&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Album of the month had to be &amp;ldquo;We Will Always Love You&amp;rdquo; by the Avalanches. One of only three albums that I bought physical copies of this year, it combines my favourite musical genres and has a novel take on the spacey-sounding album: like something beamed into space about how great humans are. That&amp;rsquo;s probably something we needed to be reminded of come the end of the year. In many ways, the Fermi paradox reminds us that quarantine and isolation are in many ways the default human condition. Even so, a signal to the outside universe must be sent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holiday Tabs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/holiday-tabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/holiday-tabs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the course of a week on holiday, I started reading many interesting articles. In lockdown there isn&amp;rsquo;t much to do but read articles, but I still find myself not that good at finishing them. My phone has lots of tabs open and has become a Rolodex of shame. This post is to confess my sins.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m trying to re-familiarise myself with Python. As with all modern software development, Python now seems atomised and hyper-complicated. As a result, this series of posts from Claudio Jolowitz was useful. He cuts through lots of the complications and explains why they are there. Someone should ask him to write a book.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #37: Lost Souls by Doves</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-37/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Doves are a band from Manchester who traded dance music for rock yet never left their former genre behind. Starting out as Sub Sub, they scored a worldwide hit in 1993 with &amp;ldquo;Ain&amp;rsquo;t No Love (Ain&amp;rsquo;t No Use)&amp;rdquo;: a timeless dance tune that immediately owns whatever room it plays in. However, subsequent releases by Sub Sub did not catch on and people started to think of the band as a one-hit wonder.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About the Album Digest</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/about-the-album-digest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 20:13:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/about-the-album-digest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t written one of my monthly album digests for over a year. The reasons mostly boil down to a lack of time and motivation but other factors include the changing way in which I listen to music. I bought more albums on vinyl and only a small proportion of those were recently released music. Meanwhile, the attractions of Spotify&amp;rsquo;s release radar proved too great to resist: it is a very convenient way to consume new music.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Albums 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/top-10-albums-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/top-10-albums-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-grails-chalice-hymnal&#34;&gt;10. Grails &amp;ldquo;Chalice Hymnal&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some albums are good because a band continues making the music that you love. Some albums are good because a band takes their ideas a step or two further than before. Chalice Hymnal is that rare album that does both of these things.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The references to past albums include the track Deeper Politics and Deep Snow II, and, as per albums past, these tracks evolve slowly out of languid guitar hooks and smoky atmospherics. If it ain’t broke don’t fix it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Songs 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/top-10-songs-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/top-10-songs-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-rolling-blackouts-cf-julies-place&#34;&gt;10. Rolling Blackouts CF &amp;ldquo;Julie&amp;rsquo;s Place&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you just want a simple pop song about going out somewhere. I enjoyed the Rolling Blackouts&amp;rsquo; EP &amp;ldquo;The French Press&amp;rdquo;. It contains many catchy tunes &lt;a href=&#34;album-digest-march-2017&#34;&gt;as I noted in my review&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;ldquo;Julie&amp;rsquo;s Place&amp;rdquo; is the best, speaking of a need to be somewhere or a promise that you will go there. Given that I often listen to music between places, it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have a song or two like that on my playlist.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, December 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-december-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-december-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;bjork-utopia&#34;&gt;Bjork &lt;em&gt;Utopia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Utopia&amp;rdquo; is Björk&amp;rsquo;s ninth album. It&amp;rsquo;s a happier album compared to the emotional wreckage of &amp;ldquo;Vulnicura&amp;rdquo;. But while &amp;ldquo;Vulnicura&amp;rdquo; was a compelling if uncomfortable listen, &amp;ldquo;Utopia&amp;rdquo; is more comfortable and, unfortunately, not that compelling. This is old ground retrodden with few glimmers of past glories.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The brevity, succinctness and sharpness are all gone. Even on the best songs (the first three), there is very little strength in the lyrics. The music is all texture and no melody. And while formlessness and adaptability are central to the album&amp;rsquo;s lyrical themes, the songs themselves are ill-served by allowing these same concepts to take hold of their arrangements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, November 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;00110100-01010100-0181&#34;&gt;00110100 01010100 &amp;ldquo;0181&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a reissue of a Four Tet rarity from 2013 that has recently surfaced on Spotify under an alias&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &amp;ldquo;0181&amp;rdquo; collects a series of short experimental pieces from throughout his career, though I&amp;rsquo;m not enough of a nerd to know whether they are in any particular order. &lt;a href=&#34;album-digest-october-2017&#34;&gt;Last month&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;proper&amp;rsquo; Four Tet album &amp;ldquo;New Energy&amp;rdquo; has a lot more bounce to it, but &amp;ldquo;0181&amp;rdquo; nevertheless has some interesting moments that raises it above mere curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Will Make Room For You - Four Tet Remix</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/i-will-make-room-for-you---four-tet-remix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/i-will-make-room-for-you---four-tet-remix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a perfect confluence of &lt;a href=&#34;album-digest-october-2011&#34;&gt;last month&amp;rsquo;s album digest&lt;/a&gt;, here&amp;rsquo;s an excellent Four Tet remix of Kaitlyn Aurelia Smith&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;I Will Make Room For You&amp;rdquo; from her album &amp;ldquo;The Kid&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ve put it into a playlist with &amp;ldquo;Lush&amp;rdquo; from Four Tet&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;New Energy&amp;rdquo; album and the original version of &amp;ldquo;I Will Make Room For You.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, October 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;mary-epworth-elytral&#34;&gt;Mary Epworth &amp;ldquo;Elytral&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This album came to my attention because its lead single &amp;ldquo;Me Swimming&amp;rdquo; appeared on my Discover Weekly playlist. I&amp;rsquo;d never heard of Mary before but this album was one of those nice discoveries that one sometimes makes when one tries to broaden what one listens to. The aforementioned &amp;ldquo;Me Swimming&amp;rdquo; is probably the best track, a beautiful slice of summery experimental pop layered over a beat that you can imagine as the kicks of a swimmer compared to the swirling lyric that imitates the pull of the strokes through the water. Or the other way round. I was a latecomer to swimming, I&amp;rsquo;m not very good at it. But I do know a good song when I hear one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #36: The Coral by The Coral</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-36/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-36/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Perhaps in today&amp;rsquo;s modern age of streaming and such, &lt;a href=&#34;http://thecoral.co.uk&#34;&gt;The Coral&lt;/a&gt; would be a bigger band and may have survived their eventual burnout. Their work ethic was evident from the start, as rumours swirled &lt;a href=&#34;https://i.ebayimg.com/images/g/YdkAAOSwfl9XBSiR/s-l300.jpg&#34;&gt;in the NME&lt;/a&gt; about a fantastic new band from Liverpool who were going to blow everybody&amp;rsquo;s socks off. I went to see them live in Bristol after they&amp;rsquo;d released three EPs and they were incredible. Their sound, a bit like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0071615/&#34;&gt;the movie &amp;ldquo;Holy Mountain&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; set to pop music, imagined a Merseybeat channelled from an alternative universe in which Lennon and McCartney took their acid in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.desertusa.com/mojave-desert.html&#34;&gt;the Mojave desert&lt;/a&gt; rather than in the English suburbs. Yes, it was derivative but somehow it also managed to be utterly new and compelling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note: Recent months have been very busy, so this album digest combines a review of the new album by The National with a couple of reviews left over from earlier in the year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written a few more album reviews in the past months but I&amp;rsquo;m so far behind (February and March have already been published on a considerable lag) that I&amp;rsquo;m just going to pepper forthcoming digests with additional reviews of older albums.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #35: Snivilisation by Orbital</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-35/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I came late to Orbital&amp;rsquo;s work. I knew of them through a few remixes and because as a mad Orb fan, they could not have avoided my notice could they? Apart from that, one of my college friends tried to get me into &amp;ldquo;In Sides&amp;rdquo; just after its release in 1996. The same friend got me into &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/understated-classics-11/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Second Toughest In The Infants&amp;rdquo; by Underworld&lt;/a&gt;. I cannot now understand the reason, but &amp;ldquo;In Sides&amp;rdquo; just left me cold.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, March 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;blanck-mass-world-eater&#34;&gt;Blanck Mass &lt;em&gt;World Eater&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This album is pretty extreme. It&amp;rsquo;s not for everyone and even for the people who &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; handle it, it&amp;rsquo;s not for all the time. This album is a soul crushing experience at points but there are also points of light. Perhaps this makes “World Eater” more reflective of life as a whole than any other of this month&amp;rsquo;s albums. On balance it&amp;rsquo;s probably less crushing than the last Blanck Mass album “Dumb Flesh”, which I reviewed back in June 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, February 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;grails-chalice-hymnal&#34;&gt;Grails &lt;em&gt;Chalice Hymnal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some albums are good because a band continues making the music that you love. Some albums are good because a band takes their ideas a step or two further than before. &lt;em&gt;Chalice Hymnal&lt;/em&gt;is that rare album that does both of these things.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The references to past albums include the track &lt;em&gt;Deeper Politics&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Deep Snow II&lt;/em&gt;, and, as per albums past, these tracks evolve slowly out of languid guitar hooks and smoky atmospherics. If it ain&amp;rsquo;t broke don&amp;rsquo;t fix it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, January 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;mike-oldfield-return-to-ommadawn&#34;&gt;Mike Oldfield &lt;em&gt;Return to Ommadawn&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With &lt;em&gt;Return to Ommadawn&lt;/em&gt;, Mike Oldfield revisits his third album Ommadawn. He has past form for this, having revisited his masterwork Tubular Bells twice (the third revisit and fourth instalment Tubular Bells 4 is due next year). I wrote about Tubular Bells II for my understated classics series. Of course Mike has in fact made many more than three Tubular Bells albums&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and this is not a first &amp;ldquo;return&amp;rdquo; to Ommadawn. His 1990 album Amorok was a similar affair.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #34: Stray by Aztec Camera</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-34/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next instalment in my understated classics series is &amp;quot;Stray&amp;quot; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://killermontstreet.net&#34;&gt;Aztec Camera&lt;/a&gt;. Released in 1990, it features two hit singles and the cover is my favourite colour: green.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My angle for writing about “Stray” was that it was an album that I &amp;quot;caught&amp;quot; from my parents. I soon realised that I wrote about some of those already, for example “The Circle and the Square&amp;quot; by Red Box. Besides, I’m not sure that my parents liked this album that much.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month&amp;rsquo;s album digest features albums by Wilco, M.I.A., Local Natives, and a collaboration between Kaitlyn Aurelia Smith and Suzanne Ciani.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;wilco-schmilco&#34;&gt;Wilco &lt;em&gt;Schmilco&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Schmilco&lt;/em&gt; is the tenth studio album by Wilco, which regular readers will know are one of my favourite bands. &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/whatever-happened-to-that-hat/&#34;&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no need to repeat that anecdote about why this blog has the name that it does.&lt;/a&gt; Meanwhile, this album follows on from last year&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; and is probably the third Wilco album to have a jokey meta- kind of title. (The other one is the rather splendid &lt;em&gt;Wilco (The Album)&lt;/em&gt; from 2009.) I didn&amp;rsquo;t write a review of &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;; it  was released for free and for some reason it passed me by. &lt;em&gt;Schmilco&lt;/em&gt; is a fairly similar album and that&amp;rsquo;s not a bad thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adventures with Discover Weekly</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/adventures-with-discover-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/adventures-with-discover-weekly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any albums coming out this month that I wanted to review for the album digest, I decided to let Spotify pick the albums to listen to. I listened to my algorithmically chosen &lt;a href=&#34;https://techcrunch.com/2015/07/20/why-browse-when-you-can-play/&#34;&gt;Discover Weekly&lt;/a&gt; playlist one week and selected albums based on the songs that I liked the most. The album also had to be released in 2016. The selections are ones that got away.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve done this before. &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/album-digest-august-2012/&#34;&gt;Three of the four albums that I wrote about in August four years ago&lt;/a&gt; were selected by &lt;a href=&#34;https://bleep.com&#34;&gt;Bleep&lt;/a&gt;: they were in the &amp;lsquo;best albums of the year so far&amp;rsquo; bundle that I bought. So this month&amp;rsquo;s album digest is bought to you by the same idea, just a different curator.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BBC Prom 47 at the Royal Albert Hall</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bbc-prom-47-royal-albert-hall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bbc-prom-47-royal-albert-hall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We went to see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ulsterorchestra.org.uk/events/2016-08-21/&#34;&gt;Prom 47&lt;/a&gt;, an afternoon prom at the Royal Albert Hall in London. The bill included a brand new work by &lt;a href=&#34;http://piershellawell.com&#34;&gt;Piers Hellawell&lt;/a&gt;, along with a Cello concerto by &lt;a href=&#34;http://classicalmusic.about.com/od/classicalcomposers/p/haydnprofile.htm&#34;&gt;Haydn&lt;/a&gt; and a symphony by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.britannica.com/biography/Pyotr-Ilyich-Tchaikovsky&#34;&gt;Tchaikovsky&lt;/a&gt;. These were all performed by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ulsterorchestra.org.uk&#34;&gt;Ulster Orchestra&lt;/a&gt;. The conductor was Rafael Payare. The tickets were an affordable £17 each which isn&amp;rsquo;t bad at all given that we were sat in the second row of the circle. We had a great view.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, July 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Album Digest July 2016 consists of a bumper five albums, mainly because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t work out which one to drop. I think they&amp;rsquo;re all pretty good though it&amp;rsquo;s great to hear new music from The Avalanches after all this time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;bat-for-lashes-the-bride&#34;&gt;Bat For Lashes &amp;ldquo;The Bride&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For her fourth album as Bat For Lashes, Natasha Khan applies her considerable songwriting skills to a concept album. She sings from the perspective of a bride whose husband dies on his way to their wedding. Almost all artists would deliver this subject matter in a melodramatic way, but Khan focusses on the sadness and delivers a beautiful suite of songs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #33: Embrya by Maxwell</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-33/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I give the impression of planning these posts but to be honest I came across an article about Maxwell a few weeks ago and fondly remembered my cassette copy of this album. The joy of Spotify is that it&amp;rsquo;s easy to dig up old favourites. The recent warm weather makes for a good opportunity to enjoy the sultry embrace of &amp;ldquo;Embrya&amp;rdquo; once more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Gestation: Mythos&amp;rdquo; burbles along for two and a half minutes, overlaying spoken word samples, string phrases and weird underwater noises, before the bass line of &amp;ldquo;Everwanting: To Want You To Want&amp;rdquo; brings things to life. Over a sinuous and aquatic background, Maxwell delivers a smooth and soulful vocal. As you might guess from the title, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely one for your late nights and warm evenings playlist. I love the way that the song takes its time: it knows where it needs to go, it knows how to get there, and damned if it isn&amp;rsquo;t going to enjoy itself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Album Digest June 2016 is a poppy batch of albums. We have the return of my long-time favourites Roxette and the heroes of my South American tour Tegan &amp;amp; Sara. There&amp;rsquo;s some dance music in the form of Flume&amp;rsquo;s album &amp;ldquo;Skin&amp;rdquo;: an Australian presence ahead of the new Avalanches album next month. Finally there is the first of two new albums by Islands - both were released back in May but one gets reviewed this month and the other next month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, May 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Album Digest May 2016 features the work of four bands or artists that I have reviewed in previous album digests. I also own (or will own) all of these albums on vinyl, so it&amp;rsquo;s handy that I&amp;rsquo;ve recently bought myself a record player!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;radiohead-a-moon-shaped-pool&#34;&gt;Radiohead &amp;ldquo;A Moon Shaped Pool&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Radiohead released &amp;ldquo;A Moon Shaped Pool&amp;rdquo; online about three weeks ago and a physical version hits the shops later in June. As with all of their recent albums, it is (mostly) a slow burner that rewards multiple listens.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, April 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month&amp;rsquo;s album digest is a mixture of comparisons. First we compare the fortunes of old hands Underworld to even older hands the Pet Shop Boys. After that I&amp;rsquo;ve found two dance albums, one that I liked and one that I didn&amp;rsquo;t. I find it quite hard to write about dance music and so the comparison is quite useful. Sometimes it helps to work out why you like one thing and not another.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Orb - Alpine EP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/orb-alpine-ep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/orb-alpine-ep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Orb return with a new EP on the &lt;a href=&#34;www.kompakt.fm&#34;&gt;Kompakt label&lt;/a&gt; called &amp;ldquo;Alpine&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Alpine&amp;rdquo; is split in to three tracks &amp;ldquo;Morning&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Evening&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Dawn&amp;rdquo;. The third of these was included on the 2016 edition of Kompakt&amp;rsquo;s annual &amp;ldquo;Pop Ambient&amp;rdquo; compilation, a gently drifting track with plenty of bells and yodels. A diversion from the sounds of &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/album-digest-june-2015/&#34;&gt;Moonbuilding 2703 AD&lt;/a&gt; (and its presumably ongoing remixed companion EPs), but it sat nicely with the other tracks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, David Bowie RIP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-special-david-bowie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-special-david-bowie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought I&amp;rsquo;d add three of my favourite David Bowie albums to my review of Blackstar to a form an album digest tribute. Also among my favourites but not included here is &amp;ldquo;Outside&amp;rdquo;, which will be included in the understated classics (currently it&amp;rsquo;s number 66) at some point. I thought about bumping &amp;ldquo;Outside&amp;rdquo; up the running order but I&amp;rsquo;d like to be objective about it when its turn comes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;station-to-station&#34;&gt;Station To Station&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not the side effects of the cocaine / I&amp;rsquo;m thinking it must be love&amp;rdquo; sings Bowie on the title track of his tenth studio album &amp;ldquo;Station To Station&amp;rdquo;, released in 1976. But this album is most definitely almost entirely built on cocaine, from the weird Kabbalah channeling title track, to the smooth funk of &amp;ldquo;Golden Years&amp;rdquo; and on toward to the weepy conclusion of his cover of &amp;ldquo;Wild Is The Wind&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Favourite Albums of 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/favourite-albums-of-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/favourite-albums-of-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Given that I gave up on writing album digests for a bit this year, I thought I would at least do a proper top ten list of my favourite albums. There are quite a few albums that I did not have room for and I might try to revisit those later. In the mean time, let&amp;rsquo;s crack on. (To save time, I have in some instances pasted my original review from the appropriate album digest.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Underworld, Second Toughest in the Infants (Superdeluxe edition)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/second-toughest-in-the-infants-superdeluxe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/second-toughest-in-the-infants-superdeluxe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week Underworld reissued their excellent second album “Second Toughest In The Infants” in various formats including a four disc super deluxe edition. I wrote about this album in my understated classics series and I want to share some thoughts on the reissue. I love this album so I was excited to hear the remaster and the additional material.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I can’t comment on the physical version of the release as I can’t afford it at the moment. I also had to wait to buy the gorgeous yellow reissue of “Dubnobasswithmyheadman” but the “Second Toughest In The Infants” box is on the list. Underworld do a really good job on the boxes with interesting artwork to accompany the large volume of material. If the “Dubnobasswithmyheadman” box is anything to go by, the new one will be pretty hefty on the coffee table.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #32: They Were Wrong So We Drowned by Liars</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-32/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As it is Halloween, I&amp;rsquo;m writing about a spooky understated classic. Liars&amp;rsquo; second album &amp;ldquo;They Were Wrong, So We Drowned&amp;rdquo; is a concept album about witches. It was the first of their albums that I owned having heard their name mentioned among those in the New York Post-punk revival scene at the start of the 00s.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I imagine that to most ears a first listen to &amp;ldquo;They Were Wrong, So We Drowned&amp;rdquo; sounds dreadful. I certainly thought so. It&amp;rsquo;s a short album and if you plough through it there are one or two nuggets that would sound great on most albums - but a lot of it initially seems to be noise and chanting and screaming. If anyone wants to make the argument that Liars are not worth the trouble, not worth the effort to like or understand, then &amp;ldquo;They Were Wrong, So We Drowned&amp;rdquo; is the album they will use as ammunition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everything Everything, Get To Heaven</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/everything-everything-get-to-heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/everything-everything-get-to-heaven/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write honestly about your feelings. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write about your feelings consistently, for a living on a regular basis. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write about your feelings when the world constantly intrudes with inanity, insanity and hatred. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write under those conditions without seeming frayed, without coming loose at the edges.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Get To Heaven&amp;rdquo;, the third album by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.everything-everything.co.uk&#34;&gt;Everything Everything&lt;/a&gt;, was forged under these stresses and pressures. For most of its running time it sounds like either a bomb ticking down to explode or like a clock inexorably counting up missed opportunities and stolen moments. It sounds for all the world as though it is trapped between fight and flight, paused between action and apathy. Yet it also subjects the listener to the yammerings of a culture that has driven itself mad. Depth and surface, glass and steel, truth and lies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #31: The White Room by The KLF</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-31/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This little masterpiece was released in 1991. I got my copy on cassette for Christmas that year, but by May in 1992 they&amp;rsquo;d already &amp;ldquo;retired&amp;rdquo; and split up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The KLF were a band in the right place at the right time with the right idea. Taking advantage of synthesizers and the idea of fusing rock and pop music with the emerging sound of house music, they laid the ground for many of the most successful electronic acts that followed them. They were also master showmen, taking a whole host of crazy conspiracy theories and smooshing them together in one stadium-sized package.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Initial Comparison of Apple Music and Spotify</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/an-initial-comparison-of-apple-music-and-spotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/an-initial-comparison-of-apple-music-and-spotify/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/why-apple-music-feels-like-a-fail/&#34;&gt;previous post about Apple Music&lt;/a&gt; was more a response to how it was presented at the WWDC Keynote rather than to the idea of Apple Music itself. I should have known better than to use that clickbait title. I knew I wasn&amp;rsquo;t writing about the product, more the flatness of its introduction (despite the names on show).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After a few days of living with it I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write about it and Spotify, so that it&amp;rsquo;s not just my snarky comments about the keynote that are on record here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To reboot this series, Album Digest June 2015 features five fantastic albums from Hot Chip, Jamie xx, Blanck Mass, Holly Herndon, and The Orb. I could pick loads more as I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to a lot of albums since &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/album-digest-february-2015/&#34;&gt;February&lt;/a&gt; but I decided to focus on the more electronic material. This means that I have no excuses for not continuing next month with a rockier theme.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;hot-chip-why-make-sense&#34;&gt;Hot Chip &amp;ldquo;Why Make Sense?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hot Chip seem to be settling in to a pattern with their album releases, alternating between messy experimental affairs and then a state of the art correction. Witness how &amp;ldquo;The Warning&amp;rdquo; smartened up the all-over-the-place &amp;ldquo;Coming On Strong&amp;rdquo; and how &amp;ldquo;One Life Stand&amp;rdquo; moulded and matured the lovestruck meandering of &amp;ldquo;Made In The Dark&amp;rdquo; into a lithe ten song set. &amp;ldquo;Why Make Sense?&amp;rdquo; takes the earnest song-based approach of &amp;ldquo;In Our Heads&amp;rdquo; and casts it into a funky fun-filled fifty minutes. It&amp;rsquo;s as concise as they&amp;rsquo;ve been since &amp;ldquo;One Life Stand&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #30: Our Aim Is to Satisfy by Red Snapper</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The thirtieth understated classic is by a band named after a fish. There isn&amp;rsquo;t a great deal for me to say about &amp;ldquo;Our Aim Is To Satisfy&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; apart from the usual insistence that it is quite good. There&amp;rsquo;s no overarching theme to write about, and no deep personal story attached. It was bound to happen eventually.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our Aim Is To Satisfy&amp;rdquo; is one of those albums spawned in the late nineties and early naughties at the height of the Electronica boom: dance music that you didn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily have to dance to. It&amp;rsquo;s not quite chill out music but nor is it song-based (for the most part) - it&amp;rsquo;s mainly instrumental electronic music.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Can’t Just Switch Off Free</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-cant-just-switch-off-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-cant-just-switch-off-free/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2015/mar/11/ministry-of-sound-streaming-switch-off-free&#34;&gt;Ministry of Sound boss Lohan Presencer does the cry baby act in today&amp;rsquo;s Guardian&lt;/a&gt;, complaining that Spotify&amp;rsquo;s freemium model doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow him to bathe in a Scrooge McDuck style swimming pool of golden coins any more. The cat is out of the bag for streaming music now, and no matter how much music companies cry foul they can&amp;rsquo;t stop Spotify and their ilk, and there wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be pots of gold waiting for them even if they could.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, February 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;aphex-twin-computer-controlled-acoustic-instruments-pt2-ep&#34;&gt;Aphex Twin &amp;ldquo;Computer Controlled Acoustic Instruments Pt2 EP&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aphex Twin follows SYRO (reviewed in &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/album-digest-september-2014/&#34;&gt;Album Digest September 2014 here&lt;/a&gt;) with this 27 minute EP of music that, if we take the title literally, features computers playing acoustic musical instruments. It&amp;rsquo;s a very different sound to SYRO and sounds acoustic for the most part. It&amp;rsquo;s an important experiment about the role of the musician, one that is already blurred in the creation of electronic music.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #29: Let It Come Down by Spiritualized</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I listened to Let It Come Down by Spiritualized for the first time during a difficult time in my life. I think this will always affect my feelings towards it. For me it&amp;rsquo;s a great big comfort blanket of a record. Coming after one of the all-time best break-up albums (in an artistic sense) in &amp;ldquo;Ladies and Gentlemen We Are Floating in Space&amp;rdquo; perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s not that much of a surprise. Layered in orchestras, horn sections, and gospel choirs, it&amp;rsquo;s not understated at all but hopefully I can persuade you that it is a classic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, January 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Album Digest January 2015 rounds up a few albums from the tail end of 2014 that I didn&amp;rsquo;t get much time to write about. The only one of these six to be released this month is the excellent &amp;ldquo;No Cities To Love&amp;rdquo; by Sleater-Kinney.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;sleater-kinney-no-cities-to-love&#34;&gt;Sleater-Kinney &amp;ldquo;No Cities To Love&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had heard of Sleater-Kinney before their boxed set “Start Together” was released in 2014. I was quite impressed that they curated their own Spotify playlist with the contents of the box. I added it and even downloaded the songs for offline listening but didn’t get around to much more than a cursory play of a few tracks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #28: The Meadowlands by The Wrens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-28/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the first lines of &amp;ldquo;The House That Guilt Built&amp;rdquo;, the soft cricket-laden lament that opens The Meadowlands by The Wrens, is &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m nowhere near where I thought I&amp;rsquo;d be&amp;rdquo;. The last line of the whole album is &amp;ldquo;this is not what you had planned&amp;rdquo;. These bookending lines set the tone for this shimmering, ramshackle masterpiece - a fatigue and careworn pride in failing to meet impossible standards writ large over its first and last eighty or so seconds. &amp;ldquo;The Meadowlands&amp;rdquo; is probably the best record you&amp;rsquo;ve never heard, and once you have heard it, you will never be the same. Even better, it changes and you change with every single listen. If you&amp;rsquo;re living your life and you really mean it, then this is the record for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Album Digest September 2014 contains four amazing albums, including the long-awaited return from the Aphex Twin, and an album from Cymbals Eat Guitars released about a week after I wondered what had happened to them. Spooky. Rounding out the selection this month are a cool punky-disco album by The Juan Maclean and a truly remarkable offering by Vessel.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;aphex-twin-syro&#34;&gt;Aphex Twin &lt;em&gt;SYRO&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SYRO&lt;/em&gt; is the sixth album by Aphex Twin and his first official Aphex Twin release since Drukqs in 2001. Announced with a typically cryptic track listing at a month&amp;rsquo;s notice via the dark web, along with artwork that resembles a tax receipt for the costs of releasing the album, his anarchic streak appears intact. Therefore the most suprising thing about SYRO is just how conventional it sounds on first listen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The album digest returns with five albums by four artists.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Karl Hyde &amp;amp; Brian Eno &lt;em&gt;Someday World&lt;/em&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;HIGH-LIFE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lone &lt;em&gt;Reality Testing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;FKA twigs &lt;em&gt;LP1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mogwai &lt;em&gt;Come On Die Young: Appendix&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;karl-hyde--brian-eno-someday-world--high-life&#34;&gt;Karl Hyde &amp;amp; Brian Eno &lt;em&gt;Someday World&lt;/em&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;HIGH-LIFE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m a big fan of both Karl Hyde’s work with Underworld and of Brian Eno’s stuff so Someday World seemed like a dream collaboration to me when it was released last May. I was a bit underwhelmed by it, to the point of overlooking it for &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/album-digest-may-2014/&#34;&gt;May’s album digest&lt;/a&gt;. Last month they released a follow-up called High-Life, which includes some of the more experimental tracks they’d worked on. Together the two albums are greater than the some of their parts, so I’m writing about both of them together this month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #27: A Ghost Is Born by Wilco</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;whatever-happened-to-that-hat&#34;&gt;I have already given some of the personal background to why I love this album&lt;/a&gt; and now it’s time to give a bit of love to the music itself so I’ll stick to giving a track by track account of “A Ghost Is Born”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are familiar with Wilco’s first few albums, you’ll know that A Ghost Is Born is on the line of best fit through Being There, Summerteeth, and Yankee Hotel Foxtrot. It continues its predecessor’s experimentation, but also gets reined in a little. Great songs - some of my favourite Wilco songs - were left off Yankee Hotel Foxtrot (“&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bemydemon.org/songs/venus.htm&#34;&gt;Venus Stopped The Train&lt;/a&gt;”, “&lt;a href=&#34;http://wilcoworld.net/#!/song/a-magazine-called-sunset/&#34;&gt;A Magazine Called Sunset&lt;/a&gt;”) so the follow-up could easily have been more of the same and everyone would have gone home happy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What IS That Noise?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-that-noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-that-noise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently spruced up a post I wrote four years ago about &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/articles/uc4/&#34;&gt;Biosphere’s wonderful album Substrata&lt;/a&gt;. I added the following footnote about the difference between voice samples and found sound:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I suppose I am distinguishing between found sound and vocal samples here. Perhaps there is very little difference, or that one is the other? When is a vocal snippet something more than found sound? Is it the fact that one has meaning? Isn’t a “meaningless” sample - like the ones here in Russian that I can’t understand - little more than found sound anyway?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Amazing Subversive Revolutionary Adolescence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-amazing-subversive-revolutionary-adolescence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-amazing-subversive-revolutionary-adolescence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;or-at-least-its-subversive-soundtrack&#34;&gt;Or at least its subversive soundtrack…&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I listened to The Orb’s amazing live album “Live ’93” the other day (after discovering the insipid “History Of The Future” collection on Spotify) and I was amazed at how countercultural and subversive it was. I was listening to this stuff at the age of 14 and now that I’m old enough to be a parent, that makes me a bit uncomfortable. Actually it does nothing of the sort, because it&amp;rsquo;s frigging awesome.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #26: Come On Die Young by Mogwai</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you about punk rock: punk rock is a word used by dilettantes and ah&amp;hellip; and ah&amp;hellip; heartless manipulators about music that takes up the energies and the bodies and the hearts and the souls and the time and the minds of young men who give what they have to it and give everything they have to it and it&amp;rsquo;s a&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s a term that&amp;rsquo;s based on contempt, it&amp;rsquo;s a term that&amp;rsquo;s based on fashion, style, elitism, satanism and everything that&amp;rsquo;s rotten about rock &amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo; roll. I don&amp;rsquo;t know &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/John_Lydon&#34;&gt;Johnny Rotten&lt;/a&gt; but I&amp;rsquo;m sure&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m sure he puts as much blood and sweat into what he does as &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Sigmund_Freud&#34;&gt;Sigmund Freud&lt;/a&gt; did. You see, what sounds to you like a big load of trashy old noise is in fact the brilliant music of a genius, myself . And that music is so powerful that it&amp;rsquo;s quite beyond my control and ah&amp;hellip; when I&amp;rsquo;m in the grips of it I don&amp;rsquo;t feel pleasure and I don&amp;rsquo;t feel pain, either physically or emotionally. Do you understand what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about? Have you ever felt like that? When you just couldn&amp;rsquo;t feel anything and you didn&amp;rsquo;t want to either. You know? Like that? Do you understand what I&amp;rsquo;m saying sir? (Iggy Pop, Canadian TV, March 11th 1977.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://temporaryresidence.com/artists/watter&#34;&gt;Watter&lt;/a&gt; are a &amp;ldquo;supergroup&amp;rdquo; composed from various members of Grails, &lt;a href=&#34;http://touchandgorecords.com/bands/band.php?id=70&#34;&gt;Slint&lt;/a&gt;, and other bands. I did not know anything about Hundred Waters before this month: &amp;ldquo;The Moon Rang Like A Bell&amp;rdquo; is their second album. In fact second albums by bands I know nothing about are a something of theme because &amp;ldquo;Sunbathing Animal&amp;rdquo; is Parquet Courts&amp;rsquo; sophomore effort and I don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about them either. Meanwhile, I&amp;rsquo;ve meant to write about &amp;ldquo;The Four Seasons Recomposed&amp;rdquo; since April.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, May 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month was strange. I didn’t listen to much new music and after &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/album-digest-april-2014/&#34;&gt;last month’s bumper digest&lt;/a&gt; there’s probably a reason for that. Not to mention that Spotify gives you more reasons to look backwards than forwards. Nevertheless, this brief post features new albums by Little Dragon and Coldplay, along with the mini-album collaboration between Röyskopp and Robyn.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;little-dragon-nabuma-rubberband&#34;&gt;Little Dragon “Nabuma Rubberband”&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I discovered Little Dragon, like most people, I imagine, via Gorillaz’ “Plastic Beach” album. When I investigated their “Machine Dreams” album I was surprised that their sound had transplanted to “Plastic Beach” intact. Sometimes you discover a band through a collaboration and their own work turns out to be disappointing, somehow diminished by the other artist(s) no longer being present. “Machine Dreams” is a fine album that breezes by, much like “Empire Ants” and “To Binge” do on “Plastic Beach”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, March 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m back in the UK so it’s back to posts about albums each month. This one is a bit different because I didn’t listen to very much new stuff while I was away so not all of the albums are up to date. I had to write about the new album by Liars though because it&amp;rsquo;s awesome and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait to discuss it! Here’s the list of albums:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tegan and Sarah &lt;em&gt;Heartthrob&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fanfarlo &lt;em&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s Go Extinct&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Liars &lt;em&gt;Mess&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;London Grammar &lt;em&gt;If You Wait&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tegan-and-sarah-_heartthrob_&#34;&gt;Tegan and Sarah &lt;em&gt;Heartthrob&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I would argue, as I have throughout my sequence of &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tags#understated-classics/&#34;&gt;understated classics&lt;/a&gt; posts, that a great album is one that changes you as a person. Sometimes an album changes your mood consistently, sometimes an album makes you think about the experiences in your life differently, and sometimes an album is just so great and comes along at just the right time to knock you for six. I’d say that in 2014 Tegan and Sara’s “Heartthrob” has been that album for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, October 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Four great albums this month for the last album digest in a while.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chvrches-the-bones-of-what-you-believe&#34;&gt;CHVRCHES &amp;ldquo;The Bones Of What You Believe&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I first got into CHVRCHES on Record Store Day, one of my purchases was an Irn Bru coloured 12&amp;quot; of the Recover EP that, according to eBay, tripled in value over night. Judging by this, their full debut, my see-through orange slab of happiness may hold its value, because it&amp;rsquo;s clear that CHVRCHES should be around for the long haul. &amp;ldquo;The Bones Of What You Believe&amp;rdquo; is a master class in upbeat pop songwriting that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to pander to the lowest common denominator.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A nice diverse selection of albums this month:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Arctic Monkeys &amp;ldquo;AM&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;BT &amp;ldquo;A Song Across Wires&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Goldfrapp &amp;ldquo;Tales of Us&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Janelle Monáe &amp;ldquo;Electric Lady&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;arctic-monkeys-am&#34;&gt;Arctic Monkeys &amp;ldquo;AM&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This whole review is basically me catching up with the rest of the world and realising that the Arctic Monkeys are ace. To be fair, I did notice how awesome they were at the opening ceremony of the Olympics last year, and I have liked the odd one or two of their singles, but up until now I haven&amp;rsquo;t really wanted to listen to any of their albums. In fact before &amp;ldquo;AM&amp;rdquo;, I already had two (ripped from the CDs of friends) but had never bothered to listen to them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #25: Long Gone Before Daylight by The Cardigans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The single biggest fact of life is that you are always going to be alone, you just might not realise it. Listening to The Cardigans&amp;rsquo; excellent 2003 &amp;ldquo;Long Gone Before Daylight&amp;rdquo; will help you see that all our relationships are essentially screwed &amp;ndash; but at least it sounds great while it does so.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Long Gone Before Daylight&amp;rdquo; (&amp;ldquo;Long Gone Before Daylight&amp;rdquo;) plays the role of &amp;ldquo;The Empire Strikes Back&amp;rdquo; in a trilogy of great albums that The Cardigans released between 1999 (the arguably better and slightly happier &amp;ldquo;Gran Turismo&amp;rdquo;) and 2006 (the unarguably inferior and definitely happier &amp;ldquo;Super Extra Gravity&amp;rdquo;). &amp;ldquo;Long Gone Before Daylight&amp;rdquo; has more of a country sound than &amp;ldquo;Gran Turismo&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Super Extra Gravity&amp;rdquo;, which meant that I ignored it for a long time: until the disintegration and failure of several relationships convinced me of its brilliance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For reasons that will become apparent, there will be a short period soon where I will not be writing album digests. Until then, I&amp;rsquo;m clearing a backlog of some albums that I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to but haven&amp;rsquo;t had enough time or motivation to write about. Only one of this month&amp;rsquo;s albums was released this month, something that&amp;rsquo;s not that uncommon at this time of the year as it is not the best time to release things. Here&amp;rsquo;s the list:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, July 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another four albums for you this month. Sometimes the problem is not finding albums to listen to but actually finding time to listen to them! Often it is not because I don&amp;rsquo;t have time but because I have already found some great albums this month and I am busy listening to those instead. As a result, a couple of these albums are ones that I have only listened to for a week or so, but they are interesting enough to write about. Here are the four albums I am going to write about this month:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just two albums this month as I am still enjoying last month&amp;rsquo;s albums so much (and I spent loads of time getting reacquainted with Boards Of Canada at the start of the month). I listened to a few more albums but not often enough to write loads about them so there is an &amp;ldquo;honourable mention&amp;rdquo; section at the end of the post that briefly discusses a few more albums.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, the two albums are:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #24: Reservoir by Fanfarlo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have written a lot in these posts about how music gets indelibly tied up with places, events and feelings. For me this album by Fanfarlo is tied up with all three of these. It makes me happy and sad at the same time in memory of great times that are now gone but are fondly remembered. I am aware that this is the youngest album on the list so far and so it might be a bit early to endow classic status upon it, but &amp;ldquo;Reservoir&amp;rdquo; is a fine album and to my ears it stands up really well. Listening to it again in the course of writing this post I found that I remembered every note and musical phrase, and yet somehow I also managed to delight in hearing new features in the production that I&amp;rsquo;d not noticed before.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, May 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;lilacs--champagne-_danish--blue_&#34;&gt;Lilacs &amp;amp; Champagne &lt;em&gt;Danish &amp;amp; Blue&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You might remember that last year &lt;a href=&#34;album-digest-february-2012&#34;&gt;I reviewed the first Lilacs &amp;amp; Champagne album&lt;/a&gt; and I liked it a lot. This album sees them back with more of the same: taking the approach that if it ain&amp;rsquo;t broke, don&amp;rsquo;t fix it. There are very few changes to the formula apart from the fact that the spoken word samples are not quite as good this time and there&amp;rsquo;s a bit more Grails-like guitar solo action.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #23: Gorgeous by 808 State</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was quite hard to choose an 808 State album for the &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;understated classics series&lt;/a&gt; for two reasons. The first is that I was introduced to 808 State quite late through a friend&amp;rsquo;s sister&amp;rsquo;s cassette copy of The Shamen&amp;rsquo;s En-Tact (the original version recorded from vinyl that had a thirteen minute version of &amp;ldquo;Evil Is Eden&amp;rdquo;) that also had &amp;ndash; to fill out the C90 &amp;ndash; the full length sweary version of &amp;ldquo;What Time Is Love?&amp;rdquo; by The KLF and four tracks: &amp;ldquo;Cubik&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Pacific&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Olympic&amp;rdquo; (I think&amp;hellip;), and &amp;ldquo;In Yer Face&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, April 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some great albums this month!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Flaming Lips &lt;em&gt;The Terror&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wire &lt;em&gt;Change Becomes Us&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;James Blake &lt;em&gt;Overgrown&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Knife &lt;em&gt;Shaking The Habitual&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-flaming-lips-_the-terror_&#34;&gt;The Flaming Lips &lt;em&gt;The Terror&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How you view &lt;em&gt;The Terror&lt;/em&gt; pretty much depends on how much you have kept up with The Flips output since their last official album, the clanking double behemoth in Merkin packaging that was &lt;em&gt;Embryonic&lt;/em&gt;. The irony being that I used &lt;em&gt;Embryonic&lt;/em&gt; to deal with a break-up and &lt;em&gt;The Terror&lt;/em&gt; is pretty much about&amp;hellip; a break-up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, March 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just the David Bowie album this month as it’s pretty much the only new music that I’ve listened to.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I must admit that I had no idea what to expect of “The Next Day”. It comes almost exactly ten years after “Reality”, an album that I have never really got into despite it having some pretty decent fun tracks like “New Killer Star” and a nice cover of “Pablo Picasso” that has never sent me in search of Jonathan Richman’s original.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #22: Walking With Thee by Clinic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Walking With Thee” is the second album by Liverpool band &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clinic_(band)&#34;&gt;Clinic&lt;/a&gt;. It was released in 2002, which seems like an age ago now. Even longer ago they released the single “The Return of Evil Bill”, which was got me interested in them in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently got back into “Walking With Thee” when I picked “Vulture” in my A-Z of Animals playlist last month. I’d forgotten just how great a song it is, both musically and lyrically. It’s a caution against letting those with more power and wealth lord it over us – viz, “the best that you’ve left here for others / is the best the rest of us know” – and so it’s surely much more a song for these times than back then in 2002. Anyway, I’m going to avoid too much reading into the lyrics for this particular understated classic, as most of the time Clinic are defiantly resistant to that kind of analysis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Work Of Art At The End Of My Road?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-work-of-art-at-the-end-of-my-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-work-of-art-at-the-end-of-my-road/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have had a lot of ideas for posts swirling around in my head in recent days. This is because I have actually done quite a lot of cool things in that time, and because I have hung out with some great people who make me think, and because I always have a whole load of things bouncing around in there anyway - space junk of the mind. I was thinking about how to put together these thoughts I have been having about art and about stories and yes, about love too. It all kind of got muddled up and then I saw it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, February 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most Februaries are quite quiet when it comes to albums (though this was not the case &lt;a href=&#34;album-digest-february-2011&#34;&gt;back in 2011&lt;/a&gt;) and although only the Foals album is a major release, I was quite surprised to find myself with four decent albums to write about. They are:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Darkstar &amp;ldquo;News From Nowhere&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Foals &amp;ldquo;Holy Fire&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Daniel Hope &amp;ldquo;Spheres&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Apparat &amp;ldquo;Krieg und Frieden (Music For Theatre)&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;darkstar-news-from-nowhere&#34;&gt;Darkstar &amp;ldquo;News From Nowhere&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t need to give too much biographical background for the Darkstar album as I don&amp;rsquo;t know too much about who the are. I saw this album and its lovely artwork in an e-mail from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bleep.com/&#34;&gt;bleep.com&lt;/a&gt;. Because it was on Spotify, I gave it a go. At first I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too impressed but over repeated listens, it has become my favourite album of the month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, January 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Only one of this month three albums was actually released this month. Nelly Furtado&amp;rsquo;s Mi plan was actually released over three years ago - I only discovered it last year when I wrote &lt;a href=&#34;album-digest-september-2012&#34;&gt;the September album digest&lt;/a&gt; following the release of &amp;ldquo;The Spirit Indestructible&amp;rdquo;, or it might have been when I wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;uc20&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Folklore&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; at around the same time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I guess these are albums that I bought with my Christmas gift vouchers!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, December 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-december-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-december-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three albums (one very Christmassey one!) and an EP this month.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tracey Thorn “Tinsel and Lights”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Woob “Have Landed”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tim Hecker and Daniel Lopatin “Instrumental Tourist”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Burial “Truant / Rough Sleeper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tracey-thorn-tinsel-and-lights&#34;&gt;Tracey Thorn “Tinsel and Lights”&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Tinsel and Lights” is that rarest of records, a Christmas record that is perfectly suited to the season and is not in any way overbearing or irritating. Most albums that are Christmas themed are usually centred on lots of covers that are taken from a small subset of well worn classics. The songs on “Tinsel And Lights” are either originals or slightly more obscure covers and this works to its great advantage. The most famous song here (“Have yourself a merry little Christmas” aside) is probably the White Stripes’ “In The Cold Cold Night” and that’s not really a Christmas song (though it works better here than I’d anticipated).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, November 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pretty much a sliding scale between songs and electronic wibble on this month’s albums and a particularly damp, chilly feeling to proceedings too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bat For Lashes “The Haunted Man”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ital “Hive Mind” and “Dream On”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Björk “Bastards”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Brian Eno “Lux”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;bat-for-lashes-the-haunted-man&#34;&gt;Bat For Lashes “The Haunted Man”&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When it comes to Bat For Lashes, I prefer her first album “Fur And Gold” to her second “Two Suns” because when I listen to the latter I don’t feel connected to any of the songs. For me, “Fur And Gold” remains a wonderful adventure throughout, it’s a fantastic listen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #21: Woob 2 by Woob</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The second Woob album (AKA “Woob 4495”) is probably the greatest ambient album ever made and is certainly the best one you have never heard of. Originally released in 1995 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.emit.cc&#34;&gt;on the em:t label&lt;/a&gt; it is also a rare record. I don’t have an actual copy but I have seen one! I downloaded it off the internet and even that is quite difficult to do. My friend is an avid collector of all the em:t releases and it is easy to see why: all the albums are titled in a specific way that is very appealing to people who like to collect things and they also have very striking nature photography on the covers. In a strange way, the label was able to create an identity for its releases in a way that many artists would try to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, October 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a strange month and I found that I didn’t listen to a lot of new music. I have been a bit down and when that’s the case I tend to take refuge in music that I know well, stuff that cheers me up. I have listened to last month’s fave a lot, Nelly Furtado’s “The Spirit Indestructible”. I said a lot of nice things about it but it probably didn’t come over in my writing just how much I really liked it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had a bit more time to listen to this month’s albums because I was on holiday for two weeks. I didn’t manage to write about them while on holiday though! In fact I bought and listened to a few more, but I will save them for next month. The albums I will discuss now (in order bought) are:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Four Tet “Pink”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The xx “Coexist”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nelly Furtado “The Spirit Indestructible”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grizzly Bear “Shields”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s quite a diverse collection and, Four Tet apart, quite song based.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #20: Folklore by Nelly Furtado</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s rather spooky but shortly after deciding to write about Nelly Furtado’s “Folklore” as the next &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;understated classic&lt;/a&gt;, I found out that she has a new album out this week. As a result, I have been listening to a lot of her music while writing this post, and I’ve been enjoying it too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As always with these choices of mine, “Folklore” is a record that I can link to particular events and emotions in my life and so I guess my perception of it is coloured by that. Nevertheless while re-listening to the album I tried to examine whether my feelings for it were &lt;em&gt;entirely&lt;/em&gt; centred on those memories and emotional responses. I think the answer is not a simple one, because in recent weeks I’ve felt very unsettled in many aspects of my life and so I probably have found it difficult to tell.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Album Digest August 2012 is also from the stack of albums that I &lt;a href=&#34;album-digest-july-2012&#34;&gt;mentioned last month&lt;/a&gt;. I chose this selection (along with the Passion Pit album) because the colours looked good together in the mosaic of covers that I make each month. Last month’s digest was about the right amount of detail so this will be another briefer digest. These are all good albums but not ones that will change your life, they&amp;rsquo;ll just happily sit alongside it. They are:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #19: The Dreaming by Kate Bush</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“I see the people working and see it working for them.” (&lt;em&gt;Sat In Your Lap&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Dreaming by Kate Bush is a strange 1982 album that many believed had destroyed her career. Two weeks before her first ever performance of “Running Up That Hill”, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nme.com/blog/index.php?blog=10&amp;amp;title=on_this_day_kate_bush_releases_hounds_of_1986&amp;amp;more=1&amp;amp;c=1&amp;amp;tb=1&amp;amp;pb=1&#34;&gt;the NME had written an editorial asking whether she had burnt herself out completely&lt;/a&gt;. Obviously “Running Up That Hill” (recently used to great effect in the Olympic Closing Ceremony) and the parent album “The Hounds Of Love” that followed showed that she had plenty more up her sleeve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, July 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a short album digest this month. I bought a stack of CDs and am parcelling them out over the next few months (together with important additional releases as they crop up). This is in the hope that I can write more considered pieces about each one. This month I’ve grouped together albums with monochrome covers and a BT album from June that I found out about recently. These albums are not just linked by their artwork, they also form a cohesive whole. As a result I dispense with reviewing each album in depth. As usual there is a playlist at the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three fantastic albums for Album Digest June 2012:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Saint Etienne &lt;em&gt;Words and Music by Saint Etienne&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Liars &lt;em&gt;WIXIW&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hot Chip &lt;em&gt;In Our Heads&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This month is a curious selection in that the albums are all by bands that I already own a few records by. When there is so much other directly related material that you can write about, it makes focussing on the album in hand quite difficult. I am always thinking up rankings and comparisons. Where does this new album fit in with the rest of them? Will I like it as much when the novelty wears off? What would it sound like if they had done Y or Z like they did back on album X?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CAN, The Lost Tapes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/can-the-lost-tapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/can-the-lost-tapes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This arrived on Monday and I thought I would give it a post of its own because at over 3 hours of music, I am unlikely to do more than dip into it before writing the album digest next week. It is a far bigger and more enjoyable artefact than I thought it was going to be, so it probably deserves special attention for that reason too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Can_(band)&#34;&gt;CAN&lt;/a&gt; are a German (“&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Krautrock&#34;&gt;Krautrock&lt;/a&gt;”) band that I got into about four years ago after my interest in the genre was sparked by the “Neu! 75” album and the Kraftwerk box set. I have four of CAN&amp;rsquo;s albums and I have thought about which one I should include as an &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;understated classic&lt;/a&gt;. It will probably be “Soon Over Babaluma” because no one really writes about that one. Then again, Portishead’s “Third” probably wouldn’t sound as awesome as it does without the influence of “Ege Bamyasi”, so that might be worth considering too. Everyone writes about “Tago Mago” and “Future Days” but for good reason.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #18: Fabric 12 mixed by The Amalgamation Of Soundz</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Say what? We’re allowing compilations now?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes. Why not? A good mix is as much an artistic statement as a full-blown single artist album. It takes a lot of skill to get from A to B and keep everything on the boil in between. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fabriclondon.com/store/catalog/product/view/id/30/s/fabric-12/categories/8/&#34;&gt;This Fabric mix by The Amalgamation Of Soundz&lt;/a&gt; is one of my favourites because it is a downtempo (but, crucially, not &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; downtempo) compilation delivered with flair and using what I consider to be unconventional sources (soundtracks, tribute albums, hip-hop) to do it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, May 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Four albums for Album Digest May 2012:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jack White &lt;em&gt;Blunderbuss&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;One Little Plane &lt;em&gt;Into The Trees&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beach House &lt;em&gt;Bloom&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oxia &lt;em&gt;Tides Of Mind&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;album-digest-april-2012&#34;&gt;April album digest&lt;/a&gt; was rather short on songs, so this month I decided to look for albums that were more based around songs not tracks. Electronic music is relatively easy to write about: the music is often simple (but not always), there are recognisable structures and genres (but not always), and there are conventions that are adhered to (but not always). The repetition of those parenthetical “not always” means that while the writing is easy, it is also often quite fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, April 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A mostly instrumental month with a comeback from Orbital, an excellent remix collection from Battles, an amazing movie documenting a live performance by the Chemical Brothers and Austin Wintory’s soundtrack to the game &lt;em&gt;Journey&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Orbital &lt;em&gt;Wonky&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Battles &lt;em&gt;Dross Glop&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Chemical Brothers &lt;em&gt;Don’t Think&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Austin Wintory &lt;em&gt;Journey (Original Soundtrack)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;orbital-_wonky_&#34;&gt;Orbital &lt;em&gt;Wonky&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am quite keen on Orbital, though perhaps not as keen as I am on the similarly named Orb. I think I have got all the Orbital albums, mostly bought on eBay after the fact. (Funny story though, I did find a copy of &lt;em&gt;In Sides&lt;/em&gt; in the loft of a house where I lived in Bath, along with several other albums…) My favourite Orbital album is probably &lt;em&gt;Snivilisation&lt;/em&gt; but they all have their moments, whether it is the genuine sliver of emotion shot through &lt;em&gt;Halcyon&lt;/em&gt; off the brown album, the proggy long-form tracks on &lt;em&gt;In Sides&lt;/em&gt; like &lt;em&gt;The Girl With The Sun In Her Head&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Out There Somewhere&lt;/em&gt; (parts one and two), or indeed the arsing about with heavy metal samples on tracks like &lt;em&gt;Tension&lt;/em&gt; off the highly underrated &lt;em&gt;The Altogether&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #17: Nearly God by Nearly God (Tricky)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sit back and let it happen, / Let us take your time away.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nearly God&lt;/em&gt; is Tricky’s second album, which was released under a different name either because Island rejected it as the follow-up to &lt;em&gt;Maxinequaye&lt;/em&gt; or because it came too quickly after and Tricky just wanted it released. I had this album before &lt;em&gt;Maxinequaye&lt;/em&gt; because back then it wasn’t as easy to go back and catch up with albums that you had missed as it is now. I had bought enough singles to get the postcards through the post that advertised &lt;em&gt;Nearly God&lt;/em&gt; (this, kids, is what we had before e-mail and liking things on Facebook) and when I heard &lt;em&gt;Poems&lt;/em&gt; for the first time on the radio I was incredibly excited.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, March 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Five albums for Album Digest March 2012&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fanfarlo &lt;em&gt;Rooms Filled With Light&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Shins &lt;em&gt;Port Of Morrow&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grails &lt;em&gt;Deep Politics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;New Build &lt;em&gt;Yesterday Was Lived And Lost&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Scuba &lt;em&gt;Personality&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A nice collection of albums this month - things usually pick up in March after a slow period after Christmas. One of these is a “catch-up” (the album by Grails) but apart from that one, everything else was released in the last five weeks or so… I should probably have included the album by Racehorses that I bought on my birthday but I will have to leave that for next month as I haven’t listened to it that much. In fact, it is still in my housemate’s car!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #16: Ambient 2 / The Plateaux Of Mirror by Howard Budd and Brian Eno</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;among-fields-of-crystal--wind-in-lonely-fences&#34;&gt;Among Fields of Crystal / Wind in Lonely Fences&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have written about a &lt;a href=&#34;uc4&#34;&gt;fair&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;uc6&#34;&gt;number of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;uc13&#34;&gt;ambient&lt;/a&gt; albums in this series (and there are at least two more to come!) but perhaps none are as unobtrusive as this one by Howard Budd and Brian Eno. It’s a subtle collection of music that sits at the margins of your consciousness: for a long time it was the music that I turned to when I could not sleep but I could just as easily imagine it as (ahem!) romantic background music as I could something to work to. I actually bought it in 2006 to listen to on an overnight flight back from the US.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, February 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One EP and three albums for Album Digest February 2012:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Burial &lt;em&gt;Kindred EP&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;John Talabot &lt;em&gt;fIN&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lilacs &amp;amp; Champagne &lt;em&gt;Lilacs &amp;amp; Champagne&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The 2 Bears &lt;em&gt;Be Strong&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;album-digest-february-2011&#34;&gt;Last February&lt;/a&gt; was a pretty good month for song based albums, although the likes of Radiohead and James Blake provided plenty of electronic noodling in and around their song structures. (Interestingly, out of the two out-and-out song based albums, one was one of the worst albums of the year and the other one of the best).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, January 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Five albums to see in the new year:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;FOE “Bad Dream Hotline”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Leila “U &amp;amp; I”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Diagrams “Black Light”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pyramids &amp;amp; Horseback “A Throne Without A King”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;FabricLive 61 mixed by Pinch&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;foe-_bad-dream-hotline_&#34;&gt;FOE &lt;em&gt;Bad Dream Hotline&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I listened to “Bad Dream Hotline” about four times thinking “who does her voice remind me of?”. In the end I realised it was Sophie Ellis-Bextor, though in parts she sounds like KT Tunstall too. Of course these are rather tame references and I don’t mean to damn with faint praise, this album is much more edgy than those two ever were. If you are after some girly power pop with a darker edge then this will no doubt be the album that you have been waiting for.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #15: Début by Björk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got into Début via a cassette from the library, much like I did with &lt;a href=&#34;uc1&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Together Alone&lt;/em&gt; by Crowded House&lt;/a&gt;. I suppose it is less obscure than many of my choices for &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;this strand&lt;/a&gt; but I do think that &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; is more well-known (because of &lt;em&gt;It’s Oh So Quiet&lt;/em&gt;, which we shall mention here only briefly) and that &lt;em&gt;Homogenic&lt;/em&gt; is probably more popular among her fans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I really like about &lt;em&gt;Début&lt;/em&gt; though, as much as the album itself, is the panoply of remixes and alternative versions that surround the release. In this way &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; is at least as strong if not stronger and you might recall that I had similar fun &lt;a href=&#34;uc13&#34;&gt;when writing about the Orb’s album U.F.Orb a while back&lt;/a&gt;. As a result of this, there will be some detours into the remixes and live versions when discussing this album. In particular, I will mention the remix collection &lt;em&gt;the best mixes from the album début for all the people who don’t buy white labels&lt;/em&gt; and the recording of an MTV Unplugged show that is available in the &lt;em&gt;Live Box&lt;/em&gt; box set.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, December 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-december-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-december-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some rather brief pen pictures of this month’s albums. I’ve been a bit busy!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;radio-slave---collected-remixes&#34;&gt;Radio Slave - Collected Remixes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thud thud thud. This is pretty much how all Radio Slave remixes go. I really liked his fabric mix and borrowed a few tracks for a playlist I made called &amp;ldquo;Dancing In Space&amp;rdquo;. Anyway, back to the thudding: it’s no bad thing, the remixes have a nice formula that works well for discovering new tracks like UNKLE’s &lt;em&gt;Burn My Shadow&lt;/em&gt; (Ian Astbury’s vocal is given plenty of room to shine) and K3’s &lt;em&gt;Play To Win&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, November 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just three albums this month as I’ve been listening to a lot of Brian Eno records ready for an upcoming understated classic. First up is &lt;em&gt;50 Words For Snow&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;Kate Bush&lt;/strong&gt;, the second album that she has released this year. &lt;a href=&#34;album-digest-may-2011&#34;&gt;Back in May&lt;/a&gt; I wrote about &lt;em&gt;Director’s Cut&lt;/em&gt;, which presented re-recorded and re-mastered versions of songs from her albums &lt;em&gt;The Sensual World&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Red Shoes&lt;/em&gt;. This time around it is an album of brand new material, the first since &lt;em&gt;Aerial&lt;/em&gt; in 2006.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #14: Clear by Bomb The Bass</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think it’s time to discuss your philosophy of drug use as it relates to artistic endeavour…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That quote is from the movie “The Naked Lunch” directed by David Cronenburg (see also &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/crash/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;) and it also opens “Bug Powder Dust” by Bomb The Bass, the five star single that opens “Clear”. A rollicking piece of rock rap dripping with pop culture references that runs for four and half minutes and does not stop until another quote from “The Naked Lunch”, it is probably one of my favourite songs of the 90s. That churning guitar line sends me right back.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, October 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month we have albums by Björk, Coldplay, M83, and Radiohead.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;album-digest-october-2011---intro&#34;&gt;Album Digest October 2011 - Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I listened to Wilco’s &lt;em&gt;The Whole Love&lt;/em&gt; again the other day. I happened to be walking past the venue in Portsmouth where I went to see them live back in 2004 and it seemed the right fit. I really enjoyed the album after a period of not having listened to it and I found that being familiar with the songs allowed me to better appreciate the production of the album. It really is better than I had said last time when I included it in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/2011/09/album-digest-september-2011/&#34;&gt;September Album Digest&lt;/a&gt;, I suppose that it was the danger in writing about music you have only had with you for a few weeks (or days in the case of &lt;em&gt;The Whole Love&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hmmm, a rather grey looking selection of covers this month. The albums I have listened to most are:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;John Beltran &lt;em&gt;Ambient Selections&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;FabricLive 59 mixed by Four Tet&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Rapture &lt;em&gt;In The Grace Of Your Love&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wilco &lt;em&gt;The Whole Love&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have actually only had the Wilco album since Monday of this week (the 26th) but it has inveigled its way into my consciousness quite quickly. As I have said before, &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/2010/playlist-1-metallic/&#34;&gt;this blog owes its name to a Wilco song&lt;/a&gt; and they are quite an important band to me. The other albums are mostly electronic, although The Rapture are distinctly indie flavoured as they hit the dance floor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #13: U.F.Orb by The Orb</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FUN FACT:&lt;/strong&gt; It was because of the artwork to this album that I obsessively scrawled onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome on my pencil case at school. I also had a very passable u.f.orb logo drawn on it too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-the-blue-room&#34;&gt;In The Blue Room&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had my first “close encounter” with The Orb in 1992 when the single &lt;em&gt;Blue Room&lt;/em&gt; was in the charts. Back then, as I &lt;a href=&#34;uc2&#34;&gt;mentioned previously&lt;/a&gt;, I would listen to the radio a lot and this tune - introduced as the longest single ever to enter the UK chart - struck me as really interesting. The radio edit was a burbling wash of synths and female vocals underpinned by a hefty bass performance from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newstatesman.com/music/2008/06/wobble-life-music-dub-leaving&#34;&gt;Jah Wobble&lt;/a&gt;. Incidentally, the same week that &lt;em&gt;Blue Room&lt;/em&gt; entered the chart, I was actually listening out for &lt;em&gt;Sentinel&lt;/em&gt; by Mike Oldfield and this single (&lt;a href=&#34;uc10&#34;&gt;from Tubular Bells II&lt;/a&gt;) featured two remixes by The Orb.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I bought a collection of electronic music this month. I mixed them all up in a smart playlist on iTunes, the smart aspect being to limit to tracks that had been played fewer than five then six then seven times etc. This made sure I was still listening to all the tracks equally often, despite the randomness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Biosphere &lt;em&gt;N-plants&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ford &amp;amp; Lopatin &lt;em&gt;Channel Pressure&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gus Gus &lt;em&gt;Arabian Horse&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Instra:Mental &lt;em&gt;Resolution 653&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jon Tejada &lt;em&gt;Parabolas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;biosphere-_n-plants_&#34;&gt;Biosphere &lt;em&gt;N-Plants&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think this album makes Biosphere the most reviewed musician on this blog at the moment but I don’t mind too much, he makes some great stuff. &lt;em&gt;N-Plants&lt;/em&gt; is a series of pieces about Japanese nuclear power plants and was ready for release by about February this year, just before the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fukushima_Daiichi_nuclear_disaster&#34;&gt;Fukishima nuclear disaster&lt;/a&gt; in March. It ended up being released in June. I am not sure if this represents a delay or not but as this quote shows, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.touchmusic.org.uk/catalogue/to84_biosphere_nplants.html&#34;&gt;Geir Jenssen is aware of how spooky the timing was&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #12: Look Sharp! by Roxette</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;happy-birthday&#34;&gt;Happy Birthday!&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No matter how intellectual one gets about these things, the primary function of music is to have fun. With this in mind it is a good time to turn to Roxette then, as they are almost always the epitome of fun.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I received &lt;em&gt;Look Sharp!&lt;/em&gt; as a present for my ninth birthday. This was probably a bit young to fully understand all the emotions expressed on the record. It’s just as well that it is also crammed with the kind of pop confections that made &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_Bore_Us,_Get_to_the_Chorus!&#34;&gt;“Don’t bore us, get to the chorus!”&lt;/a&gt; something of a band motto and made for a great introduction to the world of pop for a nine year old boy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, July 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quite a mixed bag this month.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SBTRKT &lt;em&gt;SBTRKT&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Zomby &lt;em&gt;Dedication&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Brian Eno &lt;em&gt;Drums Between The Bells&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bon Iver &lt;em&gt;Bon Iver&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Washed Out &lt;em&gt;Within and Without&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This month’s collection of albums is a rather mellow bunch. The SBTRKT album (self-titled) is probably the most frenetic of the five though even that does not exactly pound four to the floor. Most of it is pretty calm, though  the occasional burst of pop to spice things up: sometimes it is as downtempo as the rest (&lt;em&gt;Right Thing To Do&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Trials Of The Past&lt;/em&gt;) but at other times things spark into life, as on &lt;em&gt;Pharaohs&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #11: Second Toughest In The Infants by Underworld</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-rails-your-fins-your-thin-paper-wings&#34;&gt;Your rails, your fins, your thin paper wings&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Second Toughest in the Infants&lt;/em&gt; (STITI) is the second album by Underworld, released in 1995. This was just ahead of the mania caused by the .NUXX version of Born Slippy appearing on the &lt;em&gt;Trainspotting&lt;/em&gt; soundtrack a little later. &lt;em&gt;Born Slippy&lt;/em&gt; itself, the blippy techno confection released between their début &lt;em&gt;Dubnobasswithmyheadman&lt;/em&gt; and this album. STITI then is very much the calm before the storm and features a band (in the truest sense, which is unusual among electronic acts) in full flow. The sure hands are apparent from the off with the all-in-one trifecta of &lt;em&gt;Juanita&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Kiteless&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;To Dream of Love&lt;/em&gt;: a huge slab of a track that propels, mashes and then glides over various tempos in its sixteen minute run.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have had the sort of month that is not conducive to listening to much new music. Therefore this month’s post is only going to consider two new albums and two albums that I have bought behind time. Because of various bits of stress and poor mood, I have ended up going back and taking refuge in some old favourites and not listening to new stuff. At other points I have also gone back to the Fleet Foxes’ album that I wrote about last month, which has grown on me even more since. Sometimes I think that I should writing about these albums on a two month delay. Meanwhile, I even have new music that I haven’t listened to &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt;, namely &lt;strong&gt;Bon Iver&lt;/strong&gt;’s self-titled album. It has received so many good reviews that I have been too intimidated to listen to it. I will try to write about it next month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #10: Tubular Bells II by Mike Oldfield</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was the artwork that got me interested in Tubular Bells II. Rendering Trevor Key&amp;rsquo;s wonderful icon of the twisted tubular bell in yellow and blue made it all the more mysterious. Seeing it one day in Woolworth&amp;rsquo;s in Leigh Park back in 1992 aroused my curiosity. The huge display must have been part of the massive publicity drive for the album. Despite dwindling sales for his albums at that time, a sequel to Tubular Bells represented a huge potential for sales. This is why Oldfield had been lured from his previous home at Virgin records over to Warner Music. At that point Oldfield had not made a good album since his soundtrack to the movie &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0087553/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Killing Fields&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in 1985, the end of a hot streak (perhaps 1980&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;QE2&lt;/em&gt; aside) that had lasted since the original &lt;em&gt;Tubular Bells&lt;/em&gt; back in 1973.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, May 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Four albums this month:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kate Bush &lt;em&gt;Director’s Cut&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Africa Hitech &lt;em&gt;93 Million Miles&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fleet Foxes &lt;em&gt;Helplessness Blues&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;TV On The Radio &lt;em&gt;Nine Types of Light&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a pleasing red hue to all the covers this month. I had time to write four full reviews of the major albums I listened to. Like last month I have included a video at the foot of each review. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;kate-bush-_directors-cut_&#34;&gt;Kate Bush &lt;em&gt;Director’s Cut&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Director’s Cut&lt;/em&gt; is not a new album from Kate Bush but a collection of re-visits to old songs, four from &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Sensual_World&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Sensual World&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (1989) and seven from [&lt;em&gt;The Red Shoes&lt;/em&gt;](&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Red_Shoes_(album)&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Red_Shoes_(album)&lt;/a&gt; (1993). It is certainly an interesting idea to re-examine old songs with hindsight, something usually only done with live albums or dodgy remixes. It is rare to have an artist to even admit flaws in their earlier material, let alone for them to go back and attempt to fix them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #9: Tiger Bay by Saint Etienne</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tiger Bay&lt;/em&gt; is Saint Etienne&amp;rsquo;s third album and I think it is among their best. It was released in June 1994 on Heavenly records. I first owned a copy in 1998 when I picked it up while living in halls as an undergraduate. The reason for including this album in the understated classics series is the same as for &lt;a href=&#34;uc8&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Second Light&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Dreadzone: it marries traditional forms to newer electronic music&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Second Light&lt;/em&gt; melds classical music and sea shanties to house and dub reggae to evoke the rolling hills and mystic caves of England. &lt;em&gt;Tiger Bay&lt;/em&gt; grafts folk structures on to Balearic pop songs and electronic experiments in order to visit motorway verges, windswept seashores, and Mediterranean holidays. There is even a ghost story (&lt;em&gt;Boy Scouts of America&lt;/em&gt;) for good measure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, April 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;album-of-the-month-_mirrorwriting_-by-jamie-woon&#34;&gt;Album of the month: &lt;em&gt;Mirrorwriting&lt;/em&gt; by Jamie Woon&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jamie Woon was brought to my attention late last year by Pitchfork who wrote an article about the video for lead single &lt;em&gt;Night Air&lt;/em&gt;. I’ve put that video down below because I think that it is very good, a simple well executed and the tune itself is brilliant, probably my favourite individual track of 2010. It’s a downtempo tune full of dark spaces and empty beats, full of nocturnal promise and mystery. Hungry for more, I also bought the &lt;em&gt;Wayfaring Stranger&lt;/em&gt; EP and pre-ordered &lt;em&gt;Mirrorwriting&lt;/em&gt; as soon as it was possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, March 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/this-is-not-an-album-digest-march-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/this-is-not-an-album-digest-march-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-is-not-an-album-digest-march-2011&#34;&gt;This is not an Album Digest March 2011&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well as I said at the end of &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/album-digest-february-2011/&#34;&gt;last month’s album digest post&lt;/a&gt;, I took a bit of a break from pursuing new music quite as closely as I have been. As promised, I sidestepped the new R.E.M. and Elbow albums - although I had been promised the latter as a birthday present it is yet to show up, maybe I will look at in April.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #8: Second Light by Dreadzone</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;understated classics&lt;/a&gt; series, I try to alternate between pop/rock and electronic albums. Keeping with this trend number eight is the wonderful dub-infused album &lt;em&gt;Second Light&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dreadzone.com&#34;&gt;Dreadzone&lt;/a&gt;. Released in 1996 it was well-received critically and four of its tracks featured on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/radio1/johnpeel/&#34;&gt;John Peel&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s best-of-year list that year. &lt;em&gt;Little Britain&lt;/em&gt; received a lot of radio play, a popular choice for that flag-waving period of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mojo4music.com/13834/the-story-of-britpop-in-60-albums/&#34;&gt;britpop&lt;/a&gt; and assorted other demons.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The strengths of &lt;em&gt;Second Light&lt;/em&gt; as an album is the anglicana&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; of its first half and the subversion of it in the second half. I often talk of how albums are front-loaded with the best tracks to get you immersed in them. This is probably a hangover from vinyl where you could repeatedly play one side, making it necessary to make cohesive &amp;lsquo;sides&amp;rsquo; of music.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, February 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;February, the shortest month, harbinger of such delights as Groundhog Day and Valentine’s Day. Could it possibly produce any good albums? Well the candidates are the eponymous début album by &lt;strong&gt;James Blake&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Zonoscope&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;Cut/Copy&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Let England Shake&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;PJ Harvey&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Smart Flesh&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;The Low Anthem&lt;/strong&gt;. Furthermore, there was an unexpected bonus when &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.radiohead.com/deadairspace/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Radiohead&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; announced that their new album would be out and available to listen to this month too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, January 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s to 2011 and the start of a monthly album digest. I want it to be a brief trot through some of the albums I have listened to each month. Sometimes January can bring a few quiet releases by big name bands. This happens if the previous album did not do as well as the record company hoped or if it is the kind of artist who would get lost under the hype of all the Christmas releases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #7: 100 Broken Windows by Idlewild</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Idewild are a solid band who have released four or five albums that I could consider for this series. I&amp;rsquo;m even in the sleeve credits of one: &lt;em&gt;Post-Electric Blues&lt;/em&gt;, if you&amp;rsquo;re asking.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the end I went for &lt;em&gt;100 Broken Windows&lt;/em&gt; because it means a lot to me. It has more of a place in my life than the others. Usually I find that this happens if I can remember where I bought an album. In this case I bought a copy of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-22533522&#34;&gt;cassette&lt;/a&gt; in Bath HMV at Easter 2000. I can remember the first time that I listened to it too, it was as I marched home to Oldfield Park down Bathwick hill from the &lt;a href=&#34;www.bath.ac.uk&#34;&gt;university&lt;/a&gt; that same afternoon. It took exactly the two sides of the tape to get from one door to the other.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #6: Arbor Bona Arbor Mala by The Shamen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ask anyone into pop music between 1991 and 1993 about The Shamen, and you&amp;rsquo;ll either receive a flood of euphoric good will about excellent tracks like &lt;em&gt;Move Any Mountain&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;LSI&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Phorever People&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;; or they will rant at you about the evils of &lt;em&gt;Ebeneezer Goode&lt;/em&gt;. The Shamen are either one of the pantheon of great acts from early 90&amp;rsquo;s dance and electronic music, or they are a shameless vaudeville novelty act.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #5: A Weekend In The City by Bloc Party</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-weekend-in-the-city-background&#34;&gt;A Weekend In The City: Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the youngest album I have chosen for this series. I try to pick albums that are at least ten years old but every now and then, I will think of an album that matches the sort of things I want to write about. That&amp;rsquo;s the case here. &lt;em&gt;A Weekend in the City&lt;/em&gt; is an unusual album that, in a reversal of the old adage, is “easy to love but hard to admire”. Nevertheless I do love and admire it, and I would like to share my thoughts about it with you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #4: Substrata by Biosphere</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/other/UC4add1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I bought this album in the summer between my two years at college. I remember listening to this music under skies glowering with clouds so 1997 must have been a poor summer. I’d just bought a book of photography too, which placed photos from the north and south poles on opposite pages. I bought it mainly for the penguins that were, of course, on pretty much every other page. The pictures of snow and ice soon became the ideal companions to this album.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #3: The Circle &amp; The Square by Red Box</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-is-understated-not-understated&#34;&gt;When is understated not understated?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The trouble with writing a series of articles all themed somehow is that eventually you might find something that sits naturally in the sequence but at the same time goes against the grain a little. Et voila, I give you “The Circle &amp;amp; The Square” by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.redboxmusic.net/htm/home.htm&#34;&gt;Red Box&lt;/a&gt;. An album that hardly anyone has heard containing two top 10 UK singles that probably everyone has heard. Don’t get me wrong, it is a complete and utter classic - but it is definitely not understated: it is pompous, pretentious, ornate, artistic, all-encompassing, weird and awesome. I could continue but some innate inner law prevents me from using any more adjectives than that in one sentence. It is a chimeral entity standing way apart from its time, timeless and beautiful. The fact that it sold sod-all copies means that holding &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cherryred.co.uk/cherrypop-exd.asp?id=873&#34;&gt;a CD remaster&lt;/a&gt; makes you feel as if you were clutching a cuddly dodo and thinking “if only, if only…”. So this barking, bonkers, beautiful album gets its “&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tags#understated-classics/&#34;&gt;understated classic&lt;/a&gt;” status because it just isn’t stated often enough just what an amazing record it is.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #2: Sinking by The Aloof</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-discovered-the-aloof-while-listening-to-the-top-40&#34;&gt;I discovered The Aloof while listening to the Top 40&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I was younger, I used to listen to the Top 40 every Sunday. To begin with, this was partly an endurance thing and partly an obsession with one day seeing Roxette top the charts - alas, they never did, though for one thrilling spring “Joyride” did flirt with the upper reaches of the chart.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Listening to the charts is probably the best way to become a lover of music. Nearly all my musical loves stem from listening to the top 40 chart, either directly from crouching next to my static-y radio on Sunday evening, or as something that evolving beyond those initial tastes later on. I soon realised that listening to music at the lower end of the chart was more rewarding and not just because this was where all &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Church_of_Your_Heart&#34;&gt;the later Roxette singles ended up&lt;/a&gt;. It was where all the oddities washed in, sometimes there one week and never to be heard again - sometimes growing up into something big. I remember first hearing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.prideofmanchester.com/music/ucc.htm&#34;&gt;“The Key The Secret” by the Urban Cookie Collective&lt;/a&gt; entering the chart at number 40, it eventually climbed to number 2. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/nottingham/content/articles/2004/11/20/entertainment_music_local_bands_kws_feature.shtml&#34;&gt;Also “Please Don’t Go” by KWS which crept all the way up to number 1&lt;/a&gt; - these were great dance records that grew by word of mouth at a time when great dance records were weird and new and meant something.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #1: Together Alone by Crowded House</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week Arcade Fire released their hotly anticipated third album &amp;ldquo;The Suburbs&amp;rdquo;.  I loved &amp;ldquo;Neon Bible&amp;rdquo; but critics found it preachy, as overbearing as the religious folk it sought to satirise. I disagree and think it was an impressive continuation from an exciting debut. &amp;ldquo;The Suburbs&amp;rdquo; steps on from their previous two albums, both in subject matter and tone. It&amp;rsquo;s sad, thoughtful, resigned, angry and tetchy - among other things. “The Suburbs” isn&amp;rsquo;t the understated classic that I want to discuss though: with all the praise and plaudits, it may never suit this new thread of posts. I want to write about &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Together_Alone&#34;&gt;Together Alone by Crowded House&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
