<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>808 State, Don Solaris</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/808-state-don-solaris/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/808-state-don-solaris/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I sometimes wonder if I picked the correct 808 State album for my understated classics series. That&amp;rsquo;s because today I was listening to their 1996 album &lt;em&gt;Don Solaris&lt;/em&gt; and it&amp;rsquo;s pretty darn good. For understated classics I chose their earlier effort &lt;em&gt;Gorgeous&lt;/em&gt;, partly out of the belief that probably no one else ever would, but also because &lt;em&gt;10X10&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Plan 9&lt;/em&gt; are such total bangers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bill Drummond, 45</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bill-drummond-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bill-drummond-45/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;45&lt;/em&gt; is Bill Drummond&amp;rsquo;s sort of memoir, albeit one with a hazy memory of the events most readers (myself included) are likely to be interested in. Drummond is/was one half of pop-pranksters The KLF, but &lt;em&gt;45&lt;/em&gt; barely mentions them at all. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot about before (e.g. managing Echo and the Bunnymen in late-70s and early-80s Liverpool) and after (various shenanigans in the art world and attempting to relate to his children), some of that writing is very interesting. Nevertheless the whole lacuna of his pop heyday seems to punches a hole through the entire book.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robin Egg Blue</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/robin-egg-blue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/robin-egg-blue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is record one of nine from the new &amp;ldquo;A Ghost Is Born&amp;rdquo; superdeluxe edition. I was hoping to write a review tonight but I haven&amp;rsquo;t managed to listen to it all yet!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peter Gabriel, So</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/peter-gabriel-so/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/peter-gabriel-so/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently watched the entry about Peter Gabriel&amp;rsquo;s 1986 album &amp;ldquo;So&amp;rdquo; in the Classic Albums series on Amazon Prime. It was an entertaining way to fill an evening hour.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I absolutely love &amp;ldquo;So&amp;rdquo;. I came to its songs via the &amp;ldquo;Secret World Live&amp;rdquo; album, and it was &amp;ldquo;Red Rain&amp;rdquo; specifically that convinced me of his greatness. Previously, I&amp;rsquo;d been aware of &amp;ldquo;Sledgehammer&amp;rdquo; (also on this album) and &amp;ldquo;Steam&amp;rdquo; (from the similarly titled &amp;ldquo;Us&amp;rdquo;), but &amp;ldquo;Red Rain&amp;rdquo; really captured my imagination.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Praise of Pomme Fritz</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-pomme-fritz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-pomme-fritz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The release of Pomme Fritz by The Orb in 1994 was a moment of genuine excitement for me as it was the first new material they released after I&amp;rsquo;d become aware of them. Not only that, but thanks to my hard work riding around Emsworth on my BMX at unsafe speeds belting out Green Day&amp;rsquo;s Dookie as out-of-tune-ly as is humanly possible, I&amp;rsquo;d managed to secure the funds to buy the album for myself. My excitement had been mounting from the moment the promotional postcard arrived a few weeks beforehand. I took my £4.99 to Our Price in Portsmouth Cascades on Saturday afternoon and bought myself a copy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And boy, I pretty much hated it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ian MacDonald, Revolution in the Head</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ian-macdonald-revolution-in-the-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ian-macdonald-revolution-in-the-head/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ian MacDonald&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Revolution in the Head&amp;rdquo; is a book that I&amp;rsquo;ve read parts of dozens of times and even all the way through once or twice. I picked it up again today and thought I would write about it. It&amp;rsquo;s a detailed analysis of every Beatles song ever released, along with the details and events of their recording. I own a copy of the second edition which was updated to include the anthology material. Today you can still get hold of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.waterstones.com/book/revolution-in-the-head/ian-macdonald/9780099526797&#34;&gt;a 3rd edition on the Waterstones website&lt;/a&gt; (not sure that I like the new cover though).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Albums Matter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/albums-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/albums-matter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having recently completed my review of 2024&amp;rsquo;s best albums, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reflecting on what a strange year it was for me in terms of the music I listened to. According to my Last.fm annual report, I listened to 51% &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; music in 2024 compared with 2023 (and 2023 was itself a peak listening year). Moreover, I listened to 709 artists, of which 37% were new discoveries. I listened to over 2 albums a day apparently, with &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/posts/2024-albums-03-acopia/&#34;&gt;Acopia&lt;/a&gt; being the album I listened to most often. Apparently I was the 11th top listener on Last.fm of my number 1 album of the year &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/posts/2024-albums-01-bolis-pupul-letter-to-yu/&#34;&gt;Letter to Yu by Bolis Pupul&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parquet Courts, Sympathy For Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/parquet-courts-sympathy-for-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/parquet-courts-sympathy-for-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Getting back to my occasional album revisits, I&amp;rsquo;d like to consider the 2021 Parquet Courts album &amp;ldquo;Sympathy For Life&amp;rdquo;. This is partly because I own it on vinyl and put it on the other day while I was doing some rather humdrum data downloading at work. It&amp;rsquo;s that kind of album, quite loose and jam-based.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Albums of the Year #6: Total Blue, Total Blue</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-06-total-blue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-06-total-blue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What do you think of when you think of the colour blue? The sea? Perhaps the sky? Maybe it makes you think of blue stones like sapphires, or flowers such as forget-me-nots? Maybe the colour blue is the glow of a phone screen on someone&amp;rsquo;s face (maybe yours) in the dark? Blue gathers at the edges of the harsh white LED light that has come to dominate our night time existence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums: Honourable Mentions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-honourable-mentions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-honourable-mentions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A quick list of ten other albums I considered to be among the best of last year. I either listened to these less, or in the cases of &amp;ldquo;Transmission Three&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Be Opened By The Wonderful&amp;rdquo; considered them to be ineligible as they are compilations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #1: Sofia Kourtesis, Madres</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-01-sofia-kourtesis-madres/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-01-sofia-kourtesis-madres/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sofia Kourtesis is a Berlin-based Peruvian dance producer, &amp;ldquo;Madres&amp;rdquo; is her debut album which follows on from a 2021 EP &amp;ldquo;Fresia Magdalena&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;&lt;span class=&#34;marginfigure&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/sofia-kourtesis-madres.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Madres by Sofia Kourtesis&#34; /&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Cover of &lt;em&gt;Madres&lt;/em&gt; by Sofia Kourtesis&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;It was trailed by several singles, including the title track which caught my attention back in May. The album is dedicated to her parents and there are also songs dedicated to the surgeon who performed life-saving surgery on Kourtesis’s mother. The whole album is a heady mix of positivity and dedication to both music and to family.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For me, ten years on from my trip to South America, I think my response to this album has been to its fusion of European and South American dance music, perhaps reminding me that it is possible to incorporate the experiences one has in other places into our viewpoint on the world. It seems to be that we are in a point in history that rather than acknowledging that we are interconnected and responsible for and to one another, that we have instead lurched into a protectionist and selfish mode of thinking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #2: James Holden, Imagine This is a High Dimensional Space of All Possibilities</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-02-james-holden-imagine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-02-james-holden-imagine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cool artwork! No, we don&amp;rsquo;t have it but it&amp;rsquo;s coming in next week.&amp;ldquo;&lt;span class=&#34;marginfigure&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/james-holden-imagine.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Imagine This is a High Dimensional Space of All Possibilities by James Holden&#34; /&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Cover of &lt;em&gt;Imagine This is a High Dimensional Space of All Possibilities&lt;/em&gt; by James Holden&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cool artwork! We haven&amp;rsquo;t had a copy in but I can order it for you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Me picking it up a week later: &amp;ldquo;Cool artwork!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Imagine This is a High Dimensional Space of All Possibilities&amp;rdquo; is definitely album title of the year, made all the more topical with the intrusion of Chat-GPT and the like into the cultural conversation. Large Language Models (LLMs) like Chat-GPT work by absorbing large amounts of textual data (i.e. this blog, helping to make all those instant album reviews you can write now just a tiny bit more shit) and breaking them down into tokens, with each token having a meaning and a grammatical role and so on. These meanings and roles form higher dimensional spaces in which the tokens are vectors, where the rules of the LLMs help determine which tokens live near to one another and which pairs are likely to sit together in &amp;lsquo;meaningful&amp;rsquo; sentences etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #3: Barry Can&#39;t Swim, When Will We Land?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-03-barry-cant-swim-when-will-we-land/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-03-barry-cant-swim-when-will-we-land/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some albums you come to one way: a good review on a blog you respect,&#xA;&lt;span class=&#34;marginfigure&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/barry-cant-swim-when-will-we-land.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of _When Will We Land_ by Barry Can&amp;#39;t Swim&#34; /&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Cover of &lt;em&gt;When Will We Land&lt;/em&gt; by Barry Can&amp;rsquo;t Swim&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;a track appearing on a playlist by someone whose taste you trust, etc and so on. And sometimes you get directed to something multiple times. This is what happened to me this year with the irrepressible “When Will We Land?” by Barry Can’t Swim. Anyway, tracks by &amp;ldquo;Barry&amp;rdquo; appeared in mixes a lot this year and the album kept popping up in eagerly anticipated lists.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to this album a lot but I still have questions. Like is &amp;ldquo;can&amp;rsquo;t swim&amp;rdquo; his last name? Was he not made to learn in detention at lunchtime in the school&amp;rsquo;s outdoor pool in an English April like yours truly?!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The album starts with the title track, a nice minimalist piece that is nearly “not dance music” in the way that so many opening tracks on dance albums are. It puts me in mind of Steve Reich played by Bonobo. The next track “Deadbeat Gospel” is an impromptu rap by an old school friend while on a night out sampled and cut to fit the beat, it’s pretty cool but I’m glad it’s near the beginning so I can skip over it if I’m not feeling it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #4: The National, &#34;First Two Pages of Frankenstein&#34; and &#34;Laugh Track&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-04-the-national-frankenstein-laugh-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-04-the-national-frankenstein-laugh-track/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s probably no surprise that as we reach the top four (or five if you like) we also&#xA;&lt;span class=&#34;marginfigure&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/the-national-first-two-pages.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of First Two Pages of Frankenstein by The National&#34; /&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Cover of &lt;em&gt;First Two Pages of Frankenstein&lt;/em&gt; by The National&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;get to the two albums The National released in 2023. The first, “First Two Pages of Frankenstein”, was trailed with a big reveal early on in the year, while the second, “Laugh Track”, was dropped all of a sudden in October. Once I got to know both albums, I swung between liking each one more for a while, hence putting them both at the same point in the list and not considering each separately.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the purposes of this list, we can consider both albums as one homogeneous collection of songs, though some reviews did pick out that “Laugh Track” has more live drums and the songs on that latter album are looser and longer than their “… Frankenstein” counterparts. I think there are songs that are similar to one another on both albums, and that for those tracks, the song on the first album is a bit better than the one on “Laugh Track”. Some of the songs on “Laugh Track” are almost invisible on the first few listens, songs like “Dreaming”, “Hornets” and “Tour Manager”, though the latter of those three has become one of my favourite songs on both albums.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #5: Nation of Language, Strange Disciple</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-05-nation-of-language-strange-disciple/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-05-nation-of-language-strange-disciple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It would be remiss of me to claim that this is a placeholder for any number&#xA;&lt;span class=&#34;marginfigure&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/nation-of-language-strange-disciple.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Strange Disciple by Nation of Language&#34; /&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Cover of &lt;em&gt;Strange Disciple&lt;/em&gt; by Nation of Language&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;of (quite different sounding) song based albums that came out this year (Yves Tumor, Wilco to mention two) but it feels that way. This album came high up my list of listens because it&amp;rsquo;s a very good breakfast album, one to listen to while getting the Day started - though there are also some bangers on here too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nation of language are a three piece band from New York. I think one of them is famous for being in a band I&amp;rsquo;ve not heard of (or is that their producer, I must do some fact checking) and two of them are married, even going so far as to have had a gofundme or whatever for the band as a present at a wedding. (That doesn&amp;rsquo;t give off future &amp;ldquo;we are a duo now&amp;rdquo; vibes at all!)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #6: Grails, Anches en Maat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-06-grails-anches-en-maat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-06-grails-anches-en-maat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Grails are one of those bands who always get played a lot at my house.&#xA;&lt;span class=&#34;marginfigure&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/grails-anches-en-maat.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Anches en Maat by Grails&#34; /&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Cover of &lt;em&gt;Anches en Maat&lt;/em&gt; by Grails&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;There&amp;rsquo;s something about their slow incremental instrumental pieces that my brain just loves to get lost in. Anches en Maat, their first album in six years or so, and the first with the entire band in the studio together since 2008, is their most Grails-y album in a long time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #7: Maara, The Ancient Truth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-07-maara-ancient-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-07-maara-ancient-truth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There isn&amp;rsquo;t a great deal I can write about The Ancient Truth without sounding vague and anodyne.&#xA;&lt;span class=&#34;marginfigure&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/maara-ancient-truth.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of The Ancient Truth by Maara&#34; /&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Cover of &lt;em&gt;The Ancient Truth&lt;/em&gt; by Maara&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;While I try to come think about different forms of music and go into some analysis of what makes one album more interesting than another, sometimes you end up just saying &amp;ldquo;this album is great because I like it and I always have a good time listening to it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #8: Everything But The Girl, Fuse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-08-ebtg-fuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-08-ebtg-fuse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you get older nostalgia becomes an ever important part of listening to music.&#xA;&lt;span class=&#34;marginfigure&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/ebtg-fuse.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Fuse by Everything But The Girl&#34; /&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Cover of &lt;em&gt;Fuse&lt;/em&gt; by Everything But The Girl&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;It often feels like the business relies on convincing an aging population of fans to part with their money on new versions of old material. It&amp;rsquo;s nostalgia, the feeling of recapturing something you loved in your youth, that often makes this acceptable. Of course it&amp;rsquo;s also nice to get &lt;strong&gt;new&lt;/strong&gt; music from your favourite bands, especially when it&amp;rsquo;s as good as &amp;ldquo;Fuse&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #9: Fever Ray, Radical Romantics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-09-fever-ray-radical-romantics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-09-fever-ray-radical-romantics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Radical Romantics, the third album by Fever Ray was released in April. I bought a copy on red vinyl which is a beautiful sight to behold.&lt;span class=&#34;marginfigure&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/fever-ray-radical-romantics.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Radical Romantics by Fever Ray&#34; /&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Cover of &lt;em&gt;Radical Romantics&lt;/em&gt; by Fever Ray&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/span&gt; I listened to a lot when it was released but eased up a bit until listening to it a couple more times while writing this list. It&amp;rsquo;s a great collection of songs, probably better than their second album &amp;ldquo;Plunge&amp;rdquo;. The cover art is just as scary though.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #10: Wata Igarashi, Agartha</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-10-wata-igarashi-agartha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-10-wata-igarashi-agartha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Agartha is the debut album by Japanese electronic artist Wata Igarashi.&lt;span class=&#34;marginfigure&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/wata-igarashi-agartha.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Agartha by Wata Igarashi&#34; /&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Cover of &lt;em&gt;Agartha&lt;/em&gt; by Wata Igarashi&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/span&gt; I don&amp;rsquo;t really know much about him, but I do know that I enjoy releases on the German record label Kompakt and I have really enjoyed Japanese techno in recent years. Over lockdown I discovered Haruomi Hosono&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Polyharmony&amp;rdquo; album and re-discovered the work of Shinichi Atobe, particularly their album &amp;ldquo;Love of Plastic&amp;rdquo;. Both of those albums could be future understated classics and while both are by Japanese artists working in electronic music, there the comparison ends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year Preview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/albums-of-the-year-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/albums-of-the-year-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another year (nearly) over and so starting from tomorrow, I&amp;rsquo;m going to count down my top 10 albums of 2023. The rules are:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ellie Goulding - Bright Lights</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ellie-goulding-bright-lights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ellie-goulding-bright-lights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So today &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/how-random-should-things-be/&#34;&gt;my random album script&lt;/a&gt; picked out &amp;ldquo;Bright Lights&amp;rdquo; by Ellie Goulding, an album I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure I&amp;rsquo;ve ever listened to. I looked in my music library and there it was! As a result this is not so much an &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tag/album%20revisit/&#34;&gt;album revisit&lt;/a&gt; as an album &lt;em&gt;visit&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabric 44 by John Tejada</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fabric-44-by-john-tejada/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fabric-44-by-john-tejada/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is one of my more played Fabric mix CDs so I decided to go for it when my random prompter plumped for this earlier today. One constraint of these posts was to write it in roughly the amount of time it takes to listen to it. You&amp;rsquo;d think that for a mix CD that would be ok. After all, this mix is a full CD and 74 minutes long.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How random should things be?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-random-should-things-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-random-should-things-be/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to extract my music library, including all the albums I&amp;rsquo;ve added to streaming, as a CSV file and write a routine in R to select an album at random. The plan is to write about that album for the blog in roughly the time that it takes to listen to that album all the way through. I already did this yesterday for &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/goldfrapp-black-cherry&#34;&gt;Goldfrapp&amp;rsquo;s Black Cherry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goldfrapp - Black Cherry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/goldfrapp-black-cherry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/goldfrapp-black-cherry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the first in an unplanned series of &lt;strong&gt;album revisits&lt;/strong&gt;, I will write a post explaining the process soon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Orb, Live at Brighton Concord 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-orb---brighton-concord-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-orb---brighton-concord-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Went with my friend Nick to see The Orb at Concord 2 last night. The last time I&amp;rsquo;d seen the Orb was back in 2004, at the start of their relatively dry spell. That night, they&amp;rsquo;d been a bit lacklustre despite playing (some of) the hits and a relatively decent album in &amp;ldquo;Bicycles and Tricycles&amp;rdquo;. I left feeling that I&amp;rsquo;d seen the past rather than the future, something that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t glimpse again in their records until 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #39: Lifeforms by Future Sound of London</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-39/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-39/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lifeforms&lt;/strong&gt; is the 1994 album from the Future Sound of London. A double album (just), it also features the talents of Robert Fripp, Ozric Tentacles, Talvin Singh, Toni Halliday, and Liz Frazer. It reached number 6 on the UK album chart and went silver.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics Or Not?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-or-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-or-not/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the new year, thoughts and spare time for writing point me toward writing some new posts for my understated classics series. Expect some new ones soon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A pox on both their houses</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-pox-on-both-their-houses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-pox-on-both-their-houses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How hard is it to just listen to music these days?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If anything, make it weirder</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/make-it-weird/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/make-it-weird/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I listened to &amp;lsquo;Cloudbusting&amp;rsquo; by Kate Bush for the first time in a while. What a gloriously strange song it is. Best of all, it&amp;rsquo;s one of those songs that obscures what it is really about. It&amp;rsquo;s not a song about a change in the weather, but about &lt;a href=&#34;https://wilhelmreichmuseum.org/about/biography-of-wilhelm-reich/&#34;&gt;Wilhelm Reich&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Orgone&#34;&gt;orgone&lt;/a&gt; accumulator, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cultofweird.com/medical/radium-girls/&#34;&gt;fluorescent yo-yos&lt;/a&gt;, and a son (rather than a &lt;em&gt;sun&lt;/em&gt;) coming out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #38: Trance Nation (Various Artists)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-38/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-38/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, but lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been in need of some music that:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve listened to music in slightly different ways to normal in the last nine months, but it’s still been a decent year for music. When I checked out my Spotify Unwrapped and my Last.fm reports, I had listened to more 2020 music than I thought.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holiday Tabs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/holiday-tabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/holiday-tabs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the course of a week on holiday, I started reading many interesting articles. In lockdown there isn&amp;rsquo;t much to do but read articles, but I still find myself not that good at finishing them. My phone has lots of tabs open and has become a Rolodex of shame. This post is to confess my sins.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #37: Lost Souls by Doves</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-37/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Doves are a band from Manchester who traded dance music for rock yet never left their former genre behind. Starting out as Sub Sub, they scored a worldwide hit in 1993 with &amp;ldquo;Ain&amp;rsquo;t No Love (Ain&amp;rsquo;t No Use)&amp;rdquo;: a timeless dance tune that immediately owns whatever room it plays in. However, subsequent releases by Sub Sub did not catch on and people started to think of the band as a one-hit wonder.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About the Album Digest</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/about-the-album-digest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/about-the-album-digest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t written one of my monthly album digests for over a year. The reasons mostly boil down to a lack of time and motivation but other factors include the changing way in which I listen to music. I bought more albums on vinyl and only a small proportion of those were recently released music. Meanwhile, the attractions of Spotify&amp;rsquo;s release radar proved too great to resist: it is a very convenient way to consume new music.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Albums 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/top-10-albums-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/top-10-albums-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Songs 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/top-10-songs-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/top-10-songs-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, December 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-december-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-december-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, November 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Will Make Room For You - Four Tet Remix</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/i-will-make-room-for-you---four-tet-remix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/i-will-make-room-for-you---four-tet-remix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a perfect confluence of &lt;a href=&#34;album-digest-october-2011&#34;&gt;last month&amp;rsquo;s album digest&lt;/a&gt;, here&amp;rsquo;s an excellent Four Tet remix of Kaitlyn Aurelia Smith&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;I Will Make Room For You&amp;rdquo; from her album &amp;ldquo;The Kid&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ve put it into a playlist with &amp;ldquo;Lush&amp;rdquo; from Four Tet&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;New Energy&amp;rdquo; album and the original version of &amp;ldquo;I Will Make Room For You.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, October 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #36: The Coral by The Coral</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-36/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-36/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Perhaps in today&amp;rsquo;s modern age of streaming and such, &lt;a href=&#34;http://thecoral.co.uk&#34;&gt;The Coral&lt;/a&gt; would be a bigger band and may have survived their eventual burnout. Their work ethic was evident from the start, as rumours swirled &lt;a href=&#34;https://i.ebayimg.com/images/g/YdkAAOSwfl9XBSiR/s-l300.jpg&#34;&gt;in the NME&lt;/a&gt; about a fantastic new band from Liverpool who were going to blow everybody&amp;rsquo;s socks off. I went to see them live in Bristol after they&amp;rsquo;d released three EPs and they were incredible. Their sound, a bit like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0071615/&#34;&gt;the movie &amp;ldquo;Holy Mountain&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; set to pop music, imagined a Merseybeat channelled from an alternative universe in which Lennon and McCartney took their acid in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.desertusa.com/mojave-desert.html&#34;&gt;the Mojave desert&lt;/a&gt; rather than in the English suburbs. Yes, it was derivative but somehow it also managed to be utterly new and compelling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note: Recent months have been very busy, so this album digest combines a review of the new album by The National with a couple of reviews left over from earlier in the year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written a few more album reviews in the past months but I&amp;rsquo;m so far behind (February and March have already been published on a considerable lag) that I&amp;rsquo;m just going to pepper forthcoming digests with additional reviews of older albums.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #35: Snivilisation by Orbital</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-35/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I came late to Orbital&amp;rsquo;s work. I knew of them through a few remixes and because as a mad Orb fan, they could not have avoided my notice could they? Apart from that, one of my college friends tried to get me into &amp;ldquo;In Sides&amp;rdquo; just after its release in 1996. The same friend got me into &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/understated-classics-11/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Second Toughest In The Infants&amp;rdquo; by Underworld&lt;/a&gt;. I cannot now understand the reason, but &amp;ldquo;In Sides&amp;rdquo; just left me cold.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, March 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, February 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, January 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #34: Stray by Aztec Camera</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-34/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next instalment in my understated classics series is &amp;quot;Stray&amp;quot; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://killermontstreet.net&#34;&gt;Aztec Camera&lt;/a&gt;. Released in 1990, it features two hit singles and the cover is my favourite colour: green.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month&amp;rsquo;s album digest features albums by Wilco, M.I.A., Local Natives, and a collaboration between Kaitlyn Aurelia Smith and Suzanne Ciani.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adventures with Discover Weekly</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/adventures-with-discover-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/adventures-with-discover-weekly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any albums coming out this month that I wanted to review for the album digest, I decided to let Spotify pick the albums to listen to. I listened to my algorithmically chosen &lt;a href=&#34;https://techcrunch.com/2015/07/20/why-browse-when-you-can-play/&#34;&gt;Discover Weekly&lt;/a&gt; playlist one week and selected albums based on the songs that I liked the most. The album also had to be released in 2016. The selections are ones that got away.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BBC Prom 47 at the Royal Albert Hall</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bbc-prom-47-royal-albert-hall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bbc-prom-47-royal-albert-hall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We went to see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ulsterorchestra.org.uk/events/2016-08-21/&#34;&gt;Prom 47&lt;/a&gt;, an afternoon prom at the Royal Albert Hall in London. The bill included a brand new work by &lt;a href=&#34;http://piershellawell.com&#34;&gt;Piers Hellawell&lt;/a&gt;, along with a Cello concerto by &lt;a href=&#34;http://classicalmusic.about.com/od/classicalcomposers/p/haydnprofile.htm&#34;&gt;Haydn&lt;/a&gt; and a symphony by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.britannica.com/biography/Pyotr-Ilyich-Tchaikovsky&#34;&gt;Tchaikovsky&lt;/a&gt;. These were all performed by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ulsterorchestra.org.uk&#34;&gt;Ulster Orchestra&lt;/a&gt;. The conductor was Rafael Payare. The tickets were an affordable £17 each which isn&amp;rsquo;t bad at all given that we were sat in the second row of the circle. We had a great view.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, July 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Album Digest July 2016 consists of a bumper five albums, mainly because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t work out which one to drop. I think they&amp;rsquo;re all pretty good though it&amp;rsquo;s great to hear new music from The Avalanches after all this time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #33: Embrya by Maxwell</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-33/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I give the impression of planning these posts but to be honest I came across an article about Maxwell a few weeks ago and fondly remembered my cassette copy of this album. The joy of Spotify is that it&amp;rsquo;s easy to dig up old favourites. The recent warm weather makes for a good opportunity to enjoy the sultry embrace of &amp;ldquo;Embrya&amp;rdquo; once more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Album Digest June 2016 is a poppy batch of albums. We have the return of my long-time favourites Roxette and the heroes of my South American tour Tegan &amp;amp; Sara. There&amp;rsquo;s some dance music in the form of Flume&amp;rsquo;s album &amp;ldquo;Skin&amp;rdquo;: an Australian presence ahead of the new Avalanches album next month. Finally there is the first of two new albums by Islands - both were released back in May but one gets reviewed this month and the other next month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, May 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Album Digest May 2016 features the work of four bands or artists that I have reviewed in previous album digests. I also own (or will own) all of these albums on vinyl, so it&amp;rsquo;s handy that I&amp;rsquo;ve recently bought myself a record player!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, April 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month&amp;rsquo;s album digest is a mixture of comparisons. First we compare the fortunes of old hands Underworld to even older hands the Pet Shop Boys. After that I&amp;rsquo;ve found two dance albums, one that I liked and one that I didn&amp;rsquo;t. I find it quite hard to write about dance music and so the comparison is quite useful. Sometimes it helps to work out why you like one thing and not another.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Orb - Alpine EP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/orb-alpine-ep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/orb-alpine-ep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Orb return with a new EP on the &lt;a href=&#34;www.kompakt.fm&#34;&gt;Kompakt label&lt;/a&gt; called &amp;ldquo;Alpine&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, David Bowie RIP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-special-david-bowie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-special-david-bowie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought I&amp;rsquo;d add three of my favourite David Bowie albums to my review of Blackstar to a form an album digest tribute. Also among my favourites but not included here is &amp;ldquo;Outside&amp;rdquo;, which will be included in the understated classics (currently it&amp;rsquo;s number 66) at some point. I thought about bumping &amp;ldquo;Outside&amp;rdquo; up the running order but I&amp;rsquo;d like to be objective about it when its turn comes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Favourite Albums of 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/favourite-albums-of-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/favourite-albums-of-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Given that I gave up on writing album digests for a bit this year, I thought I would at least do a proper top ten list of my favourite albums. There are quite a few albums that I did not have room for and I might try to revisit those later. In the mean time, let&amp;rsquo;s crack on. (To save time, I have in some instances pasted my original review from the appropriate album digest.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Underworld, Second Toughest in the Infants (Superdeluxe edition)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/second-toughest-in-the-infants-superdeluxe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/second-toughest-in-the-infants-superdeluxe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week Underworld reissued their excellent second album “Second Toughest In The Infants” in various formats including a four disc super deluxe edition. I wrote about this album in my understated classics series and I want to share some thoughts on the reissue. I love this album so I was excited to hear the remaster and the additional material.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #32: They Were Wrong So We Drowned by Liars</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-32/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As it is Halloween, I&amp;rsquo;m writing about a spooky understated classic. Liars&amp;rsquo; second album &amp;ldquo;They Were Wrong, So We Drowned&amp;rdquo; is a concept album about witches. It was the first of their albums that I owned having heard their name mentioned among those in the New York Post-punk revival scene at the start of the 00s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everything Everything, Get To Heaven</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/everything-everything-get-to-heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/everything-everything-get-to-heaven/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write honestly about your feelings. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write about your feelings consistently, for a living on a regular basis. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write about your feelings when the world constantly intrudes with inanity, insanity and hatred. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write under those conditions without seeming frayed, without coming loose at the edges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #31: The White Room by The KLF</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-31/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This little masterpiece was released in 1991. I got my copy on cassette for Christmas that year, but by May in 1992 they&amp;rsquo;d already &amp;ldquo;retired&amp;rdquo; and split up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Initial Comparison of Apple Music and Spotify</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/an-initial-comparison-of-apple-music-and-spotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/an-initial-comparison-of-apple-music-and-spotify/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/why-apple-music-feels-like-a-fail/&#34;&gt;previous post about Apple Music&lt;/a&gt; was more a response to how it was presented at the WWDC Keynote rather than to the idea of Apple Music itself. I should have known better than to use that clickbait title. I knew I wasn&amp;rsquo;t writing about the product, more the flatness of its introduction (despite the names on show).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To reboot this series, Album Digest June 2015 features five fantastic albums from Hot Chip, Jamie xx, Blanck Mass, Holly Herndon, and The Orb. I could pick loads more as I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to a lot of albums since &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/album-digest-february-2015/&#34;&gt;February&lt;/a&gt; but I decided to focus on the more electronic material. This means that I have no excuses for not continuing next month with a rockier theme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #30: Our Aim Is to Satisfy by Red Snapper</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The thirtieth understated classic is by a band named after a fish. There isn&amp;rsquo;t a great deal for me to say about &amp;ldquo;Our Aim Is To Satisfy&amp;rdquo;&lt;label for=&#34;sidenote-0d5ce721c6374d08ef5be2ea13137861-0&#34; class=&#34;margin-toggle sidenote-number&#34;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; id=&#34;sidenote-0d5ce721c6374d08ef5be2ea13137861-0&#34; class=&#34;margin-toggle&#34;/&gt;&#xA;&lt;span class=&#34;sidenote&#34;&gt;A note on the title of the album, some sources refer to is as &amp;ldquo;Our Aim Is To Satisfy Red Snapper&amp;rdquo;. Personally I think this is ridiculous.&lt;/span&gt; apart from the usual insistence that it is quite good. There&amp;rsquo;s no overarching theme to write about, and no deep personal story attached. It was bound to happen eventually.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Can’t Just Switch Off Free</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-cant-just-switch-off-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-cant-just-switch-off-free/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2015/mar/11/ministry-of-sound-streaming-switch-off-free&#34;&gt;Ministry of Sound boss Lohan Presencer does the cry baby act in today&amp;rsquo;s Guardian&lt;/a&gt;, complaining that Spotify&amp;rsquo;s freemium model doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow him to bathe in a Scrooge McDuck style swimming pool of golden coins any more. The cat is out of the bag for streaming music now, and no matter how much music companies cry foul they can&amp;rsquo;t stop Spotify and their ilk, and there wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be pots of gold waiting for them even if they could.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, February 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #29: Let It Come Down by Spiritualized</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I listened to Let It Come Down by Spiritualized for the first time during a difficult time in my life. I think this will always affect my feelings towards it. For me it&amp;rsquo;s a great big comfort blanket of a record. Coming after one of the all-time best break-up albums (in an artistic sense) in &amp;ldquo;Ladies and Gentlemen We Are Floating in Space&amp;rdquo; perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s not that much of a surprise. Layered in orchestras, horn sections, and gospel choirs, it&amp;rsquo;s not understated at all but hopefully I can persuade you that it is a classic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, January 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Album Digest January 2015 rounds up a few albums from the tail end of 2014 that I didn&amp;rsquo;t get much time to write about. The only one of these six to be released this month is the excellent &amp;ldquo;No Cities To Love&amp;rdquo; by Sleater-Kinney.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #28: The Meadowlands by The Wrens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-28/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the first lines of &amp;ldquo;The House That Guilt Built&amp;rdquo;, the soft cricket-laden lament that opens The Meadowlands by The Wrens, is &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m nowhere near where I thought I&amp;rsquo;d be&amp;rdquo;. The last line of the whole album is &amp;ldquo;this is not what you had planned&amp;rdquo;. These bookending lines set the tone for this shimmering, ramshackle masterpiece - a fatigue and careworn pride in failing to meet impossible standards writ large over its first and last eighty or so seconds. &amp;ldquo;The Meadowlands&amp;rdquo; is probably the best record you&amp;rsquo;ve never heard, and once you have heard it, you will never be the same. Even better, it changes and you change with every single listen. If you&amp;rsquo;re living your life and you really mean it, then this is the record for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Album Digest September 2014 contains four amazing albums, including the long-awaited return from the Aphex Twin, and an album from Cymbals Eat Guitars released about a week after I wondered what had happened to them. Spooky. Rounding out the selection this month are a cool punky-disco album by The Juan Maclean and a truly remarkable offering by Vessel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The album digest returns with five albums by four artists.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #27: A Ghost Is Born by Wilco</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/whatever-happened-to-that-hat/&#34;&gt;I have already given some of the personal background to why I love this album&lt;/a&gt; and now it’s time to give a bit of love to the music itself so I’ll stick to giving a track by track account of “A Ghost Is Born”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are familiar with Wilco’s first few albums, you’ll know that A Ghost Is Born is on the line of best fit through Being There, Summerteeth, and Yankee Hotel Foxtrot. It continues its predecessor’s experimentation, but also gets reined in a little. Great songs - some of my favourite Wilco songs - were left off Yankee Hotel Foxtrot (“&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bemydemon.org/songs/venus.htm&#34;&gt;Venus Stopped The Train&lt;/a&gt;”, “&lt;a href=&#34;http://wilcoworld.net/#!/song/a-magazine-called-sunset/&#34;&gt;A Magazine Called Sunset&lt;/a&gt;”) so the follow-up could easily have been more of the same and everyone would have gone home happy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What IS That Noise?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-that-noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-that-noise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently spruced up a post I wrote four years ago about &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-4/&#34;&gt;Biosphere’s wonderful album Substrata&lt;/a&gt;. I added the following footnote about the difference between voice samples and found sound:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Amazing Subversive Revolutionary Adolescence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-amazing-subversive-revolutionary-adolescence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-amazing-subversive-revolutionary-adolescence/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #26: Come On Die Young by Mogwai</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you about punk rock: punk rock is a word used by dilettantes and ah&amp;hellip; and ah&amp;hellip; heartless manipulators about music that takes up the energies and the bodies and the hearts and the souls and the time and the minds of young men who give what they have to it and give everything they have to it and it&amp;rsquo;s a&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s a term that&amp;rsquo;s based on contempt, it&amp;rsquo;s a term that&amp;rsquo;s based on fashion, style, elitism, satanism and everything that&amp;rsquo;s rotten about rock &amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo; roll. I don&amp;rsquo;t know &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/John_Lydon&#34;&gt;Johnny Rotten&lt;/a&gt; but I&amp;rsquo;m sure&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m sure he puts as much blood and sweat into what he does as &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Sigmund_Freud&#34;&gt;Sigmund Freud&lt;/a&gt; did. You see, what sounds to you like a big load of trashy old noise is in fact the brilliant music of a genius, myself . And that music is so powerful that it&amp;rsquo;s quite beyond my control and ah&amp;hellip; when I&amp;rsquo;m in the grips of it I don&amp;rsquo;t feel pleasure and I don&amp;rsquo;t feel pain, either physically or emotionally. Do you understand what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about? Have you ever felt like that? When you just couldn&amp;rsquo;t feel anything and you didn&amp;rsquo;t want to either. You know? Like that? Do you understand what I&amp;rsquo;m saying sir? (Iggy Pop, Canadian TV, March 11th 1977.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://temporaryresidence.com/artists/watter&#34;&gt;Watter&lt;/a&gt; are a &amp;ldquo;supergroup&amp;rdquo; composed from various members of Grails, &lt;a href=&#34;http://touchandgorecords.com/bands/band.php?id=70&#34;&gt;Slint&lt;/a&gt;, and other bands. I did not know anything about Hundred Waters before this month: &amp;ldquo;The Moon Rang Like A Bell&amp;rdquo; is their second album. In fact second albums by bands I know nothing about are a something of theme because &amp;ldquo;Sunbathing Animal&amp;rdquo; is Parquet Courts&amp;rsquo; sophomore effort and I don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about them either. Meanwhile, I&amp;rsquo;ve meant to write about &amp;ldquo;The Four Seasons Recomposed&amp;rdquo; since April.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, May 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month was strange. I didn’t listen to much new music and after &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/album-digest-april-2014/&#34;&gt;last month’s bumper digest&lt;/a&gt; there’s probably a reason for that. Not to mention that Spotify gives you more reasons to look backwards than forwards. Nevertheless, this brief post features new albums by Little Dragon and Coldplay, along with the mini-album collaboration between Röyskopp and Robyn.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, March 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m back in the UK so it’s back to posts about albums each month. This one is a bit different because I didn’t listen to very much new stuff while I was away so not all of the albums are up to date. I had to write about the new album by Liars though because it&amp;rsquo;s awesome and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait to discuss it! Here’s the list of albums:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, October 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Four great albums this month for the last album digest in a while.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A nice diverse selection of albums this month:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #25: Long Gone Before Daylight by The Cardigans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The single biggest fact of life is that you are always going to be alone, you just might not realise it. Listening to The Cardigans&amp;rsquo; excellent 2003 &amp;ldquo;Long Gone Before Daylight&amp;rdquo; will help you see that all our relationships are essentially screwed &amp;ndash; but at least it sounds great while it does so.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For reasons that will become apparent, there will be a short period soon where I will not be writing album digests. Until then, I&amp;rsquo;m clearing a backlog of some albums that I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to but haven&amp;rsquo;t had enough time or motivation to write about. Only one of this month&amp;rsquo;s albums was released this month, something that&amp;rsquo;s not that uncommon at this time of the year as it is not the best time to release things. Here&amp;rsquo;s the list:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, July 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another four albums for you this month. Sometimes the problem is not finding albums to listen to but actually finding time to listen to them! Often it is not because I don&amp;rsquo;t have time but because I have already found some great albums this month and I am busy listening to those instead. As a result, a couple of these albums are ones that I have only listened to for a week or so, but they are interesting enough to write about. Here are the four albums I am going to write about this month:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just two albums this month as I am still enjoying last month&amp;rsquo;s albums so much (and I spent loads of time getting reacquainted with Boards Of Canada at the start of the month). I listened to a few more albums but not often enough to write loads about them so there is an &amp;ldquo;honourable mention&amp;rdquo; section at the end of the post that briefly discusses a few more albums.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #24: Reservoir by Fanfarlo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have written a lot in these posts about how music gets indelibly tied up with places, events and feelings. For me this album by Fanfarlo is tied up with all three of these. It makes me happy and sad at the same time in memory of great times that are now gone but are fondly remembered. I am aware that this is the youngest album on the list so far and so it might be a bit early to endow classic status upon it, but &amp;ldquo;Reservoir&amp;rdquo; is a fine album and to my ears it stands up really well. Listening to it again in the course of writing this post I found that I remembered every note and musical phrase, and yet somehow I also managed to delight in hearing new features in the production that I&amp;rsquo;d not noticed before.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, May 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2013/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #23: Gorgeous by 808 State</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was quite hard to choose an 808 State album for the &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;understated classics series&lt;/a&gt; for two reasons. The first is that I was introduced to 808 State quite late through a friend&amp;rsquo;s sister&amp;rsquo;s cassette copy of The Shamen&amp;rsquo;s En-Tact (the original version recorded from vinyl that had a thirteen minute version of &amp;ldquo;Evil Is Eden&amp;rdquo;) that also had &amp;ndash; to fill out the C90 &amp;ndash; the full length sweary version of &amp;ldquo;What Time Is Love?&amp;rdquo; by The KLF and four tracks: &amp;ldquo;Cubik&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Pacific&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Olympic&amp;rdquo; (I think&amp;hellip;), and &amp;ldquo;In Yer Face&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, April 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some great albums this month!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, March 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just the David Bowie album this month as it’s pretty much the only new music that I’ve listened to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #22: Walking With Thee by Clinic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Walking With Thee” is the second album by Liverpool band &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clinic_(band)&#34;&gt;Clinic&lt;/a&gt;. It was released in 2002, which seems like an age ago now. Even longer ago they released the single “The Return of Evil Bill”, which was got me interested in them in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Work Of Art At The End Of My Road?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-work-of-art-at-the-end-of-my-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-work-of-art-at-the-end-of-my-road/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have had a lot of ideas for posts swirling around in my head in recent days. This is because I have actually done quite a lot of cool things in that time, and because I have hung out with some great people who make me think, and because I always have a whole load of things bouncing around in there anyway - space junk of the mind. I was thinking about how to put together these thoughts I have been having about art and about stories and yes, about love too. It all kind of got muddled up and then I saw it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, February 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most Februaries are quite quiet when it comes to albums (though this was not the case &lt;a href=&#34;album-digest-february-2011&#34;&gt;back in 2011&lt;/a&gt;) and although only the Foals album is a major release, I was quite surprised to find myself with four decent albums to write about. They are:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, January 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Only one of this month three albums was actually released this month. Nelly Furtado&amp;rsquo;s Mi plan was actually released over three years ago - I only discovered it last year when I wrote &lt;a href=&#34;album-digest-september-2012&#34;&gt;the September album digest&lt;/a&gt; following the release of &amp;ldquo;The Spirit Indestructible&amp;rdquo;, or it might have been when I wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;uc20&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Folklore&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; at around the same time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, December 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-december-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-december-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three albums (one very Christmassey one!) and an EP this month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, November 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pretty much a sliding scale between songs and electronic wibble on this month’s albums and a particularly damp, chilly feeling to proceedings too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #21: Woob 2 by Woob</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The second Woob album (AKA “Woob 4495”) is probably the greatest ambient album ever made and is certainly the best one you have never heard of. Originally released in 1995 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.emit.cc&#34;&gt;on the em:t label&lt;/a&gt; it is also a rare record. I don’t have an actual copy but I have seen one! I downloaded it off the internet and even that is quite difficult to do. My friend is an avid collector of all the em:t releases and it is easy to see why: all the albums are titled in a specific way that is very appealing to people who like to collect things and they also have very striking nature photography on the covers. In a strange way, the label was able to create an identity for its releases in a way that many artists would try to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, October 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a strange month and I found that I didn’t listen to a lot of new music. I have been a bit down and when that’s the case I tend to take refuge in music that I know well, stuff that cheers me up. I have listened to last month’s fave a lot, Nelly Furtado’s “The Spirit Indestructible”. I said a lot of nice things about it but it probably didn’t come over in my writing just how much I really liked it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had a bit more time to listen to this month’s albums because I was on holiday for two weeks. I didn’t manage to write about them while on holiday though! In fact I bought and listened to a few more, but I will save them for next month. The albums I will discuss now (in order bought) are:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #20: Folklore by Nelly Furtado</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s rather spooky but shortly after deciding to write about Nelly Furtado’s “Folklore” as the next &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;understated classic&lt;/a&gt;, I found out that she has a new album out this week. As a result, I have been listening to a lot of her music while writing this post, and I’ve been enjoying it too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Album Digest August 2012 is also from the stack of albums that I &lt;a href=&#34;album-digest-july-2012&#34;&gt;mentioned last month&lt;/a&gt;. I chose this selection (along with the Passion Pit album) because the colours looked good together in the mosaic of covers that I make each month. Last month’s digest was about the right amount of detail so this will be another briefer digest. These are all good albums but not ones that will change your life, they&amp;rsquo;ll just happily sit alongside it. They are:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #19: The Dreaming by Kate Bush</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“I see the people working and see it working for them.” (&lt;em&gt;Sat In Your Lap&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, July 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a short album digest this month. I bought a stack of CDs and am parcelling them out over the next few months (together with important additional releases as they crop up). This is in the hope that I can write more considered pieces about each one. This month I’ve grouped together albums with monochrome covers and a BT album from June that I found out about recently. These albums are not just linked by their artwork, they also form a cohesive whole. As a result I dispense with reviewing each album in depth. As usual there is a playlist at the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three fantastic albums for Album Digest June 2012:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CAN, The Lost Tapes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/can-the-lost-tapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/can-the-lost-tapes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This arrived on Monday and I thought I would give it a post of its own because at over 3 hours of music, I am unlikely to do more than dip into it before writing the album digest next week. It is a far bigger and more enjoyable artefact than I thought it was going to be, so it probably deserves special attention for that reason too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #18: Fabric 12 mixed by The Amalgamation Of Soundz</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Say what? We’re allowing compilations now?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, May 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Four albums for Album Digest May 2012:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, April 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A mostly instrumental month with a comeback from Orbital, an excellent remix collection from Battles, an amazing movie documenting a live performance by the Chemical Brothers and Austin Wintory’s soundtrack to the game &lt;em&gt;Journey&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #17: Nearly God by Nearly God (Tricky)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sit back and let it happen, / Let us take your time away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, March 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Five albums for Album Digest March 2012&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #16: Ambient 2 / The Plateaux Of Mirror by Howard Budd and Brian Eno</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-16/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, February 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One EP and three albums for Album Digest February 2012:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, January 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Five albums to see in the new year:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #15: Début by Björk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got into Début via a cassette from the library, much like I did with &lt;a href=&#34;uc1&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Together Alone&lt;/em&gt; by Crowded House&lt;/a&gt;. I suppose it is less obscure than many of my choices for &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;this strand&lt;/a&gt; but I do think that &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; is more well-known (because of &lt;em&gt;It’s Oh So Quiet&lt;/em&gt;, which we shall mention here only briefly) and that &lt;em&gt;Homogenic&lt;/em&gt; is probably more popular among her fans.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, December 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-december-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-december-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some rather brief pen pictures of this month’s albums. I’ve been a bit busy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, November 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just three albums this month as I’ve been listening to a lot of Brian Eno records ready for an upcoming understated classic. First up is &lt;em&gt;50 Words For Snow&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;Kate Bush&lt;/strong&gt;, the second album that she has released this year. &lt;a href=&#34;album-digest-may-2011&#34;&gt;Back in May&lt;/a&gt; I wrote about &lt;em&gt;Director’s Cut&lt;/em&gt;, which presented re-recorded and re-mastered versions of songs from her albums &lt;em&gt;The Sensual World&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Red Shoes&lt;/em&gt;. This time around it is an album of brand new material, the first since &lt;em&gt;Aerial&lt;/em&gt; in 2006.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #14: Clear by Bomb The Bass</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think it’s time to discuss your philosophy of drug use as it relates to artistic endeavour…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, October 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month we have albums by Björk, Coldplay, M83, and Radiohead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hmmm, a rather grey looking selection of covers this month. The albums I have listened to most are:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #13: U.F.Orb by The Orb</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FUN FACT:&lt;/strong&gt; It was because of the artwork to this album that I obsessively scrawled onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome on my pencil case at school. I also had a very passable u.f.orb logo drawn on it too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I bought a collection of electronic music this month. I mixed them all up in a smart playlist on iTunes, the smart aspect being to limit to tracks that had been played fewer than five then six then seven times etc. This made sure I was still listening to all the tracks equally often, despite the randomness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #12: Look Sharp! by Roxette</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-12/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, July 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quite a mixed bag this month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #11: Second Toughest In The Infants by Underworld</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-11/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have had the sort of month that is not conducive to listening to much new music. Therefore this month’s post is only going to consider two new albums and two albums that I have bought behind time. Because of various bits of stress and poor mood, I have ended up going back and taking refuge in some old favourites and not listening to new stuff. At other points I have also gone back to the Fleet Foxes’ album that I wrote about last month, which has grown on me even more since. Sometimes I think that I should writing about these albums on a two month delay. Meanwhile, I even have new music that I haven’t listened to &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt;, namely &lt;strong&gt;Bon Iver&lt;/strong&gt;’s self-titled album. It has received so many good reviews that I have been too intimidated to listen to it. I will try to write about it next month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #10: Tubular Bells II by Mike Oldfield</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was the artwork that got me interested in Tubular Bells II. Rendering Trevor Key&amp;rsquo;s wonderful icon of the twisted tubular bell in yellow and blue made it all the more mysterious. Seeing it one day in Woolworth&amp;rsquo;s in Leigh Park back in 1992 aroused my curiosity. The huge display must have been part of the massive publicity drive for the album. Despite dwindling sales for his albums at that time, a sequel to Tubular Bells represented a huge potential for sales. This is why Oldfield had been lured from his previous home at Virgin records over to Warner Music. At that point Oldfield had not made a good album since his soundtrack to the movie &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0087553/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Killing Fields&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in 1985, the end of a hot streak (perhaps 1980&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;QE2&lt;/em&gt; aside) that had lasted since the original &lt;em&gt;Tubular Bells&lt;/em&gt; back in 1973.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, May 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Four albums this month:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kate Bush &lt;em&gt;Director’s Cut&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Africa Hitech &lt;em&gt;93 Million Miles&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fleet Foxes &lt;em&gt;Helplessness Blues&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;TV On The Radio &lt;em&gt;Nine Types of Light&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #9: Tiger Bay by Saint Etienne</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-9/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, April 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2011/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, March 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/this-is-not-an-album-digest-march-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/this-is-not-an-album-digest-march-2011/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #8: Second Light by Dreadzone</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;understated classics&lt;/a&gt; series, I try to alternate between pop/rock and electronic albums. Keeping with this trend number eight is the wonderful dub-infused album &lt;em&gt;Second Light&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dreadzone.com&#34;&gt;Dreadzone&lt;/a&gt;. Released in 1996 it was well-received critically and four of its tracks featured on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/radio1/johnpeel/&#34;&gt;John Peel&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s best-of-year list that year. &lt;em&gt;Little Britain&lt;/em&gt; received a lot of radio play, a popular choice for that flag-waving period of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mojo4music.com/13834/the-story-of-britpop-in-60-albums/&#34;&gt;britpop&lt;/a&gt; and assorted other demons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, February 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;February, the shortest month, harbinger of such delights as Groundhog Day and Valentine’s Day. Could it possibly produce any good albums? Well the candidates are the eponymous début album by &lt;strong&gt;James Blake&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Zonoscope&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;Cut/Copy&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Let England Shake&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;PJ Harvey&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Smart Flesh&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;The Low Anthem&lt;/strong&gt;. Furthermore, there was an unexpected bonus when &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.radiohead.com/deadairspace/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Radiohead&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; announced that their new album would be out and available to listen to this month too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, January 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s to 2011 and the start of a monthly album digest. I want it to be a brief trot through some of the albums I have listened to each month. Sometimes January can bring a few quiet releases by big name bands. This happens if the previous album did not do as well as the record company hoped or if it is the kind of artist who would get lost under the hype of all the Christmas releases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #7: 100 Broken Windows by Idlewild</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Idewild are a solid band who have released four or five albums that I could consider for this series. I&amp;rsquo;m even in the sleeve credits of one: &lt;em&gt;Post-Electric Blues&lt;/em&gt;, if you&amp;rsquo;re asking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #6: Arbor Bona Arbor Mala by The Shamen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-6/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #5: A Weekend In The City by Bloc Party</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-5/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #4: Substrata by Biosphere</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I bought this album in the summer between my two years at college. I remember listening to this music under skies glowering with clouds so 1997 must have been a poor summer. I’d just bought a book of photography too, which placed photos from the north and south poles on opposite pages. I bought it mainly for the penguins that were, of course, on pretty much every other page. The pictures of&#xA;snow and ice soon became the ideal companions to this album.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #3: The Circle &amp; The Square by Red Box</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next entry in the understated classics series is &amp;ldquo;The Circle &amp;amp; The Square&amp;rdquo; by Red Box.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #2: Sinking by The Aloof</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #1: Together Alone by Crowded House</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week Arcade Fire released their hotly anticipated third album &amp;ldquo;The Suburbs&amp;rdquo;.  I loved &amp;ldquo;Neon Bible&amp;rdquo; but critics found it preachy, as overbearing as the religious folk it sought to satirise. I disagree and think it was an impressive continuation from an exciting debut. &amp;ldquo;The Suburbs&amp;rdquo; steps on from their previous two albums, both in subject matter and tone. It&amp;rsquo;s sad, thoughtful, resigned, angry and tetchy - among other things. “The Suburbs” isn&amp;rsquo;t the understated classic that I want to discuss though: with all the praise and plaudits, it may never suit this new thread of posts. I want to write about &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Together_Alone&#34;&gt;Together Alone by Crowded House&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
