<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pet Shop Boys on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/pet-shop-boys/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pet Shop Boys on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/pet-shop-boys/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2024 Albums of the Year #8: Pet Shop Boys Nonetheless</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-08-pet-shop-boys-nonetheless/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-08-pet-shop-boys-nonetheless/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./images/psb-nonetheless.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Nonetheless by the Pet Shop Boys&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-options&#34;&gt;Other options&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Because I&amp;rsquo;ve loved so many albums this year, after each review I am going to include a couple of pointers to additional albums that you might enjoy if you like the album in the main review. This is not me showing off (well, not much), but rather giving credit to the many excellent albums released this year!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, April 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month&amp;rsquo;s album digest is a mixture of comparisons. First we compare the fortunes of old hands Underworld to even older hands the Pet Shop Boys. After that I&amp;rsquo;ve found two dance albums, one that I liked and one that I didn&amp;rsquo;t. I find it quite hard to write about dance music and so the comparison is quite useful. Sometimes it helps to work out why you like one thing and not another.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, July 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another four albums for you this month. Sometimes the problem is not finding albums to listen to but actually finding time to listen to them! Often it is not because I don&amp;rsquo;t have time but because I have already found some great albums this month and I am busy listening to those instead. As a result, a couple of these albums are ones that I have only listened to for a week or so, but they are interesting enough to write about. Here are the four albums I am going to write about this month:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
