<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pet Shop Boys on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/pet-shop-boys/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pet Shop Boys on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/pet-shop-boys/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2024 Albums of the Year #8: Pet Shop Boys Nonetheless</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-08-pet-shop-boys-nonetheless/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-08-pet-shop-boys-nonetheless/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless is the fifteenth album by the Pet Shop Boys. As seems to be a common theme with this top 10 so far, it&amp;rsquo;s an album that initially underwhelmed me. Well, perhaps &amp;ldquo;underwhelmed&amp;rdquo; is a little unfair, it was more that it didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to have much to it to distinguish it from their previous albums, and there have been some palpable duds in the previous fourteen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, April 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month&amp;rsquo;s album digest is a mixture of comparisons. First we compare the fortunes of old hands Underworld to even older hands the Pet Shop Boys. After that I&amp;rsquo;ve found two dance albums, one that I liked and one that I didn&amp;rsquo;t. I find it quite hard to write about dance music and so the comparison is quite useful. Sometimes it helps to work out why you like one thing and not another.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, July 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another four albums for you this month. Sometimes the problem is not finding albums to listen to but actually finding time to listen to them! Often it is not because I don&amp;rsquo;t have time but because I have already found some great albums this month and I am busy listening to those instead. As a result, a couple of these albums are ones that I have only listened to for a week or so, but they are interesting enough to write about. Here are the four albums I am going to write about this month:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
