<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travel on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travel on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 22:13:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on 2023</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/reflections-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 22:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/reflections-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;travel&#34;&gt;Travel&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2023, it was Germany or go home.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Went to Cologne in January. Here is photographic evidence:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/2023/cologne-proof.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Photographic evidence of my visit to Cologne&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We took the Eurostar via Brussels. A bit of a long day on the way back but much less stressful compared to flying.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We went to the Isle of Wight in June. It was the first time I&amp;rsquo;d been since I was about 8. This time I didn&amp;rsquo;t get Chicken Pox. Anyway, here is photographic evidence:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Travel Writing After All This</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/travel-writing-after-all-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/travel-writing-after-all-this/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While sprucing up this blog a bit during lockdown, I fell into reading my old posts about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/tag/south%20america/&#34;&gt;South America&lt;/a&gt;. I enjoyed it, mostly for the memories, but also because the current lockdown is warping my sense of time and space. Hours feel like weeks, but then I blink and a month&amp;rsquo;s gone by. I find myself traipsing similar orbits each day around the house, and then perhaps over to the supermarket or the park. There&amp;rsquo;s a palpable escapism to be had in reminiscing about South America and other places.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Great Ocean Road</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-great-ocean-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-great-ocean-road/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a &lt;a href=&#34;articles/the-same-yet-different&#34;&gt;wedding present&lt;/a&gt;, Ingrid&amp;rsquo;s Mum Maria kindly took us for a trip along &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_Ocean_Road&#34;&gt;The Great Ocean Road&lt;/a&gt;, the longest war memorial in the world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Stretching 151 miles from Torquay (not that one!) to Allansford, the road was deliberately built as a tourist attraction as a means of providing meaningful work for troops returning home from the First World War. Regarded as one of the world&amp;rsquo;s greatest scenic roads, it certainly holds it own against things like the roads I experienced in Chile and Bolivia when I travelled over the Andes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More Melbourne</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/metros-suburbs-barbies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/metros-suburbs-barbies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On our second full day in Australia we went shopping in central Melbourne, before Ingrid&amp;rsquo;s mum Maria picked us up ahead of our trip along the Great Ocean Road.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We took the metro into the city. I always love watching the fabric of cities knit itself together around train lines and Melbourne is no exception. Along the way, Ingrid had plenty of stories to tell about the various places she had lived.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taking It Easy In Melbourne</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/australia-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/australia-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On our first full day in Melbourne we took it easy. It was warm and sunny, so different to the weather we&amp;rsquo;d left behind!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ingrid needed more time than me to sleep off her jet-lag. I sat in the sunshine and read the book I&amp;rsquo;d ignored on the plane. An easy read, it drew me into its characters. I&amp;rsquo;ll post a review later, perhaps after I have read the sequel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Day in the Air</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/australia-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/australia-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/australia_1/australia_1_01.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Plane&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It seemed to last forever but we made it. We left for Heathrow at 6AM and left London at around midday. I waved goodbye to home for nearly four weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We stopped over in Dubai for an hour or so while the plane refuelled. We walked in circles trying to shake off the fatigue. I&amp;rsquo;d equalled one of my longest ever flights just getting to Dubai and now I was facing almost twice as much time again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A little trip to Italy</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/a-little-trip-to-italy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/a-little-trip-to-italy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We bought a cheap package holiday in the British Airways Black Friday sale. The weekend spanned Ingrid&amp;rsquo;s birthday, so it was ideal. £99 each for flights and a hotel, and we bagged a hire car quite cheaply too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Because our flight was from Heathrow and the trains from Chichester are both expensive and inconvenient for early flights, we spoiled ourselves with a taxi to the airport. It felt very strange to be whisked through the Sussex and Surrey countryside at six am on a Friday morning!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lausanne, Switzerland, March 2016</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/lausanne-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/lausanne-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just before Easter Ingrid and I went to Lausanne in Switzerland for a few days. It was a much-needed break and my first trip out of the UK since I got back from South America.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We caught an early train to Gatwick. It took a strange route along the coast via Worthing and Hove, which was annoying because we could have left later if a more direct train were available at that time of day. At least it wasn&#39;t late, which for Southern is really rare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
