<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Theatre on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/theatre/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Theatre on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/theatre/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Summer 1954</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/summer-1954/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/summer-1954/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Summer 1954 is a pair of one-act plays by Sir Terrence Rattigan that are currently being performed together at the Chichester Festival Theatre. I really enjoyed both plays.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;table-number-seven&#34;&gt;Table Number Seven&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first play is &lt;em&gt;Table Number Seven&lt;/em&gt;, which is set in a boarding hotel in Bournemouth. We&amp;rsquo;re gradually introduced to a cast of characters - mostly elderly ladies - who are staying there. One of them, the major, who in a Fawlty Towers way won&amp;rsquo;t shut up once you get talking to him, is particularly interested in an article in an obscure local paper.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Threepenny Opera</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/threepenny-opera/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/threepenny-opera/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, Ingrid and I went to see The Threepenny Opera at the National Theatre.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Threepenny Opera was written by Bertolt Brecht and Kurt Weill, based on Elisabeth Hauptmann&amp;rsquo;s German translation of John Gay&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;A Beggar&amp;rsquo;s Opera&amp;rdquo;. It was first performed in Weimar Berlin in 1928 and has evolved over time through many adaptations, including several film and off-Broadway versions. It&amp;rsquo;s a work with very powerful musical overtones and, despite avowals otherwise throughout by the narrator, it has a powerful moral message.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Nutcracker</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-nutcracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-nutcracker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For Ingrid&amp;rsquo;s birthday, we went to see &lt;a href=&#34;http://moscowcityballet.com/en/repertoire/ballet/1&#34;&gt;The Nutcracker performed by the Moscow City Ballet&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;http://kingsportsmouth.co.uk&#34;&gt;The King&amp;rsquo;s Theatre in Southsea&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The original conversation went something along the lines of &amp;ldquo;Matt, please come and see some ballet with me on my birthday! It might not be your thing but I&amp;rsquo;d love someone to come and see it with me&amp;rdquo;. As I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved a bit of Tchaikovsky, I said yes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My only previous encounter with a ballet was an adaptation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_II_(ballet)&#34;&gt;Christopher Marlowe&amp;rsquo;s Edward II by John McCabe&lt;/a&gt; during my English Literature A-level. We got a day trip to exotic Bristol out of it, which when I was 17 meant the chance to visit all the cool record shops looking for rare KLF vinyl that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford. We also got underage hammered at the pub before going to the Hippodrome to watch a ballet in which a man flounced around with a giant pink strap-on on (as if male ballet dancers didn&amp;rsquo;t have enough of that action going on already!). Needless to say, it did little to convert me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
