<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fabric on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/fabric/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fabric on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/fabric/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fabric 44 by John Tejada</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/fabric-44-by-john-tejada/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/fabric-44-by-john-tejada/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is one of my more played Fabric mix CDs so I decided to go for it when my random prompter plumped for this earlier today. One constraint of these posts was to write it in roughly the amount of time it takes to listen to it. You&amp;rsquo;d think that for a mix CD that would be ok. After all, this mix is a full CD and 74 minutes long.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #18: Fabric 12 mixed by The Amalgamation Of Soundz</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Say what? We’re allowing compilations now?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes. Why not? A good mix is as much an artistic statement as a full-blown single artist album. It takes a lot of skill to get from A to B and keep everything on the boil in between. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fabriclondon.com/store/catalog/product/view/id/30/s/fabric-12/categories/8/&#34;&gt;This Fabric mix by The Amalgamation Of Soundz&lt;/a&gt; is one of my favourites because it is a downtempo (but, crucially, not &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; downtempo) compilation delivered with flair and using what I consider to be unconventional sources (soundtracks, tribute albums, hip-hop) to do it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, January 2012</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-january-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-january-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Five albums to see in the new year:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;FOE “Bad Dream Hotline”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Leila “U &amp;amp; I”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Diagrams “Black Light”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pyramids &amp;amp; Horseback “A Throne Without A King”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;FabricLive 61 mixed by Pinch&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;foe-_bad-dream-hotline_&#34;&gt;FOE &lt;em&gt;Bad Dream Hotline&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I listened to “Bad Dream Hotline” about four times thinking “who does her voice remind me of?”. In the end I realised it was Sophie Ellis-Bextor, though in parts she sounds like KT Tunstall too. Of course these are rather tame references and I don’t mean to damn with faint praise, this album is much more edgy than those two ever were. If you are after some girly power pop with a darker edge then this will no doubt be the album that you have been waiting for.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, April 2011</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-april-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-april-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;album-of-the-month-_mirrorwriting_-by-jamie-woon&#34;&gt;Album of the month: &lt;em&gt;Mirrorwriting&lt;/em&gt; by Jamie Woon&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jamie Woon was brought to my attention late last year by Pitchfork who wrote an article about the video for lead single &lt;em&gt;Night Air&lt;/em&gt;. I’ve put that video down below because I think that it is very good, a simple well executed and the tune itself is brilliant, probably my favourite individual track of 2010. It’s a downtempo tune full of dark spaces and empty beats, full of nocturnal promise and mystery. Hungry for more, I also bought the &lt;em&gt;Wayfaring Stranger&lt;/em&gt; EP and pre-ordered &lt;em&gt;Mirrorwriting&lt;/em&gt; as soon as it was possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
