<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tate Modern on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/tate-modern/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tate Modern on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/tate-modern/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Georgia O&#39;Keeffe at Tate Modern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/georgia-okeeffe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/georgia-okeeffe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We went to see the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tate.org.uk/whats-on/tate-modern/exhibition/georgia-okeeffe&#34;&gt;Georgia O&amp;rsquo;Keeffe exhibition at the Tate Modern&lt;/a&gt; last year. At the time, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know much about her, other than the fact she was famous for painting flowers. And that people get a bit hot under the collar about what those paintings might represent. Was the art world of the 1920s and 1930s so repressed that it managed to get into a lather about some paintings of flowers? And more importantly, are they any good?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mira Schendel at Tate Modern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/mira-schendel-tate-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/mira-schendel-tate-modern/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2013/sep/29/mira-schendel-tate-modern-review&#34;&gt;Mira Schendel&lt;/a&gt; was a Brazilian artist who was active throughout the middle to late twentieth century. She is considered to be one of South America&amp;rsquo;s best artists. Known mostly for her abstract paintings, she also experimented with sculptures and installations. Many of her works use text and semiotics to explore and define possible meanings for more abstract works.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I saw this exhibition during its run in the Tate Modern in the Autumn of 2013. I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like writing about it at the time. In fact I may not have had any time because it was quite close to my departure for South America.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ellen Gallagher at Tate Modern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ellen-gallagher-at-tate-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ellen-gallagher-at-tate-modern/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ellen Gallagher is an American artist and her &amp;ldquo;AxME&amp;rdquo; show recently finished at the Tate Modern. I went along a few weeks ago and have only now had a bit of time to write up my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My biggest regret is that I didn&amp;rsquo;t go along to it sooner, so that I had a chance to see it more than once. It was certainly a larger show than I was expecting (it was about the size of the &lt;a href=&#34;ibrahim-el-salahi-at-tate-modern&#34;&gt;Ibrahim El-salahi&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;choucair-at-tate-modern&#34;&gt;Saloua Choucair&lt;/a&gt; shows put together) and I hadn&amp;rsquo;t left myself with a lot of time to see everything when I did go.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ibrahim El-Salahi At Tate Modern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ibrahim-el-salahi-at-tate-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ibrahim-el-salahi-at-tate-modern/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ibrahim El-Salahi is a modernist artist from Sudan. I believe this exhibition is a first for an African artist at the Tate Modern. Much like &lt;a href=&#34;choucair-at-tate-modern&#34;&gt;the Choucair show&lt;/a&gt; (which is still on everyone!), it&amp;rsquo;s an engaging but too short introduction to an interesting artist that you have probably never heard of.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The pieces are roughly divided between large blank and white ink drawings that are mounted on multiple panels and oil paintings in earthy colours that depict abstract scenes. There are one or two pieces that buck this trend, such as &amp;ldquo;Portrait of Mrs. McKelvey&amp;rdquo; and a couple of other portraits toward the beginning of the exhibition. Frustratingly, pictures of his work are rather hard to come by online and the only two works that I was able to surreptitiously snap while at the show were the mesmeric &amp;ldquo;Reborn Sounds of Childhood Dreams I&amp;rdquo; and the mirage-like &amp;ldquo;They Always Appear&amp;rdquo;. (2020 Update: I have removed some images from posts, these being two of them.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choucair At Tate Modern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/choucair-at-tate-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/choucair-at-tate-modern/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I went to see the Saloua Raouda Choucair show at the Tate Modern. As it was quite small, I went to see &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/lichtenstein-at-tate-modern/&#34;&gt;the Lichtenstein show&lt;/a&gt; again as well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Choucair is an underrated Lebanese artist and many of the paintings and sculptures shown were created in the fifties and sixties. Her sculptures in particular are amazing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first room is lined with paintings that were nearly all gouache on paper, about 40cm by 30cm. These paintings were vibrant and abstract. I prefer larger oil paintings and it took me a while to get to grips with the small format and the bright colours, but they are really quite wonderful: the colours swim and dance in front of you. I thought the nudes were particularly interesting, mainly because nudes are executed by almost every artist at some stage (there are some rather spotty ones by Lichtenstein for example) and are usually quite memorable &amp;ndash; so seeing an artist&amp;rsquo;s nudes can give you a point of relation to other artists. Choucair&amp;rsquo;s nudes are pink and ample and altogether the more charming for it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lichtenstein At Tate Modern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/lichtenstein-at-tate-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/lichtenstein-at-tate-modern/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was a show that I had put off going to see for quite a while now. Looking online at the pictures featured in the show did not really excite me enough to get out and see it. I&amp;rsquo;d seen &lt;em&gt;Whaam!&lt;/em&gt; before in isolation (it&amp;rsquo;s part of the Tate collection and will no doubt return once the retrospective show is over) and it didn&amp;rsquo;t really grab me, arresting as it is. However, with plenty of free time this week it was an ideal time to go see it and I was happy to be proved wrong.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Work Of Art At The End Of My Road?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-work-of-art-at-the-end-of-my-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-work-of-art-at-the-end-of-my-road/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have had a lot of ideas for posts swirling around in my head in recent days. This is because I have actually done quite a lot of cool things in that time, and because I have hung out with some great people who make me think, and because I always have a whole load of things bouncing around in there anyway - space junk of the mind. I was thinking about how to put together these thoughts I have been having about art and about stories and yes, about love too. It all kind of got muddled up and then I saw it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
