<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Underworld on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/underworld/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Underworld on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/underworld/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Underworld, Strawberrry Hotel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/underworld-strawberrry-hotel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/underworld-strawberrry-hotel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An album that arrived a bit too late to be considered in the best of the year list, &lt;em&gt;Strawberry Hotel&lt;/em&gt; by Underworld is a solid effort. Their 11th album, it remarks their return to the format after five years after the &lt;em&gt;Drift&lt;/em&gt; series in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Drift&lt;/em&gt; had been an interesting experiment where Underworld had tried to put out a new track each week and grouping several weeks worth into EPs before putting out a massive 6+ hour box set. The striking thing about the project was that it was so good. They released a sampler edition of the album which cherry picked the best songs, but almost every track released as part of &lt;em&gt;Drift&lt;/em&gt; could be swapped into that sampler.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, April 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month&amp;rsquo;s album digest is a mixture of comparisons. First we compare the fortunes of old hands Underworld to even older hands the Pet Shop Boys. After that I&amp;rsquo;ve found two dance albums, one that I liked and one that I didn&amp;rsquo;t. I find it quite hard to write about dance music and so the comparison is quite useful. Sometimes it helps to work out why you like one thing and not another.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Underworld, Second Toughest in the Infants (Superdeluxe edition)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/second-toughest-in-the-infants-superdeluxe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/second-toughest-in-the-infants-superdeluxe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week Underworld reissued their excellent second album “Second Toughest In The Infants” in various formats including a four disc super deluxe edition. I wrote about this album in my understated classics series and I want to share some thoughts on the reissue. I love this album so I was excited to hear the remaster and the additional material.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I can’t comment on the physical version of the release as I can’t afford it at the moment. I also had to wait to buy the gorgeous yellow reissue of “Dubnobasswithmyheadman” but the “Second Toughest In The Infants” box is on the list. Underworld do a really good job on the boxes with interesting artwork to accompany the large volume of material. If the “Dubnobasswithmyheadman” box is anything to go by, the new one will be pretty hefty on the coffee table.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The album digest returns with five albums by four artists.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Karl Hyde &amp;amp; Brian Eno &lt;em&gt;Someday World&lt;/em&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;HIGH-LIFE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lone &lt;em&gt;Reality Testing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;FKA twigs &lt;em&gt;LP1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mogwai &lt;em&gt;Come On Die Young: Appendix&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;karl-hyde--brian-eno-someday-world--high-life&#34;&gt;Karl Hyde &amp;amp; Brian Eno &lt;em&gt;Someday World&lt;/em&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;HIGH-LIFE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m a big fan of both Karl Hyde’s work with Underworld and of Brian Eno’s stuff so Someday World seemed like a dream collaboration to me when it was released last May. I was a bit underwhelmed by it, to the point of overlooking it for &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/album-digest-may-2014/&#34;&gt;May’s album digest&lt;/a&gt;. Last month they released a follow-up called High-Life, which includes some of the more experimental tracks they’d worked on. Together the two albums are greater than the some of their parts, so I’m writing about both of them together this month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #11: Second Toughest In The Infants by Underworld</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-rails-your-fins-your-thin-paper-wings&#34;&gt;Your rails, your fins, your thin paper wings&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Second Toughest in the Infants&lt;/em&gt; (STITI) is the second album by Underworld, released in 1995. This was just ahead of the mania caused by the .NUXX version of Born Slippy appearing on the &lt;em&gt;Trainspotting&lt;/em&gt; soundtrack a little later. &lt;em&gt;Born Slippy&lt;/em&gt; itself, the blippy techno confection released between their début &lt;em&gt;Dubnobasswithmyheadman&lt;/em&gt; and this album. STITI then is very much the calm before the storm and features a band (in the truest sense, which is unusual among electronic acts) in full flow. The sure hands are apparent from the off with the all-in-one trifecta of &lt;em&gt;Juanita&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Kiteless&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;To Dream of Love&lt;/em&gt;: a huge slab of a track that propels, mashes and then glides over various tempos in its sixteen minute run.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
