<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Underworld on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/underworld/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Underworld on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/underworld/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, April 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2016/</guid>
      <description>This month&amp;rsquo;s album digest is a mixture of comparisons. First we compare the fortunes of old hands Underworld to even older hands the Pet Shop Boys. After that I&amp;rsquo;ve found two dance albums, one that I liked and one that I didn&amp;rsquo;t. I find it quite hard to write about dance music and so the comparison is quite useful. Sometimes it helps to work out why you like one thing and not another.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Underworld, Second Toughest in the Infants (Superdeluxe edition)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/second-toughest-in-the-infants-superdeluxe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/second-toughest-in-the-infants-superdeluxe/</guid>
      <description>Last week Underworld reissued their excellent second album “Second Toughest In The Infants” in various formats including a four disc super deluxe edition. I wrote about this album in my understated classics series and I want to share some thoughts on the reissue. I love this album so I was excited to hear the remaster and the additional material.&#xA;I can’t comment on the physical version of the release as I can’t afford it at the moment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2014/</guid>
      <description>The album digest returns with five albums by four artists.&#xA;Karl Hyde &amp;amp; Brian Eno Someday World &amp;amp; HIGH-LIFE Lone Reality Testing FKA twigs LP1 Mogwai Come On Die Young: Appendix Karl Hyde &amp;amp; Brian Eno Someday World &amp;amp; HIGH-LIFE I’m a big fan of both Karl Hyde’s work with Underworld and of Brian Eno’s stuff so Someday World seemed like a dream collaboration to me when it was released last May.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #11: Second Toughest In The Infants by Underworld</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-11/</guid>
      <description>Your rails, your fins, your thin paper wings Second Toughest in the Infants (STITI) is the second album by Underworld, released in 1995. This was just ahead of the mania caused by the .NUXX version of Born Slippy appearing on the Trainspotting soundtrack a little later. Born Slippy itself, the blippy techno confection released between their début Dubnobasswithmyheadman and this album. STITI then is very much the calm before the storm and features a band (in the truest sense, which is unusual among electronic acts) in full flow.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
