<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Christmas on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/christmas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Christmas on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/christmas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Italo Calvino, If on a Winter&#39;s Night a Traveller</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/italo-calvino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/italo-calvino/</guid>
      <description>Last year I started to write a review of Italo Calvino&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;If on a Winter&amp;rsquo;s Night a Traveller&amp;rdquo;. I read it while we were in Germany for Christmas. We&amp;rsquo;d visited Bremen and also undergone the bizarreness of Christmas in another language - the same motifs played out in different words and different customs. I&amp;rsquo;d tried to write the review in a similar structure to the book but, in a testament to Calvino&amp;rsquo;s writing I couldn&amp;rsquo;t pull it off.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South America, Part 9</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/south-america-trip-part-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/south-america-trip-part-9/</guid>
      <description>In a tour full of highlights, Christmas week of 2013 was nonetheless one of the greatest weeks of my life. I may have moaned, groaned, and got completely soaked, but it was worth it to see Machu Picchu in the sunshine.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;The Story So Far&amp;rdquo; Arriving in Quito Otovalo and Misahualli Banos Ingapirca and Cuenca Into Peru The Road to Lima The Nazca Lines Arequipa and Cusco The Sacred Valley On 22nd December, we set off from the hotel in Cusco for a trip along the Sacred Valley that lines the Urubamba river.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tales From Home</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/tales-from-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/tales-from-home/</guid>
      <description>A question of identity Three letters for Dad in the mail today, three variations on our surname including the aquatic Dory version and the lesser-spotted Dorny. It is perhaps best not to go back to the time he was accidentally listed in the Thompson directory as Mr. Dopey, bringing forth prank calls from all teenagers within a ten mile radius. Fortunately, Dr. Dorey doesn’t have this problem with his mail: he doesn’t get any.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
