<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>July on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/july/</link>
    <description>Recent content in July on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/july/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, July 2016</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-july-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-july-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Album Digest July 2016 consists of a bumper five albums, mainly because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t work out which one to drop. I think they&amp;rsquo;re all pretty good though it&amp;rsquo;s great to hear new music from The Avalanches after all this time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;bat-for-lashes-the-bride&#34;&gt;Bat For Lashes &amp;ldquo;The Bride&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For her fourth album as Bat For Lashes, Natasha Khan applies her considerable songwriting skills to a concept album. She sings from the perspective of a bride whose husband dies on his way to their wedding. Almost all artists would deliver this subject matter in a melodramatic way, but Khan focusses on the sadness and delivers a beautiful suite of songs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, July 2013</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-july-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-july-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another four albums for you this month. Sometimes the problem is not finding albums to listen to but actually finding time to listen to them! Often it is not because I don&amp;rsquo;t have time but because I have already found some great albums this month and I am busy listening to those instead. As a result, a couple of these albums are ones that I have only listened to for a week or so, but they are interesting enough to write about. Here are the four albums I am going to write about this month:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, July 2012</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-july-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-july-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a short album digest this month. I bought a stack of CDs and am parcelling them out over the next few months (together with important additional releases as they crop up). This is in the hope that I can write more considered pieces about each one. This month I’ve grouped together albums with monochrome covers and a BT album from June that I found out about recently. These albums are not just linked by their artwork, they also form a cohesive whole. As a result I dispense with reviewing each album in depth. As usual there is a playlist at the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, July 2011</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-july-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-july-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quite a mixed bag this month.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SBTRKT &lt;em&gt;SBTRKT&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Zomby &lt;em&gt;Dedication&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Brian Eno &lt;em&gt;Drums Between The Bells&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bon Iver &lt;em&gt;Bon Iver&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Washed Out &lt;em&gt;Within and Without&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This month’s collection of albums is a rather mellow bunch. The SBTRKT album (self-titled) is probably the most frenetic of the five though even that does not exactly pound four to the floor. Most of it is pretty calm, though  the occasional burst of pop to spice things up: sometimes it is as downtempo as the rest (&lt;em&gt;Right Thing To Do&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Trials Of The Past&lt;/em&gt;) but at other times things spark into life, as on &lt;em&gt;Pharaohs&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
