<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Twenty Five on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/twenty-five/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Twenty Five on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/twenty-five/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>In Praise of Pilates</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-pilates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-pilates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In searching for something to write about today, I wondered whether I had ever written about Pilates on this blog before. I modified &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/fun-with-chat-gpt/&#34;&gt;the search of my posts from yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post&lt;/a&gt; to look for the word Pilates&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and it only came up once in &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/ambitions-revisited/&#34;&gt;a post about revisiting my ambitions ten years on&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There I wrote:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I haven’t taken up meditation at all because the inside of my head is way too noisy. What I did do (at Ingrid’s suggestion) is take up Pilates: I swear by it now. It’s not quite the same as meditation but I’ve found the improvements to my core strength to be quite useful for my mental health.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fun With Chat-GPT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fun-with-chatgpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fun-with-chatgpt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I asked:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For my blog I have a folder called posts. In that folder are more folders that are named for the slug of each post, as per the conventions of the Hugo static site generator. Those folders each contain a markdown file named index.md, each of which has a YAML header. Draft posts have a YAML key called draft which has the value true. Please can you write me a shell script that I can run from the directory above posts that tells me which folders in the posts folder contain draft posts?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Break The Chain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dont-break-the-chain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dont-break-the-chain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2025 might be a tough year, but I am going to try and blog every day. It means that now and then I might be writing a post like this one, where I am writing for the sake of continuing the streak. If I find myself doing that too often then I will take the hint and stop trying!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This weekend was the 3rd round of the FA Cup, which is when the premier league and championship teams enter the competition. This is the first time for quite a few years where Portsmouth have entered at this stage. Naturally, they&amp;rsquo;re already out! Mind you, in recent years when they&amp;rsquo;ve entered at the first round they haven&amp;rsquo;t made it past those rounds either. That was bad news for one pub in Portsmouth which always made a big show of not taking down their Christmas decorations until Pompey were out of the FA Cup!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
