<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Twenty Five on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/twenty-five/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Twenty Five on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/twenty-five/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>In Praise of Pomme Fritz</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-pomme-fritz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-pomme-fritz/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dive In?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dive-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dive-in/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dithering Around</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dithering-around/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dithering-around/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While off sick and under the weather I decided to play around with presenting the photos on this blog in a fashion more in keeping with the current Hugo theme.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://imagemagick.org&#34;&gt;Imagemagick&lt;/a&gt; to process the same files from &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-paris/&#34;&gt;the Paris post&lt;/a&gt; earlier this week. I made them a bit smaller, reduced the number of colours to 256, posterized them (a built-in Imagemagick function that groups colours), and then did a dither on them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FODMAP February</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fodmap-february/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fodmap-february/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charlie XCX, Brat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/charlie-xcx-brat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/charlie-xcx-brat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When making my albums of the year posts at the start of the month, I realised that compared to many other critics lists, there was no sign of &lt;em&gt;Brat&lt;/em&gt; by Charlie XCX. In this post, I re-evaluate the album and see whether it should have made the list.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dora Carrington</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dora-carrington-at-pallant-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dora-carrington-at-pallant-house/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dora Carrington was an artist loosely affiliated with the Bloomsbury Group and noted for her unconventional lifestyle. Despite a short career, her work had a great impact and &lt;a href=&#34;https://pallant.org.uk/whats-on/dora-carrington/&#34;&gt;a retrospective at the Pallant House Gallery in Chichester&lt;/a&gt; brings together some of her major works.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was a bit confused at the start of the show, as I had got my Carrington&amp;rsquo;s wrong! I&amp;rsquo;d been thinking this was a show about &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leonora_Carrington&#34;&gt;Leonora Carrington&lt;/a&gt; who was active later, initially in circles with Max Ernst, and later on in her own right in Mexico City. I will have to wait for a retrospective of her work another time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thai Green Curry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/thai-green-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/thai-green-curry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thai Green Curry is one of our favourites. Often when we are travelling we will find a Thai restaurant and order it. It&amp;rsquo;s a nice way to see how a familiar dish is rendered in your new surroundings. More importantly, it&amp;rsquo;s a dish that&amp;rsquo;s reliably gluten and tomato free.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;paste-ingredients&#34;&gt;Paste ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;8 g coriander roots&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tsp coriander powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp cumin powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp turmeric powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tsp galangal&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tsp minced or grated ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3 shredded kefir lime leaves&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tbsp minced lemon grass&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 tsp brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 minced long green chilli&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 1/2 tbsp canola oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;paste-method&#34;&gt;Paste Method&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Blitz all the above ingredients together into a paste, using a food processor or a pestle and mortar. For the latter, you will need to do this in batches.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Praise of Paris</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-paris/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-paris/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This time last year, Ingrid and I were on the Eurostar to Paris for four days. We did so much in our time there that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t write about it at the time. Here&amp;rsquo;s a little summary with a few photos.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our chief aim was to take in as much Rodin as possible (as he&amp;rsquo;s Ingrid&amp;rsquo;s favourite sculptor) so on the Saturday we set out for Montparnasse and struck out for Meudon, where his house is. And&amp;hellip; it was closed for winter!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Human in the Loop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-human-in-the-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-human-in-the-loop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to start making generative art again. I can&amp;rsquo;t say I ever did it that seriously but using programming languages to generate &amp;lsquo;art&amp;rsquo; is a pretty fun to while away the hours, especially when one&amp;rsquo;s talents for drawing truculently refuse to improve. Of course, more recently the phrase generative art might be said to have grown to encompass the GPT-class models that generate images from prompts. So what would be the point of coding something, when you can make &amp;lsquo;proper&amp;rsquo; art?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summer 1954</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/summer-1954/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/summer-1954/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Summer 1954 is a pair of one-act plays by Sir Terrence Rattigan that are currently being performed together at the Chichester Festival Theatre. I really enjoyed both plays.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;table-number-seven&#34;&gt;Table Number Seven&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first play is &lt;em&gt;Table Number Seven&lt;/em&gt;, which is set in a boarding hotel in Bournemouth. We&amp;rsquo;re gradually introduced to a cast of characters - mostly elderly ladies - who are staying there. One of them, the major, who in a Fawlty Towers way won&amp;rsquo;t shut up once you get talking to him, is particularly interested in an article in an obscure local paper.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ian MacDonald, Revolution in the Head</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ian-macdonald-revolution-in-the-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ian-macdonald-revolution-in-the-head/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ian MacDonald&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Revolution in the Head&amp;rdquo; is a book that I&amp;rsquo;ve read parts of dozens of times and even all the way through once or twice. I picked it up again today and thought I would write about it. It&amp;rsquo;s a detailed analysis of every Beatles song ever released, along with the details and events of their recording. I own a copy of the second edition which was updated to include the anthology material. Today you can still get hold of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.waterstones.com/book/revolution-in-the-head/ian-macdonald/9780099526797&#34;&gt;a 3rd edition on the Waterstones website&lt;/a&gt; (not sure that I like the new cover though).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Underworld, Strawberrry Hotel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/underworld-strawberrry-hotel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/underworld-strawberrry-hotel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An album that arrived a bit too late to be considered in the best of the year list, &lt;em&gt;Strawberry Hotel&lt;/em&gt; by Underworld is a solid effort. Their 11th album, it remarks their return to the format after five years after the &lt;em&gt;Drift&lt;/em&gt; series in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Drift&lt;/em&gt; had been an interesting experiment where Underworld had tried to put out a new track each week and grouping several weeks worth into EPs before putting out a massive 6+ hour box set. The striking thing about the project was that it was so good. They released a sampler edition of the album which cherry picked the best songs, but almost every track released as part of &lt;em&gt;Drift&lt;/em&gt; could be swapped into that sampler.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Push the right key</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/push-the-right-key/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/push-the-right-key/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the absurd barriers to writing regularly is that my new post script is written to open the new markdown file in Neovim and until this week I had no idea how to type a hashtag (which markdown uses for headers) in this editor.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Neovim, and its venerable predecessors vi and vim, is notorious for being a bit tricksy to work with. This is because it is a modal editor: you use keys to switch the editor between modes. The same key presses mean different things in different modes, which can be frustrating when you first start out and have no clue what is going on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sticky Toffee Pudding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sticky-toffee-pudding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sticky-toffee-pudding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We had great success with our sticky toffee pudding as a Christmas Day dessert. It&amp;rsquo;s a hybrid of a recipe by Jamie Oliver, one that we found in a gluten free cookbook, and one for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.co.uk/food/recipes/sticky_toffee_pudding_25161&#34;&gt;a make-ahead pudding by the hairy bikers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;pudding&#34;&gt;Pudding&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;200-250g chopped dates&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;200ml boiling water (or tea)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;100g softened unsalted butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon of bicarbonate of soda&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;170g sugar (85g golden caster, 50g light soft brown, 35g dark soft brown)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;170g self-raising flour&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon mixed spice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon ground cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 eggs (room temperature)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;sauce&#34;&gt;Sauce&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;110g unsalted butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;110g sugar (half light soft brown sugar, half dark soft brown sugar)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;140ml double cream&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;method&#34;&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;pudding-1&#34;&gt;Pudding&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soak the chopped dates in the boiling water with the bicarbonate of soda for 30 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mash the dates with a fork.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cream the butter and sugar.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the eggs and flour and spices.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mix the dates in to the batter and spoon into a greased baking dish.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cook for 45 minutes at 180˚C. Check with a skewer and if it comes out with batter on, return to the oven for 5-10 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;sauce-1&#34;&gt;Sauce&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add all the ingredients to a small pan and cook together on a low heat. Stir gently initially.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Make sure you remove the stones from your dates!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We did this as a make-ahead for Christmas day. When we made the sauce at the same time as we made the sponge and poured about a third over the top. We let it all cool before storing in the fridge. We reheated for about 20 minutes at 180˚C and microwaved the sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s very nice (but also incredibly over-indulgent!) served with vanilla ice cream.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The reason for using a mixture of sugars is both for the colour (more dark sugar makes for a more appealing toffee sauce) and for the overall toffee/caramel taste of the pudding. You can change the ratios here to suit your own tastes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a fairly lenient recipe so don&amp;rsquo;t get too hung up on exact quantities.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Praise of Putting Pen to Paper</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-putting-pen-to-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-putting-pen-to-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Around this time last year, I wrote in praise of writing a diary. I also rather misanthropically referred to it as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-negativity-casket/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;negativity casket&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; because I found that I was pouring a lot of negative feelings into the notebook. It&amp;rsquo;s not really a diary as such because I don&amp;rsquo;t write everyday and I also make other non-diaristic notes, but it does appear to have been something of a process that has helped me to work through my negative feelings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nineteen Out Of Nineteen?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/nineteen-out-of-nineteen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/nineteen-out-of-nineteen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m having trouble finding something to write about today. Partly the problem of having a productive weekend of doing things rather than ruminating on blog topics. So unfortunately, we get another space-filling post.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got lots of books on the go at the moment, including &amp;ldquo;Orbital&amp;rdquo; which won the Booker prize this year and &amp;ldquo;Otherlands&amp;rdquo; which is a really cool book about natural history going back in time through the eras of the Earth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lost Guide to CIV VI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-lost-guide-to-civ-vi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-lost-guide-to-civ-vi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written some guides about how to play as various leaders in Sid Meier&amp;rsquo;s Civilization VI, covering &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/posts/civ-leaders-1/&#34;&gt;Hojo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/posts/civ-leaders-2/&#34;&gt;Alexander&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/posts/civ-leaders-3/&#34;&gt;Amanitore&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/posts/civ-leaders-4/&#34;&gt;Qin&lt;/a&gt; in his Mandate of Heaven persona. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I also wrote a guide to Gorgo at some point but all I can find are game screenshots I took one of the times that I played as her.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./images/gorgo_1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot of a CIV VI game where I played as Gorgo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As such, I lost momentum on what would have been quite a nice writing project. However, with less than a month to go until Civ VII, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem as though writing those posts would even be useful for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Albums Matter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/albums-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/albums-matter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having recently completed my review of 2024&amp;rsquo;s best albums, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reflecting on what a strange year it was for me in terms of the music I listened to. According to my Last.fm annual report, I listened to 51% &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; music in 2024 compared with 2023 (and 2023 was itself a peak listening year). Moreover, I listened to 709 artists, of which 37% were new discoveries. I listened to over 2 albums a day apparently, with &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/posts/2024-albums-03-acopia/&#34;&gt;Acopia&lt;/a&gt; being the album I listened to most often. Apparently I was the 11th top listener on Last.fm of my number 1 album of the year &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/posts/2024-albums-01-bolis-pupul-letter-to-yu/&#34;&gt;Letter to Yu by Bolis Pupul&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Realisation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-realisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-realisation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the best pieces of advice I have ever been given about how to tackle programming problems is to treat your code as comments that describe your program to the computer, whilst the comments that are there for humans to read should tell them how the program is supposed to work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In recent days I have come to a realisation that you also need to try and see things as the computer sees them, rather than expecting it to see what you can see. I was working with some data that were formatted in a pretty way for humans and I was completely flummoxed because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; of it into R. The more I stared at the files, the more I began to see all these weird anomalies like completely blank columns that had been shrunk to near zero widths and inconsistencies between files with how the main components of the data were stored. It&amp;rsquo;s been a strange experience!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parquet Courts Sympathy For Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/parquet-courts-sympathy-for-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/parquet-courts-sympathy-for-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./images/parquet-courts-sympathy-for-life.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover art of Sympathy for Life by Parquet Courts&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Getting back to my occasional album revisits, I&amp;rsquo;d like to consider the 2021 Parquet Courts album &amp;ldquo;Sympathy For Life&amp;rdquo;. This is partly because I own it on vinyl and put it on the other day while I was doing some rather humdrum data downloading at work. It&amp;rsquo;s that kind of album, quite loose and jam-based.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recorded just before lockdown, first in New York then at the Real World studios in Box, the album seems eerily prescient of what was to come later in the Covid pandemic. These are songs about constantly being watched by AI and the sort of coddling of the modern mind that results from this. It&amp;rsquo;s not quite as good as the previous album &amp;ldquo;Wide Awake&amp;rdquo; but is probably better than &amp;ldquo;Human Performance&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s so relaxed and different to the previous album that you might have expected it to appear under their Parkay Quarts alias.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gluten Free Toad In The Hole</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gluten-free-toad-in-the-hole/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gluten-free-toad-in-the-hole/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tbsp of sunflower oil or other high smoke point oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;60g cornflour&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;60g gluten-free flour&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3 eggs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;pinch of salt (if wanted)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;pinch of sage (if wanted)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;200ml of milk (substitute with non-dairy options if wanted)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Four sausages&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;method&#34;&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preheat an oven to 220C (200C for a fan-assisted oven).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pour some high smoke-point oil into a metal pan (approx one tablespoon), add the sausages and warm for five minutes in the oven while preparing the batter.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mix flour, cornflour and eggs either by hand or with a stand mixer. Beat to a smooth paste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add salt if using. Once the mixture is smooth, start to slowly add the milk while continuing to beat the mixture.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once all the milk has been added, continue to beat the mixture for a further minute or until lightly foaming.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Turn the sausages and return to the oven for two more minutes. In this time add dried herbs to the batter if using. Sage works well. Re-beat the mixture once last time.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the batter to the pan and cook for 25 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Flour ratios can be changed. E.g., you can use 70g/50g cornflour to flour. Don&amp;rsquo;t use more than 125g total for the flours.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You may need slightly more oil if using vegetarian sausages.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In terms of alternative milks, a pea-based milk (e.g. Wunda milk) produces quite an aerated and crispy batter. We&amp;rsquo;ve had less success with things like oat or soy milk.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This batter can also be used for Yorkshire pudding and for pancakes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Try wrapping the sausages in bacon for a tasty (but rather unhealthy treat).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Most recipes prefer lard to oil, but oil is usually fine. Rape seed oil (AKA canola oil) is working well for us at the moment.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balancing Bad Luck</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/balancing-bad-luck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/balancing-bad-luck/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Praise of Pilates</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-pilates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-pilates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In searching for something to write about today, I wondered whether I had ever written about Pilates on this blog before. I modified &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/fun-with-chatgpt/&#34;&gt;the search of my posts from yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post&lt;/a&gt; to look for the word Pilates&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and it only came up once in &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/ambitions-revisited/&#34;&gt;a post about revisiting my ambitions ten years on&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There I wrote:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I haven’t taken up meditation at all because the inside of my head is way too noisy. What I did do (at Ingrid’s suggestion) is take up Pilates: I swear by it now. It’s not quite the same as meditation but I’ve found the improvements to my core strength to be quite useful for my mental health.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fun With Chat-GPT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fun-with-chatgpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fun-with-chatgpt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I asked:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For my blog I have a folder called posts. In that folder are more folders that are named for the slug of each post, as per the conventions of the Hugo static site generator. Those folders each contain a markdown file named index.md, each of which has a YAML header. Draft posts have a YAML key called draft which has the value true. Please can you write me a shell script that I can run from the directory above posts that tells me which folders in the posts folder contain draft posts?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Break The Chain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dont-break-the-chain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dont-break-the-chain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2025 might be a tough year, but I am going to try and blog every day. It means that now and then I might be writing a post like this one, where I am writing for the sake of continuing the streak. If I find myself doing that too often then I will take the hint and stop trying!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This weekend was the 3rd round of the FA Cup, which is when the premier league and championship teams enter the competition. This is the first time for quite a few years where Portsmouth have entered at this stage. Naturally, they&amp;rsquo;re already out! Mind you, in recent years when they&amp;rsquo;ve entered at the first round they haven&amp;rsquo;t made it past those rounds either. That was bad news for one pub in Portsmouth which always made a big show of not taking down their Christmas decorations until Pompey were out of the FA Cup!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
