<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Twenty Five on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/twenty-five/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Twenty Five on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/twenty-five/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Some more thoughts on Civ 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/some-more-thoughts-on-civ-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/some-more-thoughts-on-civ-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been about 5 months now since the release of Civilisation VII and it&amp;rsquo;s starting to become a playable game. This is partly due to me getting used to it and partly the effect of quality of life patches and additional features.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLMs and Cryptic Crosswords</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/llms-and-cryptic-crosswords/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/llms-and-cryptic-crosswords/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing, one way to demonstrate the illusory nature of LLM intelligence is to get one to try and answer a cryptic crossword clue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Birds and then the Bees</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-birds-and-then-the-bees/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-birds-and-then-the-bees/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve never had one fail&amp;rdquo; says my Dad brandishing his drill on Boxing Day 2022, before heading out into the garden and putting up our Christmas gift, a handsome wooden bird box. &amp;ldquo;If I put it up, they&amp;rsquo;ll come along eventually.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal Development Environment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/personal-development-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/personal-development-environment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to settle on a text editor, IDE, and terminal for a long time now. Partly I&amp;rsquo;m limited by what I can use at work because I owe to myself and my colleagues to be able to reproduce all my skills in a work setting. However, part of me has also wandered off a bit after reading about the idea of a &amp;ldquo;personal Development Environment&amp;rdquo; (or PDE I guess, though in a former life that &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Partial_differential_equation&#34;&gt;meant something very different&lt;/a&gt;), which is essentially an application where you can do anything and have it configured exactly how you like. Here&amp;rsquo;s an update on my progress on that front:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tree Shopping</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/tree-shopping/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/tree-shopping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of getting the garden done, we&amp;rsquo;ve been out and about looking for trees. It&amp;rsquo;s quite exciting seeing in person all the trees we&amp;rsquo;ve discussed with our garden designer. Here are some of the species we&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bill Drummond, 45</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bill-drummond-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bill-drummond-45/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;45&lt;/em&gt; is Bill Drummond&amp;rsquo;s sort of memoir, albeit one with a hazy memory of the events most readers (myself included) are likely to be interested in. Drummond is/was one half of pop-pranksters The KLF, but &lt;em&gt;45&lt;/em&gt; barely mentions them at all. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot about before (e.g. managing Echo and the Bunnymen in late-70s and early-80s Liverpool) and after (various shenanigans in the art world and attempting to relate to his children), some of that writing is very interesting. Nevertheless the whole lacuna of his pop heyday seems to punches a hole through the entire book.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wilco, A Ghost Is Born (Superdeluxe edition)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/wilco-a-ghost-is-born-superdeluxe-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/wilco-a-ghost-is-born-superdeluxe-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2022, I invested in the big superdeluxe box for Wilco&amp;rsquo;s most successful album &amp;ldquo;Yankee Hotel Foxtrot&amp;rdquo;. Across 11 pieces of &amp;lsquo;silver&amp;rsquo; vinyl and one CD, the box set showed the tortuous process that Wilco went through to create that album. It&amp;rsquo;s a magnificent collection of music, though if you don&amp;rsquo;t like hearing multiple versions of the same song and are not fond of unfinished material, it&amp;rsquo;s not going to be as pleasant an afternoon as it is for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Praise of Pulling Everything out of the Shed...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-pulling-everything-out-of-the-shed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-pulling-everything-out-of-the-shed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I pulled everything out of our shed and we took the stuff we didn&amp;rsquo;t need down to the dump. No one likes going to the dump, but it was strangely cathartic. It&amp;rsquo;s due in part to letting go of things from the past, but also the fact that I haven&amp;rsquo;t felt up to much lately. It ended up being a sunny afternoon so it was a pleasant walk back after we dropped off the hire car.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post Statistics, Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-statistics-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-statistics-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are some more stats about the blog after I ran out of time yesterday due to&#xA;data cleaning! This time I&amp;rsquo;ve taken the date of each post and extracted the&#xA;month and year. Then I added the number of posts in each month and the number of&#xA;words written. I had to left join on the complete time span between August 2010&#xA;and February 2025, filling in any NA values for the zeros that were missing&#xA;before I did that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post Statistics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-statistics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s of graph of how the number of posts and the total word count on mattischrome has evolved over the years:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Only Spring Indoors So Far</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/only-spring-indoors-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/only-spring-indoors-so-far/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s still quite wintry outside, especially in the wind. We&amp;rsquo;re having to make do with daffodils indoors to brighten our day. They&amp;rsquo;re being kept in the ensuite because the cats keep knocking them over.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robin Egg Blue</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/robin-egg-blue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/robin-egg-blue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is record one of nine from the new &amp;ldquo;A Ghost Is Born&amp;rdquo; superdeluxe edition. I was hoping to write a review tonight but I haven&amp;rsquo;t managed to listen to it all yet!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Collection of Links About Blogging</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-collection-of-links-about-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-collection-of-links-about-blogging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are thinking about making your own blog, here are some links to help you on your way.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a very simple introduction to making websites that Pixel Shannon wrote for her daughter to help her create a website for a class project. It&amp;rsquo;s not completely at a 12 year old&amp;rsquo;s level, so don&amp;rsquo;t be put off by that idea. She gives a very good introduction to what HTML is and what else you have to put in there to get a website up and running. There&amp;rsquo;s also a big list of resources that I won&amp;rsquo;t repeat here, so be sure to check those out too:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Initial Thoughts About Civilization VII</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/some-initial-thoughts-about-civilization-vii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/some-initial-thoughts-about-civilization-vii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sid Meier&amp;rsquo;s Civilization VII is out today to much fanfare. After spending what top scientists are calling &amp;ldquo;far too long&amp;rdquo; playing Civ VI and a couple of run-throughs of the new game during the early access period, here are some thoughts on the new instalment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Praise of Playing the Long Game</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-playing-the-long-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-playing-the-long-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I bought a Barbara Hepworth calendar in the sale at the Tate Modern shop that I thought was a steal until I realised it was a 2024 calendar, not a 2025 one! However, the joke&amp;rsquo;s on them because I only have to wait until 2029 for the next year that starts with a Monday.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, unlike 2024, 2029 is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a leap year. This means all the days of the week would be wrong from March 1st onwards. It gets worse! The next two years that start on a Monday are 2035 and 2046, both of which quite obviously fail to be leap years.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Oh dear&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peter Gabriel, So</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/peter-gabriel-so/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/peter-gabriel-so/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently watched the entry about Peter Gabriel&amp;rsquo;s 1986 album &amp;ldquo;So&amp;rdquo; in the Classic Albums series on Amazon Prime. It was an entertaining way to fill an evening hour.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I absolutely love &amp;ldquo;So&amp;rdquo;. I came to its songs via the &amp;ldquo;Secret World Live&amp;rdquo; album, and it was &amp;ldquo;Red Rain&amp;rdquo; specifically that convinced me of his greatness. Previously, I&amp;rsquo;d been aware of &amp;ldquo;Sledgehammer&amp;rdquo; (also on this album) and &amp;ldquo;Steam&amp;rdquo; (from the similarly titled &amp;ldquo;Us&amp;rdquo;), but &amp;ldquo;Red Rain&amp;rdquo; really captured my imagination.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All Part of the Process</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/all-part-of-the-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/all-part-of-the-process/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing a blog post every day is not essential. It&amp;rsquo;s not part of some new year&amp;rsquo;s resolution, despite the fact that the start of this unbroken streak of posts was January 1st. If anything my new year&amp;rsquo;s resolution has been to try and step gently away from my perfection. And the adoption of that resolution began in the middle of 2024 rather than new year&amp;rsquo;s day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Around September time, I realised and began to recognise myself as I read many descriptions of crippling perfectionism, especially in how it relates to depression. Depression is a weird experience that is simultaneously subjective but also measurable in many ways. It became clearer and clearer to me that perfectionism was a significant component to my problems, in both work and the rest of life (i.e. the part that is most important). And so I began to try and undo a lifetime of thinking in a particular way, mostly guided by a set of rules that I now write down in all my notebooks. Those rules are for me, so I won&amp;rsquo;t share them here, at least not today. But they are eminently findable on the internet and recognisable variations of common themes in self-help literature. I still need to work out which of them are genuine rules and which are merely guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Incredible Shrinking Blog Post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-incredible-shrinking-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-incredible-shrinking-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The problem with keeping up a blog streak for however many days it is now is that you don&amp;rsquo;t actually get a huge amount of time to think of ideas for posts and actually write them. Ironically, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about this post for a while though.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ingrid&#39;s Pottery</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ingrids-pottery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ingrids-pottery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are some photos of Ingrid&amp;rsquo;s pottery, some very pretty pots! (And more complex pieces are on the way!)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patch (A poem)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/patch-a-poem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/patch-a-poem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a short poem I wrote for Ingrid about our little herb garden. I am reproducing it here in celebration of work that is shortly going to start on our new garden!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More Uses For Little Notebooks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/more-uses-for-little-notebooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/more-uses-for-little-notebooks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m an avid collector of small notebooks. So much so that I have a box full of them in my office. I&amp;rsquo;m not afraid of writing in them, it&amp;rsquo;s just that I&amp;rsquo;ve bought so many over the years I can&amp;rsquo;t get through them quick enough.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Praise of Pomme Fritz</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-pomme-fritz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-pomme-fritz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The release of Pomme Fritz by The Orb in 1994 was a moment of genuine excitement for me as it was the first new material they released after I&amp;rsquo;d become aware of them. Not only that, but thanks to my hard work riding around Emsworth on my BMX at unsafe speeds belting out Green Day&amp;rsquo;s Dookie as out-of-tune-ly as is humanly possible, I&amp;rsquo;d managed to secure the funds to buy the album for myself. My excitement had been mounting from the moment the promotional postcard arrived a few weeks beforehand. I took my £4.99 to Our Price in Portsmouth Cascades on Saturday afternoon and bought myself a copy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And boy, I pretty much hated it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slots and Pipes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/slots-and-pipes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/slots-and-pipes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recent explorations in R have reminded me about two ways of thinking about how you refer to objects or (parts of objects) in the language.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Slots are probably what you learn about first, they use the &lt;code&gt;$&lt;/code&gt; syntax. In R, the &lt;code&gt;$&lt;/code&gt; operator is used to access specific elements or columns within a data structure, such as a list, data frame, or environment. You can think of it as an ersatz shorthand for the &lt;code&gt;tidyverse::select()&lt;/code&gt; function, except that the latter is more powerful because you can do funky things like selecting multiple columns programmatically. By programmatically I mean &amp;ldquo;in some way that is not predetermined until you run your code&amp;rdquo;, e.g. because you are selecting a subset of columns of your data frame that didn&amp;rsquo;t exist until (long) before that step. Anyway, back to &lt;code&gt;$&lt;/code&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s a way of selecting a particular column of a data frame or any smaller part of an object in R. In fact, one of my main use cases for &lt;code&gt;$&lt;/code&gt; used to be for recalculating columns in a data frame when I wasn&amp;rsquo;t confident about using &lt;code&gt;mutate()&lt;/code&gt;: changing a column to a factor with &lt;code&gt;mutate()&lt;/code&gt; gave me the heebie-jeebies for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Into February</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/into-february/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/into-february/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having made it to one post per day in January, we now move into February: that graveyard of good habits for the new year. What is it about flipping over the calendar to a new month that does away with our resolve to continue with our resolutions? My office calendar has a lovely picture of a German steam train in the snow, in case you were wondering.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to reward myself at some point by allowing myself to fiddle with the blog&amp;rsquo;s theme a little more. Over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve probably fiddled more with how the blog looks, rather than focussing on what to write. I&amp;rsquo;ve also turned on Hugo&amp;rsquo;s related posts module. The results are pretty high quality and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to affect the build time of the site. A custom version is still a pet project for the future though.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dithering Around</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dithering-around/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dithering-around/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While off sick and under the weather I decided to play around with presenting the photos on this blog in a fashion more in keeping with the current Hugo theme.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://imagemagick.org&#34;&gt;Imagemagick&lt;/a&gt; to process the same files from &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-paris/&#34;&gt;the Paris post&lt;/a&gt; earlier this week. I made them a bit smaller, reduced the number of colours to 256, posterized them (a built-in Imagemagick function that groups colours), and then did a dither on them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charlie XCX, Brat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/charlie-xcx-brat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/charlie-xcx-brat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When making my albums of the year posts at the start of the month, I realised that compared to many other critics lists, there was no sign of &lt;em&gt;Brat&lt;/em&gt; by Charlie XCX. And when it came up again on my album shuffle the other day, I  thought I should re-evaluate the album and whether it should have made my list.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Listening to &lt;em&gt;Brat&lt;/em&gt; again for this post, it was clear that I&amp;rsquo;d missed out on something special. This was partly because I went for a walk with it on my headphones and that always lets me hear the details of the music. I think too many times when this album came on at home, it would be a little bit too doof-doof to be background music. These are songs that do demand (and deserve) a bit of attention.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dora Carrington</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dora-carrington-at-pallant-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dora-carrington-at-pallant-house/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dora Carrington was an artist loosely affiliated with the Bloomsbury Group and noted for her unconventional lifestyle. Despite a short career, her work had a great impact and &lt;a href=&#34;https://pallant.org.uk/whats-on/dora-carrington/&#34;&gt;a retrospective at the Pallant House Gallery in Chichester&lt;/a&gt; brings together some of her major works.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was a bit confused at the start of the show, as I had got my Carrington&amp;rsquo;s wrong! I&amp;rsquo;d been thinking this was a show about &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leonora_Carrington&#34;&gt;Leonora Carrington&lt;/a&gt; who was active later, initially in circles with Max Ernst, and later on in her own right in Mexico City. I will have to wait for a retrospective of her work another time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thai Green Curry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/thai-green-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/thai-green-curry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thai Green Curry is one of our favourites. Often when we are travelling we will find a Thai restaurant and order it. It&amp;rsquo;s a nice way to see how a familiar dish is rendered in your new surroundings. More importantly, it&amp;rsquo;s a dish that&amp;rsquo;s reliably gluten and tomato free.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Praise of Paris</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-paris/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-paris/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This time last year, Ingrid and I were on the Eurostar to Paris for four days. We did so much in our time there that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t write about it at the time. Here&amp;rsquo;s a little summary with a few photos.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our chief aim was to take in as much Rodin as possible (as he&amp;rsquo;s Ingrid&amp;rsquo;s favourite sculptor) so on the Saturday we set out for Montparnasse and struck out for Meudon, where his house is. And&amp;hellip; it was closed for winter!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Human in the Loop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-human-in-the-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-human-in-the-loop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to start making generative art again. I can&amp;rsquo;t say I ever did it that seriously but using programming languages to generate &amp;lsquo;art&amp;rsquo; is a pretty fun to while away the hours, especially when one&amp;rsquo;s talents for drawing truculently refuse to improve. Of course, more recently the phrase generative art might be said to have grown to encompass the GPT-class models that generate images from prompts. So what would be the point of coding something, when you can make &amp;lsquo;proper&amp;rsquo; art?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summer 1954</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/summer-1954/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/summer-1954/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Summer 1954 is a pair of one-act plays by Sir Terrence Rattigan that are currently being performed together at the Chichester Festival Theatre. I really enjoyed both plays.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ian MacDonald, Revolution in the Head</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ian-macdonald-revolution-in-the-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ian-macdonald-revolution-in-the-head/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ian MacDonald&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Revolution in the Head&amp;rdquo; is a book that I&amp;rsquo;ve read parts of dozens of times and even all the way through once or twice. I picked it up again today and thought I would write about it. It&amp;rsquo;s a detailed analysis of every Beatles song ever released, along with the details and events of their recording. I own a copy of the second edition which was updated to include the anthology material. Today you can still get hold of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.waterstones.com/book/revolution-in-the-head/ian-macdonald/9780099526797&#34;&gt;a 3rd edition on the Waterstones website&lt;/a&gt; (not sure that I like the new cover though).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Underworld, Strawberrry Hotel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/underworld-strawberrry-hotel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/underworld-strawberrry-hotel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An album that arrived a bit too late to be considered in the best of the year list, &lt;em&gt;Strawberry Hotel&lt;/em&gt; by Underworld is a solid effort. Their 11th album, it remarks their return to the format after five years after the &lt;em&gt;Drift&lt;/em&gt; series in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Drift&lt;/em&gt; had been an interesting experiment where Underworld had tried to put out a new track each week and grouping several weeks worth into EPs before putting out a massive 6+ hour box set. The striking thing about the project was that it was so good. They released a sampler edition of the album which cherry picked the best songs, but almost every track released as part of &lt;em&gt;Drift&lt;/em&gt; could be swapped into that sampler.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Push the right key</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/push-the-right-key/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/push-the-right-key/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the absurd barriers to writing regularly is that my new post script is written to open the new markdown file in Neovim and until this week I had no idea how to type a hashtag (which markdown uses for headers) in this editor.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Neovim, and its venerable predecessors vi and vim, is notorious for being a bit tricksy to work with. This is because it is a modal editor: you use keys to switch the editor between modes. The same key presses mean different things in different modes, which can be frustrating when you first start out and have no clue what is going on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sticky Toffee Pudding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sticky-toffee-pudding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sticky-toffee-pudding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We had great success with our sticky toffee pudding as a Christmas Day dessert. It&amp;rsquo;s a hybrid of a recipe by Jamie Oliver, one that we found in a gluten free cookbook, and one for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.co.uk/food/recipes/sticky_toffee_pudding_25161&#34;&gt;a make-ahead pudding by the hairy bikers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Praise of Putting Pen to Paper</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-putting-pen-to-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-putting-pen-to-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Around this time last year, I wrote in praise of writing a diary. I also rather misanthropically referred to it as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-negativity-casket/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;negativity casket&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; because I found that I was pouring a lot of negative feelings into the notebook. It&amp;rsquo;s not really a diary as such because I don&amp;rsquo;t write everyday and I also make other non-diaristic notes, but it does appear to have been something of a process that has helped me to work through my negative feelings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nineteen Out Of Nineteen?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/nineteen-out-of-nineteen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/nineteen-out-of-nineteen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m having trouble finding something to write about today. Partly the problem of having a productive weekend of doing things rather than ruminating on blog topics. So unfortunately, we get another space-filling post.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got lots of books on the go at the moment, including &amp;ldquo;Orbital&amp;rdquo; which won the Booker prize this year and &amp;ldquo;Otherlands&amp;rdquo; which is a really cool book about natural history going back in time through the eras of the Earth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lost Guide to CIV VI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-lost-guide-to-civ-vi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-lost-guide-to-civ-vi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written some guides about how to play as various leaders in Sid Meier&amp;rsquo;s Civilization VI, covering &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/posts/civ-leaders-1/&#34;&gt;Hojo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/posts/civ-leaders-2/&#34;&gt;Alexander&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/posts/civ-leaders-3/&#34;&gt;Amanitore&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/posts/civ-leaders-4/&#34;&gt;Qin&lt;/a&gt; in his Mandate of Heaven persona. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I also wrote a guide to Gorgo at some point but all I can find are game screenshots I took one of the times that I played as her.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Albums Matter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/albums-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/albums-matter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having recently completed my review of 2024&amp;rsquo;s best albums, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reflecting on what a strange year it was for me in terms of the music I listened to. According to my Last.fm annual report, I listened to 51% &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; music in 2024 compared with 2023 (and 2023 was itself a peak listening year). Moreover, I listened to 709 artists, of which 37% were new discoveries. I listened to over 2 albums a day apparently, with &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/posts/2024-albums-03-acopia/&#34;&gt;Acopia&lt;/a&gt; being the album I listened to most often. Apparently I was the 11th top listener on Last.fm of my number 1 album of the year &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/posts/2024-albums-01-bolis-pupul-letter-to-yu/&#34;&gt;Letter to Yu by Bolis Pupul&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Realisation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-realisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-realisation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the best pieces of advice I have ever been given about how to tackle programming problems is to treat your code as comments that describe your program to the computer, whilst the comments that are there for humans to read should tell them how the program is supposed to work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In recent days I have come to a realisation that you also need to try and see things as the computer sees them, rather than expecting it to see what you can see. I was working with some data that were formatted in a pretty way for humans and I was completely flummoxed because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; of it into R. The more I stared at the files, the more I began to see all these weird anomalies like completely blank columns that had been shrunk to near zero widths and inconsistencies between files with how the main components of the data were stored. It&amp;rsquo;s been a strange experience!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parquet Courts Sympathy For Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/parquet-courts-sympathy-for-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/parquet-courts-sympathy-for-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Getting back to my occasional album revisits, I&amp;rsquo;d like to consider the 2021 Parquet Courts album &amp;ldquo;Sympathy For Life&amp;rdquo;. This is partly because I own it on vinyl and put it on the other day while I was doing some rather humdrum data downloading at work. It&amp;rsquo;s that kind of album, quite loose and jam-based.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gluten Free Toad In The Hole</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gluten-free-toad-in-the-hole/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gluten-free-toad-in-the-hole/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a weekly lifter of spirits during the winter months!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Praise of Pilates</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-pilates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-pilates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In searching for something to write about today, I wondered whether I had ever written about Pilates on this blog before. I modified &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/fun-with-chatgpt/&#34;&gt;the search of my posts from yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post&lt;/a&gt; to look for the word Pilates&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and it only came up once in &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/ambitions-revisited/&#34;&gt;a post about revisiting my ambitions ten years on&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There I wrote:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I haven’t taken up meditation at all because the inside of my head is way too noisy. What I did do (at Ingrid’s suggestion) is take up Pilates: I swear by it now. It’s not quite the same as meditation but I’ve found the improvements to my core strength to be quite useful for my mental health.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fun With Chat-GPT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fun-with-chatgpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fun-with-chatgpt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I asked:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For my blog I have a folder called posts. In that folder are more folders that are named for the slug of each post, as per the conventions of the Hugo static site generator. Those folders each contain a markdown file named index.md, each of which has a YAML header. Draft posts have a YAML key called draft which has the value true. Please can you write me a shell script that I can run from the directory above posts that tells me which folders in the posts folder contain draft posts?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Break The Chain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dont-break-the-chain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dont-break-the-chain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2025 might be a tough year, but I am going to try and blog every day. It means that now and then I might be writing a post like this one, where I am writing for the sake of continuing the streak. If I find myself doing that too often then I will take the hint and stop trying!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This weekend was the 3rd round of the FA Cup, which is when the premier league and championship teams enter the competition. This is the first time for quite a few years where Portsmouth have entered at this stage. Naturally, they&amp;rsquo;re already out! Mind you, in recent years when they&amp;rsquo;ve entered at the first round they haven&amp;rsquo;t made it past those rounds either. That was bad news for one pub in Portsmouth which always made a big show of not taking down their Christmas decorations until Pompey were out of the FA Cup!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
