<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogging on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/blogging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogging on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/blogging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Orphan Project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-orphan-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-orphan-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A nice feature I added to this blog in its recent update was a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/tags/&#34;&gt;tags page&lt;/a&gt;. With the help of this &lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io/t/how-to-get-a-tags-page/24213/4&#34;&gt;very useful discourse thread&lt;/a&gt; and some additional CSS tweaks, the resulting page is something that I am very happy with. It lists all of the tags that apply to any post, along with the number of posts with that tag, in alphabetical order. It&amp;rsquo;s mostly intended as a guide for you the reader, to help you see whether your preoccupations match my own.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The new look mattischrome</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/new-look-mattischrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 20:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/new-look-mattischrome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the new look for my blog. I&amp;rsquo;ve had my eye on a more minimal look for a while now. Whether this new look is successful or not depends on how often I write new posts. To that end, this theme also supports a separate (or almost separate) stream of photos. Once I&amp;rsquo;ve got back in to the habit of putting photos up, that should be a nice additional stream of content.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unindexed?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/unindexed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/unindexed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/c/23998379/google-search-seo-algorithm-webpage-optimization&#34;&gt;an excellent article on The Verge yesterday about how Google is transforming the kinds of sites and blogs that are on the internet&lt;/a&gt;. I also read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fromjason.xyz/p/notebook/where-have-all-the-websites-gone/&#34;&gt;this slightly more personal take by Jason Velasquez&lt;/a&gt;, which is more about how social networks have gobbled up all the time and attention of people who might otherwise be making interesting web sites. This has made me think deeply about what this blog is &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt;, and why I might continue to blog in Twenty Twenty Four.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Git Instructions for Future Matt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/git-instructions-for-future-matt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 21:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/git-instructions-for-future-matt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Future Matt,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Always look up instructions for what you want to do in the Git documentation. It&amp;rsquo;s dry but it&amp;rsquo;s good. In a pinch, look at Stack Overflow. Don&amp;rsquo;t ask Chat-GPT for advice on Git problems!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To reverse mistakes, consult the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ohshitgit.com&#34;&gt;Oh Shit Git&lt;/a&gt; website.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To make things easier, delete the remote to your Github repository and then add it (the remote) back again. This is so much easier than the alternative.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Best wishes,&#xA;Past Matt (with his annual flash of January git confidence).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on 2023</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/reflections-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 22:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/reflections-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;travel&#34;&gt;Travel&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2023, it was Germany or go home.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Went to Cologne in January. Here is photographic evidence:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/2023/cologne-proof.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Photographic evidence of my visit to Cologne&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We took the Eurostar via Brussels. A bit of a long day on the way back but much less stressful compared to flying.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We went to the Isle of Wight in June. It was the first time I&amp;rsquo;d been since I was about 8. This time I didn&amp;rsquo;t get Chicken Pox. Anyway, here is photographic evidence:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year Preview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/albums-of-the-year-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/albums-of-the-year-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another year (nearly) over and so starting from tomorrow, I&amp;rsquo;m going to count down my top 10 albums of 2023. The rules are:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;They have to have to have been released in 2023.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;They need to be albums. I&amp;rsquo;m defining this as either more than 7 tracks or songs, or more than forty minutes in length.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To make the top ten, they need to have been played the most times. I admit that I don&amp;rsquo;t have a precise measure of this, as I do still buy vinyl and about four of these albums will have had play counts missed by not being captured through a streaming service.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Compilations are not included, whether they feature multiple artists or a retrospective of a single artist.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s pretty much it. Have I done any prep work? Well no, not really. I made a preliminary list at the start of October and not only was the number one album not out at the time (!) but I also had mistakenly included two albums from 2022. So yeah, this is not a pro operation. 😂&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is in my Rakefile? (March 2023 edition)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-in-my-rakefile-march-2023-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-in-my-rakefile-march-2023-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Because I am bored of forgetting what&amp;rsquo;s in my website&amp;rsquo;s Rakefile, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write a list. Also, as I&amp;rsquo;m probably going to move over to a node based approach soon, it&amp;rsquo;s a handy wish list for my &lt;code&gt;package.json&lt;/code&gt; file when the time comes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;make-a-new-post-in-_posts-named-title&#34;&gt;Make a new post in &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; named &amp;ldquo;Title&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;rake post[&amp;quot;Title&amp;quot;]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If no title is given, you will be prompted for one. The post will be opened in the editor specified in the Rakefile.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The paths in the wood</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-paths-in-the-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-paths-in-the-wood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I began writing this post after realising that it is the first of June and I might as well attempt once more to write a post every day. The speed with which the first of the month comes around, inviting another such promise, always amuses me. But at the moment I am not sure whether this blog will still exist come the end of the month. I think I want to start again in pastures new.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A February Project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/second-february-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/second-february-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hmmm it seems as though the &lt;code&gt;ffi&lt;/code&gt; gem as installed by bundler is not compatible with a Mac that has an M1 chip. This limits my ability to preview blog posts locally. I might have to swap to a more modern static site generator (which is probably easier than working out what &lt;code&gt;ffi&lt;/code&gt; actually does) - seems like a good February project!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Checking In</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/first-of-feb-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/first-of-feb-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite my best intentions, I didn’t manage to continue writing posts after the first day of 2022! But perhaps now I can try again as an excuse to test my blogging set up on my new computer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sprucing up the Blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sprucing-up-the-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sprucing-up-the-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post explains some of the modifications I made to a minimal Jekyll theme to get this blog as I wanted it. This blog (currently) uses the excellent &lt;a href=&#34;https://sidey-jekyll.netlify.app/about&#34;&gt;Sidey theme&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ronaldsvilcins.com&#34;&gt;Ronalds Vilciņš&lt;/a&gt;. His site looks eerily similar to this one, at least at time of writing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The theme is pretty minimal in terms of features (and appearance) but it scores well on the Google Page Speed test. The features I added have increased the build time, but have not affected the speed of the site in terms of the page speed test.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ambitions Revisited</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ambitions-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 21:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ambitions-revisited/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in 2012 &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/ambitions&#34;&gt;I wrote a post&lt;/a&gt; listing my ambitions for the future. Well it&amp;rsquo;s the future now isn&amp;rsquo;t it? Almost. After all, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/How-long-does-it-take-for-most-of-the-atoms-in-your-body-to-be-replaced-by-others&#34;&gt;I’m a whole new person now&lt;/a&gt;. Anyway it&amp;rsquo;s probably time to take stock. Have I achieved any of them? Have any of my ambitions changed? What&amp;rsquo;s replaced the things that I&amp;rsquo;ve decided not to worry about? What has come after the things I managed to do?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First off, here&amp;rsquo;s my justification for writing the list in the original post:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reboot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/reboot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/reboot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As much as I hate to write about writing, especially when I write so infrequently, I feel I need to reboot this blog. I wrote so few posts in recent months I considered giving up altogether.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been stressed. Sometimes this manifests in being unable to sleep. Sometimes it manifests in all my interests and ideas seeming to be completely pointless. Sometimes one of those precedes the other. Sometimes it works vice versa. Often since getting back from Australia I’ve felt stuck in a vicious circle of insomnia and disinterest. Perhaps it’s just been the longest case of jet lag ever.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Diary?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-diary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-diary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year promises to be exciting so this week I tried to buy a diary. One of those day-to-a-page affairs for scribbling down all the things I&amp;rsquo;ve seen and learned about. I thought they might be cheap now the calendar is turning to February. No such luck. There were a few week-to-view diaries going for half price in Waterstones but nothing suitable for my needs. I have lots of Field Notes notebooks if my urge to write gets too much to resist.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Valleys</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/valleys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/valleys/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my last post, I wrote about hills. I tried to use them as a metaphor to explain nagging sense of incompletion when you single out one activity over another. The feeling that there&amp;rsquo;s always a more exciting hill off in the distance to go climb, instead of the one you&amp;rsquo;re on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I said my next post would be about how to pick between different options, particularly when you have many to choose from. This post is not that. This is a short piece about an experience I had in South America that relates to the hills post: about contentment in the moment and letting things go.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hills</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hills/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hills/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of books. The way they transport you away to other places and so on. As repositories of knowledge and adventure they can&amp;rsquo;t be beat. I can think of no better way out of an existential fix than reading.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The trouble is I tend to hoard them. I&amp;rsquo;ve posted pictures of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/reading-list-mid-april-2012/&#34;&gt;book stacks before&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/another-reading-list/&#34;&gt;on more than one occasion&lt;/a&gt;). I could probably repeat that every month if I wanted to, perhaps even more often. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a networked thinker, able to see (at least superficially) the connections between all sorts of things. Because of this I get excited and enthusiastic about all kinds of things, and I want to learn them all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/changes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;moving-the-blog-to-jekyll-again-sort-of&#34;&gt;Moving the blog to Jekyll (again, sort of)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Et voila, my blog lives! In a new body (&lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;) and at &lt;a href=&#34;%7B%7Babsolute.url%7D%7D&#34;&gt;a new location&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-process&#34;&gt;The Process&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I set up Jekyll on my MacBook Air after loads of initial problems with installing the theme and getting assorted Ruby gems installed and working. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.stackoverflow.com&#34;&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt; is a friend for life now. By way of comparison, getting things up and running on my new Mac was simple.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Don&#39;t Have a Clue, part 43</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/no-clue-part-43/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/no-clue-part-43/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A little man wearing a bow tie, and possibly a fez, scurries into the middle of the frame clutching a clapboard. Breathing heavily he hoists the clapboard up to chest height. He holds the clapper up then brings down while slurring &amp;quot;This is a blog post about not having a clue, take 43&amp;quot;. He exits to the right of the frame.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My feet are hot. The bed seems too small. Why are my feet always too hot on nights like these? I bet I could sleep if my feet weren&#39;t so hot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Long Post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-long-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-long-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am writing a long post that I will either publish as one long post (about five or six thousand words) or as about seven smaller ones each closer to the average post length of about eight hundred words. I have to get it out-of-the-way soon as my mind needs to focus on my health economics essay.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is hard to write short posts to a timetable, let alone churn out long posts on a regular basis. As a result, this longer post is not likely to become the norm. It&amp;rsquo;s an idea I had that bloomed into something ever bigger and this time I decided to have a crack at it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time Is Time and That Is That</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/time-is-time-and-that-is-that/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/time-is-time-and-that-is-that/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A brief rant about Facebook: I hate the fact that the news feed defaults to “Top Stories” even though I change it back to “Most Recent” every time I log in. It’s a horrible pattern of user abuse that needs to stop. Time is time and that is that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So why does Facebook feel the need to jiggle things about into a random order? Well most of you have that mobile phone app of theirs that sucks your battery and your data allowance like crazy (mainly by auto-playing videos like a dick). They know you’re checking your Facebook on the loo at work and that that limits your interaction time. During this precious interlude they want you to see the stuff that they think interests you and the things that other people paid for you to see. You’re going to see some hick’s new tattoo, at least one photo of someone else’s child and an advert telling you to vote Conservative - whether you like it or not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Little Bit Intimidating Really</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-little-bit-intimidating-really/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-little-bit-intimidating-really/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is so much good writing out there. All you have to do is fire up &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/uk/&#34;&gt;the guardian website&lt;/a&gt;, or download the &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/m/app&#34;&gt;medium app to your smartphone&lt;/a&gt;, or visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://xianity.me/&#34;&gt;my friend Barrie&amp;rsquo;s site&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://narami.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Lee&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;, and so on and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When it comes to my little whisper into this great choir, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to feel a bit intimidated. How do I add my voice? How do I feel distinct? How do I do it as well as all these other wonderful writers?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Writing As It Happens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/writing-as-it-happens/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/writing-as-it-happens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m pretty close to a round number. To date I have written 298,500 words for this blog, not counting posts that I have discarded or deleted. This will be the 505th post currently on the blog, which makes for an average of just under 600 words per post. Some posts are just a picture or a video or a gallery though, so that distorts the average a bit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don’t think I can write the 1500 words I need to hit 300,000 in this post. It’s quite hard to write on demand and I often feel like my bright ideas are unassailable when I sit down to type them up. I’m conscious that I have to keep turning up to type but I’m not sure that it’s worthwhile to write posts like this simply to keep up a streak. A blog should be like an iceberg: the heft below the water line will make everything above it more beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Jackson X</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/jackson-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/jackson-x/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I set myself the task of writing about a fictional character for this blog post, so this post is about Jackson X. His surname isn’t really X, it’s just one of the details about him that I haven’t fleshed out yet. This is because Jackson X is the one of the protagonists of the novel I’m (not) writing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The name of the novel is “The Summer of the Giant Space Whale”. I’m quite happy to discuss its plot and structure here. I don’t need to worry about anyone stealing the idea because it is already a rip-off of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/112537.Rendezvous_with_Rama&#34;&gt;Arthur C. Clarke’s “Rendezvous With Rama”&lt;/a&gt; (or, less charitably, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0092007/?ref_=nv_sr_1&#34;&gt;“Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home”&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On convictions, whereas to the strength of and belief in same</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-conviction-and-belief/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-conviction-and-belief/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Overlong reflection upon the past is one sure way to make yourself unhappy so I try to avoid it. Nevertheless it becomes unavoidable at this time of year, especially if, like me, you are somewhat prone to reflection.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At this time last year I was, &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/articles/south-america-trip-part-11/&#34;&gt;as detailed in the most recent report of my South American adventure&lt;/a&gt;, in La Paz, Bolivia. I think I felt as lost then as I do now, though back then I had the novelty of new places and good friends to steer me through. This year I find myself stuck in an expensive flat that I can hardly afford to heat in a city where I hardly know anyone: it seems ridiculous that I had more people around me in La Paz than I do here but there you go.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>October and November 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/october-november-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/october-november-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently started a new job and moved in to a new flat. This means I&amp;rsquo;m too busy to write any long blog posts at the moment. Also I&amp;rsquo;m still not quite at home there, so I tend to spend my evenings tidying up or setting up new things. It&amp;rsquo;s a shame because I have plenty of things to write about (even without observations on moving, starting a new job, etc) but I guess the writing will happen eventually&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Useful Ulysses</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/useful-ulysses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/useful-ulysses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-it-is&#34;&gt;What it is&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ulyssesapp.com&#34;&gt;Ulysses&lt;/a&gt; is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&#34;&gt;markdown&lt;/a&gt; editor for the Mac. It has a simple drafting model that makes it easy to organise ideas and move between them. Pieces of writing are represented as sheets that can be tagged and grouped together - the grouping can be made manually or using filters. There are no files, the sheets are entries in a single database that is synced with iCloud. Because everything is plain text it won’t eat up your storage space. Individual sheets can be archived for use with Mac Os X’s versions feature.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Net Loss</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/net-loss/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/net-loss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I pay to have this blog up and running. That is, I pay for the space where it is stored and I pay for the name. I have to look after all the files and plug-ins, I have to perform all the updates and optimise the database tables. All this is great fun but wouldn’t it be cheaper to slap the mattischro.me address onto a hosted WordPress.com account?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, yes it would. I suppose I just like the independence of having my own little patch of cyberspace, sitting there waiting for all you dear readers to come and visit. Nice ideas don’t make the world go round though and so I need a better reason than that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five lessons from a year of blogging</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/five-lessons-from-a-year-of-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/five-lessons-from-a-year-of-blogging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have now been writing decent length articles on this site for about a year. I have learned a lot in this time, mostly about writing but also how to express your feelings and how to marshal your ideas and passions into action. For this month’s “five on the fifth”, I would like to share  with you some of the things I have learned.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing posts consistently is hard…&lt;/strong&gt; There are a lot of things that get in the way of regular posting. Sometimes it is ambition undermines me, I have ideas for posts that are easy to think up that turn out to be much harder to actually write. Other times life does just get in the way, it is  a time-consuming activity to write five hundred or more words every day. I like to write posts out longhand before typing them up. I often find mistakes or horrible phrasing when I do this and often what seemed like a simple matter of typing something up becomes a bit of a mission. Of course, there are times when I am just lazy or uninspired.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…except when it is easy.&lt;/strong&gt; I discovered early on that having a few arcs through the posts was a good idea as it makes you think a few in advance about what to do next. I prefer to be a generalist but it is nice to have the movie reviews, the &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;understated classics&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;j-g-ballard&#34;&gt;JG Ballard&lt;/a&gt; novels to fall back on. Truth be told I am a little bored of Ballard now but even if I retire that particular strand of posts (Spoiler: Don’t worry, &lt;em&gt;High-Rise&lt;/em&gt; is on the way soon) I can always resume it later. Meanwhile, I can pad out the off days with some quotes or some photos.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easier to read is easier to write.&lt;/strong&gt; I hope that the blog is easier to read now than when I started. I still find myself producing the odd clunky phrase now and then but the number of passive sentences is decreasing. The unexpected benefit of this has been that I find it easier to check earlier posts in search for inspiration about what to write next. Early on, I would often end up editing old posts into something more comprehensible instead of writing new material. The “After the Deadline” feature of &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/jetpack/&#34;&gt;Jetpack for WordPress&lt;/a&gt; has been very helpful in training me to write better.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WordPress is a lot of fun.&lt;/strong&gt; The statistic is that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wordpress.org/&#34;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; now powers about 500 million websites. It is not hard to see why, it is easy to install, easy to customise to suit to your tastes and most of all, it rewards you for continuing to produce content. I have installed all sorts of plug-ins, including a &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/wp-word-count/&#34;&gt;word count plug-in&lt;/a&gt; that tells me that I have (up to this post) written a total of 89,032 published words. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Length_of_a_novel&#34;&gt;If Wikipedia is to be believed&lt;/a&gt;, that is about the length of a pretty long novel. At least now I know I could write a novel in a year even if it was a rather surreal one featuring a 10K run, spiders and an Apatosaurus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I still have a lot more to do, a lot more to learn.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2017-update&#34;&gt;2017 Update&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adding to this footnote some years later (2017) I realise that not all blog posts are permanent. Sometimes you write what you need to at the time and then take it down later. We don&amp;rsquo;t have to be permanently changed by what we once wrote on a Wednesday afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
