<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Twenty on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/twenty/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Twenty on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/twenty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Italo Calvino, If on a Winter&#39;s Night a Traveller</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/italo-calvino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/italo-calvino/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I started to write a review of Italo Calvino&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;If on a Winter&amp;rsquo;s Night a Traveller&amp;rdquo;. I read it while we were in Germany for Christmas. We&amp;rsquo;d visited Bremen and also undergone the bizarreness of Christmas in another language - the same motifs played out in different words and different customs. I&amp;rsquo;d tried to write the review in a similar structure to the book but, in a testament to Calvino&amp;rsquo;s writing I couldn&amp;rsquo;t pull it off. Here&amp;rsquo;s the opening paragraph:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Richard Powers, Orfeo</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/richard-powers-orfeo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/richard-powers-orfeo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The mind may give up its desire to improve on creation and function as a faithful receiver of experience.&amp;rdquo; John Cage&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After enjoying &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/the-overstory/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Overstory&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I wanted to read more of Richard Powers&amp;rsquo; novels. &lt;em&gt;Orfeo&lt;/em&gt;  was also long listed for the Booker prize. Perhaps more of his novels would have been had the prize been opened to American authors earlier.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Orfeo&lt;/em&gt; is about Peter Els, a seventy year old composer who accidentally alerts Homeland Security to the existence of his home laboratory, in which he has been trying to recode the genetic material of a bacterium to include a piece of his music. He ends up on the run, which provides the catalyst for a narrative in which we ponders the past and returns to it. Woven throughout is a history of contemporary classical music, most real and some invented.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest 2020</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve listened to music in slightly different ways to normal in the last nine months, but it’s still been a decent year for music. When I checked out my Spotify Unwrapped and my Last.fm reports, I had listened to more 2020 music than I thought.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;december&#34;&gt;December&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Album of the month had to be &amp;ldquo;We Will Always Love You&amp;rdquo; by the Avalanches. One of only three albums that I bought physical copies of this year, it combines my favourite musical genres and has a novel take on the spacey-sounding album: like something beamed into space about how great humans are. That&amp;rsquo;s probably something we needed to be reminded of come the end of the year. In many ways, the Fermi paradox reminds us that quarantine and isolation are in many ways the default human condition. Even so, a signal to the outside universe must be sent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Old photographs</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/old-photographs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/old-photographs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve had cause to dig out some old photos. If I&amp;rsquo;m honest it&amp;rsquo;s made me sad. Sadder than I was expecting. There&amp;rsquo;s a quote from Nan Goldin that once felt like a warning but now just sounds like a sad statement of ongoing affairs:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“I used to think that I could never lose anyone if I photographed them enough. In fact, my pictures show me how much I’ve lost.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategy one</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/strategy-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/strategy-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to create my own deck of creativity cards. I was sick of all the adverts for similar products on Instagram. You know the kind. They&amp;rsquo;re covered in pictures, patterns, and buzzwords. You shuffle the cards and draw them one at a time. As you place each card on the table, the brain’s natural desire to tell stories, create patterns and produce meaning takes over.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I made a deck without too much thought for form or consequence. It was an unconscious collection of signs and symbols. The peaks of curves. Greek letters. Compartments, boxes, arrows. I told myself that I could create new things like this. I could break out of old mannerisms and entrenched thinking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Am I caring for a naughty cat?</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/am-i-caring-for-a-naughty-cat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/am-i-caring-for-a-naughty-cat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;He keeps biting me on the leg&amp;rdquo; says Ingrid one day as I mill around her desk during the new water cooler moment that is a comfort break on a Microsoft Teams call. I pat Martok, one of our cats, and he rubs up against me, pretending that he might nibble at me too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I experience this regularly. It used to be at half five, then at five, and these days at half past four. He strides into my office, circles around the chair and nips me on the calf. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why it&amp;rsquo;s getting earlier each day. It&amp;rsquo;s probably a brazen campaign for dinner, but I have been steadfast in feeding them no earlier than the S of six.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sprucing up the Blog</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/sprucing-up-the-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/sprucing-up-the-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post explains some of the modifications I made to a minimal Jekyll theme to get this blog as I wanted it. This blog (currently) uses the excellent &lt;a href=&#34;https://sidey-jekyll.netlify.app/about&#34;&gt;Sidey theme&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ronaldsvilcins.com&#34;&gt;Ronalds Vilciņš&lt;/a&gt;. His site looks eerily similar to this one, at least at time of writing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The theme is pretty minimal in terms of features (and appearance) but it scores well on the Google Page Speed test. The features I added have increased the build time, but have not affected the speed of the site in terms of the page speed test.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Travel Writing After All This</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/travel-writing-after-all-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/travel-writing-after-all-this/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While sprucing up this blog a bit during lockdown, I fell into reading my old posts about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/tag/south%20america/&#34;&gt;South America&lt;/a&gt;. I enjoyed it, mostly for the memories, but also because the current lockdown is warping my sense of time and space. Hours feel like weeks, but then I blink and a month&amp;rsquo;s gone by. I find myself traipsing similar orbits each day around the house, and then perhaps over to the supermarket or the park. There&amp;rsquo;s a palpable escapism to be had in reminiscing about South America and other places.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holiday Tabs</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/holiday-tabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/holiday-tabs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the course of a week on holiday, I started reading many interesting articles. In lockdown there isn&amp;rsquo;t much to do but read articles, but I still find myself not that good at finishing them. My phone has lots of tabs open and has become a Rolodex of shame. This post is to confess my sins.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m trying to re-familiarise myself with Python. As with all modern software development, Python now seems atomised and hyper-complicated. As a result, this series of posts from Claudio Jolowitz was useful. He cuts through lots of the complications and explains why they are there. Someone should ask him to write a book.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Living in the Pi Hole</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/living-in-the-pi-hole/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/living-in-the-pi-hole/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ingrid bought me a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.org&#34;&gt;raspberry pi&lt;/a&gt; for my birthday. I&amp;rsquo;ve set it up to run the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.pi-hole.net&#34;&gt;Pi-hole&lt;/a&gt; software. Pi-hole is a nifty bit of kit that intercepts your web requests and purges any that ask for material on known ad servers. Essentially it&amp;rsquo;s like having an ad blocker on your network rather than just your computer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written before about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/net-loss/&#34;&gt;why I hate web advertising&lt;/a&gt;, and since then it&amp;rsquo;s got even more malign. The use of our web browsing habits to track our every move and sell us crap has gotten way worse. Instagram is particularly &lt;em&gt;awful&lt;/em&gt; for it and gets more awful with every amendment that Facebook makes. An ad-blocking solution that works for apps as well as in the browser is especially welcome.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>George Saunders, Lincoln In The Bardo</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/george-saunders-lincoln-in-the-bardo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/george-saunders-lincoln-in-the-bardo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I read this book on holiday in Belgium last year. Having forgotten to pack a novel I scoured almost every book in the Waterstones at St. Pancras station before settling on this Booker prize winning novel by George Saunders.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lincoln in the Bardo&lt;/em&gt; fictionalises a period in Abraham Lincoln&amp;rsquo;s life immediately after the death of his son Willie. The story alternates between factual accounts of what happened at the time and the observations of ghosts in the graveyard where young Willie is buried. Lincoln visits the grave several times over the course of an evening, something that causes costernation and intrigue among the ghosts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Civ Leaders #3: Amanitore of Nubia</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/civ-leaders-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/civ-leaders-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amanitore of Nubia is available in a base game DLC. She also has her own scenario “The Gifts of the Nile”, which like most scenarios has unique tech and civic trees. You need to assert your dominance over the Nile by building seven temples. The scenario combines faith and military tactics in a satisfying way and you can also play it as Cleopatra for a different perspective.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;civ-ability&#34;&gt;Civ ability&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ta-Seti&lt;/em&gt; +50% Production toward Ranged units. Note that this bonus does not apply fully with respect to archers because the Nubian unique archer (see below) costs more to produce. You can get around this by building Slingers and promoting them. All Ranged units gain +50% combat experience. Mines over strategic resources provide +1 Production. Mines over bonus and luxury resources provide +2 Gold.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things to Remember</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/things-to-remember/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/things-to-remember/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These are some things I jotted down one day last week, I&amp;rsquo;ll refine them a bit more later on. Think of it as an aide-memoire of things that work for me, your milage may vary.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about things that haven&amp;rsquo;t happened.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t turn whatever has happened and/or is bothering you into a catastrophe, especially if no one else is telling you that it is one. Seek out someone you trust and ask them &amp;ldquo;is this a catastrophe?&amp;rdquo; Not only will they say no about 99.9% of the time, they will often tell you why it isn&amp;rsquo;t a catastrophe.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The people who are important to you will not use your personal characteristics as a laundry list of personal failings in the same way that you do. In fact they won&amp;rsquo;t do it all. What you perceive as your own obvious and innate failings, others will often struggle to even see. Self awareness and hyper-awareness are two different things.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There will be people who don&amp;rsquo;t like you, people who don&amp;rsquo;t think you&amp;rsquo;re good enough, and people who won&amp;rsquo;t give you a chance. They most likely intersect, meaning there are fewer of them than you might think. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to satisfy these people, only those who like you and support you. Most of all, you have to be good enough for you.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Everybody has different needs and wants in life. Even though your needs and wants will often intersect with those of others, there is still no reason to use other people as the measure for what you should be getting out of life.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A person has more depth and dimensions than are measurable. If you focus solely on a single metric when you measure yourself against some standard or goal, you will be wrong in some way or another. A qualified and multi-dimensional validation of your progress will give you a more nuanced and more supportive sense of where you are heading and how to correct yourself.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Always focus on your capability. Regard potential as something to be shaped into capability.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Take time to think about things in many different ways, employing both proven mental models and lateral thinking.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Often problems are easier to tackle once you have been for a walk in the countryside.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Long Post</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-long-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-long-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am writing a long post that I will either publish as one long post (about five or six thousand words) or as about seven smaller ones each closer to the average post length of about eight hundred words. I have to get it out-of-the-way soon as my mind needs to focus on my health economics essay.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is hard to write short posts to a timetable, let alone churn out long posts on a regular basis. As a result, this longer post is not likely to become the norm. It&amp;rsquo;s an idea I had that bloomed into something ever bigger and this time I decided to have a crack at it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contagion: A Short Review</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/contagion-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/contagion-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was much excitement about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1598778/&#34;&gt;Contagion&lt;/a&gt; at work. Finally a movie that explains  as part of the plot! A bunch of us went to see it, mainly to see whether &lt;a href=&#34;http://contagionmovie.warnerbros.com/index.html&#34;&gt;a disaster movie about a global pandemic&lt;/a&gt; could hold up as entertainment and to have a bit of a giggle if it couldn’t.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I liked three things in particular about the film. I liked the cinematography, especially the opening sequences with the index cases staggering around. I liked the soundtrack except for when it intruded a bit too much into proceedings. Finally, I liked Marion Cotillard, who seems to be in every interesting movie at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
