<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Battles on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/battles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Battles on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/battles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Favourite Albums of 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/favourite-albums-of-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/favourite-albums-of-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Given that I gave up on writing album digests for a bit this year, I thought I would at least do a proper top ten list of my favourite albums. There are quite a few albums that I did not have room for and I might try to revisit those later. In the mean time, let&amp;rsquo;s crack on. (To save time, I have in some instances pasted my original review from the appropriate album digest.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, April 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A mostly instrumental month with a comeback from Orbital, an excellent remix collection from Battles, an amazing movie documenting a live performance by the Chemical Brothers and Austin Wintory’s soundtrack to the game &lt;em&gt;Journey&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Orbital &lt;em&gt;Wonky&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Battles &lt;em&gt;Dross Glop&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Chemical Brothers &lt;em&gt;Don’t Think&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Austin Wintory &lt;em&gt;Journey (Original Soundtrack)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;orbital-_wonky_&#34;&gt;Orbital &lt;em&gt;Wonky&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am quite keen on Orbital, though perhaps not as keen as I am on the similarly named Orb. I think I have got all the Orbital albums, mostly bought on eBay after the fact. (Funny story though, I did find a copy of &lt;em&gt;In Sides&lt;/em&gt; in the loft of a house where I lived in Bath, along with several other albums…) My favourite Orbital album is probably &lt;em&gt;Snivilisation&lt;/em&gt; but they all have their moments, whether it is the genuine sliver of emotion shot through &lt;em&gt;Halcyon&lt;/em&gt; off the brown album, the proggy long-form tracks on &lt;em&gt;In Sides&lt;/em&gt; like &lt;em&gt;The Girl With The Sun In Her Head&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Out There Somewhere&lt;/em&gt; (parts one and two), or indeed the arsing about with heavy metal samples on tracks like &lt;em&gt;Tension&lt;/em&gt; off the highly underrated &lt;em&gt;The Altogether&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have had the sort of month that is not conducive to listening to much new music. Therefore this month’s post is only going to consider two new albums and two albums that I have bought behind time. Because of various bits of stress and poor mood, I have ended up going back and taking refuge in some old favourites and not listening to new stuff. At other points I have also gone back to the Fleet Foxes’ album that I wrote about last month, which has grown on me even more since. Sometimes I think that I should writing about these albums on a two month delay. Meanwhile, I even have new music that I haven’t listened to &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt;, namely &lt;strong&gt;Bon Iver&lt;/strong&gt;’s self-titled album. It has received so many good reviews that I have been too intimidated to listen to it. I will try to write about it next month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
