<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rock on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/rock/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rock on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/rock/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #4: The National, &#34;First Two Pages of Frankenstein&#34; and &#34;Laugh Track&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-04-the-national-frankenstein-laugh-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-04-the-national-frankenstein-laugh-track/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s probably no surprise that as we reach the top four (or five if you like) we also get to the two albums The National released in 2023. The first, “First Two Pages of Frankenstein”, was trailed with a big reveal early on in the year, while the second, “Laugh Track”, was dropped all of a sudden in October. Once I got to know both albums, I swung between liking each one more for a while, hence putting them both at the same point in the list and not considering each separately.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #6: Grails, Anches en Maat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-06-grails-anches-en-maat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-06-grails-anches-en-maat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/grails-anches-en-maat.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Anches en Maat by Grails&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Grails are one of those bands who always get played a lot at my house. There&amp;rsquo;s something about their slow incremental instrumental pieces that my brain just loves to get lost in. Anches en Maat, their first album in six years or so, and the first with the entire band in the studio together since 2008, is their most Grails-y album in a long time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics Or Not?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-or-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-or-not/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the new year, thoughts and spare time for writing point me toward writing some new posts for my understated classics series. Expect some new ones soon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I also reflected on my previous choices and thought a bit about how my music tastes have changed recently. Some of this has to do with streaming and the frustrations I wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/a-pox-on-both-their-houses&#34;&gt;in my last post&lt;/a&gt;. Some of it is just down to getting older: I have less time to listen to new music, and much of the &amp;rsquo;new&amp;rsquo; stuff I listen to is me investigating the stuff I missed first time around. Who knew Art of Noise were so good? Not me, but I do now!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If anything, make it weirder</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/make-it-weird/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/make-it-weird/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I listened to &amp;lsquo;Cloudbusting&amp;rsquo; by Kate Bush for the first time in a while. What a gloriously strange song it is. Best of all, it&amp;rsquo;s one of those songs that obscures what it is really about. It&amp;rsquo;s not a song about a change in the weather, but about &lt;a href=&#34;https://wilhelmreichmuseum.org/about/biography-of-wilhelm-reich/&#34;&gt;Wilhelm Reich&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Orgone&#34;&gt;orgone&lt;/a&gt; accumulator, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cultofweird.com/medical/radium-girls/&#34;&gt;fluorescent yo-yos&lt;/a&gt;, and a son (rather than a &lt;em&gt;sun&lt;/em&gt;) coming out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Cloudbusting&amp;rsquo; is from &amp;lsquo;Hounds of Love&amp;rsquo;, Kate&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;comeback&amp;rsquo; album following the commercial failure of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/understated-classics-19&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;The Dreaming&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;, an album I wrote about in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/tag/understated%20classics/&#34;&gt;understated classics series&lt;/a&gt;. It features four UK top 10 singles and some of her best work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #36: The Coral by The Coral</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-36/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-36/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Perhaps in today&amp;rsquo;s modern age of streaming and such, &lt;a href=&#34;http://thecoral.co.uk&#34;&gt;The Coral&lt;/a&gt; would be a bigger band and may have survived their eventual burnout. Their work ethic was evident from the start, as rumours swirled &lt;a href=&#34;https://i.ebayimg.com/images/g/YdkAAOSwfl9XBSiR/s-l300.jpg&#34;&gt;in the NME&lt;/a&gt; about a fantastic new band from Liverpool who were going to blow everybody&amp;rsquo;s socks off. I went to see them live in Bristol after they&amp;rsquo;d released three EPs and they were incredible. Their sound, a bit like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0071615/&#34;&gt;the movie &amp;ldquo;Holy Mountain&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; set to pop music, imagined a Merseybeat channelled from an alternative universe in which Lennon and McCartney took their acid in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.desertusa.com/mojave-desert.html&#34;&gt;the Mojave desert&lt;/a&gt; rather than in the English suburbs. Yes, it was derivative but somehow it also managed to be utterly new and compelling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #34: Stray by Aztec Camera</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-34/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next instalment in my understated classics series is &amp;quot;Stray&amp;quot; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://killermontstreet.net&#34;&gt;Aztec Camera&lt;/a&gt;. Released in 1990, it features two hit singles and the cover is my favourite colour: green.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My angle for writing about “Stray” was that it was an album that I &amp;quot;caught&amp;quot; from my parents. I soon realised that I wrote about some of those already, for example “The Circle and the Square&amp;quot; by Red Box. Besides, I’m not sure that my parents liked this album that much.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #29: Let It Come Down by Spiritualized</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I listened to Let It Come Down by Spiritualized for the first time during a difficult time in my life. I think this will always affect my feelings towards it. For me it&amp;rsquo;s a great big comfort blanket of a record. Coming after one of the all-time best break-up albums (in an artistic sense) in &amp;ldquo;Ladies and Gentlemen We Are Floating in Space&amp;rdquo; perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s not that much of a surprise. Layered in orchestras, horn sections, and gospel choirs, it&amp;rsquo;s not understated at all but hopefully I can persuade you that it is a classic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #28: The Meadowlands by The Wrens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-28/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the first lines of &amp;ldquo;The House That Guilt Built&amp;rdquo;, the soft cricket-laden lament that opens The Meadowlands by The Wrens, is &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m nowhere near where I thought I&amp;rsquo;d be&amp;rdquo;. The last line of the whole album is &amp;ldquo;this is not what you had planned&amp;rdquo;. These bookending lines set the tone for this shimmering, ramshackle masterpiece - a fatigue and careworn pride in failing to meet impossible standards writ large over its first and last eighty or so seconds. &amp;ldquo;The Meadowlands&amp;rdquo; is probably the best record you&amp;rsquo;ve never heard, and once you have heard it, you will never be the same. Even better, it changes and you change with every single listen. If you&amp;rsquo;re living your life and you really mean it, then this is the record for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #27: A Ghost Is Born by Wilco</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;whatever-happened-to-that-hat&#34;&gt;I have already given some of the personal background to why I love this album&lt;/a&gt; and now it’s time to give a bit of love to the music itself so I’ll stick to giving a track by track account of “A Ghost Is Born”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are familiar with Wilco’s first few albums, you’ll know that A Ghost Is Born is on the line of best fit through Being There, Summerteeth, and Yankee Hotel Foxtrot. It continues its predecessor’s experimentation, but also gets reined in a little. Great songs - some of my favourite Wilco songs - were left off Yankee Hotel Foxtrot (“&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bemydemon.org/songs/venus.htm&#34;&gt;Venus Stopped The Train&lt;/a&gt;”, “&lt;a href=&#34;http://wilcoworld.net/#!/song/a-magazine-called-sunset/&#34;&gt;A Magazine Called Sunset&lt;/a&gt;”) so the follow-up could easily have been more of the same and everyone would have gone home happy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #26: Come On Die Young by Mogwai</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you about punk rock: punk rock is a word used by dilettantes and ah&amp;hellip; and ah&amp;hellip; heartless manipulators about music that takes up the energies and the bodies and the hearts and the souls and the time and the minds of young men who give what they have to it and give everything they have to it and it&amp;rsquo;s a&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s a term that&amp;rsquo;s based on contempt, it&amp;rsquo;s a term that&amp;rsquo;s based on fashion, style, elitism, satanism and everything that&amp;rsquo;s rotten about rock &amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo; roll. I don&amp;rsquo;t know &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/John_Lydon&#34;&gt;Johnny Rotten&lt;/a&gt; but I&amp;rsquo;m sure&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m sure he puts as much blood and sweat into what he does as &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Sigmund_Freud&#34;&gt;Sigmund Freud&lt;/a&gt; did. You see, what sounds to you like a big load of trashy old noise is in fact the brilliant music of a genius, myself . And that music is so powerful that it&amp;rsquo;s quite beyond my control and ah&amp;hellip; when I&amp;rsquo;m in the grips of it I don&amp;rsquo;t feel pleasure and I don&amp;rsquo;t feel pain, either physically or emotionally. Do you understand what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about? Have you ever felt like that? When you just couldn&amp;rsquo;t feel anything and you didn&amp;rsquo;t want to either. You know? Like that? Do you understand what I&amp;rsquo;m saying sir? (Iggy Pop, Canadian TV, March 11th 1977.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #25: Long Gone Before Daylight by The Cardigans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The single biggest fact of life is that you are always going to be alone, you just might not realise it. Listening to The Cardigans&amp;rsquo; excellent 2003 &amp;ldquo;Long Gone Before Daylight&amp;rdquo; will help you see that all our relationships are essentially screwed &amp;ndash; but at least it sounds great while it does so.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Long Gone Before Daylight&amp;rdquo; (&amp;ldquo;Long Gone Before Daylight&amp;rdquo;) plays the role of &amp;ldquo;The Empire Strikes Back&amp;rdquo; in a trilogy of great albums that The Cardigans released between 1999 (the arguably better and slightly happier &amp;ldquo;Gran Turismo&amp;rdquo;) and 2006 (the unarguably inferior and definitely happier &amp;ldquo;Super Extra Gravity&amp;rdquo;). &amp;ldquo;Long Gone Before Daylight&amp;rdquo; has more of a country sound than &amp;ldquo;Gran Turismo&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Super Extra Gravity&amp;rdquo;, which meant that I ignored it for a long time: until the disintegration and failure of several relationships convinced me of its brilliance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #24: Reservoir by Fanfarlo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have written a lot in these posts about how music gets indelibly tied up with places, events and feelings. For me this album by Fanfarlo is tied up with all three of these. It makes me happy and sad at the same time in memory of great times that are now gone but are fondly remembered. I am aware that this is the youngest album on the list so far and so it might be a bit early to endow classic status upon it, but &amp;ldquo;Reservoir&amp;rdquo; is a fine album and to my ears it stands up really well. Listening to it again in the course of writing this post I found that I remembered every note and musical phrase, and yet somehow I also managed to delight in hearing new features in the production that I&amp;rsquo;d not noticed before.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #22: Walking With Thee by Clinic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Walking With Thee” is the second album by Liverpool band &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clinic_(band)&#34;&gt;Clinic&lt;/a&gt;. It was released in 2002, which seems like an age ago now. Even longer ago they released the single “The Return of Evil Bill”, which was got me interested in them in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently got back into “Walking With Thee” when I picked “Vulture” in my A-Z of Animals playlist last month. I’d forgotten just how great a song it is, both musically and lyrically. It’s a caution against letting those with more power and wealth lord it over us – viz, “the best that you’ve left here for others / is the best the rest of us know” – and so it’s surely much more a song for these times than back then in 2002. Anyway, I’m going to avoid too much reading into the lyrics for this particular understated classic, as most of the time Clinic are defiantly resistant to that kind of analysis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #19: The Dreaming by Kate Bush</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“I see the people working and see it working for them.” (&lt;em&gt;Sat In Your Lap&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Dreaming by Kate Bush is a strange 1982 album that many believed had destroyed her career. Two weeks before her first ever performance of “Running Up That Hill”, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nme.com/blog/index.php?blog=10&amp;amp;title=on_this_day_kate_bush_releases_hounds_of_1986&amp;amp;more=1&amp;amp;c=1&amp;amp;tb=1&amp;amp;pb=1&#34;&gt;the NME had written an editorial asking whether she had burnt herself out completely&lt;/a&gt;. Obviously “Running Up That Hill” (recently used to great effect in the Olympic Closing Ceremony) and the parent album “The Hounds Of Love” that followed showed that she had plenty more up her sleeve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CAN, The Lost Tapes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/can-the-lost-tapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/can-the-lost-tapes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This arrived on Monday and I thought I would give it a post of its own because at over 3 hours of music, I am unlikely to do more than dip into it before writing the album digest next week. It is a far bigger and more enjoyable artefact than I thought it was going to be, so it probably deserves special attention for that reason too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Can_(band)&#34;&gt;CAN&lt;/a&gt; are a German (“&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Krautrock&#34;&gt;Krautrock&lt;/a&gt;”) band that I got into about four years ago after my interest in the genre was sparked by the “Neu! 75” album and the Kraftwerk box set. I have four of CAN&amp;rsquo;s albums and I have thought about which one I should include as an &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;understated classic&lt;/a&gt;. It will probably be “Soon Over Babaluma” because no one really writes about that one. Then again, Portishead’s “Third” probably wouldn’t sound as awesome as it does without the influence of “Ege Bamyasi”, so that might be worth considering too. Everyone writes about “Tago Mago” and “Future Days” but for good reason.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #10: Tubular Bells II by Mike Oldfield</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was the artwork that got me interested in Tubular Bells II. Rendering Trevor Key&amp;rsquo;s wonderful icon of the twisted tubular bell in yellow and blue made it all the more mysterious. Seeing it one day in Woolworth&amp;rsquo;s in Leigh Park back in 1992 aroused my curiosity. The huge display must have been part of the massive publicity drive for the album. Despite dwindling sales for his albums at that time, a sequel to Tubular Bells represented a huge potential for sales. This is why Oldfield had been lured from his previous home at Virgin records over to Warner Music. At that point Oldfield had not made a good album since his soundtrack to the movie &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0087553/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Killing Fields&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in 1985, the end of a hot streak (perhaps 1980&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;QE2&lt;/em&gt; aside) that had lasted since the original &lt;em&gt;Tubular Bells&lt;/em&gt; back in 1973.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #7: 100 Broken Windows by Idlewild</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Idewild are a solid band who have released four or five albums that I could consider for this series. I&amp;rsquo;m even in the sleeve credits of one: &lt;em&gt;Post-Electric Blues&lt;/em&gt;, if you&amp;rsquo;re asking.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the end I went for &lt;em&gt;100 Broken Windows&lt;/em&gt; because it means a lot to me. It has more of a place in my life than the others. Usually I find that this happens if I can remember where I bought an album. In this case I bought a copy of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-22533522&#34;&gt;cassette&lt;/a&gt; in Bath HMV at Easter 2000. I can remember the first time that I listened to it too, it was as I marched home to Oldfield Park down Bathwick hill from the &lt;a href=&#34;www.bath.ac.uk&#34;&gt;university&lt;/a&gt; that same afternoon. It took exactly the two sides of the tape to get from one door to the other.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #5: A Weekend In The City by Bloc Party</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-weekend-in-the-city-background&#34;&gt;A Weekend In The City: Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the youngest album I have chosen for this series. I try to pick albums that are at least ten years old but every now and then, I will think of an album that matches the sort of things I want to write about. That&amp;rsquo;s the case here. &lt;em&gt;A Weekend in the City&lt;/em&gt; is an unusual album that, in a reversal of the old adage, is “easy to love but hard to admire”. Nevertheless I do love and admire it, and I would like to share my thoughts about it with you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #1: Together Alone by Crowded House</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week Arcade Fire released their hotly anticipated third album &amp;ldquo;The Suburbs&amp;rdquo;.  I loved &amp;ldquo;Neon Bible&amp;rdquo; but critics found it preachy, as overbearing as the religious folk it sought to satirise. I disagree and think it was an impressive continuation from an exciting debut. &amp;ldquo;The Suburbs&amp;rdquo; steps on from their previous two albums, both in subject matter and tone. It&amp;rsquo;s sad, thoughtful, resigned, angry and tetchy - among other things. “The Suburbs” isn&amp;rsquo;t the understated classic that I want to discuss though: with all the praise and plaudits, it may never suit this new thread of posts. I want to write about &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Together_Alone&#34;&gt;Together Alone by Crowded House&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
