<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reading Projects on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/reading-projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reading Projects on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/reading-projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Isaac Asimov, Foundation and Empire, Second Foundation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-rest-of-the-foundation-trilogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-rest-of-the-foundation-trilogy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I managed to read all of the foundation novels since I &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/foundation&#34;&gt;wrote about the first one&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, I’ll write about the next two, which covers the original trilogy of ‘novels’ created from the original short stories. I’ve tried to avoid spoilers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isaac Asimov, Foundation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/foundation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For our &lt;a href=&#34;the-same-but-different&#34;&gt;first anniversary&lt;/a&gt; we decided to exhange books. What better way to &lt;a href=&#34;https://ideas.hallmark.com/articles/anniversary-ideas/anniversary-gifts-by-year/&#34;&gt;celebrate a paper anniversary&lt;/a&gt;? Ingrid bought me the entire Foundation saga, most of which were &lt;a href=&#34;https://abcoverd.co.uk/archive/designers/topping-mike&#34;&gt;reissued in fancy new paperback designs by Mike Topping&lt;/a&gt; in 2016. All save for 1993&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/7lueju/asimovs_forward_the_foundation_published_in_2016/&#34;&gt;Forward The Foundation&lt;/a&gt; that is, but Ingrid got me a copy anyway. Hence, here is a new series of blog posts!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, Hello America</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-america/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had low expectations for &amp;ldquo;Hello America&amp;rdquo;, the next in &lt;a href=&#34;j-g-ballard&#34;&gt;the series of Ballard novels&lt;/a&gt; that I started reading over seven years ago. However, it turned out to be a hoot. A couple of years ago, this novel would have been a wig-out bit of standard Ballard weirdness (a bit like &lt;a href=&#34;the-drowned-world&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Drowned World&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;the-crystal-world&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Crystal World&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;) but given recent events &amp;ldquo;Hello America&amp;rdquo; is starting to take on an eerie prescience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Unlimited Dream Company</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-unlimited-dream-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-unlimited-dream-company/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/high-rise/&#34;&gt;I last wrote about a JG Ballard novel nearly three years ago&lt;/a&gt;. That one - &amp;ldquo;High-Rise&amp;rdquo; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/film/2016/mar/20/high-rise-review-ben-wheatley-jg-ballard-tom-hiddleston&#34;&gt;has since been made into a film&lt;/a&gt;. The subject of this post is &amp;ldquo;The Unlimited Dream Company&amp;rdquo;, my favourite among his novels: a silly romp through suburban sexual repression that glitters with sinister wit. Even after many read-throughs I still can&amp;rsquo;t work out whether it is a crazy masterpiece or something light that we&amp;rsquo;re meant to throw away after reading.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, High-Rise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/high-rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/high-rise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a few false starts I managed to finish &amp;ldquo;High-Rise&amp;rdquo;, the next in &lt;a href=&#34;j-g-ballard&#34;&gt;my collection of JG Ballard novels&lt;/a&gt;. For a book that I had trouble getting into, it turned out to be a pretty good read - even if it was also a pretty unpleasant one. Published in 1975, &amp;ldquo;High-Rise&amp;rdquo; is perhaps ahead of its time in exploring the effects of social breakdown in stylised and artificial situations where people are in close contact. You might think the plot, about a luxury high-rise that goes to hell, is in some way political or sociological but it really isn&amp;rsquo;t. It&amp;rsquo;s just a big playground in which Ballard throws around some of his most twisted ideas, all the while remarking on the very artifice of the situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Never Mind The Ballards</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/never-mind-the-ballards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/never-mind-the-ballards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;j-g-ballard&#34;&gt;Ages ago&lt;/a&gt; I set out to write a post for each of JG Ballard’s novels. In fact it is the oldest post on this blog. Most of the novels (I don’t have the two autobiographical novels &lt;em&gt;Empire Of The Sun&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;The Kindness Of Women&lt;/em&gt; and the late period novel &lt;em&gt;Milennium People&lt;/em&gt;) are sat in a row on top of my broken bookshelf, part of the weight there that bowed outer frame of the unit and made the inner shelves collapse. Had I known that it would be a task unfinished nearly eighteen months later and destroy a piece a furniture that I did not yet own, I may have been less ambitious.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, Concrete Island</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/concrete-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/concrete-island/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More Books</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/more-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/more-books/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, Crash</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/crash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/crash/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Crystal World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-crystal-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-crystal-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At last, Ballard in full flow. The Crystal World (TCW) is definitely the most enjoyable of the early trio of apocalyptic novels. It takes the successful elements of the first two and embellishes them with new details and ideas. At time of writing, TCW is definitely the best Ballard novel that I have read in its entirety.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Drought</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-drought/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-drought/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On to The Drought by J. G. Ballard in &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/j-g-ballard/&#34;&gt;my ongoing quest to read and review all of his novels&lt;/a&gt;. This is his second novel, if we assume his convention of never acknowledging “The Wind From Nowhere” as being his first novel. “The Drought” itself was renamed from “The Burning World” and additional content added later on. This was quite common practice in SF in the 50s and 60s where novels were serialised in magazines like &lt;a href=&#34;http://philsp.com/mags/amazing_stories.html&#34;&gt;Amazing SF&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://ttapress.com/interzone/about/&#34;&gt;Interzone&lt;/a&gt;. It is evidence though of Ballard finding his voice as he wrote and from The Drought it is easy to see that he is iterating his thought processes and subject matter with each novel.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“The Drought” is marvellous in a way that “The Drowned World” is not. Here Ballard has cut away much of the ropy science of that novel and left us with a much more realistic scenario of global drought without having to worry about all the outré trappings of giant iguanas and dragonflies the size of your head. Instead, all the magnetic and mesmerising elements of Ballard’s work are beginning to take form: the eccentric recluse with possible sinister intent, the confused and detached protagonist, the ambivalently regarded woman of standing, the encroachment of nature and the human tendency to defile pretty much all it touches, including all that it has constructed and lived alongside.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Drowned World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-drowned-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-drowned-world/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/j-g-ballard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/j-g-ballard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading &amp;ldquo;Crash&amp;rdquo; at 17 left me in a state of numb shock. It got me hooked and left me with &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/J._G._Ballard&#34;&gt;J. G. Ballard&lt;/a&gt; as one of my favourite authors. I then devoured a short story collection called &amp;ldquo;Myths of the Near Future&amp;rdquo; around the same time. You may recognise it because the Klaxons appropriated the title for their debut album. Those stories captured my imagination, in particular the eponymous story of a world gone to run amid &amp;ldquo;space sickness&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
