<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reading Projects on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/reading-projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reading Projects on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 21:30:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/reading-projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Isaac Asimov, Foundation and Empire, Second Foundation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-rest-of-the-foundation-trilogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 21:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-rest-of-the-foundation-trilogy/</guid>
      <description>I managed to read all of the foundation novels since I wrote about the first one. In this post, I’ll write about the next two, which covers the original trilogy of ‘novels’ created from the original short stories. I’ve tried to avoid spoilers.&#xA;Foundation and Empire Foundation and Empire comprises two novella length stories. The first story (“The General”) picks up from shortly after where the last of the five short stories in Foundation left off.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isaac Asimov, Foundation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/foundation/</guid>
      <description>For our first anniversary we decided to exhange books. What better way to celebrate a paper anniversary? Ingrid bought me the entire Foundation saga, most of which were reissued in fancy new paperback designs by Mike Topping in 2016. All save for 1993&amp;rsquo;s Forward The Foundation that is, but Ingrid got me a copy anyway. Hence, here is a new series of blog posts!&#xA;The Foundation novels detail a galactic empire in decline.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, Hello America</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-america/</guid>
      <description>I had low expectations for &amp;ldquo;Hello America&amp;rdquo;, the next in the series of Ballard novels that I started reading over seven years ago. However, it turned out to be a hoot. A couple of years ago, this novel would have been a wig-out bit of standard Ballard weirdness (a bit like &amp;ldquo;The Drowned World&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;The Crystal World&amp;rdquo;) but given recent events &amp;ldquo;Hello America&amp;rdquo; is starting to take on an eerie prescience.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Unlimited Dream Company</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-unlimited-dream-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-unlimited-dream-company/</guid>
      <description>I last wrote about a JG Ballard novel nearly three years ago. That one - &amp;ldquo;High-Rise&amp;rdquo; - has since been made into a film. The subject of this post is &amp;ldquo;The Unlimited Dream Company&amp;rdquo;, my favourite among his novels: a silly romp through suburban sexual repression that glitters with sinister wit. Even after many read-throughs I still can&amp;rsquo;t work out whether it is a crazy masterpiece or something light that we&amp;rsquo;re meant to throw away after reading.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, High-Rise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/high-rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/high-rise/</guid>
      <description>After a few false starts I managed to finish &amp;ldquo;High-Rise&amp;rdquo;, the next in my collection of JG Ballard novels. For a book that I had trouble getting into, it turned out to be a pretty good read - even if it was also a pretty unpleasant one. Published in 1975, &amp;ldquo;High-Rise&amp;rdquo; is perhaps ahead of its time in exploring the effects of social breakdown in stylised and artificial situations where people are in close contact.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Never Mind The Ballards</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/never-mind-the-ballards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/never-mind-the-ballards/</guid>
      <description>Ages ago I set out to write a post for each of JG Ballard’s novels. In fact it is the oldest post on this blog. Most of the novels (I don’t have the two autobiographical novels Empire Of The Sun or The Kindness Of Women and the late period novel Milennium People) are sat in a row on top of my broken bookshelf, part of the weight there that bowed outer frame of the unit and made the inner shelves collapse.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, Concrete Island</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/concrete-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/concrete-island/</guid>
      <description>No man is an island (not any more) You are tracked pretty much everywhere you go. CCTV, the GPS on your phone or the signals sent by your more primitive model to the masts to keep in touch with the network. Your cash withdrawals, your purchases in Tesco and your journeys on public transport all add to the picture of where you are. If you drive, your sat nav will hold clues to where you have been and, if you disappear, where you might have gone to.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More Books</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/more-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/more-books/</guid>
      <description>Never mind the Ballards I have been writing about books by J.G. Ballard pretty much to the exclusion of all others. Gradually the posts have tricked out about four novels and ground to a halt. I’ve got a fair way through two other books but I am getting very tired of reading his novels all the time, much as I love them. The mistake I made was that I hadn’t read enough of them in the first place.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, Crash</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/crash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/crash/</guid>
      <description>Form and function, deformation and dysfunction I think we should get one thing out of the way first. For me, there is nothing erotic about a car or a motorway. The place in popular culture of the car in particular as sexual icon has always bemused me. In fact, I’m really rather ambivalent about cars. This matters when discussing Crash, the 1973 novel by JG Ballard that resumes this strand of posts about his novels.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Crystal World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-crystal-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-crystal-world/</guid>
      <description>Crystallising the world, the body, or the mind? At last, Ballard in full flow. The Crystal World (TCW) is definitely the most enjoyable of the early trio of apocalyptic novels. It takes the successful elements of the first two and embellishes them with new details and ideas. At time of writing, TCW is definitely the best Ballard novel that I have read in its entirety.&#xA;The book begins with a steamer travelling up a river in Cameroon carrying the novel’s main protagonist Edward Sanders, a doctor at a hospital for lepers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Drought</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-drought/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-drought/</guid>
      <description>The world created by nature versus the world constructed by humans On to The Drought by J. G. Ballard in my ongoing quest to read and review all of his novels. This is his second novel, if we assume his convention of never acknowledging “The Wind From Nowhere” as being his first novel. “The Drought” itself was renamed from “The Burning World” and additional content added later on. This was quite common practice in SF in the 50s and 60s where novels were serialised in magazines like Amazing SF and Interzone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Drowned World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-drowned-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-drowned-world/</guid>
      <description>Does Science Fiction have to be believable to be meaningful? Should science fiction have predictive power? In plotting the vast unknowns of the future, should authors aim for prescience? Will people be able to say of the best SF novels in five hundred years time that some novels were right about some things and that these novels are better than the ones that didn’t?&#xA;I would say no, otherwise we would be remarkably unfair on an awful lot of good writing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/j-g-ballard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/j-g-ballard/</guid>
      <description>Reading &amp;ldquo;Crash&amp;rdquo; at 17 left me in a state of numb shock. It got me hooked and left me with J. G. Ballard as one of my favourite authors. I then devoured a short story collection called &amp;ldquo;Myths of the Near Future&amp;rdquo; around the same time. You may recognise it because the Klaxons appropriated the title for their debut album. Those stories captured my imagination, in particular the eponymous story of a world gone to run amid &amp;ldquo;space sickness&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
