<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Album on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/album/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Album on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/album/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>808 State, Don Solaris</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/808-state-don-solaris/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/808-state-don-solaris/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I sometimes wonder if I picked the correct 808 State album for my understated classics series. That&amp;rsquo;s because today I was listening to their 1996 album &lt;em&gt;Don Solaris&lt;/em&gt; and it&amp;rsquo;s pretty darn good. For understated classics I chose their earlier effort &lt;em&gt;Gorgeous&lt;/em&gt;, partly out of the belief that probably no one else ever would, but also because &lt;em&gt;10X10&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Plan 9&lt;/em&gt; are such total bangers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Underworld, Strawberrry Hotel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/underworld-strawberrry-hotel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/underworld-strawberrry-hotel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An album that arrived a bit too late to be considered in the best of the year list, &lt;em&gt;Strawberry Hotel&lt;/em&gt; by Underworld is a solid effort. Their 11th album, it remarks their return to the format after five years after the &lt;em&gt;Drift&lt;/em&gt; series in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Albums of the Year #1: Bolis Pupul, Letter To Yu</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-01-bolis-pupul-letter-to-yu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-01-bolis-pupul-letter-to-yu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bolispupul.bandcamp.com&#34;&gt;Bolis Pupul&lt;/a&gt; (the stage name of Boris Zeebroek) is an artist on &lt;a href=&#34;https://deew.ee/catalogue&#34;&gt;Soulwax&amp;rsquo;s Deewee label&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://deew.ee/catalogue/074&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Letter to Yu&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is his debut album, inspired by a trip to Hong Kong to investigate his family history. It investigates themes of place, family, and identity. We are exposed to everywhere all at once but we&amp;rsquo;re also all &lt;em&gt;from&lt;/em&gt; somewhere, even if it&amp;rsquo;s somewhere we might not recommend or understand.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Albums of the Year #2: Waxahatchee, Tigers Blood</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-02-waxahatchee-tigers-blood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-02-waxahatchee-tigers-blood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Tiger&amp;rsquo;s Blood&amp;rdquo; is a glorious bundle of songs that writhe with brains and heart, with love and friendship, and many other complements and opposites. The music is mostly alternative AOR with a distinct country twang. The lyrics were pretty impenetrable to me, at least until I looked them up online (and they&amp;rsquo;re also on the back of the poster that came with the LP), but they&amp;rsquo;re mostly songs of hope and happiness. It was satisfying to listen to an album this care-free, even if there is a hint of darker times in the background.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Albums of the Year #3: Acopia, Acopia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-03-acopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-03-acopia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Acopia are a band from Melbourne Australia with that time honoured line up of one girl and two guys. This eponymous album is their second and it&amp;rsquo;s full of slinky electronic ballads that echo classic 90s trip hop. It&amp;rsquo;s got that same downtempo downbeat vibe, the sorts of songs that revel in sadness but also the joy of a killer bass line.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Albums of the Year #4: Adrianne Lenker, Bright Future</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-04-adrianne-lenker-bright-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-04-adrianne-lenker-bright-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One album that&amp;rsquo;s lurking in the periphery of my &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;understated classics series&lt;/a&gt; is &amp;ldquo;Dragon New Warm Mountain I Believe In You&amp;rdquo; by Big Thief. &amp;ldquo;Bright Future&amp;rdquo; is the latest solo album by Big Thief singer-songwriter Adrianne Lenker and it is just as good. Intimate and intricate, it draws the listener in as Adrianne sings live with a very small band. At times you can hear breaths drawn and the sound feels like a small space that you are cocooned in: this could be sound engineering (spatial audio would have us believe anything is possible) but it&amp;rsquo;s most likely equipment set up intelligently in a cosy studio.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Albums of the Year #5: Il Quadro di Troisi, La Commedia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-05-il-quadro-di-troisi-la-commedia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-05-il-quadro-di-troisi-la-commedia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting that an album sung entirely in Italian ended up being one of my favourites of the year, but perhaps not surprising given well written and arranged these songs are. They&amp;rsquo;re just the right side of electro-pop but also with an air of sophistication.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
