<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Short Story on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/short-story/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Short Story on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/short-story/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Strategy one</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/strategy-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/strategy-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to create my own deck of creativity cards. I was sick of all the adverts for similar products on Instagram. You know the kind. They&amp;rsquo;re covered in pictures, patterns, and buzzwords. You shuffle the cards and draw them one at a time. As you place each card on the table, the brain’s natural desire to tell stories, create patterns and produce meaning takes over.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Jackson X</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/jackson-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/jackson-x/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I set myself the task of writing about a fictional character for this blog post, so this post is about Jackson X. His surname isn’t really X, it’s just one of the details about him that I haven’t fleshed out yet. This is because Jackson X is the one of the protagonists of the novel I’m (not) writing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Mountain Story</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-mountain-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-mountain-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A cat reaches the top of a mountain after a long climb through the snow. He is cold from the bottom of his fur to the tips of his claws. He is sodden and wet, and we all know how much a cat hates to be wet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Painter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-painter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-painter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time there was a man who loved to paint. He studied the art and craft of painting for many years. He chose to invest his time and energy into creating the most realistic portraits that he could paint. For him the joy came not from completing the paintings but the process of recreating the real world with the strokes of his brush.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
