<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Short Story on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/short-story/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Short Story on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/short-story/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Strategy one</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/strategy-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/strategy-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to create my own deck of creativity cards. I was sick of all the adverts for similar products on Instagram. You know the kind. They&amp;rsquo;re covered in pictures, patterns, and buzzwords. You shuffle the cards and draw them one at a time. As you place each card on the table, the brain’s natural desire to tell stories, create patterns and produce meaning takes over.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I made a deck without too much thought for form or consequence. It was an unconscious collection of signs and symbols. The peaks of curves. Greek letters. Compartments, boxes, arrows. I told myself that I could create new things like this. I could break out of old mannerisms and entrenched thinking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Jackson X</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/jackson-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/jackson-x/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I set myself the task of writing about a fictional character for this blog post, so this post is about Jackson X. His surname isn’t really X, it’s just one of the details about him that I haven’t fleshed out yet. This is because Jackson X is the one of the protagonists of the novel I’m (not) writing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The name of the novel is “The Summer of the Giant Space Whale”. I’m quite happy to discuss its plot and structure here. I don’t need to worry about anyone stealing the idea because it is already a rip-off of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/112537.Rendezvous_with_Rama&#34;&gt;Arthur C. Clarke’s “Rendezvous With Rama”&lt;/a&gt; (or, less charitably, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0092007/?ref_=nv_sr_1&#34;&gt;“Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home”&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Mountain Story</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-mountain-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-mountain-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A cat reaches the top of a mountain after a long climb through the snow. He is cold from the bottom of his fur to the tips of his claws. He is sodden and wet, and we all know how much a cat hates to be wet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the top of the mountain there is not much to see. What may have been a breathtaking view is instead a murk of freezing mist and at any rate, snow assails the cat’s eyes and whiskers. He shivers and sneezes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Painter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-painter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-painter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time there was a man who loved to paint. He studied the art and craft of painting for many years. He chose to invest his time and energy into creating the most realistic portraits that he could paint. For him the joy came not from completing the paintings but the process of recreating the real world with the strokes of his brush.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For many years he continued to study the art of painting. He learned new techniques for abstracting from reality but he always favoured the realism above all else. Meanwhile, his friends and family mocked him and said that he would always be a poor boy who loved to paint but could not make money from it. He had no answer to this criticism, the satisfaction he gained from applying the brush to the canvas was to great to worry about whether his paintings would be finished or not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
