<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Booker Prize on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/booker-prize/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Booker Prize on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/booker-prize/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>George Saunders, Lincoln In The Bardo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/george-saunders-lincoln-in-the-bardo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/george-saunders-lincoln-in-the-bardo/</guid>
      <description>I read this book on holiday in Belgium last year. Having forgotten to pack a novel I scoured almost every book in the Waterstones at St. Pancras station before settling on this Booker prize winning novel by George Saunders.&#xA;Lincoln in the Bardo fictionalises a period in Abraham Lincoln&amp;rsquo;s life immediately after the death of his son Willie. The story alternates between factual accounts of what happened at the time and the observations of ghosts in the graveyard where young Willie is buried.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Satin Island by Tom McCarthy: Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/satin-island-tom-mccarthy-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/satin-island-tom-mccarthy-review/</guid>
      <description>As much as I wanted it to, Satin Island by Tom McCarthy did not win the Booker Prize. Having read it all I realise it was a long shot. However it is an interesting book that deserved consideration, even if it does have some flaws.&#xA;Normally I promise that there will be no spoilers. Not this time. There are some spoilers here. Because it took me so long to work out what I thought Satin Island was actually about, I want to use this post to explore those ideas.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Booker Prize Pick 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/booker-prize-pick-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/booker-prize-pick-2015/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Satin Island&amp;rdquo; is my pick for the Man Booker prize, announced tomorrow. I&amp;rsquo;ve not managed to read all of it yet. Also, I&amp;rsquo;ve only glanced at the others on the shortlist.&#xA;My prediction record on selecting the winner of the Booker from the shortlist is pretty good, though all I&amp;rsquo;m ever doing is guess the outcome of a 1 in 6 chance, like the roll of a die. Often it&amp;rsquo;s a book that I really hope will win rather than one I know will (except &amp;ldquo;Wolf Hall&amp;rdquo; and its sequel).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
