<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>November on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/november/</link>
    <description>Recent content in November on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/november/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, November 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2017/</guid>
      <description>00110100 01010100 &amp;ldquo;0181&amp;rdquo; This is a reissue of a Four Tet rarity from 2013 that has recently surfaced on Spotify under an alias1. &amp;ldquo;0181&amp;rdquo; collects a series of short experimental pieces from throughout his career, though I&amp;rsquo;m not enough of a nerd to know whether they are in any particular order. Last month&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;proper&amp;rsquo; Four Tet album &amp;ldquo;New Energy&amp;rdquo; has a lot more bounce to it, but &amp;ldquo;0181&amp;rdquo; nevertheless has some interesting moments that raises it above mere curiosity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, November 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2012/</guid>
      <description>Pretty much a sliding scale between songs and electronic wibble on this month’s albums and a particularly damp, chilly feeling to proceedings too.&#xA;Bat For Lashes “The Haunted Man” Ital “Hive Mind” and “Dream On” Björk “Bastards” Brian Eno “Lux” Bat For Lashes “The Haunted Man” When it comes to Bat For Lashes, I prefer her first album “Fur And Gold” to her second “Two Suns” because when I listen to the latter I don’t feel connected to any of the songs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, November 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2011/</guid>
      <description>Just three albums this month as I’ve been listening to a lot of Brian Eno records ready for an upcoming understated classic. First up is 50 Words For Snow by Kate Bush, the second album that she has released this year. Back in May I wrote about Director’s Cut, which presented re-recorded and re-mastered versions of songs from her albums The Sensual World and The Red Shoes. This time around it is an album of brand new material, the first since Aerial in 2006.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
