<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wilco on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/wilco/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wilco on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/wilco/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2016/</guid>
      <description>This month&amp;rsquo;s album digest features albums by Wilco, M.I.A., Local Natives, and a collaboration between Kaitlyn Aurelia Smith and Suzanne Ciani.&#xA;Wilco Schmilco Schmilco is the tenth studio album by Wilco, which regular readers will know are one of my favourite bands. There&amp;rsquo;s no need to repeat that anecdote about why this blog has the name that it does. Meanwhile, this album follows on from last year&amp;rsquo;s Star Wars and is probably the third Wilco album to have a jokey meta- kind of title.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #27: A Ghost Is Born by Wilco</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-27/</guid>
      <description>I have already given some of the personal background to why I love this album and now it’s time to give a bit of love to the music itself so I’ll stick to giving a track by track account of “A Ghost Is Born”.&#xA;If you are familiar with Wilco’s first few albums, you’ll know that A Ghost Is Born is on the line of best fit through Being There, Summerteeth, and Yankee Hotel Foxtrot.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whatever Happened To That Hat?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/whatever-happened-to-that-hat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/whatever-happened-to-that-hat/</guid>
      <description>The hat in question is a Wilco baseball cap that I bought at a gig of theirs in 2004, the night that Germany got eliminated from Euro 2004. I&amp;rsquo;d love to show you a picture of it but I can&amp;rsquo;t, there isn&amp;rsquo;t even a picture of it from a Wilco merch site: at least not one that Google or Bing images can see anyway. I did manage to find a side-on picture of it in my bedroom in 2005 and zoom right in on it like they do in CSI.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2011/</guid>
      <description>Hmmm, a rather grey looking selection of covers this month. The albums I have listened to most are:&#xA;John Beltran Ambient Selections FabricLive 59 mixed by Four Tet The Rapture In The Grace Of Your Love Wilco The Whole Love I have actually only had the Wilco album since Monday of this week (the 26th) but it has inveigled its way into my consciousness quite quickly. As I have said before, this blog owes its name to a Wilco song and they are quite an important band to me.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
