<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wilco on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/wilco/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wilco on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/wilco/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wilco, A Ghost Is Born (Superdeluxe edition)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/wilco-a-ghost-is-born-superdeluxe-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/wilco-a-ghost-is-born-superdeluxe-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2022, I invested in the big superdeluxe box for Wilco&amp;rsquo;s most successful album &amp;ldquo;Yankee Hotel Foxtrot&amp;rdquo;. Across 11 pieces of &amp;lsquo;silver&amp;rsquo; vinyl and one CD, the box set showed the tortuous process that Wilco went through to create that album. It&amp;rsquo;s a magnificent collection of music, though if you don&amp;rsquo;t like hearing multiple versions of the same song and are not fond of unfinished material, it&amp;rsquo;s not going to be as pleasant an afternoon as it is for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robin Egg Blue</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/robin-egg-blue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/robin-egg-blue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is record one of nine from the new &amp;ldquo;A Ghost Is Born&amp;rdquo; superdeluxe edition. I was hoping to write a review tonight but I haven&amp;rsquo;t managed to listen to it all yet!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month&amp;rsquo;s album digest features albums by Wilco, M.I.A., Local Natives, and a collaboration between Kaitlyn Aurelia Smith and Suzanne Ciani.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;wilco-schmilco&#34;&gt;Wilco &lt;em&gt;Schmilco&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Schmilco&lt;/em&gt; is the tenth studio album by Wilco, which regular readers will know are one of my favourite bands. &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/whatever-happened-to-that-hat/&#34;&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no need to repeat that anecdote about why this blog has the name that it does.&lt;/a&gt; Meanwhile, this album follows on from last year&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; and is probably the third Wilco album to have a jokey meta- kind of title. (The other one is the rather splendid &lt;em&gt;Wilco (The Album)&lt;/em&gt; from 2009.) I didn&amp;rsquo;t write a review of &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;; it  was released for free and for some reason it passed me by. &lt;em&gt;Schmilco&lt;/em&gt; is a fairly similar album and that&amp;rsquo;s not a bad thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #27: A Ghost Is Born by Wilco</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/whatever-happened-to-that-hat/&#34;&gt;I have already given some of the personal background to why I love this album&lt;/a&gt; and now it’s time to give a bit of love to the music itself so I’ll stick to giving a track by track account of “A Ghost Is Born”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are familiar with Wilco’s first few albums, you’ll know that A Ghost Is Born is on the line of best fit through Being There, Summerteeth, and Yankee Hotel Foxtrot. It continues its predecessor’s experimentation, but also gets reined in a little. Great songs - some of my favourite Wilco songs - were left off Yankee Hotel Foxtrot (“&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bemydemon.org/songs/venus.htm&#34;&gt;Venus Stopped The Train&lt;/a&gt;”, “&lt;a href=&#34;http://wilcoworld.net/#!/song/a-magazine-called-sunset/&#34;&gt;A Magazine Called Sunset&lt;/a&gt;”) so the follow-up could easily have been more of the same and everyone would have gone home happy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whatever Happened To That Hat?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/whatever-happened-to-that-hat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/whatever-happened-to-that-hat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The hat in question is a Wilco baseball cap that I bought at a gig of theirs in 2004, the night that Germany got eliminated from Euro 2004. I&amp;rsquo;d love to show you a picture of it but I can&amp;rsquo;t, there isn&amp;rsquo;t even a picture of it from a Wilco merch site: at least not one that Google or Bing images can see anyway. I did manage to find a side-on picture of it in my bedroom in 2005 and zoom right in on it like they do in CSI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hmmm, a rather grey looking selection of covers this month. The albums I have listened to most are:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;John Beltran &lt;em&gt;Ambient Selections&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;FabricLive 59 mixed by Four Tet&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Rapture &lt;em&gt;In The Grace Of Your Love&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wilco &lt;em&gt;The Whole Love&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have actually only had the Wilco album since Monday of this week (the 26th) but it has inveigled its way into my consciousness quite quickly. As I have said before, &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/2010/playlist-1-metallic/&#34;&gt;this blog owes its name to a Wilco song&lt;/a&gt; and they are quite an important band to me. The other albums are mostly electronic, although The Rapture are distinctly indie flavoured as they hit the dance floor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
