<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fourteen on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/fourteen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fourteen on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/fourteen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>South America, Part 12</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-trip-part-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-trip-part-12/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South America, Part 11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-trip-part-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-trip-part-11/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On convictions, whereas to the strength of and belief in same</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-conviction-and-belief/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-conviction-and-belief/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Overlong reflection upon the past is one sure way to make yourself unhappy so I try to avoid it. Nevertheless it becomes unavoidable at this time of year, especially if, like me, you are somewhat prone to reflection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>October and November 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/october-november-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/october-november-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently started a new job and moved in to a new flat. This means I&amp;rsquo;m too busy to write any long blog posts at the moment. Also I&amp;rsquo;m still not quite at home there, so I tend to spend my evenings tidying up or setting up new things. It&amp;rsquo;s a shame because I have plenty of things to write about (even without observations on moving, starting a new job, etc) but I guess the writing will happen eventually&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Brains</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-brains/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-brains/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a longer form post about artificial intelligence inspired by reading a little bit of &amp;ldquo;The Pale King&amp;rdquo; by David Foster Wallace and putting a picture of a &amp;ldquo;ghost&amp;rdquo; up on Instagram. This might be the last of these that I&amp;rsquo;m able to write for a while.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Album Digest September 2014 contains four amazing albums, including the long-awaited return from the Aphex Twin, and an album from Cymbals Eat Guitars released about a week after I wondered what had happened to them. Spooky. Rounding out the selection this month are a cool punky-disco album by The Juan Maclean and a truly remarkable offering by Vessel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to generate random numbers in R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/generate-random-numbers-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/generate-random-numbers-in-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post deals with how to generate random numbers in R. It is good to know how to generate random numbers with a particular language or software package for at least one of the following three reasons:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evie Wyld, All The Birds, Singing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/all-the-birds-singing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/all-the-birds-singing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently finished reading &lt;em&gt;All The Birds, Singing&lt;/em&gt;, the second novel by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eviewyld.com&#34;&gt;Evie Wyld&lt;/a&gt;. It’s about a woman called Jake who lives alone on a farm with a dog called Dog on an island somewhere off the coast of Britain. She has sheep to look after but something keeps coming in the middle of the night to kill them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The album digest returns with five albums by four artists.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haruki Murakami, Colorless Tsukuru Tazaki And His Years Of Pilgrimage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/colorless-tsukuru-tazaki/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/colorless-tsukuru-tazaki/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Colorless Tsukuru Tazaki And His Years Of Pilgrimage is the latest novel by Haruki Murakami. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/books/2014/jun/19/haruki-murakami-marketing-publishers-stickers&#34;&gt;It comes with free stickers&lt;/a&gt;. Perhaps that tells you everything you need to know about this book, which is slimmer than Murakami&amp;rsquo;s recent efforts. The plot begins with an intriguing premise. Tsukuru is part of a group of close friends and is one day expelled from the group for no reason. Unfortunately, the development of the plot is uncontrolled and by the end  of novel too many holes have developed for it all to hold together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Useful Ulysses</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/useful-ulysses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/useful-ulysses/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #27: A Ghost Is Born by Wilco</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/whatever-happened-to-that-hat/&#34;&gt;I have already given some of the personal background to why I love this album&lt;/a&gt; and now it’s time to give a bit of love to the music itself so I’ll stick to giving a track by track account of “A Ghost Is Born”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are familiar with Wilco’s first few albums, you’ll know that A Ghost Is Born is on the line of best fit through Being There, Summerteeth, and Yankee Hotel Foxtrot. It continues its predecessor’s experimentation, but also gets reined in a little. Great songs - some of my favourite Wilco songs - were left off Yankee Hotel Foxtrot (“&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bemydemon.org/songs/venus.htm&#34;&gt;Venus Stopped The Train&lt;/a&gt;”, “&lt;a href=&#34;http://wilcoworld.net/#!/song/a-magazine-called-sunset/&#34;&gt;A Magazine Called Sunset&lt;/a&gt;”) so the follow-up could easily have been more of the same and everyone would have gone home happy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South America, Part 10</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-trip-part-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-trip-part-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/2014/05/south-america-trip-part-9/&#34;&gt;Picking up where I left off&lt;/a&gt; at Machu Picchu, we headed down into Aguas Calientes (trans. “hot waters”) by coach and by the time we got there it was torrenting down with rain. So much for exploration. We waited out the downpour in a pizza place and deliberated over whether to buy souvenier snaps from the tour guides. Ironically for a town named after hot waters, it was bitterly cold. One of those places where the sound of running water follows you wherever you go, the best thing about it was the huge trains that ran down the middle of street - big clanking hulks pulling huge passenger trains.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clarice Lispector, Hour of the Star</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hour-of-the-star-by-clarice-lispector/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hour-of-the-star-by-clarice-lispector/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.penguin.co.uk/nf/Book/BookDisplay/0,,9780141392035,00.html?strSrchSql=hour+of+the+star/Hour_of_the_Star_Clarice_Lispector&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hour of the Star&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a short novel by &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clarice_Lispector&#34;&gt;Clarice Lispector&lt;/a&gt;, a Ukrainian-born Brazilian author with an interesting life story. This is her last novel and is a remarkable book: inventive, funny, and sad, all at once. I found it in a special selection at the local library dedicated to Brazil because of the World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What IS That Noise?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-that-noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-that-noise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently spruced up a post I wrote four years ago about &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-4/&#34;&gt;Biosphere’s wonderful album Substrata&lt;/a&gt;. I added the following footnote about the difference between voice samples and found sound:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guardians of the Galaxy: A Short Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/guardians-of-the-galaxy-fifteen-observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/guardians-of-the-galaxy-fifteen-observations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finally&lt;/em&gt; saw Guardians of the Galaxy today. Here are fifteen observations about the film that may or may not constitute a short review.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Amazing Subversive Revolutionary Adolescence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-amazing-subversive-revolutionary-adolescence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-amazing-subversive-revolutionary-adolescence/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #26: Come On Die Young by Mogwai</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you about punk rock: punk rock is a word used by dilettantes and ah&amp;hellip; and ah&amp;hellip; heartless manipulators about music that takes up the energies and the bodies and the hearts and the souls and the time and the minds of young men who give what they have to it and give everything they have to it and it&amp;rsquo;s a&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s a term that&amp;rsquo;s based on contempt, it&amp;rsquo;s a term that&amp;rsquo;s based on fashion, style, elitism, satanism and everything that&amp;rsquo;s rotten about rock &amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo; roll. I don&amp;rsquo;t know &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/John_Lydon&#34;&gt;Johnny Rotten&lt;/a&gt; but I&amp;rsquo;m sure&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m sure he puts as much blood and sweat into what he does as &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Sigmund_Freud&#34;&gt;Sigmund Freud&lt;/a&gt; did. You see, what sounds to you like a big load of trashy old noise is in fact the brilliant music of a genius, myself . And that music is so powerful that it&amp;rsquo;s quite beyond my control and ah&amp;hellip; when I&amp;rsquo;m in the grips of it I don&amp;rsquo;t feel pleasure and I don&amp;rsquo;t feel pain, either physically or emotionally. Do you understand what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about? Have you ever felt like that? When you just couldn&amp;rsquo;t feel anything and you didn&amp;rsquo;t want to either. You know? Like that? Do you understand what I&amp;rsquo;m saying sir? (Iggy Pop, Canadian TV, March 11th 1977.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whatever Happened To That Hat?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/whatever-happened-to-that-hat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/whatever-happened-to-that-hat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The hat in question is a Wilco baseball cap that I bought at a gig of theirs in 2004, the night that Germany got eliminated from Euro 2004. I&amp;rsquo;d love to show you a picture of it but I can&amp;rsquo;t, there isn&amp;rsquo;t even a picture of it from a Wilco merch site: at least not one that Google or Bing images can see anyway. I did manage to find a side-on picture of it in my bedroom in 2005 and zoom right in on it like they do in CSI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://temporaryresidence.com/artists/watter&#34;&gt;Watter&lt;/a&gt; are a &amp;ldquo;supergroup&amp;rdquo; composed from various members of Grails, &lt;a href=&#34;http://touchandgorecords.com/bands/band.php?id=70&#34;&gt;Slint&lt;/a&gt;, and other bands. I did not know anything about Hundred Waters before this month: &amp;ldquo;The Moon Rang Like A Bell&amp;rdquo; is their second album. In fact second albums by bands I know nothing about are a something of theme because &amp;ldquo;Sunbathing Animal&amp;rdquo; is Parquet Courts&amp;rsquo; sophomore effort and I don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about them either. Meanwhile, I&amp;rsquo;ve meant to write about &amp;ldquo;The Four Seasons Recomposed&amp;rdquo; since April.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, May 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month was strange. I didn’t listen to much new music and after &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/album-digest-april-2014/&#34;&gt;last month’s bumper digest&lt;/a&gt; there’s probably a reason for that. Not to mention that Spotify gives you more reasons to look backwards than forwards. Nevertheless, this brief post features new albums by Little Dragon and Coldplay, along with the mini-album collaboration between Röyskopp and Robyn.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South America, Part 9</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-trip-part-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-trip-part-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a tour full of highlights, Christmas week of 2013 was nonetheless one of the greatest weeks of my life. I may have moaned, groaned, and got completely soaked, but it was worth it to see Machu Picchu in the sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should I Drop Dropbox?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/should-i-drop-dropbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/should-i-drop-dropbox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am thinking about whether I want to use Dropbox to sync my files anymore. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, I love Dropbox. It came along in beta in just 2008 just as I needed it to manage my PhD thesis. In fact I often jokingly claim to having invented it by asking on the MacRumors forums whether a program like it existed  - just a few weeks before its beta rode in to my life like a knight in shining armour. I recognised the need for a service that would synchronise a single directory and its contents between multiple computers using The Power Of The Internet™. I was used to using commands like scp to maintain my static blog on the university&amp;rsquo;s servers and the multiple computers that I authored it from, though in 2008 when I moved back to my parents&amp;rsquo; house to write up my PhD I was frustrated that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t work out how to do the same things when the target was a PC running Windows XP.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, March 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m back in the UK so it’s back to posts about albums each month. This one is a bit different because I didn’t listen to very much new stuff while I was away so not all of the albums are up to date. I had to write about the new album by Liars though because it&amp;rsquo;s awesome and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait to discuss it! Here’s the list of albums:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South America, Part 8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-trip-part-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-trip-part-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Arequipa and Cusco &amp;ndash; the two cities that are the subject of this post &amp;ndash; are probably the two cities in Peru that are most amenable to travellers (though Lima certainly has a lot to offer too). For me they should have been punctuated with a trip to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Colca_Canyon&#34;&gt;Colca canyon&lt;/a&gt;, one of the deepest canyons in the world and twice as deep as the Grand Canyon. Unfortunately, I got really sick on the second day in Arequipa as my attempts at keeping my tummy bug at bay finally failed. (Even so, I didn&amp;rsquo;t actually seek any proper medical help till the second day in Cusco, I was pretty boneheaded about it.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South America, Part 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-trip-part-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-trip-part-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Next up was a piecemeal section of the trip that took in a varied set of sights and helped us get to know the new passengers who joined in Lima. On the first day we took a boat trip out to the Ballestas Islands, a nature reserve that is informally known as “the poor man’s galapagos”. Living there are penguins, sea birds, sea lions and seals. The speed boat out was a little wet and wild (and in fact the return trip was even wetter and wilder) so we all got soaked (twice) but the microclimate around the islands themselves was calm and warm, and we all got good value out of our cameras (if they still worked that is). We even saw a pelican get taken down by a sea-lion which was an interesting if not altogether pleasant display of nature red in tooth and claw. Also, who knew that guano was so valuable?!?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South America, Part 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-trip-part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-trip-part-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From Punta Sal we took a long driving down to Huanchaco, via a stop off at the Lord of Saipan museum. The lord of Saipan is a Moche mummy found dressed in all manner of gold and surrounded by artefacts and other sacrifices (including other humans and decapitated llamas). The tour took a while to get going (our guide was late) but the exhibition was so amazing (the pieces were painstakingly restored in Germany) that it was hugely enjoyable. The diorama at the end featuring moving animatronic waxworks of Moche people was extremely weird though.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
