<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Liars on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/liars/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Liars on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/liars/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #32: They Were Wrong So We Drowned by Liars</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-32/</guid>
      <description>As it is Halloween, I&amp;rsquo;m writing about a spooky understated classic. Liars&amp;rsquo; second album &amp;ldquo;They Were Wrong, So We Drowned&amp;rdquo; is a concept album about witches. It was the first of their albums that I owned having heard their name mentioned among those in the New York Post-punk revival scene at the start of the 00s.&#xA;I imagine that to most ears a first listen to &amp;ldquo;They Were Wrong, So We Drowned&amp;rdquo; sounds dreadful.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, March 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2014/</guid>
      <description>I’m back in the UK so it’s back to posts about albums each month. This one is a bit different because I didn’t listen to very much new stuff while I was away so not all of the albums are up to date. I had to write about the new album by Liars though because it&amp;rsquo;s awesome and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait to discuss it! Here’s the list of albums:&#xA;Tegan and Sarah Heartthrob Fanfarlo Let&amp;rsquo;s Go Extinct Liars Mess London Grammar If You Wait Tegan and Sarah Heartthrob I would argue, as I have throughout my sequence of understated classics posts, that a great album is one that changes you as a person.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2012/</guid>
      <description>Three fantastic albums for Album Digest June 2012:&#xA;Saint Etienne Words and Music by Saint Etienne Liars WIXIW Hot Chip In Our Heads This month is a curious selection in that the albums are all by bands that I already own a few records by. When there is so much other directly related material that you can write about, it makes focussing on the album in hand quite difficult. I am always thinking up rankings and comparisons.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
