<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>October on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/october/</link>
    <description>Recent content in October on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/october/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, October 2017</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-october-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-october-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;mary-epworth-elytral&#34;&gt;Mary Epworth &amp;ldquo;Elytral&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This album came to my attention because its lead single &amp;ldquo;Me Swimming&amp;rdquo; appeared on my Discover Weekly playlist. I&amp;rsquo;d never heard of Mary before but this album was one of those nice discoveries that one sometimes makes when one tries to broaden what one listens to. The aforementioned &amp;ldquo;Me Swimming&amp;rdquo; is probably the best track, a beautiful slice of summery experimental pop layered over a beat that you can imagine as the kicks of a swimmer compared to the swirling lyric that imitates the pull of the strokes through the water. Or the other way round. I was a latecomer to swimming, I&amp;rsquo;m not very good at it. But I do know a good song when I hear one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, October 2013</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-october-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-october-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Four great albums this month for the last album digest in a while.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chvrches-the-bones-of-what-you-believe&#34;&gt;CHVRCHES &amp;ldquo;The Bones Of What You Believe&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I first got into CHVRCHES on Record Store Day, one of my purchases was an Irn Bru coloured 12&amp;quot; of the Recover EP that, according to eBay, tripled in value over night. Judging by this, their full debut, my see-through orange slab of happiness may hold its value, because it&amp;rsquo;s clear that CHVRCHES should be around for the long haul. &amp;ldquo;The Bones Of What You Believe&amp;rdquo; is a master class in upbeat pop songwriting that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to pander to the lowest common denominator.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, October 2012</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-october-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-october-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a strange month and I found that I didn’t listen to a lot of new music. I have been a bit down and when that’s the case I tend to take refuge in music that I know well, stuff that cheers me up. I have listened to last month’s fave a lot, Nelly Furtado’s “The Spirit Indestructible”. I said a lot of nice things about it but it probably didn’t come over in my writing just how much I really liked it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, October 2011</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-october-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-october-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month we have albums by Björk, Coldplay, M83, and Radiohead.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;album-digest-october-2011---intro&#34;&gt;Album Digest October 2011 - Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I listened to Wilco’s &lt;em&gt;The Whole Love&lt;/em&gt; again the other day. I happened to be walking past the venue in Portsmouth where I went to see them live back in 2004 and it seemed the right fit. I really enjoyed the album after a period of not having listened to it and I found that being familiar with the songs allowed me to better appreciate the production of the album. It really is better than I had said last time when I included it in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/2011/09/album-digest-september-2011/&#34;&gt;September Album Digest&lt;/a&gt;, I suppose that it was the danger in writing about music you have only had with you for a few weeks (or days in the case of &lt;em&gt;The Whole Love&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
