<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jekyll on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/jekyll/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jekyll on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/jekyll/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is in my Rakefile? (March 2023 edition)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-in-my-rakefile-march-2023-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-in-my-rakefile-march-2023-edition/</guid>
      <description>Because I am bored of forgetting what&amp;rsquo;s in my website&amp;rsquo;s Rakefile, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write a list. Also, as I&amp;rsquo;m probably going to move over to a node based approach soon, it&amp;rsquo;s a handy wish list for my package.json file when the time comes.&#xA;Make a new post in _posts named &amp;ldquo;Title&amp;rdquo; rake post[&amp;quot;Title&amp;quot;]&#xA;If no title is given, you will be prompted for one. The post will be opened in the editor specified in the Rakefile.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A February Project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/second-february-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/second-february-post/</guid>
      <description>Hmmm it seems as though the ffi gem as installed by bundler is not compatible with a Mac that has an M1 chip. This limits my ability to preview blog posts locally. I might have to swap to a more modern static site generator (which is probably easier than working out what ffi actually does) - seems like a good February project!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sprucing up the Blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sprucing-up-the-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sprucing-up-the-blog/</guid>
      <description>This post explains some of the modifications I made to a minimal Jekyll theme to get this blog as I wanted it. This blog (currently) uses the excellent Sidey theme by Ronalds Vilciņš. His site looks eerily similar to this one, at least at time of writing.&#xA;The theme is pretty minimal in terms of features (and appearance) but it scores well on the Google Page Speed test. The features I added have increased the build time, but have not affected the speed of the site in terms of the page speed test.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
