<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Economics on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Economics on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Living in the Pi Hole</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/living-in-the-pi-hole/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/living-in-the-pi-hole/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ingrid bought me a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.org&#34;&gt;raspberry pi&lt;/a&gt; for my birthday. I&amp;rsquo;ve set it up to run the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.pi-hole.net&#34;&gt;Pi-hole&lt;/a&gt; software. Pi-hole is a nifty bit of kit that intercepts your web requests and purges any that ask for material on known ad servers. Essentially it&amp;rsquo;s like having an ad blocker on your network rather than just your computer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written before about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/net-loss/&#34;&gt;why I hate web advertising&lt;/a&gt;, and since then it&amp;rsquo;s got even more malign. The use of our web browsing habits to track our every move and sell us crap has gotten way worse. Instagram is particularly &lt;em&gt;awful&lt;/em&gt; for it and gets more awful with every amendment that Facebook makes. An ad-blocking solution that works for apps as well as in the browser is especially welcome.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jim&#39;s Conservatory</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/jims-conservatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/jims-conservatory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s assume that Jim has just had a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2008_United_Kingdom_bank_rescue_package&#34;&gt;sudden unexpected expenditure&lt;/a&gt;: a neighbour released a bull into his back garden and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/business/2007/nov/01/creditcrunch.subprimecrisis&#34;&gt;it destroyed his conservatory&lt;/a&gt;. Let&amp;rsquo;s assume that the conservatory is essential to Jim&amp;rsquo;s wellbeing, so it has to be fixed immediately. As a result Jim&amp;rsquo;s debts, which &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/business/2015/may/03/senior-tory-financial-crash-was-purely-a-banking-crisis-not-labour-overspend&#34;&gt;were previously small and well-managed&lt;/a&gt;, have now increased somewhat.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Obviously Jim can&amp;rsquo;t keep that debt hanging over him forever. What does he do?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for Jim, the circumstances of his borrowing aren&amp;rsquo;t so different before and after the event. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/finance/personalfinance/interest-rates/9922941/Interest-rates-predictions-Four-more-years-of-0.5.html&#34;&gt;Interest rates are low and are predicted to stay low&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-21554311&#34;&gt;terms of his credit haven&amp;rsquo;t changed a great deal despite his increased borrowing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Can’t Just Switch Off Free</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/you-cant-just-switch-off-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/you-cant-just-switch-off-free/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2015/mar/11/ministry-of-sound-streaming-switch-off-free&#34;&gt;Ministry of Sound boss Lohan Presencer does the cry baby act in today&amp;rsquo;s Guardian&lt;/a&gt;, complaining that Spotify&amp;rsquo;s freemium model doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow him to bathe in a Scrooge McDuck style swimming pool of golden coins any more. The cat is out of the bag for streaming music now, and no matter how much music companies cry foul they can&amp;rsquo;t stop Spotify and their ilk, and there wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be pots of gold waiting for them even if they could.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Net Loss</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/net-loss/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/net-loss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I pay to have this blog up and running. That is, I pay for the space where it is stored and I pay for the name. I have to look after all the files and plug-ins, I have to perform all the updates and optimise the database tables. All this is great fun but wouldn’t it be cheaper to slap the mattischro.me address onto a hosted WordPress.com account?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, yes it would. I suppose I just like the independence of having my own little patch of cyberspace, sitting there waiting for all you dear readers to come and visit. Nice ideas don’t make the world go round though and so I need a better reason than that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
