<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Time Passing on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/time-passing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Time Passing on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/time-passing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Oh heck it&#39;s June</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/oh-heck-its-june/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/oh-heck-its-june/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;White rabbits and all that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even more than during the pandemic, I&amp;rsquo;m feeling these days like the days, weeks, and months are all blurring into one another. It&amp;rsquo;s getting harder to figure out what year something happened, how the old the cats are, and just how overdue all my promises are. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely getting harder to look at this blog and wonder whether it will ever get back to its heyday of regularly posted updates. It&amp;rsquo;s possible that the continued erosion of various social media sites might make blogs useful, useable, and used again, though popularity of a medium is no guarantee that I will actually use it!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ambitions Revisited</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ambitions-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ambitions-revisited/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in 2012 &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/ambitions&#34;&gt;I wrote a post&lt;/a&gt; listing my ambitions for the future. Well it&amp;rsquo;s the future now isn&amp;rsquo;t it? Almost. After all, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/How-long-does-it-take-for-most-of-the-atoms-in-your-body-to-be-replaced-by-others&#34;&gt;I’m a whole new person now&lt;/a&gt;. Anyway it&amp;rsquo;s probably time to take stock. Have I achieved any of them? Have any of my ambitions changed? What&amp;rsquo;s replaced the things that I&amp;rsquo;ve decided not to worry about? What has come after the things I managed to do?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First off, here&amp;rsquo;s my justification for writing the list in the original post:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five years after</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/five-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/five-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Five years ago I set out at 3am for Heathrow airport to catch the early morning flight to Madrid. There I connected with a flight to Quito in Ecuador. The previous days and weeks had been fraught with worry about whether I was doing the right thing. Did I get the right vaccinations? Would I have enough money? Would I cope with all that travel? Was I coming back? What was I going to do with all my stuff?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Years</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/three-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/three-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three years ago today I moved in to my little flat in Chichester, soon to start a new job. I had no money left but at least, after a character building stint of six months sleeping on the floor, I had a bed. In the intervening three years, my job role has expanded, I&amp;rsquo;ve done another degree, the flat has become a home, and I&amp;rsquo;ve met and married Ingrid. Add to that the fact that it&amp;rsquo;s almost four years since I left for South America and I start to realise that I&amp;rsquo;ve done a crazy amount of things in that time. I don&amp;rsquo;t intend to stop.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year 2015!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/happy-new-year-for-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/happy-new-year-for-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a brief message to wish everyone a happy new year. Getting my flat connected to the internet continues to be a trial so it&amp;rsquo;s still not as easy to post as I would like. However, I have some workarounds now and I hope to write (and post) more often from now on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like everyone I make resolutions at this time of year, though as the years pass I realise that the best resolutions are to apopt a new way of being rather than a new way of doing. I find it quite difficult to &amp;ldquo;change&amp;rdquo; myself by willpower alone. I think this is true of most people. Travelling taught me that it&amp;rsquo;s better to evolve. I just do one little thing differently and then try to notice the benefits as they accrue. As you become are of how you are changing it gets easier and you can shift your focus to doing another little thing a bit differently, a bit better. At least that&amp;rsquo;s the theory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
