<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sixteen on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/sixteen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sixteen on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/sixteen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #34: Stray by Aztec Camera</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-34/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next instalment in my understated classics series is &amp;quot;Stray&amp;quot; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://killermontstreet.net&#34;&gt;Aztec Camera&lt;/a&gt;. Released in 1990, it features two hit singles and the cover is my favourite colour: green.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My angle for writing about “Stray” was that it was an album that I &amp;quot;caught&amp;quot; from my parents. I soon realised that I wrote about some of those already, for example “The Circle and the Square&amp;quot; by Red Box. Besides, I’m not sure that my parents liked this album that much.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mira Schendel at Tate Modern</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/mira-schendel-tate-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/mira-schendel-tate-modern/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2013/sep/29/mira-schendel-tate-modern-review&#34;&gt;Mira Schendel&lt;/a&gt; was a Brazilian artist who was active throughout the middle to late twentieth century. She is considered to be one of South America&amp;rsquo;s best artists. Known mostly for her abstract paintings, she also experimented with sculptures and installations. Many of her works use text and semiotics to explore and define possible meanings for more abstract works.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I saw this exhibition during its run in the Tate Modern in the Autumn of 2013. I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like writing about it at the time. In fact I may not have had any time because it was quite close to my departure for South America.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2016</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-september-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-september-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month&amp;rsquo;s album digest features albums by Wilco, M.I.A., Local Natives, and a collaboration between Kaitlyn Aurelia Smith and Suzanne Ciani.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;wilco-schmilco&#34;&gt;Wilco &lt;em&gt;Schmilco&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Schmilco&lt;/em&gt; is the tenth studio album by Wilco, which regular readers will know are one of my favourite bands. &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/whatever-happened-to-that-hat/&#34;&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no need to repeat that anecdote about why this blog has the name that it does.&lt;/a&gt; Meanwhile, this album follows on from last year&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; and is probably the third Wilco album to have a jokey meta- kind of title. (The other one is the rather splendid &lt;em&gt;Wilco (The Album)&lt;/em&gt; from 2009.) I didn&amp;rsquo;t write a review of &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;; it  was released for free and for some reason it passed me by. &lt;em&gt;Schmilco&lt;/em&gt; is a fairly similar album and that&amp;rsquo;s not a bad thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Threepenny Opera</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/threepenny-opera/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/threepenny-opera/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, Ingrid and I went to see The Threepenny Opera at the National Theatre.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Threepenny Opera was written by Bertolt Brecht and Kurt Weill, based on Elisabeth Hauptmann&amp;rsquo;s German translation of John Gay&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;A Beggar&amp;rsquo;s Opera&amp;rdquo;. It was first performed in Weimar Berlin in 1928 and has evolved over time through many adaptations, including several film and off-Broadway versions. It&amp;rsquo;s a work with very powerful musical overtones and, despite avowals otherwise throughout by the narrator, it has a powerful moral message.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Notebook</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/new-notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/new-notebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Witness the pressure of a new notebook. You sit at your desk, trying to get it started with an amazing piece of writing. Something worthy of that crisp new page. You want it to tumble out of you, fully formed and coherent. Something that justifies you abandoning the previous one. As though first drafts don&amp;rsquo;t exist. You cast yourself into the role of shaman, of seer - of someone gifted a prophetic vision. But it&amp;rsquo;s a role that you cannot and will not fulfil.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Don&#39;t Have a Clue, part 43</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/no-clue-part-43/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/no-clue-part-43/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A little man wearing a bow tie, and possibly a fez, scurries into the middle of the frame clutching a clapboard. Breathing heavily he hoists the clapboard up to chest height. He holds the clapper up then brings down while slurring &amp;quot;This is a blog post about not having a clue, take 43&amp;quot;. He exits to the right of the frame.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My feet are hot. The bed seems too small. Why are my feet always too hot on nights like these? I bet I could sleep if my feet weren&#39;t so hot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2016</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-august-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-august-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post, I allowed Spotify to pick some new albums for me this month. It chose some noodly ambient techno, a captivating slice of World Jazz, a moody gothic hallucination, and a concept album about humans being rescued by aliens. All in all a pretty good job! Here is the list:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prins Thomas &amp;ldquo;Principe del Norte&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sarathy Korwar &amp;ldquo;Day to Day&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Doomsquad &amp;ldquo;Total Time&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;United Vibrations &amp;ldquo;The Myth of the Golden Ratio&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;prins-thomas-principe-del-norte&#34;&gt;Prins Thomas &amp;ldquo;Principe del Norte&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/orb-alpine-diskomiks-sin-in-space-pt-2/&#34;&gt;Prins Thomas recently remixed the Orb&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Alpine EP&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; so I&amp;rsquo;m not surprised that Spotify included one of his tracks on my Discover Weekly playlist. The connection was obviously waiting to be made. &amp;ldquo;Principe del Norte&amp;rdquo; was released back in March and features 9 tracks over almost 90 minutes. Each track title is a single letter, save the first two which are labelled A1 and A2. I think it was B that caught my attention, a proper old school ambient tune but one with some teeth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adventures with Discover Weekly</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/adventures-with-discover-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/adventures-with-discover-weekly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any albums coming out this month that I wanted to review for the album digest, I decided to let Spotify pick the albums to listen to. I listened to my algorithmically chosen &lt;a href=&#34;https://techcrunch.com/2015/07/20/why-browse-when-you-can-play/&#34;&gt;Discover Weekly&lt;/a&gt; playlist one week and selected albums based on the songs that I liked the most. The album also had to be released in 2016. The selections are ones that got away.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve done this before. &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/album-digest-august-2012/&#34;&gt;Three of the four albums that I wrote about in August four years ago&lt;/a&gt; were selected by &lt;a href=&#34;https://bleep.com&#34;&gt;Bleep&lt;/a&gt;: they were in the &amp;lsquo;best albums of the year so far&amp;rsquo; bundle that I bought. So this month&amp;rsquo;s album digest is bought to you by the same idea, just a different curator.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BBC Prom 47 at the Royal Albert Hall</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/bbc-prom-47-royal-albert-hall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/bbc-prom-47-royal-albert-hall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We went to see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ulsterorchestra.org.uk/events/2016-08-21/&#34;&gt;Prom 47&lt;/a&gt;, an afternoon prom at the Royal Albert Hall in London. The bill included a brand new work by &lt;a href=&#34;http://piershellawell.com&#34;&gt;Piers Hellawell&lt;/a&gt;, along with a Cello concerto by &lt;a href=&#34;http://classicalmusic.about.com/od/classicalcomposers/p/haydnprofile.htm&#34;&gt;Haydn&lt;/a&gt; and a symphony by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.britannica.com/biography/Pyotr-Ilyich-Tchaikovsky&#34;&gt;Tchaikovsky&lt;/a&gt;. These were all performed by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ulsterorchestra.org.uk&#34;&gt;Ulster Orchestra&lt;/a&gt;. The conductor was Rafael Payare. The tickets were an affordable £17 each which isn&amp;rsquo;t bad at all given that we were sat in the second row of the circle. We had a great view.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, July 2016</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-july-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-july-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Album Digest July 2016 consists of a bumper five albums, mainly because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t work out which one to drop. I think they&amp;rsquo;re all pretty good though it&amp;rsquo;s great to hear new music from The Avalanches after all this time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;bat-for-lashes-the-bride&#34;&gt;Bat For Lashes &amp;ldquo;The Bride&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For her fourth album as Bat For Lashes, Natasha Khan applies her considerable songwriting skills to a concept album. She sings from the perspective of a bride whose husband dies on his way to their wedding. Almost all artists would deliver this subject matter in a melodramatic way, but Khan focusses on the sadness and delivers a beautiful suite of songs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Richard Beard, Acts of the Assassins</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/acts-of-the-assassins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/acts-of-the-assassins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.waterstones.com/book/acts-of-the-assassins/richard-beard/9780099592938&#34;&gt;Acts of the Assassins&lt;/a&gt; is an interesting novel by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.richardbeard.info&#34;&gt;Richard Beard&lt;/a&gt; that retells the story of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apostle_(Christian)&#34;&gt;the apostles&lt;/a&gt; and their deaths. It uses a modern crime genre style and a contemporary setting. The author himself refers to it as &amp;ldquo;Gospel Noir&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Cassius Gallio, a Roman CSI-type referred to as a speculator, investigates the murders of the apostles following the crucifixion and resurrection of Jesus. Gallio, charged with guarding the body following Jesus&amp;rsquo; death and greatly undermined by the disappearance of the body, views the resurrection as the greatest conspiracy of the age.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #33: Embrya by Maxwell</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-33/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I give the impression of planning these posts but to be honest I came across an article about Maxwell a few weeks ago and fondly remembered my cassette copy of this album. The joy of Spotify is that it&amp;rsquo;s easy to dig up old favourites. The recent warm weather makes for a good opportunity to enjoy the sultry embrace of &amp;ldquo;Embrya&amp;rdquo; once more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Gestation: Mythos&amp;rdquo; burbles along for two and a half minutes, overlaying spoken word samples, string phrases and weird underwater noises, before the bass line of &amp;ldquo;Everwanting: To Want You To Want&amp;rdquo; brings things to life. Over a sinuous and aquatic background, Maxwell delivers a smooth and soulful vocal. As you might guess from the title, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely one for your late nights and warm evenings playlist. I love the way that the song takes its time: it knows where it needs to go, it knows how to get there, and damned if it isn&amp;rsquo;t going to enjoy itself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South America, Part 12</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/south-america-trip-part-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/south-america-trip-part-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;uyuni-to-tupiza&#34;&gt;Uyuni to Tupiza&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We left Uyuni the night after the big storm, having stopped just a day or so to visit the salt flats. Our next stop was a strategic stay in Tupiza, a large town encircled with red hills. It resembled many towns that I visited in South America: low buildings arranged in a grid pattern. Not much greenery and plenty of dust billowing about. The reason for our stay was strategic, it&amp;rsquo;s only a short distance to the notoriously fussy border between Bolivia and Argentina. We would leave at 5am the next morning so we would reach the border early in case of a long delay, which can happen at this border.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Unlimited Dream Company</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-unlimited-dream-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-unlimited-dream-company/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/high-rise/&#34;&gt;I last wrote about a JG Ballard novel nearly three years ago&lt;/a&gt;. That one - &amp;ldquo;High-Rise&amp;rdquo; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/film/2016/mar/20/high-rise-review-ben-wheatley-jg-ballard-tom-hiddleston&#34;&gt;has since been made into a film&lt;/a&gt;. The subject of this post is &amp;ldquo;The Unlimited Dream Company&amp;rdquo;, my favourite among his novels: a silly romp through suburban sexual repression that glitters with sinister wit. Even after many read-throughs I still can&amp;rsquo;t work out whether it is a crazy masterpiece or something light that we&amp;rsquo;re meant to throw away after reading.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swaptastic Part 3: The Shiny App</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/swaptastic-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/swaptastic-part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The shiny app embedded below allows you to explore the number of packets you need to complete the Panini sticker album for this summer&amp;rsquo;s Euro tournament. This builds on the results I presented in an [earlier post](link to earlier post) and allows you to explore how many fewer packets you need to buy when you have more friends to swap with. You can also vary the number of runs performed because the model runs considerably slower with more swappers involved.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2016</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-june-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-june-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Album Digest June 2016 is a poppy batch of albums. We have the return of my long-time favourites Roxette and the heroes of my South American tour Tegan &amp;amp; Sara. There&amp;rsquo;s some dance music in the form of Flume&amp;rsquo;s album &amp;ldquo;Skin&amp;rdquo;: an Australian presence ahead of the new Avalanches album next month. Finally there is the first of two new albums by Islands - both were released back in May but one gets reviewed this month and the other next month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swaptastic Part 2</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/swaptastic-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/swaptastic-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a follow-up to my post about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/euro-2016-panini-stickers/&#34;&gt;Euro 2016 Panini Stickers&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ve now completed the collection with &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/swaptastic-part-1/&#34;&gt;the help of an online swapping site&lt;/a&gt; and by buying the last 39 stickers directly from Panini. I also managed to write a new simulator, this time with additional collectors involved.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I assume that each of N collectors will buy a packet of stickers and add any new stickers to their album. Then they attempt to swap any leftovers with the rest of their friends. The intersect function in R makes this pretty easy to code up. Every collector who finishes the album stops buying stickers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In the space between this and that</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/in-the-space-between-this-and-that/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/in-the-space-between-this-and-that/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Britain voted to leave the EU this week. It made for an angry and confused Friday morning. I posted snippy comments on Facebook at a rate of about one every fifteen minutes. I also knew that there was nothing I could do. Even when you feel like Charlton Heston at the end of &amp;quot;Planet of the Apes&amp;quot;, you have to suck it up and accept that sometimes things don&#39;t go as you like.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swaptastic Part 1</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/swaptastic-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/swaptastic-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/other/StickersInThePost.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Envelopes containing swaps that have arrived in the post in recent days.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Envelopes containing swaps that have arrived in the post in recent days. It is nice to get letters from all over the country, even if they do just contain a selection of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/euro-2016-panini-stickers/&#34;&gt;panini stickers&lt;/a&gt;. As I mentioned in a previous post, I have used &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stickerswapping.com&#34;&gt;the sticker swapping website&lt;/a&gt; to share my swaps with people all over the UK. I have sent swaps off to London, Bristol, Cornwall, Lancashire, Wales, and Gloucester. You&amp;rsquo;ll also be happy to know that I got my hands on an Aleksei Berezutski. Only 52 left to go!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Logitech K380 Review</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/logitech-k380-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/logitech-k380-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Time for a little gear review. This is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.logitech.com/en-us/product/multi-device-keyboard-k380&#34;&gt;Logitech K380 keyboard&lt;/a&gt;. It pairs with devices wirelessly over Bluetooth. I bought it to use with my Apple TV, iPad and iPhone. It runs on 2 AAA batteries, but the supplied batteries are not rechargeable. The keyboard is light and portable but you definitely know you have it in your bag.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s lovely to type on. For a go-anywhere keyboard it has a surprisingly nice feel to the keys. It also gives equal weight to Windows and Mac keys, so it&amp;rsquo;s quite easy to use across both platforms. The only frustration is that the iPad doesn&amp;rsquo;t support keyboards as it should and the iPhone is even worse. I&amp;rsquo;m expecting that to change in iOS 10, which is due to be announced at WWDC next week. Of course, none of this is the fault of the keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Euro 2016 Panini Stickers</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/euro-2016-panini-stickers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/euro-2016-panini-stickers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sound the conspicuous consumption klaxon! 📣 I know it&amp;rsquo;s foolish but I decided to collect the Panini stickers for the Euro 2016 tournament this summer. I think it&amp;rsquo;s a more edifying waste of money than a series of group game accumulators that don&amp;rsquo;t come off. If this week&amp;rsquo;s long read in The Guardian is anything to go by, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/may/31/big-gamble-dangerous-british-betting-shops&#34;&gt;we really shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be giving any more of our money to betting companies&lt;/a&gt;. The album also looks better than any of the official books. Anyway, this post celebrates my inner collector/geek and the beauty of the shiny sticker!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, May 2016</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-may-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-may-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Album Digest May 2016 features the work of four bands or artists that I have reviewed in previous album digests. I also own (or will own) all of these albums on vinyl, so it&amp;rsquo;s handy that I&amp;rsquo;ve recently bought myself a record player!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;radiohead-a-moon-shaped-pool&#34;&gt;Radiohead &amp;ldquo;A Moon Shaped Pool&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Radiohead released &amp;ldquo;A Moon Shaped Pool&amp;rdquo; online about three weeks ago and a physical version hits the shops later in June. As with all of their recent albums, it is (mostly) a slow burner that rewards multiple listens.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Werner Bischof: Point of View and Helvetica</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/werner-bischof-exhibitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/werner-bischof-exhibitions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2016 marks the centenary of the birth of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.magnumphotos.com/C.aspx?VP3=CMS3&amp;amp;VF=MAGO31_9_VForm&amp;amp;ERID=24KL534M5N&#34;&gt;Werner Bischof&lt;/a&gt;, the talented Magnum photojournalist who died in Peru in 1954, aged 38. He travelled widely, making the most of an incredible talent for photography. After the second world war, this led him all over Europe to document its aftermath. As the cold war began, Bischof found himself documenting events further afield.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We saw two exhibitions of his photography at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elysee.ch&#34;&gt;Musée de l&amp;rsquo;Elysée in Lausanne&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;ldquo;Point of View&amp;rdquo; explores his international work spanning the years 1945 to 1954. &amp;ldquo;Helvetica&amp;rdquo; explores his earlier work while isolated from travel in Switzerland during the second world war.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paul McAuley, Something Coming Through</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/something-coming-through-by-paul-mcauley/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/something-coming-through-by-paul-mcauley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Something Coming Through&amp;rdquo; is a science fiction novel set in the near future. A few years after a brief nuclear war known as &amp;ldquo;The Spasm&amp;rdquo;, an alien race known as the Jackaroo introduce themselves to humanity. The novel is funny, thoughtful, and politically charged. I found it to be a good read.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The aliens have given humanity fifteen &amp;ldquo;gift&amp;rdquo; worlds and an automated way to access them. Think of the Docklands Light Railway but with space shuttles. These worlds contain artefacts and remnants from their previous occupants. Movement between the worlds has also changed the Earth: it suffers from incursions by invasive species brought back from the other worlds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, April 2016</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-april-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-april-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month&amp;rsquo;s album digest is a mixture of comparisons. First we compare the fortunes of old hands Underworld to even older hands the Pet Shop Boys. After that I&amp;rsquo;ve found two dance albums, one that I liked and one that I didn&amp;rsquo;t. I find it quite hard to write about dance music and so the comparison is quite useful. Sometimes it helps to work out why you like one thing and not another.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lausanne, Switzerland, March 2016</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/lausanne-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/lausanne-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just before Easter Ingrid and I went to Lausanne in Switzerland for a few days. It was a much-needed break and my first trip out of the UK since I got back from South America.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We caught an early train to Gatwick. It took a strange route along the coast via Worthing and Hove, which was annoying because we could have left later if a more direct train were available at that time of day. At least it wasn&#39;t late, which for Southern is really rare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Orb - Alpine EP</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/orb-alpine-ep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/orb-alpine-ep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Orb return with a new EP on the &lt;a href=&#34;www.kompakt.fm&#34;&gt;Kompakt label&lt;/a&gt; called &amp;ldquo;Alpine&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Alpine&amp;rdquo; is split in to three tracks &amp;ldquo;Morning&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Evening&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Dawn&amp;rdquo;. The third of these was included on the 2016 edition of Kompakt&amp;rsquo;s annual &amp;ldquo;Pop Ambient&amp;rdquo; compilation, a gently drifting track with plenty of bells and yodels. A diversion from the sounds of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/album-digest-june-2015/&#34;&gt;Moonbuilding 2703 AD&lt;/a&gt; (and its presumably ongoing remixed companion EPs), but it sat nicely with the other tracks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, David Bowie RIP</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-special-david-bowie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-special-david-bowie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought I&amp;rsquo;d add three of my favourite David Bowie albums to my review of Blackstar to a form an album digest tribute. Also among my favourites but not included here is &amp;ldquo;Outside&amp;rdquo;, which will be included in the understated classics (currently it&amp;rsquo;s number 66) at some point. I thought about bumping &amp;ldquo;Outside&amp;rdquo; up the running order but I&amp;rsquo;d like to be objective about it when its turn comes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;station-to-station&#34;&gt;Station To Station&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not the side effects of the cocaine / I&amp;rsquo;m thinking it must be love&amp;rdquo; sings Bowie on the title track of his tenth studio album &amp;ldquo;Station To Station&amp;rdquo;, released in 1976. But this album is most definitely almost entirely built on cocaine, from the weird Kabbalah channeling title track, to the smooth funk of &amp;ldquo;Golden Years&amp;rdquo; and on toward to the weepy conclusion of his cover of &amp;ldquo;Wild Is The Wind&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Nutcracker</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-nutcracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-nutcracker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For Ingrid&amp;rsquo;s birthday, we went to see &lt;a href=&#34;http://moscowcityballet.com/en/repertoire/ballet/1&#34;&gt;The Nutcracker performed by the Moscow City Ballet&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;http://kingsportsmouth.co.uk&#34;&gt;The King&amp;rsquo;s Theatre in Southsea&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The original conversation went something along the lines of &amp;ldquo;Matt, please come and see some ballet with me on my birthday! It might not be your thing but I&amp;rsquo;d love someone to come and see it with me&amp;rdquo;. As I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved a bit of Tchaikovsky, I said yes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My only previous encounter with a ballet was an adaptation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_II_(ballet)&#34;&gt;Christopher Marlowe&amp;rsquo;s Edward II by John McCabe&lt;/a&gt; during my English Literature A-level. We got a day trip to exotic Bristol out of it, which when I was 17 meant the chance to visit all the cool record shops looking for rare KLF vinyl that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford. We also got underage hammered at the pub before going to the Hippodrome to watch a ballet in which a man flounced around with a giant pink strap-on on (as if male ballet dancers didn&amp;rsquo;t have enough of that action going on already!). Needless to say, it did little to convert me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
