<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ten on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ten/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ten on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ten/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Programming an UNO game</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/programming-an-uno-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/programming-an-uno-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-new-year-a-new-hobby&#34;&gt;A new year, a new hobby&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don’t write about programming enough. This is a shame because it is a very interesting subject and I find that the problem solving aspects of programming are very satisfying. Keenly aware of the need to do more hobby programming and to get up to speed on areas of software development that I’ve been neglecting, I have decided to give myself the project of creating a computerised version of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uno_(card_game)&#34;&gt;UNO card game&lt;/a&gt;. I know that one already exists, for example there’s an official one that you can play on MSN messenger.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tales From Home</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/tales-from-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/tales-from-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-question-of-identity&#34;&gt;A question of identity&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Three letters for Dad in the mail today, three variations on our surname including the aquatic &lt;em&gt;Dory&lt;/em&gt; version and the lesser-spotted &lt;em&gt;Dorny&lt;/em&gt;. It is perhaps best not to go back to the time he was accidentally listed in the Thompson directory as Mr. Dopey, bringing forth prank calls from all teenagers within a ten mile radius. Fortunately, Dr. Dorey doesn’t have this problem with his mail: he doesn’t get any.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #6: Arbor Bona Arbor Mala by The Shamen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ask anyone into pop music between 1991 and 1993 about The Shamen, and you&amp;rsquo;ll either receive a flood of euphoric good will about excellent tracks like &lt;em&gt;Move Any Mountain&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;LSI&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Phorever People&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;; or they will rant at you about the evils of &lt;em&gt;Ebeneezer Goode&lt;/em&gt;. The Shamen are either one of the pantheon of great acts from early 90&amp;rsquo;s dance and electronic music, or they are a shameless vaudeville novelty act.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Setback</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-setback/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-setback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the run there has been a bit of a hiatus in this blog. I wrote about how running was making me feel better. In fact, I should have said more. I recently stopped taking the antidepressants that I had been taking for eighteen months. This has been my longest period taking such medication but the running made me feel sufficiently good to decide that I could stop taking them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Movember 10K</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/movember-10k/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/movember-10k/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, Saturday. Finally. The big day. Would I a) be able to get to Greenwich in time for the registration? and b) be able to make it all the way around the course without collapsing and crying?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/other/movember01.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Picture of Matt at Movember 10K run 2010&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Happily the answer to both questions was a resounding “Yes!” and I really enjoyed it. The weather was really good, especially compared to the two days before hand, and Marc came along to take some brilliant photos.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #5: A Weekend In The City by Bloc Party</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-weekend-in-the-city-background&#34;&gt;A Weekend In The City: Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the youngest album I have chosen for this series. I try to pick albums that are at least ten years old but every now and then, I will think of an album that matches the sort of things I want to write about. That&amp;rsquo;s the case here. &lt;em&gt;A Weekend in the City&lt;/em&gt; is an unusual album that, in a reversal of the old adage, is “easy to love but hard to admire”. Nevertheless I do love and admire it, and I would like to share my thoughts about it with you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Crystal World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-crystal-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-crystal-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At last, Ballard in full flow. The Crystal World (TCW) is definitely the most enjoyable of the early trio of apocalyptic novels. It takes the successful elements of the first two and embellishes them with new details and ideas. At time of writing, TCW is definitely the best Ballard novel that I have read in its entirety.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #4: Substrata by Biosphere</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I bought this album in the summer between my two years at college. I remember listening to this music under skies glowering with clouds so 1997 must have been a poor summer. I’d just bought a book of photography too, which placed photos from the north and south poles on opposite pages. I bought it mainly for the penguins that were, of course, on pretty much every other page. The pictures of&#xA;snow and ice soon became the ideal companions to this album.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Drought</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-drought/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-drought/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On to The Drought by J. G. Ballard in &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/j-g-ballard/&#34;&gt;my ongoing quest to read and review all of his novels&lt;/a&gt;. This is his second novel, if we assume his convention of never acknowledging “The Wind From Nowhere” as being his first novel. “The Drought” itself was renamed from “The Burning World” and additional content added later on. This was quite common practice in SF in the 50s and 60s where novels were serialised in magazines like &lt;a href=&#34;http://philsp.com/mags/amazing_stories.html&#34;&gt;Amazing SF&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://ttapress.com/interzone/about/&#34;&gt;Interzone&lt;/a&gt;. It is evidence though of Ballard finding his voice as he wrote and from The Drought it is easy to see that he is iterating his thought processes and subject matter with each novel.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“The Drought” is marvellous in a way that “The Drowned World” is not. Here Ballard has cut away much of the ropy science of that novel and left us with a much more realistic scenario of global drought without having to worry about all the outré trappings of giant iguanas and dragonflies the size of your head. Instead, all the magnetic and mesmerising elements of Ballard’s work are beginning to take form: the eccentric recluse with possible sinister intent, the confused and detached protagonist, the ambivalently regarded woman of standing, the encroachment of nature and the human tendency to defile pretty much all it touches, including all that it has constructed and lived alongside.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #3: The Circle &amp; The Square by Red Box</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next entry in the understated classics series is &amp;ldquo;The Circle &amp;amp; The Square&amp;rdquo; by Red Box.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Drowned World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-drowned-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-drowned-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;does-science-fiction-have-to-be-believable-to-be-meaningful&#34;&gt;Does Science Fiction have to be believable to be meaningful?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Should science fiction have predictive power? In plotting the vast unknowns of the future, should authors aim for prescience? Will people be able to say of the best SF novels in five hundred years time that some novels were right about some things and that these novels are better than the ones that didn’t?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I would say no, otherwise we would be remarkably unfair on an awful lot of good writing. That said, I doubt that SF is read for the futurology. As with all literature, SF is at it is best when it has something to say about the world around us now, no matter when it may be set. And if SF has any kind of predictive record, it does better when the psychological issues arising from continued technological development are considered over the mere technology of that advancement. In the long run, a fictional account of space dog Laika (does one exist?) that rings true emotionally will probably endure longer than a pulp novel entitled “Dogs In Space!” (though that is a great title!).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #2: Sinking by The Aloof</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-discovered-the-aloof-while-listening-to-the-top-40&#34;&gt;I discovered The Aloof while listening to the Top 40&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I was younger, I used to listen to the Top 40 every Sunday. To begin with, this was partly an endurance thing and partly an obsession with one day seeing Roxette top the charts - alas, they never did, though for one thrilling spring “Joyride” did flirt with the upper reaches of the chart.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Listening to the charts is probably the best way to become a lover of music. Nearly all my musical loves stem from listening to the top 40 chart, either directly from crouching next to my static-y radio on Sunday evening, or as something that evolving beyond those initial tastes later on. I soon realised that listening to music at the lower end of the chart was more rewarding and not just because this was where all &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Church_of_Your_Heart&#34;&gt;the later Roxette singles ended up&lt;/a&gt;. It was where all the oddities washed in, sometimes there one week and never to be heard again - sometimes growing up into something big. I remember first hearing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.prideofmanchester.com/music/ucc.htm&#34;&gt;“The Key The Secret” by the Urban Cookie Collective&lt;/a&gt; entering the chart at number 40, it eventually climbed to number 2. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/nottingham/content/articles/2004/11/20/entertainment_music_local_bands_kws_feature.shtml&#34;&gt;Also “Please Don’t Go” by KWS which crept all the way up to number 1&lt;/a&gt; - these were great dance records that grew by word of mouth at a time when great dance records were weird and new and meant something.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #1: Together Alone by Crowded House</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week Arcade Fire released their hotly anticipated third album &amp;ldquo;The Suburbs&amp;rdquo;.  I loved &amp;ldquo;Neon Bible&amp;rdquo; but critics found it preachy, as overbearing as the religious folk it sought to satirise. I disagree and think it was an impressive continuation from an exciting debut. &amp;ldquo;The Suburbs&amp;rdquo; steps on from their previous two albums, both in subject matter and tone. It&amp;rsquo;s sad, thoughtful, resigned, angry and tetchy - among other things. “The Suburbs” isn&amp;rsquo;t the understated classic that I want to discuss though: with all the praise and plaudits, it may never suit this new thread of posts. I want to write about &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Together_Alone&#34;&gt;Together Alone by Crowded House&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/j-g-ballard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/j-g-ballard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading &amp;ldquo;Crash&amp;rdquo; at 17 left me in a state of numb shock. It got me hooked and left me with &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/J._G._Ballard&#34;&gt;J. G. Ballard&lt;/a&gt; as one of my favourite authors. I then devoured a short story collection called &amp;ldquo;Myths of the Near Future&amp;rdquo; around the same time. You may recognise it because the Klaxons appropriated the title for their debut album. Those stories captured my imagination, in particular the eponymous story of a world gone to run amid &amp;ldquo;space sickness&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
