<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Everything Everything on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/everything-everything/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Everything Everything on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/everything-everything/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Everything Everything, Get To Heaven</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/everything-everything-get-to-heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/everything-everything-get-to-heaven/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write honestly about your feelings. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write about your feelings consistently, for a living on a regular basis. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write about your feelings when the world constantly intrudes with inanity, insanity and hatred. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write under those conditions without seeming frayed, without coming loose at the edges.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Get To Heaven&amp;rdquo;, the third album by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.everything-everything.co.uk&#34;&gt;Everything Everything&lt;/a&gt;, was forged under these stresses and pressures. For most of its running time it sounds like either a bomb ticking down to explode or like a clock inexorably counting up missed opportunities and stolen moments. It sounds for all the world as though it is trapped between fight and flight, paused between action and apathy. Yet it also subjects the listener to the yammerings of a culture that has driven itself mad. Depth and surface, glass and steel, truth and lies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, January 2013</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-january-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-january-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Only one of this month three albums was actually released this month. Nelly Furtado&amp;rsquo;s Mi plan was actually released over three years ago - I only discovered it last year when I wrote &lt;a href=&#34;album-digest-september-2012&#34;&gt;the September album digest&lt;/a&gt; following the release of &amp;ldquo;The Spirit Indestructible&amp;rdquo;, or it might have been when I wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;uc20&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Folklore&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; at around the same time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I guess these are albums that I bought with my Christmas gift vouchers!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
