<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Aloof on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/the-aloof/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Aloof on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/the-aloof/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #2: Sinking by The Aloof</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-discovered-the-aloof-while-listening-to-the-top-40&#34;&gt;I discovered The Aloof while listening to the Top 40&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I was younger, I used to listen to the Top 40 every Sunday. To begin with, this was partly an endurance thing and partly an obsession with one day seeing Roxette top the charts - alas, they never did, though for one thrilling spring “Joyride” did flirt with the upper reaches of the chart.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Listening to the charts is probably the best way to become a lover of music. Nearly all my musical loves stem from listening to the top 40 chart, either directly from crouching next to my static-y radio on Sunday evening, or as something that evolving beyond those initial tastes later on. I soon realised that listening to music at the lower end of the chart was more rewarding and not just because this was where all &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Church_of_Your_Heart&#34;&gt;the later Roxette singles ended up&lt;/a&gt;. It was where all the oddities washed in, sometimes there one week and never to be heard again - sometimes growing up into something big. I remember first hearing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.prideofmanchester.com/music/ucc.htm&#34;&gt;“The Key The Secret” by the Urban Cookie Collective&lt;/a&gt; entering the chart at number 40, it eventually climbed to number 2. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/nottingham/content/articles/2004/11/20/entertainment_music_local_bands_kws_feature.shtml&#34;&gt;Also “Please Don’t Go” by KWS which crept all the way up to number 1&lt;/a&gt; - these were great dance records that grew by word of mouth at a time when great dance records were weird and new and meant something.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
