<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Albums on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/albums/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Albums on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/albums/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2024 Albums of the Year #10: Yard Act, Where&#39;s My Utopia?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-10-yard-act-utopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-10-yard-act-utopia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yard Act are a post-punk band from Leeds. &amp;ldquo;Where&amp;rsquo;s My Utopia?&amp;rdquo; is their second album. I first encountered Yard Act in a review of this album, which sent me to look at the excellent video to their non-album single &amp;ldquo;The Trenchcoat Museum&amp;rdquo;. I enjoyed the metatextual references both in the video and the song, so I eagerly added &amp;ldquo;Where&amp;rsquo;s My Utopia?&amp;rdquo; to my library.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, the album took a while to win me over. Fourth-wall breaking asides and meta references are fine in a single song, even one as long as &amp;ldquo;The Trenchcoat Museum&amp;rdquo;, but combined over the length of a whole album, it can be a bit off-putting. Nevertheless, WMU? rewards repeat listens (especially on headphones) because it&amp;rsquo;s genuinely funny - I think comedy is an underrated quality in Indie music - and the songs themselves are ace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums: Honourable Mentions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-honourable-mentions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 13:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-honourable-mentions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A quick list of ten other albums I considered to be among the best of last year. I either listened to these less, or in the cases of &amp;ldquo;Transmission Three&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Be Opened By The Wonderful&amp;rdquo; considered them to be ineligible as they are compilations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;yves-tumor-praise-a-lord-who-chews-but-which-does-not-consume-or-simply-hot-between-worlds&#34;&gt;Yves Tumor, &amp;ldquo;Praise a Lord Who Chews but Which Does Not Consume; (Or Simply, Hot Between Worlds)&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Great album, recommended to me by Apple Music slinging the first track into my discovery feed back when that featured was added. Lots of earworms and a really good headphone listen. My top 10 was pretty dance heavy and putting this in might have added a few more guitars. Highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #1: Sofia Kourtesis, Madres</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-01-sofia-kourtesis-madres/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-01-sofia-kourtesis-madres/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/sofia-kourtesis-madres.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Madres by Sofia Kourtesis&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sofia Kourtesis is a Berlin-based Peruvian dance producer, &amp;ldquo;Madres&amp;rdquo; is her debut album which follows on from a 2021 EP &amp;ldquo;Fresia Magdalena&amp;rdquo;. It was trailed by several singles, including the title track which caught my attention back in May. The album is dedicated to her parents and there are also songs dedicated to the surgeon who performed life-saving surgery on Kourtesis’s mother. The whole album is a heady mix of positivity and dedication to both music and to family.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #2: James Holden, Imagine This is a High Dimensional Space of All Possibilities</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-02-james-holden-imagine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-02-james-holden-imagine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/james-holden-imagine.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Imagine This is a High Dimensional Space of All Possibilities by James Holden&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cool artwork! No, we don&amp;rsquo;t have it but it&amp;rsquo;s coming in next week.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cool artwork! We haven&amp;rsquo;t had a copy in but I can order it for you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Me picking it up a week later: &amp;ldquo;Cool artwork!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Imagine This is a High Dimensional Space of All Possibilities&amp;rdquo; is definitely album title of the year, made all the more topical with the intrusion of Chat-GPT and the like into the cultural conversation. Large Language Models (LLMs) like Chat-GPT work by absorbing large amounts of textual data (i.e. this blog, helping to make all those instant album reviews you can write now just a tiny bit more shit) and breaking them down into tokens, with each token having a meaning and a grammatical role and so on. These meanings and roles form higher dimensional spaces in which the tokens are vectors, where the rules of the LLMs help determine which tokens live near to one another and which pairs are likely to sit together in &amp;lsquo;meaningful&amp;rsquo; sentences etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #3: Barry Can&#39;t Swim, When Will We Land?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-03-barry-cant-swim-when-will-we-land/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-03-barry-cant-swim-when-will-we-land/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/barry-cant-swim-when-will-we-land.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of When Will We Land by Barry Can&amp;rsquo;t Swim&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some albums you come to one way: a good review on a blog you respect, a track appearing on a playlist by someone whose taste you trust, etc and so on. And sometimes you get directed to something multiple times. This is what happened to me this year with the irrepressible “When Will We Land?” by Barry Can’t Swim. Anyway, tracks by &amp;ldquo;Barry&amp;rdquo; appeared in mixes a lot this year and the album kept popping up in eagerly anticipated lists.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #4: The National, &#34;First Two Pages of Frankenstein&#34; and &#34;Laugh Track&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-04-the-national-frankenstein-laugh-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-04-the-national-frankenstein-laugh-track/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s probably no surprise that as we reach the top four (or five if you like) we also get to the two albums The National released in 2023. The first, “First Two Pages of Frankenstein”, was trailed with a big reveal early on in the year, while the second, “Laugh Track”, was dropped all of a sudden in October. Once I got to know both albums, I swung between liking each one more for a while, hence putting them both at the same point in the list and not considering each separately.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #5: Nation of Language, Strange Disciple</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-05-nation-of-language-strange-disciple/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-05-nation-of-language-strange-disciple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/nation-of-language-strange-disciple.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Strange Disciple by Nation of Language&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It would be remiss of me to claim that this is a placeholder for any number of (quite different sounding) song based albums that came out this year (Yves Tumor, Wilco to mention two) but it feels that way. This album came high up my list of listens because it&amp;rsquo;s a very good breakfast album, one to listen to while getting the Day started - though there are also some bangers on here too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #6: Grails, Anches en Maat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-06-grails-anches-en-maat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-06-grails-anches-en-maat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/grails-anches-en-maat.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Anches en Maat by Grails&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Grails are one of those bands who always get played a lot at my house. There&amp;rsquo;s something about their slow incremental instrumental pieces that my brain just loves to get lost in. Anches en Maat, their first album in six years or so, and the first with the entire band in the studio together since 2008, is their most Grails-y album in a long time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #7: Maara, The Ancient Truth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-07-maara-ancient-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-07-maara-ancient-truth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/maara-ancient-truth.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of The Ancient Truth by Maara&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There isn&amp;rsquo;t a great deal I can write about The Ancient Truth without sounding vague and anodyne. While I try to come think about different forms of music and go into some analysis of what makes one album more interesting than another, sometimes you end up just saying &amp;ldquo;this album is great because I like it and I always have a good time listening to it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #8: Everything But The Girl, Fuse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-08-ebtg-fuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-08-ebtg-fuse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/ebtg-fuse.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Fuse by Everything But The Girl&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you get older nostalgia becomes an ever important part of listening to music. It often feels like the business relies on convincing an aging population of fans to part with their money on new versions of old material. It&amp;rsquo;s nostalgia, the feeling of recapturing something you loved in your youth, that often makes this acceptable. Of course it&amp;rsquo;s also nice to get &lt;strong&gt;new&lt;/strong&gt; music from your favourite bands, especially when it&amp;rsquo;s as good as &amp;ldquo;Fuse&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #9: Fever Ray, Radical Romantics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-09-fever-ray-radical-romantics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-09-fever-ray-radical-romantics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/fever-ray-radical-romantics.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Radical Romantics by Fever Ray&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Radical Romantics, the third album by Fever Ray was released in April. I bought a copy on red vinyl which is a beautiful sight to behold. I listened to a lot when it was released but eased up a bit until listening to it a couple more times while writing this list. It&amp;rsquo;s a great collection of songs, probably better than their second album &amp;ldquo;Plunge&amp;rdquo;. The cover art is just as scary though.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #10: Wata Igarashi, Agartha</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-10-wata-igarashi-agartha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-10-wata-igarashi-agartha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/wata-igarashi-agartha.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Agartha by Wata Igarashi&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Agartha is the debut album by Japanese electronic artist Wata Igarashi. I don&amp;rsquo;t really know much about him, but I do know that I enjoy releases on the German record label Kompakt and I have really enjoyed Japanese techno in recent years. Over lockdown I discovered Haruomi Hosono&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Polyharmony&amp;rdquo; album and re-discovered the work of Shinichi Atobe, particularly their album &amp;ldquo;Love of Plastic&amp;rdquo;. Both of those albums could be future understated classics and while both are by Japanese artists working in electronic music, there the comparison ends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year Preview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/albums-of-the-year-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/albums-of-the-year-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another year (nearly) over and so starting from tomorrow, I&amp;rsquo;m going to count down my top 10 albums of 2023. The rules are:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;They have to have to have been released in 2023.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;They need to be albums. I&amp;rsquo;m defining this as either more than 7 tracks or songs, or more than forty minutes in length.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To make the top ten, they need to have been played the most times. I admit that I don&amp;rsquo;t have a precise measure of this, as I do still buy vinyl and about four of these albums will have had play counts missed by not being captured through a streaming service.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Compilations are not included, whether they feature multiple artists or a retrospective of a single artist.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s pretty much it. Have I done any prep work? Well no, not really. I made a preliminary list at the start of October and not only was the number one album not out at the time (!) but I also had mistakenly included two albums from 2022. So yeah, this is not a pro operation. 😂&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
