<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recipe on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/recipe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recipe on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/recipe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sticky Toffee Pudding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sticky-toffee-pudding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sticky-toffee-pudding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We had great success with our sticky toffee pudding as a Christmas Day dessert. It&amp;rsquo;s a hybrid of a recipe by Jamie Oliver, one that we found in a gluten free cookbook, and one for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.co.uk/food/recipes/sticky_toffee_pudding_25161&#34;&gt;a make-ahead pudding by the hairy bikers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;pudding&#34;&gt;Pudding&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;200-250g chopped dates&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;200ml boiling water (or tea)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;100g softened unsalted butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon of bicarbonate of soda&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;170g sugar (85g golden caster, 50g light soft brown, 35g dark soft brown)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;170g self-raising flour&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon mixed spice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon ground cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 eggs (room temperature)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;sauce&#34;&gt;Sauce&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;110g unsalted butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;110g sugar (half light soft brown sugar, half dark soft brown sugar)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;140ml double cream&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;method&#34;&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;pudding-1&#34;&gt;Pudding&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soak the chopped dates in the boiling water with the bicarbonate of soda for 30 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mash the dates with a fork.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cream the butter and sugar.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the eggs and flour and spices.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mix the dates in to the batter and spoon into a greased baking dish.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cook for 45 minutes at 180˚C. Check with a skewer and if it comes out with batter on, return to the oven for 5-10 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;sauce-1&#34;&gt;Sauce&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add all the ingredients to a small pan and cook together on a low heat. Stir gently initially.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Make sure you remove the stones from your dates!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We did this as a make-ahead for Christmas day. When we made the sauce at the same time as we made the sponge and poured about a third over the top. We let it all cool before storing in the fridge. We reheated for about 20 minutes at 180˚C and microwaved the sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s very nice (but also incredibly over-indulgent!) served with vanilla ice cream.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The reason for using a mixture of sugars is both for the colour (more dark sugar makes for a more appealing toffee sauce) and for the overall toffee/caramel taste of the pudding. You can change the ratios here to suit your own tastes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a fairly lenient recipe so don&amp;rsquo;t get too hung up on exact quantities.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gluten Free Toad In The Hole</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gluten-free-toad-in-the-hole/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gluten-free-toad-in-the-hole/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tbsp of sunflower oil or other high smoke point oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;60g cornflour&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;60g gluten-free flour&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3 eggs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;pinch of salt (if wanted)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;pinch of sage (if wanted)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;200ml of milk (substitute with non-dairy options if wanted)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Four sausages&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;method&#34;&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preheat an oven to 220C (200C for a fan-assisted oven).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pour some high smoke-point oil into a metal pan (approx one tablespoon), add the sausages and warm for five minutes in the oven while preparing the batter.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mix flour, cornflour and eggs either by hand or with a stand mixer. Beat to a smooth paste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add salt if using. Once the mixture is smooth, start to slowly add the milk while continuing to beat the mixture.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once all the milk has been added, continue to beat the mixture for a further minute or until lightly foaming.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Turn the sausages and return to the oven for two more minutes. In this time add dried herbs to the batter if using. Sage works well. Re-beat the mixture once last time.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the batter to the pan and cook for 25 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Flour ratios can be changed. E.g., you can use 70g/50g cornflour to flour. Don&amp;rsquo;t use more than 125g total for the flours.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You may need slightly more oil if using vegetarian sausages.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In terms of alternative milks, a pea-based milk (e.g. Wunda milk) produces quite an aerated and crispy batter. We&amp;rsquo;ve had less success with things like oat or soy milk.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This batter can also be used for Yorkshire pudding and for pancakes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Try wrapping the sausages in bacon for a tasty (but rather unhealthy treat).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Most recipes prefer lard to oil, but oil is usually fine. Rape seed oil (AKA canola oil) is working well for us at the moment.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four Recipe Book Recommendations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/four-recipe-book-recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 11:39:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/four-recipe-book-recommendations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-a-z-of-cooking-by-felicity-cloake&#34;&gt;The A-Z of Cooking by Felicity Cloake&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book is for more luxurious and experimental recipes. There are 26 chapters, one for an ingredient beginning with each letter of the alphabet, but you probably guessed that already. Ingrid and I have been (very) slowly working our way through the chapters, making a couple of recipes from each one - we’re currently up to G for Garlic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My favourite so far has been the bread dumplings in parmesan broth because it gives us a use for our many many parmesan rinds. Mind you, the red spiced pork belly that we made over Easter has come pretty close.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turkey and Sweet Potato Stew</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/turkey-and-sweet-potato-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/turkey-and-sweet-potato-stew/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a recipe to use up your turkey leftovers after Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will need a slow cooker or an oven-proof cooking dish.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About four portions of cold turkey, torn into bite-sized pieces&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 sweet potato, chopped into small slivers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 carrot, chopped into small slivers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 onion, diced&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 cloves of garlic, diced&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 tsp mixed herbs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 tsp smoked paprika&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;20g butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;50g diced chorizo&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 chicken stock cube mixed in about 700ml water (see method)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;method&#34;&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Melt the butter and fry the onions on a medium heat until golden.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the garlic and fry this mixture for a further thirty seconds.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the diced chorizo and continue to fry, adding a little stock and turning down the heat if things get a little too sticky.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fold in the cold turkey and mix into the onions, garlic and chorizo.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add half of the stock and bring to the boil.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the carrots, the sweet potato and the remainder of the stock.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Transfer to a slow cooker or the oven proof dish. If you&amp;rsquo;re using a slow cooker, you need to make sure liquid covers the contents of the pot.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use the default high setting of your slow cooker, or cook in the oven at 160C for about two hours.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Check on the pot when about 30 minutes of cooking time remains. If you need to thicken the mixture, stir about a tablespoon of cornflour into about 20ml of water and then add this to the pot, stirring it in well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serve with rice and a green vegetable.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beetroot Bolognaise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/beetroot-bolognaise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/beetroot-bolognaise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We cook this version of bolognaise with beetroot due to Ingrid&amp;rsquo;s tomato allergy. This recipe is an attempt to capture what we do on the fly. The key to it is using the wine, the Worcestershire sauce and the herbs to even out the sweetness of the beetroot. If you can manage that, it&amp;rsquo;s super tasty. The sauce usually ends up being an unusual but pleasing pink/purple colour, as you will see from the pictures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Only Chocolate Cake Recipe You’ll Ever Need</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/chocolate-cake-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/chocolate-cake-recipe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/the-reset-button/&#34;&gt;in a previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I baked a chocolate cake the other day and it was a great success. Here is the recipe, which is a trivial modification of one that appears in Nigel Slater&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Real Food&amp;rdquo; (Amazon links: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Real-Food-Nigel-Slater/dp/1841151440/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1382362805&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=nigel+slater+real+food&#34;&gt;UK&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Real-Food-Nigel-Slater/dp/1841151440/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1382362827&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=nigel+slater+real+food&#34;&gt;US&lt;/a&gt;). &amp;ldquo;Real Food&amp;rdquo; is a cookbook that I genuinely treasure. The modification I have made for this recipe is to omit the espresso but I will point out where it should be added, in case you want to give that a try.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
