<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Food on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/food/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Food on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/food/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hot Chocolate Comparison</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/hot-chocolate-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/hot-chocolate-comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a massive fan of hot chocolate. Recently a friend recommended M&amp;amp;S hot chocolate flakes. Thanks to a promotion it was about half the price of the Montezuma&amp;rsquo;s hot chocolate discs that we usually buy. The Montezuma&amp;rsquo;s ones are lush (that&amp;rsquo;s official hot chocolate tasting terminology) but in this economy anything that saves a bit of money has got to be good right?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, there are other things to consider. For one, what&amp;rsquo;s the cost per drink? After reading the instructions for the M&amp;amp;S hot chocolate, it was clear that it might not make as many drinks as the Montezuma&amp;rsquo;s hot chocolate does.  That said, we prefer to use one disc rather than the suggested two,  and sure enough, we also found that we only needed about half the hot chocolate when using the M&amp;amp;S flakes too. Nevertheless you still get 66% more drinks from the Montezuma&amp;rsquo;s hot chocolate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four Recipe Book Recommendations</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/four-recipe-book-recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 11:39:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/four-recipe-book-recommendations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-a-z-of-cooking-by-felicity-cloake&#34;&gt;The A-Z of Cooking by Felicity Cloake&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book is for more luxurious and experimental recipes. There are 26 chapters, one for an ingredient beginning with each letter of the alphabet, but you probably guessed that already. Ingrid and I have been (very) slowly working our way through the chapters, making a couple of recipes from each one - we’re currently up to G for Garlic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My favourite so far has been the bread dumplings in parmesan broth because it gives us a use for our many many parmesan rinds. Mind you, the red spiced pork belly that we made over Easter has come pretty close.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turkey and Sweet Potato Stew</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/turkey-and-sweet-potato-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/turkey-and-sweet-potato-stew/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a recipe to use up your turkey leftovers after Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will need a slow cooker or an oven-proof cooking dish.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About four portions of cold turkey, torn into bite-sized pieces&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 sweet potato, chopped into small slivers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 carrot, chopped into small slivers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 onion, diced&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 cloves of garlic, diced&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 tsp mixed herbs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 tsp smoked paprika&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;20g butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;50g diced chorizo&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 chicken stock cube mixed in about 700ml water (see method)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;method&#34;&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Melt the butter and fry the onions on a medium heat until golden.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the garlic and fry this mixture for a further thirty seconds.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the diced chorizo and continue to fry, adding a little stock and turning down the heat if things get a little too sticky.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fold in the cold turkey and mix into the onions, garlic and chorizo.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add half of the stock and bring to the boil.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the carrots, the sweet potato and the remainder of the stock.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Transfer to a slow cooker or the oven proof dish. If you&amp;rsquo;re using a slow cooker, you need to make sure liquid covers the contents of the pot.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use the default high setting of your slow cooker, or cook in the oven at 160C for about two hours.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Check on the pot when about 30 minutes of cooking time remains. If you need to thicken the mixture, stir about a tablespoon of cornflour into about 20ml of water and then add this to the pot, stirring it in well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serve with rice and a green vegetable.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beetroot Bolognaise</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/beetroot-bolognaise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/beetroot-bolognaise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We cook this version of bolognaise with beetroot due to Ingrid&amp;rsquo;s tomato allergy. This recipe is an attempt to capture what we do on the fly. The key to it is using the wine, the Worcestershire sauce and the herbs to even out the sweetness of the beetroot. If you can manage that, it&amp;rsquo;s super tasty. The sauce usually ends up being an unusual but pleasing pink/purple colour, as you will see from the pictures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On The Humble Cheese Grater</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/humble-cheese-grater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/humble-cheese-grater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t beat a good cheese grater. Cheese just tastes better in a sandwich once it has been grated. It&amp;rsquo;s been proven by ACTUAL SCIENCE that this is the case: something about the increased surface area making it taste more zingy (NB. QI is not actually a peer-reviewed scientific journal). Of course the cheese we are grating here is a nice mature cheddar, you can&amp;rsquo;t grate Camembert or Stilton (well &lt;em&gt;technically&lt;/em&gt; you can, but why would you?). There are even cheeses that can be grated but don&amp;rsquo;t deserve it, take Red Leicester for example: the ear wax of the cheese world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
