<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pop on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/pop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pop on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/pop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Peter Gabriel, So</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/peter-gabriel-so/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/peter-gabriel-so/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently watched the entry about Peter Gabriel&amp;rsquo;s 1986 album &amp;ldquo;So&amp;rdquo; in the Classic Albums series on Amazon Prime. It was an entertaining way to fill an evening hour.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I absolutely love &amp;ldquo;So&amp;rdquo;. I came to its songs via the &amp;ldquo;Secret World Live&amp;rdquo; album, and it was &amp;ldquo;Red Rain&amp;rdquo; specifically that convinced me of his greatness. Previously, I&amp;rsquo;d been aware of &amp;ldquo;Sledgehammer&amp;rdquo; (also on this album) and &amp;ldquo;Steam&amp;rdquo; (from the similarly titled &amp;ldquo;Us&amp;rdquo;), but &amp;ldquo;Red Rain&amp;rdquo; really captured my imagination.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charlie XCX, Brat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/charlie-xcx-brat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/charlie-xcx-brat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When making my albums of the year posts at the start of the month, I realised that compared to many other critics lists, there was no sign of &lt;em&gt;Brat&lt;/em&gt; by Charlie XCX. And when it came up again on my album shuffle the other day, I  thought I should re-evaluate the album and whether it should have made my list.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Listening to &lt;em&gt;Brat&lt;/em&gt; again for this post, it was clear that I&amp;rsquo;d missed out on something special. This was partly because I went for a walk with it on my headphones and that always lets me hear the details of the music. I think too many times when this album came on at home, it would be a little bit too doof-doof to be background music. These are songs that do demand (and deserve) a bit of attention.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ian MacDonald, Revolution in the Head</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ian-macdonald-revolution-in-the-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ian-macdonald-revolution-in-the-head/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ian MacDonald&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Revolution in the Head&amp;rdquo; is a book that I&amp;rsquo;ve read parts of dozens of times and even all the way through once or twice. I picked it up again today and thought I would write about it. It&amp;rsquo;s a detailed analysis of every Beatles song ever released, along with the details and events of their recording. I own a copy of the second edition which was updated to include the anthology material. Today you can still get hold of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.waterstones.com/book/revolution-in-the-head/ian-macdonald/9780099526797&#34;&gt;a 3rd edition on the Waterstones website&lt;/a&gt; (not sure that I like the new cover though).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Albums of the Year #3: Acopia, Acopia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-03-acopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-03-acopia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Acopia are a band from Melbourne Australia with that time honoured line up of one girl and two guys. This eponymous album is their second and it&amp;rsquo;s full of slinky electronic ballads that echo classic 90s trip hop. It&amp;rsquo;s got that same downtempo downbeat vibe, the sorts of songs that revel in sadness but also the joy of a killer bass line.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This album was actually released in November 2023 but I first heard it in January 2024 after reading a glowing review of it. I can remember the first time listening to it, I took the train to see my parents in to hand over a present I&amp;rsquo;d bought for my nephew. (Fittingly, it&amp;rsquo;s his birthday today.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Albums of the Year #8: Pet Shop Boys Nonetheless</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-08-pet-shop-boys-nonetheless/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-08-pet-shop-boys-nonetheless/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless is the fifteenth album by the Pet Shop Boys. As seems to be a common theme with this top 10 so far, it&amp;rsquo;s an album that initially underwhelmed me. Well, perhaps &amp;ldquo;underwhelmed&amp;rdquo; is a little unfair, it was more that it didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to have much to it to distinguish it from their previous albums, and there have been some palpable duds in the previous fourteen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, this album is definitely a grower. As I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten to know some of the songs, I&amp;rsquo;ve come to appreciate the little details strewn throughout. For example, the lovely little rave riff that breaks into the bridge on &amp;ldquo;Loneliness&amp;rdquo;, something that turns a potentially stern song into something a lot more fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ellie Goulding - Bright Lights</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ellie-goulding-bright-lights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ellie-goulding-bright-lights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So today &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/how-random-should-things-be/&#34;&gt;my random album script&lt;/a&gt; picked out &amp;ldquo;Bright Lights&amp;rdquo; by Ellie Goulding, an album I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure I&amp;rsquo;ve ever listened to. I looked in my music library and there it was! As a result this is not so much an &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tag/album%20revisit/&#34;&gt;album revisit&lt;/a&gt; as an album _&lt;em&gt;visit&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this album was released in 2010 and did quite well. In fact, &amp;ldquo;Bright Lights&amp;rdquo; is a reissue of an album that was originally released as &amp;ldquo;Lights&amp;rdquo; (February 2010). This version adds seven extra tracks, which explains why it&amp;rsquo;s an exhausting seventeen tracks long. &amp;ldquo;Lights&amp;rdquo; was a successful debut and a few of the singles went top 20, which is what led to its re-release with all those extra songs in November of the same year. (I think this is why it is in my collection, I think I bought it for my mum or for a sibling as part of a Christmas present, and ripped the CD out of curiosity&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics Or Not?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-or-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-or-not/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the new year, thoughts and spare time for writing point me toward writing some new posts for my understated classics series. Expect some new ones soon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I also reflected on my previous choices and thought a bit about how my music tastes have changed recently. Some of this has to do with streaming and the frustrations I wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/a-pox-on-both-their-houses&#34;&gt;in my last post&lt;/a&gt;. Some of it is just down to getting older: I have less time to listen to new music, and much of the &amp;rsquo;new&amp;rsquo; stuff I listen to is me investigating the stuff I missed first time around. Who knew Art of Noise were so good? Not me, but I do now!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #34: Stray by Aztec Camera</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-34/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next instalment in my understated classics series is &amp;quot;Stray&amp;quot; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://killermontstreet.net&#34;&gt;Aztec Camera&lt;/a&gt;. Released in 1990, it features two hit singles and the cover is my favourite colour: green.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My angle for writing about “Stray” was that it was an album that I &amp;quot;caught&amp;quot; from my parents. I soon realised that I wrote about some of those already, for example “The Circle and the Square&amp;quot; by Red Box. Besides, I’m not sure that my parents liked this album that much.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #33: Embrya by Maxwell</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-33/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I give the impression of planning these posts but to be honest I came across an article about Maxwell a few weeks ago and fondly remembered my cassette copy of this album. The joy of Spotify is that it&amp;rsquo;s easy to dig up old favourites. The recent warm weather makes for a good opportunity to enjoy the sultry embrace of &amp;ldquo;Embrya&amp;rdquo; once more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Gestation: Mythos&amp;rdquo; burbles along for two and a half minutes, overlaying spoken word samples, string phrases and weird underwater noises, before the bass line of &amp;ldquo;Everwanting: To Want You To Want&amp;rdquo; brings things to life. Over a sinuous and aquatic background, Maxwell delivers a smooth and soulful vocal. As you might guess from the title, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely one for your late nights and warm evenings playlist. I love the way that the song takes its time: it knows where it needs to go, it knows how to get there, and damned if it isn&amp;rsquo;t going to enjoy itself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #31: The White Room by The KLF</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-31/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This little masterpiece was released in 1991. I got my copy on cassette for Christmas that year, but by May in 1992 they&amp;rsquo;d already &amp;ldquo;retired&amp;rdquo; and split up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The KLF were a band in the right place at the right time with the right idea. Taking advantage of synthesizers and the idea of fusing rock and pop music with the emerging sound of house music, they laid the ground for many of the most successful electronic acts that followed them. They were also master showmen, taking a whole host of crazy conspiracy theories and smooshing them together in one stadium-sized package.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #20: Folklore by Nelly Furtado</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s rather spooky but shortly after deciding to write about Nelly Furtado’s “Folklore” as the next &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;understated classic&lt;/a&gt;, I found out that she has a new album out this week. As a result, I have been listening to a lot of her music while writing this post, and I’ve been enjoying it too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As always with these choices of mine, “Folklore” is a record that I can link to particular events and emotions in my life and so I guess my perception of it is coloured by that. Nevertheless while re-listening to the album I tried to examine whether my feelings for it were &lt;em&gt;entirely&lt;/em&gt; centred on those memories and emotional responses. I think the answer is not a simple one, because in recent weeks I’ve felt very unsettled in many aspects of my life and so I probably have found it difficult to tell.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #19: The Dreaming by Kate Bush</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“I see the people working and see it working for them.” (&lt;em&gt;Sat In Your Lap&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Dreaming by Kate Bush is a strange 1982 album that many believed had destroyed her career. Two weeks before her first ever performance of “Running Up That Hill”, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nme.com/blog/index.php?blog=10&amp;amp;title=on_this_day_kate_bush_releases_hounds_of_1986&amp;amp;more=1&amp;amp;c=1&amp;amp;tb=1&amp;amp;pb=1&#34;&gt;the NME had written an editorial asking whether she had burnt herself out completely&lt;/a&gt;. Obviously “Running Up That Hill” (recently used to great effect in the Olympic Closing Ceremony) and the parent album “The Hounds Of Love” that followed showed that she had plenty more up her sleeve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #15: Début by Björk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got into Début via a cassette from the library, much like I did with &lt;a href=&#34;uc1&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Together Alone&lt;/em&gt; by Crowded House&lt;/a&gt;. I suppose it is less obscure than many of my choices for &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;this strand&lt;/a&gt; but I do think that &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; is more well-known (because of &lt;em&gt;It’s Oh So Quiet&lt;/em&gt;, which we shall mention here only briefly) and that &lt;em&gt;Homogenic&lt;/em&gt; is probably more popular among her fans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I really like about &lt;em&gt;Début&lt;/em&gt; though, as much as the album itself, is the panoply of remixes and alternative versions that surround the release. In this way &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; is at least as strong if not stronger and you might recall that I had similar fun &lt;a href=&#34;uc13&#34;&gt;when writing about the Orb’s album U.F.Orb a while back&lt;/a&gt;. As a result of this, there will be some detours into the remixes and live versions when discussing this album. In particular, I will mention the remix collection &lt;em&gt;the best mixes from the album début for all the people who don’t buy white labels&lt;/em&gt; and the recording of an MTV Unplugged show that is available in the &lt;em&gt;Live Box&lt;/em&gt; box set.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #12: Look Sharp! by Roxette</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;happy-birthday&#34;&gt;Happy Birthday!&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No matter how intellectual one gets about these things, the primary function of music is to have fun. With this in mind it is a good time to turn to Roxette then, as they are almost always the epitome of fun.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I received &lt;em&gt;Look Sharp!&lt;/em&gt; as a present for my ninth birthday. This was probably a bit young to fully understand all the emotions expressed on the record. It’s just as well that it is also crammed with the kind of pop confections that made &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_Bore_Us,_Get_to_the_Chorus!&#34;&gt;“Don’t bore us, get to the chorus!”&lt;/a&gt; something of a band motto and made for a great introduction to the world of pop for a nine year old boy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #9: Tiger Bay by Saint Etienne</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tiger Bay&lt;/em&gt; is Saint Etienne&amp;rsquo;s third album and I think it is among their best. It was released in June 1994 on Heavenly records. I first owned a copy in 1998 when I picked it up while living in halls as an undergraduate. The reason for including this album in the understated classics series is the same as for &lt;a href=&#34;uc8&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Second Light&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Dreadzone: it marries traditional forms to newer electronic music&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Second Light&lt;/em&gt; melds classical music and sea shanties to house and dub reggae to evoke the rolling hills and mystic caves of England. &lt;em&gt;Tiger Bay&lt;/em&gt; grafts folk structures on to Balearic pop songs and electronic experiments in order to visit motorway verges, windswept seashores, and Mediterranean holidays. There is even a ghost story (&lt;em&gt;Boy Scouts of America&lt;/em&gt;) for good measure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #3: The Circle &amp; The Square by Red Box</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next entry in the understated classics series is &amp;ldquo;The Circle &amp;amp; The Square&amp;rdquo; by Red Box.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #1: Together Alone by Crowded House</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week Arcade Fire released their hotly anticipated third album &amp;ldquo;The Suburbs&amp;rdquo;.  I loved &amp;ldquo;Neon Bible&amp;rdquo; but critics found it preachy, as overbearing as the religious folk it sought to satirise. I disagree and think it was an impressive continuation from an exciting debut. &amp;ldquo;The Suburbs&amp;rdquo; steps on from their previous two albums, both in subject matter and tone. It&amp;rsquo;s sad, thoughtful, resigned, angry and tetchy - among other things. “The Suburbs” isn&amp;rsquo;t the understated classic that I want to discuss though: with all the praise and plaudits, it may never suit this new thread of posts. I want to write about &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Together_Alone&#34;&gt;Together Alone by Crowded House&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
