<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Personal Development Environment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/personal-development-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/personal-development-environment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to settle on a text editor, IDE, and terminal for a long time now. Partly I&amp;rsquo;m limited by what I can use at work because I owe to myself and my colleagues to be able to reproduce all my skills in a work setting. However, part of me has also wandered off a bit after reading about the idea of a &amp;ldquo;personal Development Environment&amp;rdquo; (or PDE I guess, though in a former life that &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Partial_differential_equation&#34;&gt;meant something very different&lt;/a&gt;), which is essentially an application where you can do anything and have it configured exactly how you like. Here&amp;rsquo;s an update on my progress on that front:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post Statistics, Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-statistics-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/post-statistics-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are some more stats about the blog after I ran out of time yesterday due to&#xA;data cleaning! This time I&amp;rsquo;ve taken the date of each post and extracted the&#xA;month and year. Then I added the number of posts in each month and the number of&#xA;words written. I had to left join on the complete time span between August 2010&#xA;and February 2025, filling in any NA values for the zeros that were missing&#xA;before I did that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slots and Pipes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/slots-and-pipes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/slots-and-pipes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recent explorations in R have reminded me about two ways of thinking about how you refer to objects or (parts of objects) in the language.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Little Lesson in R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-little-lesson-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-little-lesson-in-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had to compute an indicator this week. It had confidence intervals that relied on taking 100,000 samples from the indicator&amp;rsquo;s approximate distribution. I had to repeat this over multiple GP practices and for twelve different demographic groups.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal ggplot tips and tweaks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/personal-ggplot-tips-and-tweaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/personal-ggplot-tips-and-tweaks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love making plots in R with &lt;code&gt;ggplot&lt;/code&gt;. However, there are always a few niggles that I forget about between plots. I wrote this post so that I have somewhere to look the next time I need to tweak a few things in my plots. I intend to come back and add updates in the future as I learn more things. If I keep coming back, I might also remember a few of these too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swaptastic Part 3: The Shiny App</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/swaptastic-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/swaptastic-part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The shiny app embedded below allows you to explore the number of packets you need to complete the Panini sticker album for this summer&amp;rsquo;s Euro tournament. This builds on the results I presented in an [earlier post](link to earlier post) and allows you to explore how many fewer packets you need to buy when you have more friends to swap with. You can also vary the number of runs performed because the model runs considerably slower with more swappers involved.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swaptastic Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/swaptastic-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/swaptastic-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a follow-up to my post about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/euro-2016-panini-stickers/&#34;&gt;Euro 2016 Panini Stickers&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ve now completed the collection with &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/swaptastic-part-1/&#34;&gt;the help of an online swapping site&lt;/a&gt; and by buying the last 39 stickers directly from Panini. I also managed to write a new simulator, this time with additional collectors involved.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to generate random numbers in R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/generate-random-numbers-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/generate-random-numbers-in-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post deals with how to generate random numbers in R. It is good to know how to generate random numbers with a particular language or software package for at least one of the following three reasons:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
