<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Twenty One on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/twenty-one/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Twenty One on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/twenty-one/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A pox on both their houses</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-pox-on-both-their-houses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-pox-on-both-their-houses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How hard is it to just listen to music these days?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spotify has crammed in all sorts of crap in to the app lately. Lyric videos, those weird interactive art things that are turned on by default, podcasts (so many podcasts), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22798338/spotify-netflix-hub-exclusive-audio-extras&#34;&gt;Netflix tie-ins&lt;/a&gt;, and audiobooks. It wants to be the app that opens when you plug in your headphones (not that we’ll be doing that for much longer the way things are going). But I just want to listen to music!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If anything, make it weirder</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/make-it-weird/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/make-it-weird/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I listened to &amp;lsquo;Cloudbusting&amp;rsquo; by Kate Bush for the first time in a while. What a gloriously strange song it is. Best of all, it&amp;rsquo;s one of those songs that obscures what it is really about. It&amp;rsquo;s not a song about a change in the weather, but about &lt;a href=&#34;https://wilhelmreichmuseum.org/about/biography-of-wilhelm-reich/&#34;&gt;Wilhelm Reich&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Orgone&#34;&gt;orgone&lt;/a&gt; accumulator, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cultofweird.com/medical/radium-girls/&#34;&gt;fluorescent yo-yos&lt;/a&gt;, and a son (rather than a &lt;em&gt;sun&lt;/em&gt;) coming out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Cloudbusting&amp;rsquo; is from &amp;lsquo;Hounds of Love&amp;rsquo;, Kate&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;comeback&amp;rsquo; album following the commercial failure of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/understated-classics-19&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;The Dreaming&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;, an album I wrote about in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/tag/understated%20classics/&#34;&gt;understated classics series&lt;/a&gt;. It features four UK top 10 singles and some of her best work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jab 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/jab-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/jab-two/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was due to have my second vaccination today, but like most people I rebooked to have it a bit earlier. No real side effects this time, save for a bit of malaise. Though that may have just been the thought of opening up the country when cases are still increasing quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It goes without saying that I&amp;rsquo;d urge everyone to get vaccinated and then to keep turning up for whatever boosters the people protecting us (e.g. JCVI, &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the government) recommend in future. It seems like we aren&amp;rsquo;t out of the woods yet, though the vaccination program appears to have had a decent impact on hospitalisation rates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rachel Cusk, Outline</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rachel-cusk-outline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rachel-cusk-outline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Outline&lt;/em&gt; is the first of a trilogy of novels by Rachel Cusk. In it, the narrator is travelling to Athens to help teach on a creative writing class. You could describe the rest of what happens in a couple of sentences. I won&amp;rsquo;t be doing so because first, that&amp;rsquo;s spoilers, and I don&amp;rsquo;t do spoilers; second, &lt;em&gt;Outline&lt;/em&gt; is one of those novels where what happens doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter quite so much as how it all happens.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #38: Trance Nation (Various Artists)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-38/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-38/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, but lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been in need of some music that:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Blots out the outside world&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Helps me to concentrate on my work&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Makes me feel a bit less anxious about the state of the world&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, allow me to submit the compilation Trance Nation for your consideration as an understated classic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But Matt I&amp;rsquo;ve heard trance music, I hear you say, and it&amp;rsquo;s one of the least understated forms of music possible. Yes, dear reader, we &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; talking about that borderline obnoxious musical form with the thudding beats and the tinkly high synth lines. Indeed, it is a genre that has grown and eaten itself, and the rest of pop music along with it. The &amp;ldquo;give it a drop or go home&amp;rdquo; mentality that infects modern pop musics originates in Trance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jab 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/jab-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/jab-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had my first Covid-19 vaccination on Friday. Leading up to it, I was borderline having a panic attack. From about lunchtime I was just all over the shop (the jab was at 7pm). I&amp;rsquo;m glad that the vaccination centres run with such exactitude, but also with a sense of cheeriness. By the time I&amp;rsquo;d had the jab, I was feeling much better just from the sheer relief of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drawing a line on the page</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/drawing-a-line-on-the-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/drawing-a-line-on-the-page/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ingrid has joined an online drawing class. She sits there on Teams getting feedback on her drawings, while I sit there attempting to absorb everything. I&amp;rsquo;m also learning by doing, by making a line on the page. In some ways, it&amp;rsquo;s instructive to observe the difference in what we learn with and without the feedback.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We bought some drawing materials and nice notepads. But to be honest, I still haven&amp;rsquo;t made room in my day to draw regularly. This is a shame because you do have do these things regularly in order to develop the skill.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I was twenty one at the time…</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/murakami-quote/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/murakami-quote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I was twenty-one at the time, about to turn twenty-two. No prospect of graduating soon, and yet no reason to quit school. Caught in the most curiously depressing circumstances. For months I’d been stuck, unable to take one step in any new direction. The world kept moving on; I alone was at a standstill. In the autumn, everything took a desolate cast, the colors swiftly fading before my eyes. The sunlight, the smell of the grass, the faintest patter of rain, everything got on my nerves. How many times did I dream of catching a train at night?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Haruki Murakami || A Wild Sheep Chase&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Tips For Saving Time</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/some-tips-for-saving-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/some-tips-for-saving-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A non-exhaustive list of ideas for saving time:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delete your social media&lt;/strong&gt;, and perhaps any other website or app that demands that you consume it rather than create with it.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Another way to think of it: all these sites and apps transform your time in to one thing or another, what are the most valuable products of that time? In general, Facebook products are designed to transform your time into greater awareness of companies who would like you or your friends to buy their products. (Or neo-nazis, depending on whether the day ends in a Y.)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Possible exclusions are apps or websites for reading, you have to make the calculation of whether you get more out than you are putting in. Reading books in general are better value than websites or apps, but some online media can also be a net gain.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You could also try scheduling times for using apps, particularly if need them to communicate (e.g. catching up with people on WhatsApp) or if they are a good source of ideas (e.g. Twitter is quite good for finding interesting new ways of doing things in R).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Note that scheduling is a great way of dealing with procrastination. You can warm your brain up and wind it down at certain points of the day by scheduling your interactions with various apps, websites, and people. Try paying attention to what you do in a given day and shaping that into a schedule.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Procrastination is best managed rather than avoided, so it&amp;rsquo;s better to schedule it. Be honest with yourself, do you need to procrastinate before you do things (like a run up to a jump?) or would you be better saying to yourself &amp;ldquo;I have to get X done today, but I need to leave 10 minutes to catch up on xkcd later on&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sometimes changing your sources to something more curated is useful. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently signed up to the London Review of Books. Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s a bit fusty and old-fashioned but it&amp;rsquo;s well written and expands on a wide variety of topics.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get a bike&lt;/strong&gt; (this is on my to do list!). A bike increases the distances you can travel in a short space of time, and can reduce the time it takes to do short distance chores like shopping. It has the added benefit of being better for the planet than a car and better for your body than walking or doing nothing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Borrow code from other people to get started on programming tasks.&lt;/strong&gt; I usually Google how to do a thing, once I have mapped out a rough spine of what I need to. (I find this mapping out step acts as a filter for the solutions provided to you, a sort of intuition for what the solution &lt;em&gt;should be&lt;/em&gt;) The same is true when you&amp;rsquo;re learning to do anything: be an apprentice, find someone who is good at a thing and learn from them. This is actually easy for anyone to do, and easier than you might first think.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;**Learn to communicate more effectively. **This is one that I feel I need to work on. I often feel that I am going backwards and forwards between people, whether it is trying to understand what other people want or communicating to others what it is that I want.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;One tip that gets bandied about is to record yourself speaking to people. It can be very cringy, but the trick is to be a critical friend to yourself while listening back. Just because you know it&amp;rsquo;s you, that&amp;rsquo;s no reason to judge harshly - just focus on what&amp;rsquo;s being said and how, and work from there.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I also know that I need to ask more questions. It feels weird to say that because I regard myself as being on a personal quest to find out all of the stuff. The problem is that I&amp;rsquo;m also keen on sounding like I already know all the stuff. Can you tell this from my blog posts at all?!? Sometimes it can feel like asking a whole bunch of questions undermines that world view. I now consciously try to ask more questions in support of my quest.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Also a memo to myself for later: IT DOESN&amp;rsquo;T HURT TO EDIT YOUR WRITING FROM TIME TO TIME.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Learn orthogonal skills. By which I mean, if you are a scientist try to find complementary subjects in the humanities and the arts. I&amp;rsquo;ve said &amp;ldquo;orthogonal&amp;rdquo; here to sound clever and to indicate that the connection to your chosen vocation isn&amp;rsquo;t going to be obvious, but really I just mean that it&amp;rsquo;s different and you might eventually apply it.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How does it save you time if you &lt;em&gt;spend&lt;/em&gt; time looking for connections? Well, if you find your connection, you have extra tools to use. If you fail, you may discover something else in the process.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Learn keyboard shortcuts.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;By way of a corollary, the more keyboard shortcuts you learn for an app the more you will do with an app, and the more you will use it. If there&amp;rsquo;s no shortcut for something that you do regularly, make one. If you don&amp;rsquo;t like a provided shortcut, or it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to you, change it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Second corollary. Keyboard shortcuts are a great way to learn how to memorise things. It&amp;rsquo;s low stakes but incremental, if you learn N shortcuts, you can learn N+1.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write stuff down.&lt;/strong&gt; And perhaps just as importantly &lt;strong&gt;have a strategy for coming back to things later&lt;/strong&gt;. The commandment that &lt;em&gt;thou shalt forego thy social networks&lt;/em&gt; at the top of this list is really a double headed command to use intentionality and self-control in order to sanitise your information inputs, and this is a friendly reminder that the time saved can be used to revisit and reinforce those inputs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get enough sleep.&lt;/strong&gt; I am so bad at this. I have been meaning to read &amp;ldquo;Why We Sleep&amp;rdquo; for over a year but I am too scared to learn what my terrible sleeping habits are doing to me. That said, I do tend to do better when I am following some of these other tips - especially the ones about acting with intentionality and self-control.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Again, this is another spend time (on sleeping) to save time (sluggishly prodding work tasks while waiting for the coffee or tea to kick in) later.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This could probably do with its own post of do as I say not as I do advice.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m loathe to say what the right amount of sleep is. You know when you&amp;rsquo;ve had enough. And it varies, which makes it hard to plan around. It always feels like I need two hours after the alarm clock!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think framing sleep around quotes like &amp;ldquo;studies show most people need 4/6/8/14 hours a night&amp;rdquo; is helpful, as in my experience the more I fret the worse I do and the feeling of divergence from nature tends to increase my fretfulness.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Related: &lt;strong&gt;Get enough exercise&lt;/strong&gt; - I am working on this.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get a second/third/Nth monitor&lt;/strong&gt;. I have recently done this and the jury&amp;rsquo;s still out for me. If I&amp;rsquo;m honest I just use the biggest monitor available. I&amp;rsquo;ve still included it on the list because most people won&amp;rsquo;t buy a &lt;em&gt;smaller&lt;/em&gt; monitor than the one they have. I find that seeing more means doing more and concentrating better. When I grow up I hope to have more interesting anecdotes about how I used a multiple monitor setup, but I&amp;rsquo;m still pretty green.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Forever Now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-forever-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-forever-now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing this post came about from  frustration with blogging. Specifically the tools I am using. Often it feels like a new language or paradigm comes along that shifts one or two of the pain points of blogging. The biggest are:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How long it takes to get a post on the internet once you’ve written it&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The reliability of the resulting website&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How good the resulting website looks&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note that none of this really impacts the quality of the writing. I’m not claiming to be a good writer: in fact I spend so much time blogging or thinking about blogging because it is my writing practice. (I think I am getting better, but slowly).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amal El-Mohtar &amp; Max Gladstone, This Is How You Lose the Time War</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/this-is-how-you-lose-the-time-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/this-is-how-you-lose-the-time-war/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Is How You Lose the Time War is a short novella about two members of opposing factions (Red and Blue) engaged in a &amp;rsquo;time war’: that is they travel in time and attempt to erase each other&amp;rsquo;s existence. Except that one day Red decides to taunt Blue with a letter, and a correspondence emerges.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The book is entertaining by virtue of wit and brevity. However, the elements that are skipped over that end up being more interesting to reflect on later. Clearly these are two talented writers bouncing ideas off one another, but you get a  sense that this whole fictional universe might have developed into something more. I was more interested in individual episodes than in the correspondence and its results. Perhaps the writers have ended up constrained by their witty idea.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Italo Calvino, If on a Winter&#39;s Night a Traveller</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/italo-calvino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/italo-calvino/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I started to write a review of Italo Calvino&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;If on a Winter&amp;rsquo;s Night a Traveller&amp;rdquo;. I read it while we were in Germany for Christmas. We&amp;rsquo;d visited Bremen and also undergone the bizarreness of Christmas in another language - the same motifs played out in different words and different customs. I&amp;rsquo;d tried to write the review in a similar structure to the book but, in a testament to Calvino&amp;rsquo;s writing I couldn&amp;rsquo;t pull it off. Here&amp;rsquo;s the opening paragraph:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Richard Powers, Orfeo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/richard-powers-orfeo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/richard-powers-orfeo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The mind may give up its desire to improve on creation and function as a faithful receiver of experience.&amp;rdquo; John Cage&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After enjoying &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/the-overstory/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Overstory&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I wanted to read more of Richard Powers&amp;rsquo; novels. &lt;em&gt;Orfeo&lt;/em&gt;  was also long listed for the Booker prize. Perhaps more of his novels would have been had the prize been opened to American authors earlier.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Orfeo&lt;/em&gt; is about Peter Els, a seventy year old composer who accidentally alerts Homeland Security to the existence of his home laboratory, in which he has been trying to recode the genetic material of a bacterium to include a piece of his music. He ends up on the run, which provides the catalyst for a narrative in which we ponders the past and returns to it. Woven throughout is a history of contemporary classical music, most real and some invented.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
