<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lists on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/lists/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lists on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/lists/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Albums 2017</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/top-10-albums-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/top-10-albums-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-grails-chalice-hymnal&#34;&gt;10. Grails &amp;ldquo;Chalice Hymnal&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some albums are good because a band continues making the music that you love. Some albums are good because a band takes their ideas a step or two further than before. Chalice Hymnal is that rare album that does both of these things.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The references to past albums include the track Deeper Politics and Deep Snow II, and, as per albums past, these tracks evolve slowly out of languid guitar hooks and smoky atmospherics. If it ain’t broke don’t fix it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Songs 2017</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/top-10-songs-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/top-10-songs-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-rolling-blackouts-cf-julies-place&#34;&gt;10. Rolling Blackouts CF &amp;ldquo;Julie&amp;rsquo;s Place&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you just want a simple pop song about going out somewhere. I enjoyed the Rolling Blackouts&amp;rsquo; EP &amp;ldquo;The French Press&amp;rdquo;. It contains many catchy tunes &lt;a href=&#34;album-digest-march-2017&#34;&gt;as I noted in my review&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;ldquo;Julie&amp;rsquo;s Place&amp;rdquo; is the best, speaking of a need to be somewhere or a promise that you will go there. Given that I often listen to music between places, it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have a song or two like that on my playlist.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guardians of the Galaxy: A Short Review</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/guardians-of-the-galaxy-fifteen-observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/guardians-of-the-galaxy-fifteen-observations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finally&lt;/em&gt; saw Guardians of the Galaxy today. Here are fifteen observations about the film that may or may not constitute a short review.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;At least two Oscars for &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.comicbook.com/uploads1/2014/07/guardians-of-the-galaxy-gamora-101682-101718.jpg&#34;&gt;Best Use Of Body Paint (Green)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://images.radiotimes.com/namedimage/Karen_Gillan_takes_on_Zoe_Saldana_in_extended_Guardians_of_the_Galaxy_trailer.jpg?quality=85&amp;amp;mode=crop&amp;amp;width=620&amp;amp;height=374&amp;amp;404=tv&amp;amp;url=https://mattischrome.com/uploads/images/original/53103.jpg&#34;&gt;Best Use Of Body Paint (Blue)&lt;/a&gt; are sewn up.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chris Pratt basically plays Star Lord as “&lt;a href=&#34;http://parksandrecreation.wikia.com/wiki/Andy_Dwyer&#34;&gt;Andy Dwyer&lt;/a&gt; in space” and this is fine by me.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Best movie to feature &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.etonline.com/movies/148845_bradley_cooper_explains_his_voice_guardians_of_the_galaxy/&#34;&gt;a talking raccoon&lt;/a&gt; in a long time.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://screenrant.com/thor-2-dark-world-mid-post-credits-button-scenes-explained&#34;&gt;Watching the entirety of the end credits of Thor 2&lt;/a&gt; paid off!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;“&lt;em&gt;WE&lt;/em&gt; are &lt;a href=&#34;https://uk.yahoo.com/movies/dancing-baby-groot-clip-guardians-of-the-galaxy-94738291414.html&#34;&gt;Groot&lt;/a&gt;” — aren’t we just?! All of the feels.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It features a dance off as a major event, something that it shares with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Step_Up_(film_series)&#34;&gt;Step Up movies&lt;/a&gt;. Guardians of the Galaxy is a waaaay better movie.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The first words of the credits are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mtv.com/news/1887915/guardians-of-the-galaxy-sequel/&#34;&gt;“The Guardians of the Galaxy will return”&lt;/a&gt;. It is in fact a movie that reviews itself.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The 3D version might have been pretty good. I watched the 2D version but &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cinemablend.com/new/Guardians-Galaxy-Has-Something-Special-Planned-Its-IMAX-3D-43350.html&#34;&gt;the scenes with lots of action &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; be improved with a bit of depth&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/culture/film/film-news/11033572/Guardians-of-the-Galaxy-Awesome-Mix-soundtrack-tops-Billboard-chart.html&#34;&gt;A great soundtrack&lt;/a&gt;, but there is a cheesy “smooth rock wins chicks” bit that’s a little icky half way through.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;That said, the description of the legend of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0087277/&#34;&gt;Footloose&lt;/a&gt; is hilarious. Especially the callback toward the end of the movie.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I especially enjoyed the scene with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slashfilm.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-easter-eggs-quotes/&#34;&gt;the Collector&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Karen Gillen is wasted as Nebula, but &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cinemablend.com/new/Nebula-Return-Guardians-Galaxy-2-66648.html&#34;&gt;hopefully she will be back&lt;/a&gt;. Karen’s also in what may well be &lt;a href=&#34;http://abc.go.com/shows/selfie&#34;&gt;one of the most ill-conceived TV shows of all time&lt;/a&gt; later this autumn.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I thought it was Bruce Willis playing &lt;a href=&#34;http://whatculture.com/wwe/batista-praised-role-guardians-galaxy-movie.php&#34;&gt;Drax the Destroyer&lt;/a&gt; (I’m useless at this guess the actor game). I loved his taking things literally: “Nothing goes over my head. My reflexes are too fast, I would catch it.”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you text me at any point in the next month, I will probably reply with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nerdist.com/2014/08/translate-any-website-into-groot-speak-with-this-nifty-new-button/&#34;&gt;“I am Groot”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;No Raccoons or tree creatures were harmed during the making of this film.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ideas for TV shows: Great Mathematicians</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/ideas-for-tv-shows-great-mathematicians/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/ideas-for-tv-shows-great-mathematicians/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to see a TV show about great mathematicians of the past on a channel like BBC Four. Programmes about mathematics tend to be rather condescending, at least to anyone who has a bit of mathematical knowledge. Perhaps a way around this is to delve into the social and historical circumstances of the great mathematicians and how that along with their personality produced the mathematical results for which they are famous.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ambitions</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/ambitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/ambitions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, when I am feeling a bit down, I like to write down some of my ambitions. As you can see from this list they are mostly pretty humble but they are also a bit cheesy and embarassing, so I have put them after the fold!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Be wholehearted, cheerful, and sincere&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Be creative&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Look at the world and see its many faces, hear its many voices&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Explore new recipes as often as possible when I cook&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Learn to like the taste of tomatoes and cucumbers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Be more at ease around people&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Listen to people and hear what they say&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Play my part&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Look after someone special&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Become a parent&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Share my values with others, help those who need it&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Break up all the negative things inside me&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Know what other people want, help them get it&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When I wake up each morning I would like to remember my dreams&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Understand art more than I do&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lose my fear of creepy crawlies&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Learn to drive&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Learn to write left handed (why not?)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Visit every country in Europe&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Visit the radio telescopes on Mauna Kea in Hawaii&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Let go of unnecessary things&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ditch social networks and the rest of the internet as much as possible&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Learn to appreciate the noise around me&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meditate&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Get over my reliance on sugar to improve my mood&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Get rid of things I don’t need&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grow the garden&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Write people letters&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Learn the differences between species of trees&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Be flexible and adaptable and positive about the future&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Learn how to hang a picture on a wall&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nonlinear Systems: A Rough Intro</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/nonlinear-systems-a-rough-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/nonlinear-systems-a-rough-intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is another mathematics post that does not actually feature any equations or graphs. It is intended to set the way clear for writing regularly about nonlinear systems. This in itself is a precursor to writing more about mathematical biology as biological systems are inherently complex and nonlinear. I am reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Nonlinear-Systems-Cambridge-Applied-Mathematics/dp/0521406684/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1349212296&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;P. G. Drazin’s textbook on Nonlinear Systems&lt;/a&gt; and this post is a glossary of terms from the start of the book laid down here because I wanted to remember how to typeset &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com/tags/tag_dl.asp&#34;&gt;definition lists&lt;/a&gt; in Markdown (though in the end I (ab)used &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;h4&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags because it looked better).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Case For Yellow As Your New Favourite Colour</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/a-case-for-yellow-as-your-new-favourite-colour/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/a-case-for-yellow-as-your-new-favourite-colour/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is about the films of Wes Anderson. I am no expert, I’ve just watched them all recently (inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;moonrise-kingdom-a-short-review&#34;&gt;seeing “Moonrise Kingdom”&lt;/a&gt;) and spotted a some similarities and differences between the films and I thought it would be fun to write about them. My appearance on Mastermind with “The Films of Wes Anderson” as my specialist subject will have to wait for now. Feel free to add to the discussion in the comments. In case you don’t know what the films are, here they are in order (with links to their IMDB pages):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another Reading List</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/another-reading-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/another-reading-list/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/other/June-2012-Bookstack.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;More books to add to the “University of life” course list&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More books to add to the “University of life” course list. From top to bottom: I picked up “Generation X” for 50p in a charity shop in Tintagel. “Everything Is Going To Be OK” is a picture book full of inspirational mottos. “The Happiness Hypothesis” is the most useful and interesting book that I have read in a long while. I decided to read “How To Write A Sentence” as an alternative to Strunk and White’s “The Elements Of Style” which, while useful, can be a little stuffy! “The Marriage Plot” is a novel with interesting reviews, it was also (ahem) well-priced. After love I decided to go after music as something else I wanted to read about, hence “The Music Instinct” which comes highly recommended. “The Gifts Of Imperfection” is a manifesto for embracing life in a wholehearted way. And “Gonzo”? Well, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/gonzo-a-graphic-biography-of-hunter-s-thompson/&#34;&gt;I have written about that one already&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading list, mid-April 2012</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/reading-list-mid-april-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/reading-list-mid-april-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/other/April-2012-Bookstack.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A hefty reading list that should keep me occupied into the summer.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A hefty reading list that should keep me occupied into the summer. A friend on facebook asked “What course is that for?”, to which I replied “It’s for one of the modules I am doing at the university of life.” This response was quite popular.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five lessons from a year of blogging</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/five-lessons-from-a-year-of-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/five-lessons-from-a-year-of-blogging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have now been writing decent length articles on this site for about a year. I have learned a lot in this time, mostly about writing but also how to express your feelings and how to marshal your ideas and passions into action. For this month’s “five on the fifth”, I would like to share  with you some of the things I have learned.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing posts consistently is hard…&lt;/strong&gt; There are a lot of things that get in the way of regular posting. Sometimes it is ambition undermines me, I have ideas for posts that are easy to think up that turn out to be much harder to actually write. Other times life does just get in the way, it is  a time-consuming activity to write five hundred or more words every day. I like to write posts out longhand before typing them up. I often find mistakes or horrible phrasing when I do this and often what seemed like a simple matter of typing something up becomes a bit of a mission. Of course, there are times when I am just lazy or uninspired.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…except when it is easy.&lt;/strong&gt; I discovered early on that having a few arcs through the posts was a good idea as it makes you think a few in advance about what to do next. I prefer to be a generalist but it is nice to have the movie reviews, the &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;understated classics&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;j-g-ballard&#34;&gt;JG Ballard&lt;/a&gt; novels to fall back on. Truth be told I am a little bored of Ballard now but even if I retire that particular strand of posts (Spoiler: Don’t worry, &lt;em&gt;High-Rise&lt;/em&gt; is on the way soon) I can always resume it later. Meanwhile, I can pad out the off days with some quotes or some photos.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easier to read is easier to write.&lt;/strong&gt; I hope that the blog is easier to read now than when I started. I still find myself producing the odd clunky phrase now and then but the number of passive sentences is decreasing. The unexpected benefit of this has been that I find it easier to check earlier posts in search for inspiration about what to write next. Early on, I would often end up editing old posts into something more comprehensible instead of writing new material. The “After the Deadline” feature of &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/jetpack/&#34;&gt;Jetpack for WordPress&lt;/a&gt; has been very helpful in training me to write better.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WordPress is a lot of fun.&lt;/strong&gt; The statistic is that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wordpress.org/&#34;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; now powers about 500 million websites. It is not hard to see why, it is easy to install, easy to customise to suit to your tastes and most of all, it rewards you for continuing to produce content. I have installed all sorts of plug-ins, including a &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/wp-word-count/&#34;&gt;word count plug-in&lt;/a&gt; that tells me that I have (up to this post) written a total of 89,032 published words. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Length_of_a_novel&#34;&gt;If Wikipedia is to be believed&lt;/a&gt;, that is about the length of a pretty long novel. At least now I know I could write a novel in a year even if it was a rather surreal one featuring a 10K run, spiders and an Apatosaurus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I still have a lot more to do, a lot more to learn.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2017-update&#34;&gt;2017 Update&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adding to this footnote some years later (2017) I realise that not all blog posts are permanent. Sometimes you write what you need to at the time and then take it down later. We don&amp;rsquo;t have to be permanently changed by what we once wrote on a Wednesday afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Love The Jungle Book</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/why-i-love-the-jungle-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/why-i-love-the-jungle-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just as with the &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;understated classics&lt;/a&gt; I want to set out my stall early on that good movies are good enough. Both &lt;a href=&#34;why-i-love-betty-blue&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Betty Blue&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and today’s choice &lt;em&gt;The Jungle Book&lt;/em&gt; are never going to win any sort of consensus prize for the best movies ever made but they are really good. They also have a personal history attached that makes them worth writing about.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I was younger both my sisters would be given VHS copies of Disney movies at a rate of about two a year, one for Christmas and one at their birthday. It seems strange today to think of that pace of movie acquisition, never mind the clunky VHS cassettes and how they would warp over time. I didn’t really ever get any of the Disney movies myself but I would inevitably find myself watching them with my sisters who would watch them repeatedly. With just four TV channels back then, who could blame us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Superheroes We Can Live Without</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/five-superheroes-we-can-live-without/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/five-superheroes-we-can-live-without/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The other day while writing some rather self-pitying notes in my blog book (yes, I handwrite all this rubbish before I go to bed at night!) I came up with some useless superheroes, or rather the only superheroes that a washed-up guy in his early thirties could hope to be. Because I haven’t got any ideas for “five things on the fifth” this month, I decided to flesh out a few of these. Last month I began the five on the fifth meme with &lt;a href=&#34;five-things-to-try-when-you-cant-sleep&#34;&gt;five things to try if you can’t sleep&lt;/a&gt; and so this is a rather forced attempt to keep it going. I promise that I will try and think of more interesting posts on these lines for months.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Love Betty Blue</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/why-i-love-betty-blue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/why-i-love-betty-blue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I saw &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0090563/&#34;&gt;Betty Blue&lt;/a&gt; (original French title &lt;em&gt;37,2 Le Matin&lt;/em&gt;) for the first time in 1996 shortly after having read the book and it remains one of my favourite films to this day. Although there are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.co.uk/images?hl=en&amp;amp;source=hp&amp;amp;biw=1427&amp;amp;bih=1022&amp;amp;q=b%C3%A9atrice+dalle+betty+blue&amp;amp;gbv=2&amp;amp;aq=f&amp;amp;aqi=&amp;amp;oq=&amp;amp;uss=1&#34;&gt;many obvious reasons why&lt;/a&gt; a sixteen year old boy might like it, I think it does stand up to scrutiny beyond the sex and nudity. This post is a brief explanation of some of the obvious and not-so-obvious reasons why this is a film to be loved and cherished. (It was quite interesting to write this defence of a sexy film!)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
