<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Twenty Three on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/twenty-three/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Twenty Three on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 13:35:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/twenty-three/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums: Honourable Mentions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-honourable-mentions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 13:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-honourable-mentions/</guid>
      <description>A quick list of ten other albums I considered to be among the best of last year. I either listened to these less, or in the cases of &amp;ldquo;Transmission Three&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Be Opened By The Wonderful&amp;rdquo; considered them to be ineligible as they are compilations.&#xA;Yves Tumor, &amp;ldquo;Praise a Lord Who Chews but Which Does Not Consume; (Or Simply, Hot Between Worlds)&amp;rdquo; Great album, recommended to me by Apple Music slinging the first track into my discovery feed back when that featured was added.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #1: Sofia Kourtesis, Madres</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-01-sofia-kourtesis-madres/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-01-sofia-kourtesis-madres/</guid>
      <description>Sofia Kourtesis is a Berlin-based Peruvian dance producer, &amp;ldquo;Madres&amp;rdquo; is her debut album which follows on from a 2021 EP &amp;ldquo;Fresia Magdalena&amp;rdquo;. It was trailed by several singles, including the title track which caught my attention back in May. The album is dedicated to her parents and there are also songs dedicated to the surgeon who performed life-saving surgery on Kourtesis’s mother. The whole album is a heady mix of positivity and dedication to both music and to family.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #2: James Holden, Imagine This is a High Dimensional Space of All Possibilities</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-02-james-holden-imagine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-02-james-holden-imagine/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Cool artwork! No, we don&amp;rsquo;t have it but it&amp;rsquo;s coming in next week.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Cool artwork! We haven&amp;rsquo;t had a copy in but I can order it for you.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Me picking it up a week later: &amp;ldquo;Cool artwork!&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Imagine This is a High Dimensional Space of All Possibilities&amp;rdquo; is definitely album title of the year, made all the more topical with the intrusion of Chat-GPT and the like into the cultural conversation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #3: Barry Can&#39;t Swim, When Will We Land?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-03-barry-cant-swim-when-will-we-land/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-03-barry-cant-swim-when-will-we-land/</guid>
      <description>Some albums you come to one way: a good review on a blog you respect, a track appearing on a playlist by someone whose taste you trust, etc and so on. And sometimes you get directed to something multiple times. This is what happened to me this year with the irrepressible “When Will We Land?” by Barry Can’t Swim. Anyway, tracks by &amp;ldquo;Barry&amp;rdquo; appeared in mixes a lot this year and the album kept popping up in eagerly anticipated lists.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #4: The National, &#34;First Two Pages of Frankenstein&#34; and &#34;Laugh Track&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-04-the-national-frankenstein-laugh-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-04-the-national-frankenstein-laugh-track/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s probably no surprise that as we reach the top four (or five if you like) we also get to the two albums The National released in 2023. The first, “First Two Pages of Frankenstein”, was trailed with a big reveal early on in the year, while the second, “Laugh Track”, was dropped all of a sudden in October. Once I got to know both albums, I swung between liking each one more for a while, hence putting them both at the same point in the list and not considering each separately.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #5: Nation of Language, Strange Disciple</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-05-nation-of-language-strange-disciple/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-05-nation-of-language-strange-disciple/</guid>
      <description>It would be remiss of me to claim that this is a placeholder for any number of (quite different sounding) song based albums that came out this year (Yves Tumor, Wilco to mention two) but it feels that way. This album came high up my list of listens because it&amp;rsquo;s a very good breakfast album, one to listen to while getting the Day started - though there are also some bangers on here too.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #6: Grails, Anches en Maat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-06-grails-anches-en-maat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-06-grails-anches-en-maat/</guid>
      <description>Grails are one of those bands who always get played a lot at my house. There&amp;rsquo;s something about their slow incremental instrumental pieces that my brain just loves to get lost in. Anches en Maat, their first album in six years or so, and the first with the entire band in the studio together since 2008, is their most Grails-y album in a long time.&#xA;On their last album Chalice Hymnal there were a lot of references to various band members&amp;rsquo; side projects like Watter and Lilacs &amp;amp; Champagne, along with continuations of pieces from earlier albums like Deep Politics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #7: Maara, The Ancient Truth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-07-maara-ancient-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-07-maara-ancient-truth/</guid>
      <description>There isn&amp;rsquo;t a great deal I can write about The Ancient Truth without sounding vague and anodyne. While I try to come think about different forms of music and go into some analysis of what makes one album more interesting than another, sometimes you end up just saying &amp;ldquo;this album is great because I like it and I always have a good time listening to it.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;The album has a late nineties early naughties kind of feel, all skittering breakbeats and chilly pads, but it also features a modern chill out vibe perhaps in keeping with recent reappraisals of music by artists like Enya.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #8: Everything But The Girl, Fuse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-08-ebtg-fuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-08-ebtg-fuse/</guid>
      <description>As you get older nostalgia becomes an ever important part of listening to music. It often feels like the business relies on convincing an aging population of fans to part with their money on new versions of old material. It&amp;rsquo;s nostalgia, the feeling of recapturing something you loved in your youth, that often makes this acceptable. Of course it&amp;rsquo;s also nice to get new music from your favourite bands, especially when it&amp;rsquo;s as good as &amp;ldquo;Fuse&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #9: Fever Ray, Radical Romantics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-09-fever-ray-radical-romantics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-09-fever-ray-radical-romantics/</guid>
      <description>Radical Romantics, the third album by Fever Ray was released in April. I bought a copy on red vinyl which is a beautiful sight to behold. I listened to a lot when it was released but eased up a bit until listening to it a couple more times while writing this list. It&amp;rsquo;s a great collection of songs, probably better than their second album &amp;ldquo;Plunge&amp;rdquo;. The cover art is just as scary though.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #10: Wata Igarashi, Agartha</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-10-wata-igarashi-agartha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-10-wata-igarashi-agartha/</guid>
      <description>Agartha is the debut album by Japanese electronic artist Wata Igarashi. I don&amp;rsquo;t really know much about him, but I do know that I enjoy releases on the German record label Kompakt and I have really enjoyed Japanese techno in recent years. Over lockdown I discovered Haruomi Hosono&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Polyharmony&amp;rdquo; album and re-discovered the work of Shinichi Atobe, particularly their album &amp;ldquo;Love of Plastic&amp;rdquo;. Both of those albums could be future understated classics and while both are by Japanese artists working in electronic music, there the comparison ends.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year Preview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/albums-of-the-year-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/albums-of-the-year-preview/</guid>
      <description>Another year (nearly) over and so starting from tomorrow, I&amp;rsquo;m going to count down my top 10 albums of 2023. The rules are:&#xA;They have to have to have been released in 2023. They need to be albums. I&amp;rsquo;m defining this as either more than 7 tracks or songs, or more than forty minutes in length. To make the top ten, they need to have been played the most times. I admit that I don&amp;rsquo;t have a precise measure of this, as I do still buy vinyl and about four of these albums will have had play counts missed by not being captured through a streaming service.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Civ Leaders #4: Qin Shi Huang (Mandate of Heaven) of China</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/civ-leaders-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/civ-leaders-4/</guid>
      <description>Well, it&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I wrote my last Civ VI leader post about Amanitore of Nubia and there&amp;rsquo;s been a whole host of new leaders and personas added to the game since then. Among these the number of Chinese leaders has increased from two to five. Therefore it&amp;rsquo;s probably a good time to start writing about one of them, and where better to start than the OG himself, Qin Shi Huang.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On learning new tools</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-learning-new-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-learning-new-tools/</guid>
      <description>It strikes me that it is better to sit and think about what you need to do, rather than endless try out new tools and hoping you end up with a use for them. I&amp;rsquo;m not saying that innovation is bad, or that you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t stretch yourself into some new spot once in a while, but you will become more valuable to others if you can identify what it is you are supposed to be doing and then use your existing skills to get that job done.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ellie Goulding - Bright Lights</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ellie-goulding-bright-lights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ellie-goulding-bright-lights/</guid>
      <description>So today my random album script picked out &amp;ldquo;Bright Lights&amp;rdquo; by Ellie Goulding, an album I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure I&amp;rsquo;ve ever listened to. I looked in my music library and there it was! As a result this is not so much an album revisit as an album _visit.&#xA;Anyway, this album was released in 2010 and did quite well. In fact, &amp;ldquo;Bright Lights&amp;rdquo; is a reissue of an album that was originally released as &amp;ldquo;Lights&amp;rdquo; (February 2010).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hot Chocolate Comparison</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hot-chocolate-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hot-chocolate-comparison/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a massive fan of hot chocolate. Recently a friend recommended M&amp;amp;S hot chocolate flakes. Thanks to a promotion it was about half the price of the Montezuma&amp;rsquo;s hot chocolate discs that we usually buy. The Montezuma&amp;rsquo;s ones are lush (that&amp;rsquo;s official hot chocolate tasting terminology) but in this economy anything that saves a bit of money has got to be good right?&#xA;However, there are other things to consider. For one, what&amp;rsquo;s the cost per drink?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabric 44 by John Tejada</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fabric-44-by-john-tejada/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fabric-44-by-john-tejada/</guid>
      <description>This is one of my more played Fabric mix CDs so I decided to go for it when my random prompter plumped for this earlier today. One constraint of these posts was to write it in roughly the amount of time it takes to listen to it. You&amp;rsquo;d think that for a mix CD that would be ok. After all, this mix is a full CD and 74 minutes long.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How random should things be?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-random-should-things-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-random-should-things-be/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to extract my music library, including all the albums I&amp;rsquo;ve added to streaming, as a CSV file and write a routine in R to select an album at random. The plan is to write about that album for the blog in roughly the time that it takes to listen to that album all the way through. I already did this yesterday for Goldfrapp&amp;rsquo;s Black Cherry.&#xA;But I have to level with you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goldfrapp - Black Cherry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/goldfrapp-black-cherry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/goldfrapp-black-cherry/</guid>
      <description>This is the first in an unplanned series of album revisits, I will write a post explaining the process soon.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Black Cherry&amp;rdquo; is the second album by Goldfrapp, released in 2003. I bought the lead single Train while I lived in York and also the single of the title track because by then I&amp;rsquo;d discovered M83 and they&amp;rsquo;d done a remix of it.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Black Cherry&amp;rdquo; finds the band faced with following their successful and chilled out debut album &amp;ldquo;Felt Mountain&amp;rdquo;, which back in 2000 had sounded notably weird.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oh heck it&#39;s June</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/oh-heck-its-june/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/oh-heck-its-june/</guid>
      <description>White rabbits and all that.&#xA;Even more than during the pandemic, I&amp;rsquo;m feeling these days like the days, weeks, and months are all blurring into one another. It&amp;rsquo;s getting harder to figure out what year something happened, how the old the cats are, and just how overdue all my promises are. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely getting harder to look at this blog and wonder whether it will ever get back to its heyday of regularly posted updates.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision to Leave</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/decision-to-leave/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/decision-to-leave/</guid>
      <description>I gave up writing reviews of movies because:&#xA;I never felt I got the balance right between describing the plot and why I liked the film. I don&amp;rsquo;t watch enough movies to be able to draw comparisons that are interesting, just between the small subset of total films that I have watched. I don&amp;rsquo;t know enough about film making to properly describe why a movie made me feel a particular way and how to discuss the different possibilities available to the director, the actors, and the other artists involved with creating a movie.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A list for &#39;23</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-list-for-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-list-for-23/</guid>
      <description>A set of rules for living from now on (in no particular order)&#xA;Life is too short to look at adverts. Avoid them where possible. Block them if you have to. Embrace risk and chance, as they have contributed the most to where you are now. Intervene into physical things and leave your mark upon them. Draw pictures on the blank pages of books, even if they are dear to you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is in my Rakefile? (March 2023 edition)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-in-my-rakefile-march-2023-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-in-my-rakefile-march-2023-edition/</guid>
      <description>Because I am bored of forgetting what&amp;rsquo;s in my website&amp;rsquo;s Rakefile, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write a list. Also, as I&amp;rsquo;m probably going to move over to a node based approach soon, it&amp;rsquo;s a handy wish list for my package.json file when the time comes.&#xA;Make a new post in _posts named &amp;ldquo;Title&amp;rdquo; rake post[&amp;quot;Title&amp;quot;]&#xA;If no title is given, you will be prompted for one. The post will be opened in the editor specified in the Rakefile.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Come back to us Brother Matthew</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/come-back-to-us-brother-matthew/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/come-back-to-us-brother-matthew/</guid>
      <description>As with most years, I had hoped to start off 2023 with a flurry of new blog posts. Instead I caught Covid, which knocked me out for most of &amp;lsquo;betweenmas&amp;rsquo; and put paid to my hopes for a productive start to the year. At the time of writing this post, I only just feel like I have begun to get back to &amp;rsquo;normal&amp;rsquo;, or at least as normal as things have been since 2020.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
