<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Photos on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/photos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Photos on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/photos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Great Ocean Road</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-great-ocean-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-great-ocean-road/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a &lt;a href=&#34;articles/the-same-yet-different&#34;&gt;wedding present&lt;/a&gt;, Ingrid&amp;rsquo;s Mum Maria kindly took us for a trip along &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_Ocean_Road&#34;&gt;The Great Ocean Road&lt;/a&gt;, the longest war memorial in the world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Stretching 151 miles from Torquay (not that one!) to Allansford, the road was deliberately built as a tourist attraction as a means of providing meaningful work for troops returning home from the First World War. Regarded as one of the world&amp;rsquo;s greatest scenic roads, it certainly holds it own against things like the roads I experienced in Chile and Bolivia when I travelled over the Andes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More Melbourne</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/metros-suburbs-barbies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/metros-suburbs-barbies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On our second full day in Australia we went shopping in central Melbourne, before Ingrid&amp;rsquo;s mum Maria picked us up ahead of our trip along the Great Ocean Road.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We took the metro into the city. I always love watching the fabric of cities knit itself together around train lines and Melbourne is no exception. Along the way, Ingrid had plenty of stories to tell about the various places she had lived.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spain, New Year 2017/18</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/spain-new-year-201718/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/spain-new-year-201718/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For new year Ingrid and I met up with Ingrid&amp;rsquo;s friend Ros at Barcelona airport. We went from there to Cadaqués on the Costa Brava. A winding drive over steep hills leads you down to a cute bay with the typical white houses and terracotta roofs. All the window frames were painted just the right shade of blue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The surrealist artist Salvador Dalí lived and worked in the area. This meant a trip to Figueres to see his Theatre-Museum and on new year&amp;rsquo;s eve a walk over the hill to Port Lligat to visit his house. Both required timed tickets. We couldn&amp;rsquo;t get into the Port Lligat house on our first day because there were no tickets left. Lucky for us that New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve was so much better weather-wise!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A trip to Iceland. Part 3: Flu∂ir to Vík.</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/a-trip-to-iceland-part-3-even-more-waterfalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/a-trip-to-iceland-part-3-even-more-waterfalls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;iceland-part-two&#34;&gt;We left Gulfoss&lt;/a&gt; and drove through the countryside to Fluðir where our next hotel stay would be. The hotel had cute little cabins arranged around a central square and the room itself was comfy and warm. Our dinner was nice enough, although we had a bit of a Fawlty Towers moment with Ingrid’s chicken salad. First it went back because they didn’t leave the BBQ sauce off. Then it came back &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; tomatoes. And then back again with more BBQ sauce. Fourth time lucky.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A trip to Iceland. Part 2: Reykjavík to Flu∂ir.</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/a-trip-to-iceland-part-2-all-the-waterfalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/a-trip-to-iceland-part-2-all-the-waterfalls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;iceland-part-one&#34;&gt;After a day on foot in Reykjavík&lt;/a&gt;, and with some trepidation, we returned to the car for our drive through Iceland&amp;rsquo;s countryside. We started by heading out on route 1, which is like Iceland&amp;rsquo;s M25 except that it encircles an entire country &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; about thirty times fewer people. We went to house of Nobel Prize winner Halldór Laxness, only to be turned away because it was being renovated and wouldn&amp;rsquo;t open for another month. Undeterred, we pressed on toward &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%C3%9Eingvellir&#34;&gt;Þingvellir&lt;/a&gt;, stopping off on the way to take pictures at a viewpoint. It was just crazy, a flat expanse of undisturbed snow. Just as with the drive from the airport, the territory should have been relentlessly bleak but instead we got a winter wonderland.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A trip to Iceland. Part 1: Reykjavík.</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/a-trip-to-iceland-part-1-reykjavik/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/a-trip-to-iceland-part-1-reykjavik/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We arrived in Reykjavík a few days &lt;a href=&#34;https://weather.com/news/news/reykjavik-iceland-record-snowfall-february&#34;&gt;after a monumental snowstorm&lt;/a&gt;. As such the city was still under at least six inches of snow. We collected the hire car from the airport and drove out of Keflavik. The scenery normally looks like a moonscape, but for us it was a frosty white wonderland.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/iceland/iceland_01.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After about an hour&amp;rsquo;s drive, we arrived at the Hotel Nattura. From the outside it looks like a huge secondary school but as soon as you step inside it&amp;rsquo;s warm and comfortable. This is quite good when you&amp;rsquo;ve just parked next to a snow bank that&amp;rsquo;s two and half metres tall and then bambi&amp;rsquo;d it in over the icy paths with your luggage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The same, but different</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-same-yet-different/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-same-yet-different/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ingrid and I got married a month ago. It was a lovely day. We had a simple ceremony with two witnesses, our friends Sue and Andrew. We kept it quiet and small, as we just wanted to be married without too much fuss. A month on, we&amp;rsquo;re happy to report that we are glad we did it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;d like to thank everyone who nonetheless sent cards and gifts, and to all of those who wished us well on Facebook. Much as I&amp;rsquo;m wary of social networks this did seem to be one of those events to which an announcement on Facebook was well suited. We intend to have additional celebrations at some point in the near future so keep your eyes peeled. We&amp;rsquo;re aware that our little dyad cannot be the only point where our families intersect. We hope to overcome that, but it is those sorts of complications that drove us to a smaller scale event in the first place. I&amp;rsquo;m very keen on the &amp;lsquo;win the lottery and hire a few private jets&amp;rsquo; approach but they keep selling me faulty tickets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A little trip to Italy</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/a-little-trip-to-italy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/a-little-trip-to-italy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We bought a cheap package holiday in the British Airways Black Friday sale. The weekend spanned Ingrid&amp;rsquo;s birthday, so it was ideal. £99 each for flights and a hotel, and we bagged a hire car quite cheaply too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Because our flight was from Heathrow and the trains from Chichester are both expensive and inconvenient for early flights, we spoiled ourselves with a taxi to the airport. It felt very strange to be whisked through the Sussex and Surrey countryside at six am on a Friday morning!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mira Schendel at Tate Modern</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/mira-schendel-tate-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/mira-schendel-tate-modern/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2013/sep/29/mira-schendel-tate-modern-review&#34;&gt;Mira Schendel&lt;/a&gt; was a Brazilian artist who was active throughout the middle to late twentieth century. She is considered to be one of South America&amp;rsquo;s best artists. Known mostly for her abstract paintings, she also experimented with sculptures and installations. Many of her works use text and semiotics to explore and define possible meanings for more abstract works.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I saw this exhibition during its run in the Tate Modern in the Autumn of 2013. I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like writing about it at the time. In fact I may not have had any time because it was quite close to my departure for South America.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South America, Part 12</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/south-america-trip-part-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/south-america-trip-part-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;uyuni-to-tupiza&#34;&gt;Uyuni to Tupiza&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We left Uyuni the night after the big storm, having stopped just a day or so to visit the salt flats. Our next stop was a strategic stay in Tupiza, a large town encircled with red hills. It resembled many towns that I visited in South America: low buildings arranged in a grid pattern. Not much greenery and plenty of dust billowing about. The reason for our stay was strategic, it&amp;rsquo;s only a short distance to the notoriously fussy border between Bolivia and Argentina. We would leave at 5am the next morning so we would reach the border early in case of a long delay, which can happen at this border.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swaptastic Part 1</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/swaptastic-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/swaptastic-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/other/StickersInThePost.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Envelopes containing swaps that have arrived in the post in recent days.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Envelopes containing swaps that have arrived in the post in recent days. It is nice to get letters from all over the country, even if they do just contain a selection of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/euro-2016-panini-stickers/&#34;&gt;panini stickers&lt;/a&gt;. As I mentioned in a previous post, I have used &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stickerswapping.com&#34;&gt;the sticker swapping website&lt;/a&gt; to share my swaps with people all over the UK. I have sent swaps off to London, Bristol, Cornwall, Lancashire, Wales, and Gloucester. You&amp;rsquo;ll also be happy to know that I got my hands on an Aleksei Berezutski. Only 52 left to go!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Werner Bischof: Point of View and Helvetica</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/werner-bischof-exhibitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/werner-bischof-exhibitions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2016 marks the centenary of the birth of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.magnumphotos.com/C.aspx?VP3=CMS3&amp;amp;VF=MAGO31_9_VForm&amp;amp;ERID=24KL534M5N&#34;&gt;Werner Bischof&lt;/a&gt;, the talented Magnum photojournalist who died in Peru in 1954, aged 38. He travelled widely, making the most of an incredible talent for photography. After the second world war, this led him all over Europe to document its aftermath. As the cold war began, Bischof found himself documenting events further afield.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We saw two exhibitions of his photography at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elysee.ch&#34;&gt;Musée de l&amp;rsquo;Elysée in Lausanne&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;ldquo;Point of View&amp;rdquo; explores his international work spanning the years 1945 to 1954. &amp;ldquo;Helvetica&amp;rdquo; explores his earlier work while isolated from travel in Switzerland during the second world war.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lausanne, Switzerland, March 2016</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/lausanne-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/lausanne-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just before Easter Ingrid and I went to Lausanne in Switzerland for a few days. It was a much-needed break and my first trip out of the UK since I got back from South America.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We caught an early train to Gatwick. It took a strange route along the coast via Worthing and Hove, which was annoying because we could have left later if a more direct train were available at that time of day. At least it wasn&#39;t late, which for Southern is really rare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South America, Part 11</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/south-america-trip-part-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/south-america-trip-part-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;la-paz-to-potosi&#34;&gt;La Paz to Potosi&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/south_america/part_11/01.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We left La Paz, this time ascending the rim of steep hills around the city in a slightly less clunky &amp;ldquo;Death Bus&amp;rdquo;. Perhaps it was because we were travelling uphill or because it was daylight, but it didn&amp;rsquo;t seem so bad.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/south_america/part_11/02.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/south_america/part_11/03.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We set off to Potosi through strange towns with weird monuments (see the pictures) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lonelyplanet.com/bolivia/the-southwest/oruro/travel-tips-and-articles/76305&#34;&gt;Oruro where great festivals happen around Ash Wednesday each year&lt;/a&gt; that are famous throughout the continent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another Reading List</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/another-reading-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/another-reading-list/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/other/June-2012-Bookstack.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;More books to add to the “University of life” course list&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More books to add to the “University of life” course list. From top to bottom: I picked up “Generation X” for 50p in a charity shop in Tintagel. “Everything Is Going To Be OK” is a picture book full of inspirational mottos. “The Happiness Hypothesis” is the most useful and interesting book that I have read in a long while. I decided to read “How To Write A Sentence” as an alternative to Strunk and White’s “The Elements Of Style” which, while useful, can be a little stuffy! “The Marriage Plot” is a novel with interesting reviews, it was also (ahem) well-priced. After love I decided to go after music as something else I wanted to read about, hence “The Music Instinct” which comes highly recommended. “The Gifts Of Imperfection” is a manifesto for embracing life in a wholehearted way. And “Gonzo”? Well, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/gonzo-a-graphic-biography-of-hunter-s-thompson/&#34;&gt;I have written about that one already&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading list, mid-April 2012</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/reading-list-mid-april-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/reading-list-mid-april-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/other/April-2012-Bookstack.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A hefty reading list that should keep me occupied into the summer.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A hefty reading list that should keep me occupied into the summer. A friend on facebook asked “What course is that for?”, to which I replied “It’s for one of the modules I am doing at the university of life.” This response was quite popular.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tales From Home</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/tales-from-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/tales-from-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-question-of-identity&#34;&gt;A question of identity&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Three letters for Dad in the mail today, three variations on our surname including the aquatic &lt;em&gt;Dory&lt;/em&gt; version and the lesser-spotted &lt;em&gt;Dorny&lt;/em&gt;. It is perhaps best not to go back to the time he was accidentally listed in the Thompson directory as Mr. Dopey, bringing forth prank calls from all teenagers within a ten mile radius. Fortunately, Dr. Dorey doesn’t have this problem with his mail: he doesn’t get any.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Movember 10K</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/movember-10k/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/movember-10k/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, Saturday. Finally. The big day. Would I a) be able to get to Greenwich in time for the registration? and b) be able to make it all the way around the course without collapsing and crying?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/other/movember01.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Picture of Matt at Movember 10K run 2010&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Happily the answer to both questions was a resounding “Yes!” and I really enjoyed it. The weather was really good, especially compared to the two days before hand, and Marc came along to take some brilliant photos.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
