<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ideas on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ideas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ideas on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ideas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Doing the thing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/doing-the-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/doing-the-thing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I find it hard to get started on projects. This may have always been the case. I definitely remember instances of complex plans for school projects that I&amp;rsquo;d barely have time to finish. I once got up at 6AM to finish making a calendar in French—I thought it was going to be this outstanding piece of work that would genuinely replace my teacher&amp;rsquo;s calendar! Reality didn&amp;rsquo;t quite match the idea though.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If anything, make it weirder</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/make-it-weird/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/make-it-weird/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I listened to &amp;lsquo;Cloudbusting&amp;rsquo; by Kate Bush for the first time in a while. What a gloriously strange song it is. Best of all, it&amp;rsquo;s one of those songs that obscures what it is really about. It&amp;rsquo;s not a song about a change in the weather, but about &lt;a href=&#34;https://wilhelmreichmuseum.org/about/biography-of-wilhelm-reich/&#34;&gt;Wilhelm Reich&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Orgone&#34;&gt;orgone&lt;/a&gt; accumulator, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cultofweird.com/medical/radium-girls/&#34;&gt;fluorescent yo-yos&lt;/a&gt;, and a son (rather than a &lt;em&gt;sun&lt;/em&gt;) coming out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Cloudbusting&amp;rsquo; is from &amp;lsquo;Hounds of Love&amp;rsquo;, Kate&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;comeback&amp;rsquo; album following the commercial failure of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/understated-classics-19&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;The Dreaming&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;, an album I wrote about in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/tag/understated%20classics/&#34;&gt;understated classics series&lt;/a&gt;. It features four UK top 10 singles and some of her best work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drawing a line on the page</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/drawing-a-line-on-the-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/drawing-a-line-on-the-page/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ingrid has joined an online drawing class. She sits there on Teams getting feedback on her drawings, while I sit there attempting to absorb everything. I&amp;rsquo;m also learning by doing, by making a line on the page. In some ways, it&amp;rsquo;s instructive to observe the difference in what we learn with and without the feedback.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We bought some drawing materials and nice notepads. But to be honest, I still haven&amp;rsquo;t made room in my day to draw regularly. This is a shame because you do have do these things regularly in order to develop the skill.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Tips For Saving Time</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/some-tips-for-saving-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/some-tips-for-saving-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A non-exhaustive list of ideas for saving time:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delete your social media&lt;/strong&gt;, and perhaps any other website or app that demands that you consume it rather than create with it.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Another way to think of it: all these sites and apps transform your time in to one thing or another, what are the most valuable products of that time? In general, Facebook products are designed to transform your time into greater awareness of companies who would like you or your friends to buy their products. (Or neo-nazis, depending on whether the day ends in a Y.)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Possible exclusions are apps or websites for reading, you have to make the calculation of whether you get more out than you are putting in. Reading books in general are better value than websites or apps, but some online media can also be a net gain.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You could also try scheduling times for using apps, particularly if need them to communicate (e.g. catching up with people on WhatsApp) or if they are a good source of ideas (e.g. Twitter is quite good for finding interesting new ways of doing things in R).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Note that scheduling is a great way of dealing with procrastination. You can warm your brain up and wind it down at certain points of the day by scheduling your interactions with various apps, websites, and people. Try paying attention to what you do in a given day and shaping that into a schedule.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Procrastination is best managed rather than avoided, so it&amp;rsquo;s better to schedule it. Be honest with yourself, do you need to procrastinate before you do things (like a run up to a jump?) or would you be better saying to yourself &amp;ldquo;I have to get X done today, but I need to leave 10 minutes to catch up on xkcd later on&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sometimes changing your sources to something more curated is useful. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently signed up to the London Review of Books. Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s a bit fusty and old-fashioned but it&amp;rsquo;s well written and expands on a wide variety of topics.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get a bike&lt;/strong&gt; (this is on my to do list!). A bike increases the distances you can travel in a short space of time, and can reduce the time it takes to do short distance chores like shopping. It has the added benefit of being better for the planet than a car and better for your body than walking or doing nothing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Borrow code from other people to get started on programming tasks.&lt;/strong&gt; I usually Google how to do a thing, once I have mapped out a rough spine of what I need to. (I find this mapping out step acts as a filter for the solutions provided to you, a sort of intuition for what the solution &lt;em&gt;should be&lt;/em&gt;) The same is true when you&amp;rsquo;re learning to do anything: be an apprentice, find someone who is good at a thing and learn from them. This is actually easy for anyone to do, and easier than you might first think.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;**Learn to communicate more effectively. **This is one that I feel I need to work on. I often feel that I am going backwards and forwards between people, whether it is trying to understand what other people want or communicating to others what it is that I want.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;One tip that gets bandied about is to record yourself speaking to people. It can be very cringy, but the trick is to be a critical friend to yourself while listening back. Just because you know it&amp;rsquo;s you, that&amp;rsquo;s no reason to judge harshly - just focus on what&amp;rsquo;s being said and how, and work from there.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I also know that I need to ask more questions. It feels weird to say that because I regard myself as being on a personal quest to find out all of the stuff. The problem is that I&amp;rsquo;m also keen on sounding like I already know all the stuff. Can you tell this from my blog posts at all?!? Sometimes it can feel like asking a whole bunch of questions undermines that world view. I now consciously try to ask more questions in support of my quest.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Also a memo to myself for later: IT DOESN&amp;rsquo;T HURT TO EDIT YOUR WRITING FROM TIME TO TIME.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Learn orthogonal skills. By which I mean, if you are a scientist try to find complementary subjects in the humanities and the arts. I&amp;rsquo;ve said &amp;ldquo;orthogonal&amp;rdquo; here to sound clever and to indicate that the connection to your chosen vocation isn&amp;rsquo;t going to be obvious, but really I just mean that it&amp;rsquo;s different and you might eventually apply it.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How does it save you time if you &lt;em&gt;spend&lt;/em&gt; time looking for connections? Well, if you find your connection, you have extra tools to use. If you fail, you may discover something else in the process.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Learn keyboard shortcuts.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;By way of a corollary, the more keyboard shortcuts you learn for an app the more you will do with an app, and the more you will use it. If there&amp;rsquo;s no shortcut for something that you do regularly, make one. If you don&amp;rsquo;t like a provided shortcut, or it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to you, change it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Second corollary. Keyboard shortcuts are a great way to learn how to memorise things. It&amp;rsquo;s low stakes but incremental, if you learn N shortcuts, you can learn N+1.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write stuff down.&lt;/strong&gt; And perhaps just as importantly &lt;strong&gt;have a strategy for coming back to things later&lt;/strong&gt;. The commandment that &lt;em&gt;thou shalt forego thy social networks&lt;/em&gt; at the top of this list is really a double headed command to use intentionality and self-control in order to sanitise your information inputs, and this is a friendly reminder that the time saved can be used to revisit and reinforce those inputs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get enough sleep.&lt;/strong&gt; I am so bad at this. I have been meaning to read &amp;ldquo;Why We Sleep&amp;rdquo; for over a year but I am too scared to learn what my terrible sleeping habits are doing to me. That said, I do tend to do better when I am following some of these other tips - especially the ones about acting with intentionality and self-control.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Again, this is another spend time (on sleeping) to save time (sluggishly prodding work tasks while waiting for the coffee or tea to kick in) later.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This could probably do with its own post of do as I say not as I do advice.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m loathe to say what the right amount of sleep is. You know when you&amp;rsquo;ve had enough. And it varies, which makes it hard to plan around. It always feels like I need two hours after the alarm clock!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think framing sleep around quotes like &amp;ldquo;studies show most people need 4/6/8/14 hours a night&amp;rdquo; is helpful, as in my experience the more I fret the worse I do and the feeling of divergence from nature tends to increase my fretfulness.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Related: &lt;strong&gt;Get enough exercise&lt;/strong&gt; - I am working on this.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get a second/third/Nth monitor&lt;/strong&gt;. I have recently done this and the jury&amp;rsquo;s still out for me. If I&amp;rsquo;m honest I just use the biggest monitor available. I&amp;rsquo;ve still included it on the list because most people won&amp;rsquo;t buy a &lt;em&gt;smaller&lt;/em&gt; monitor than the one they have. I find that seeing more means doing more and concentrating better. When I grow up I hope to have more interesting anecdotes about how I used a multiple monitor setup, but I&amp;rsquo;m still pretty green.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Travel Writing After All This</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/travel-writing-after-all-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/travel-writing-after-all-this/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While sprucing up this blog a bit during lockdown, I fell into reading my old posts about &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tag/south%20america/&#34;&gt;South America&lt;/a&gt;. I enjoyed it, mostly for the memories, but also because the current lockdown is warping my sense of time and space. Hours feel like weeks, but then I blink and a month&amp;rsquo;s gone by. I find myself traipsing similar orbits each day around the house, and then perhaps over to the supermarket or the park. There&amp;rsquo;s a palpable escapism to be had in reminiscing about South America and other places.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holiday Tabs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/holiday-tabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/holiday-tabs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the course of a week on holiday, I started reading many interesting articles. In lockdown there isn&amp;rsquo;t much to do but read articles, but I still find myself not that good at finishing them. My phone has lots of tabs open and has become a Rolodex of shame. This post is to confess my sins.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m trying to re-familiarise myself with Python. As with all modern software development, Python now seems atomised and hyper-complicated. As a result, this series of posts from Claudio Jolowitz was useful. He cuts through lots of the complications and explains why they are there. Someone should ask him to write a book.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things to Remember</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/things-to-remember/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/things-to-remember/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These are some things I jotted down one day last week, I&amp;rsquo;ll refine them a bit more later on. Think of it as an aide-memoire of things that work for me, your milage may vary.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about things that haven&amp;rsquo;t happened.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t turn whatever has happened and/or is bothering you into a catastrophe, especially if no one else is telling you that it is one. Seek out someone you trust and ask them &amp;ldquo;is this a catastrophe?&amp;rdquo; Not only will they say no about 99.9% of the time, they will often tell you why it isn&amp;rsquo;t a catastrophe.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The people who are important to you will not use your personal characteristics as a laundry list of personal failings in the same way that you do. In fact they won&amp;rsquo;t do it all. What you perceive as your own obvious and innate failings, others will often struggle to even see. Self awareness and hyper-awareness are two different things.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There will be people who don&amp;rsquo;t like you, people who don&amp;rsquo;t think you&amp;rsquo;re good enough, and people who won&amp;rsquo;t give you a chance. They most likely intersect, meaning there are fewer of them than you might think. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to satisfy these people, only those who like you and support you. Most of all, you have to be good enough for you.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Everybody has different needs and wants in life. Even though your needs and wants will often intersect with those of others, there is still no reason to use other people as the measure for what you should be getting out of life.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A person has more depth and dimensions than are measurable. If you focus solely on a single metric when you measure yourself against some standard or goal, you will be wrong in some way or another. A qualified and multi-dimensional validation of your progress will give you a more nuanced and more supportive sense of where you are heading and how to correct yourself.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Always focus on your capability. Regard potential as something to be shaped into capability.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Take time to think about things in many different ways, employing both proven mental models and lateral thinking.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Often problems are easier to tackle once you have been for a walk in the countryside.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ambitions Revisited</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ambitions-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 21:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ambitions-revisited/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in 2012 &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/ambitions&#34;&gt;I wrote a post&lt;/a&gt; listing my ambitions for the future. Well it&amp;rsquo;s the future now isn&amp;rsquo;t it? Almost. After all, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/How-long-does-it-take-for-most-of-the-atoms-in-your-body-to-be-replaced-by-others&#34;&gt;I’m a whole new person now&lt;/a&gt;. Anyway it&amp;rsquo;s probably time to take stock. Have I achieved any of them? Have any of my ambitions changed? What&amp;rsquo;s replaced the things that I&amp;rsquo;ve decided not to worry about? What has come after the things I managed to do?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First off, here&amp;rsquo;s my justification for writing the list in the original post:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five years after</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/five-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/five-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Five years ago I set out at 3am for Heathrow airport to catch the early morning flight to Madrid. There I connected with a flight to Quito in Ecuador. The previous days and weeks had been fraught with worry about whether I was doing the right thing. Did I get the right vaccinations? Would I have enough money? Would I cope with all that travel? Was I coming back? What was I going to do with all my stuff?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reboot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/reboot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/reboot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As much as I hate to write about writing, especially when I write so infrequently, I feel I need to reboot this blog. I wrote so few posts in recent months I considered giving up altogether.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been stressed. Sometimes this manifests in being unable to sleep. Sometimes it manifests in all my interests and ideas seeming to be completely pointless. Sometimes one of those precedes the other. Sometimes it works vice versa. Often since getting back from Australia I’ve felt stuck in a vicious circle of insomnia and disinterest. Perhaps it’s just been the longest case of jet lag ever.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Diary?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-diary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-diary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year promises to be exciting so this week I tried to buy a diary. One of those day-to-a-page affairs for scribbling down all the things I&amp;rsquo;ve seen and learned about. I thought they might be cheap now the calendar is turning to February. No such luck. There were a few week-to-view diaries going for half price in Waterstones but nothing suitable for my needs. I have lots of Field Notes notebooks if my urge to write gets too much to resist.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Valleys</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/valleys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/valleys/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my last post, I wrote about hills. I tried to use them as a metaphor to explain nagging sense of incompletion when you single out one activity over another. The feeling that there&amp;rsquo;s always a more exciting hill off in the distance to go climb, instead of the one you&amp;rsquo;re on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I said my next post would be about how to pick between different options, particularly when you have many to choose from. This post is not that. This is a short piece about an experience I had in South America that relates to the hills post: about contentment in the moment and letting things go.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hills</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hills/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hills/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of books. The way they transport you away to other places and so on. As repositories of knowledge and adventure they can&amp;rsquo;t be beat. I can think of no better way out of an existential fix than reading.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The trouble is I tend to hoard them. I&amp;rsquo;ve posted pictures of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/reading-list-mid-april-2012/&#34;&gt;book stacks before&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/another-reading-list/&#34;&gt;on more than one occasion&lt;/a&gt;). I could probably repeat that every month if I wanted to, perhaps even more often. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a networked thinker, able to see (at least superficially) the connections between all sorts of things. Because of this I get excited and enthusiastic about all kinds of things, and I want to learn them all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/create/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/create/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It can be a struggle to keep writing. I&amp;rsquo;ve found this happened a lot since I moved the blog. First, there was  the business of moving things over. That meant a lot of thought about old posts and which ones I should keep. A lot of the time I thought &amp;ldquo;how on earth did I have time to write this?!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then there seemed to be a lot more barriers to writing than previously. We can say what we like about the machinery that WordPress runs on, it does make it easy to write regularly. It also provides a lot of tools for making writing fun and for learning things as you go. I still have access to those things but it&amp;rsquo;s a little different now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Notebook</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/new-notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/new-notebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Witness the pressure of a new notebook. You sit at your desk, trying to get it started with an amazing piece of writing. Something worthy of that crisp new page. You want it to tumble out of you, fully formed and coherent. Something that justifies you abandoning the previous one. As though first drafts don&amp;rsquo;t exist. You cast yourself into the role of shaman, of seer - of someone gifted a prophetic vision. But it&amp;rsquo;s a role that you cannot and will not fulfil.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Don&#39;t Have a Clue, part 43</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/no-clue-part-43/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/no-clue-part-43/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A little man wearing a bow tie, and possibly a fez, scurries into the middle of the frame clutching a clapboard. Breathing heavily he hoists the clapboard up to chest height. He holds the clapper up then brings down while slurring &amp;quot;This is a blog post about not having a clue, take 43&amp;quot;. He exits to the right of the frame.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My feet are hot. The bed seems too small. Why are my feet always too hot on nights like these? I bet I could sleep if my feet weren&#39;t so hot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/untitled-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/untitled-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months ago &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/jackson-x/&#34;&gt;I wrote about an idea for a novel that I&amp;rsquo;d abandoned&lt;/a&gt;. I mentioned in that post that I&amp;rsquo;d abandoned it because there was another idea that I wanted to pursue. The working title for it is &amp;ldquo;Untitled 2&amp;rdquo;. (It isn&amp;rsquo;t really, I have an actual working title that would give things away or would at least make me feel like the idea was out in the world.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Light, Last Light</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/first-light-last-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/first-light-last-light/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I often ponder whether the joys of waking up early are greater than those of staying up late. Empirical evidence seems to bear this out: all those people who get to work before you do, super-eager to get everything done. But then all the people walking under your windows late at night, drunk and laughing, they sound like they&amp;rsquo;re having a whale of a time too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I oscillate between the two extremes, though I tend to sleep better if I stay up late. My natural sleep hours are 1am to 8am, though I am usually human if I can get up just after 7. Whenever I try to stick to getting up early, to do masochistic things like running or being organised, I often find it harder to get to sleep or I wake up at 3 rather than 6. I end up second guessing my alarm clock.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time Is Time and That Is That</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/time-is-time-and-that-is-that/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/time-is-time-and-that-is-that/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A brief rant about Facebook: I hate the fact that the news feed defaults to “Top Stories” even though I change it back to “Most Recent” every time I log in. It’s a horrible pattern of user abuse that needs to stop. Time is time and that is that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So why does Facebook feel the need to jiggle things about into a random order? Well most of you have that mobile phone app of theirs that sucks your battery and your data allowance like crazy (mainly by auto-playing videos like a dick). They know you’re checking your Facebook on the loo at work and that that limits your interaction time. During this precious interlude they want you to see the stuff that they think interests you and the things that other people paid for you to see. You’re going to see some hick’s new tattoo, at least one photo of someone else’s child and an advert telling you to vote Conservative - whether you like it or not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jim&#39;s Conservatory</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/jims-conservatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/jims-conservatory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s assume that Jim has just had a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2008_United_Kingdom_bank_rescue_package&#34;&gt;sudden unexpected expenditure&lt;/a&gt;: a neighbour released a bull into his back garden and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/business/2007/nov/01/creditcrunch.subprimecrisis&#34;&gt;it destroyed his conservatory&lt;/a&gt;. Let&amp;rsquo;s assume that the conservatory is essential to Jim&amp;rsquo;s wellbeing, so it has to be fixed immediately. As a result Jim&amp;rsquo;s debts, which &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/business/2015/may/03/senior-tory-financial-crash-was-purely-a-banking-crisis-not-labour-overspend&#34;&gt;were previously small and well-managed&lt;/a&gt;, have now increased somewhat.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Obviously Jim can&amp;rsquo;t keep that debt hanging over him forever. What does he do?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for Jim, the circumstances of his borrowing aren&amp;rsquo;t so different before and after the event. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/finance/personalfinance/interest-rates/9922941/Interest-rates-predictions-Four-more-years-of-0.5.html&#34;&gt;Interest rates are low and are predicted to stay low&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-21554311&#34;&gt;terms of his credit haven&amp;rsquo;t changed a great deal despite his increased borrowing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Consider the Donut</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/consider-the-donut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/consider-the-donut/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;or-from-there-to-here-with-the-simpsons&#34;&gt;Or, From There to Here With the Simpsons&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Old episodes of The Simpsons are great. The other night “Bart After Dark” was on and I really enjoyed seeing it again. It’s from season eight, the one where Bart ends up working in the Maison Derriére. I thought it was older; mind you, this makes it nineteen years old. When I thought about the episode later on that evening, I realised how the story anarchically set out in multiple directions before settling into its main storyline. This still happens in newer Simpsons episodes, though the show is rarely as joyfully chaotic now as it was back then.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Little Bit Intimidating Really</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-little-bit-intimidating-really/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-little-bit-intimidating-really/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is so much good writing out there. All you have to do is fire up &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/uk/&#34;&gt;the guardian website&lt;/a&gt;, or download the &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/m/app&#34;&gt;medium app to your smartphone&lt;/a&gt;, or visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://xianity.me/&#34;&gt;my friend Barrie&amp;rsquo;s site&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://narami.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Lee&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;, and so on and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When it comes to my little whisper into this great choir, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to feel a bit intimidated. How do I add my voice? How do I feel distinct? How do I do it as well as all these other wonderful writers?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Fireworks Work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-fireworks-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-fireworks-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night an impromptu firework display occurred. I watched it from my bathroom window. Very pretty and somewhat extravagant, given that there’s no reason for one on the calendar. I could have filmed it on meerkat but it would have diminished the spectacle. However, it did at least motivate me to write this piece that I have put off for a while (since about November I guess?). One where I find out (i.e. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fireworks&#34;&gt;look up on Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;) how fireworks work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Can’t Just Switch Off Free</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-cant-just-switch-off-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-cant-just-switch-off-free/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2015/mar/11/ministry-of-sound-streaming-switch-off-free&#34;&gt;Ministry of Sound boss Lohan Presencer does the cry baby act in today&amp;rsquo;s Guardian&lt;/a&gt;, complaining that Spotify&amp;rsquo;s freemium model doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow him to bathe in a Scrooge McDuck style swimming pool of golden coins any more. The cat is out of the bag for streaming music now, and no matter how much music companies cry foul they can&amp;rsquo;t stop Spotify and their ilk, and there wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be pots of gold waiting for them even if they could.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On The Humble Cheese Grater</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/humble-cheese-grater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/humble-cheese-grater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t beat a good cheese grater. Cheese just tastes better in a sandwich once it has been grated. It&amp;rsquo;s been proven by ACTUAL SCIENCE that this is the case: something about the increased surface area making it taste more zingy (NB. QI is not actually a peer-reviewed scientific journal). Of course the cheese we are grating here is a nice mature cheddar, you can&amp;rsquo;t grate Camembert or Stilton (well &lt;em&gt;technically&lt;/em&gt; you can, but why would you?). There are even cheeses that can be grated but don&amp;rsquo;t deserve it, take Red Leicester for example: the ear wax of the cheese world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Jackson X</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/jackson-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/jackson-x/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I set myself the task of writing about a fictional character for this blog post, so this post is about Jackson X. His surname isn’t really X, it’s just one of the details about him that I haven’t fleshed out yet. This is because Jackson X is the one of the protagonists of the novel I’m (not) writing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The name of the novel is “The Summer of the Giant Space Whale”. I’m quite happy to discuss its plot and structure here. I don’t need to worry about anyone stealing the idea because it is already a rip-off of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/112537.Rendezvous_with_Rama&#34;&gt;Arthur C. Clarke’s “Rendezvous With Rama”&lt;/a&gt; (or, less charitably, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0092007/?ref_=nv_sr_1&#34;&gt;“Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home”&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Brains</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-brains/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/building-brains/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a longer form post about artificial intelligence inspired by reading a little bit of &amp;ldquo;The Pale King&amp;rdquo; by David Foster Wallace and putting a picture of a &amp;ldquo;ghost&amp;rdquo; up on Instagram. This might be the last of these that I&amp;rsquo;m able to write for a while.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-not-reading-the-pale-king&#34;&gt;On Not Reading &amp;ldquo;The Pale King&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Pale King&amp;rdquo; is the third and final novel by American author &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newsweek.com/david-foster-wallace-appreciation-david-gates-89371&#34;&gt;David Foster Wallace&lt;/a&gt;. He was working on it when he committed suicide in 2008. It was compiled from incomplete notes and released posthumously in 2011. It deals with several characters around an &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internal_Revenue_Service&#34;&gt;IRS&lt;/a&gt; tax office in Peoria, Illinois&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What IS That Noise?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-that-noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-that-noise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently spruced up a post I wrote four years ago about &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/articles/uc4/&#34;&gt;Biosphere’s wonderful album Substrata&lt;/a&gt;. I added the following footnote about the difference between voice samples and found sound:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I suppose I am distinguishing between found sound and vocal samples here. Perhaps there is very little difference, or that one is the other? When is a vocal snippet something more than found sound? Is it the fact that one has meaning? Isn’t a “meaningless” sample - like the ones here in Russian that I can’t understand - little more than found sound anyway?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Posters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/posters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/posters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2005, towards the end of the second year of my PhD I presented a poster at a conference in Dresden, Germany. My eccentric colleagues and I stayed on a huge canal boat moored on the Elbe for no discernible reason other than it seemed like a laugh at the time. In reality I was the second worst snorer of the three of us and it also turned out that our room was right underneath the gang-plank and every morning at six the person who made breakfast would stomp across it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ideas for TV shows: Great Mathematicians</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ideas-for-tv-shows-great-mathematicians/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ideas-for-tv-shows-great-mathematicians/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to see a TV show about great mathematicians of the past on a channel like BBC Four. Programmes about mathematics tend to be rather condescending, at least to anyone who has a bit of mathematical knowledge. Perhaps a way around this is to delve into the social and historical circumstances of the great mathematicians and how that along with their personality produced the mathematical results for which they are famous.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Mountain Story</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-mountain-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-mountain-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A cat reaches the top of a mountain after a long climb through the snow. He is cold from the bottom of his fur to the tips of his claws. He is sodden and wet, and we all know how much a cat hates to be wet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the top of the mountain there is not much to see. What may have been a breathtaking view is instead a murk of freezing mist and at any rate, snow assails the cat’s eyes and whiskers. He shivers and sneezes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ambitions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ambitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ambitions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, when I am feeling a bit down, I like to write down some of my ambitions. As you can see from this list they are mostly pretty humble but they are also a bit cheesy and embarassing, so I have put them after the fold!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Be wholehearted, cheerful, and sincere&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Be creative&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Look at the world and see its many faces, hear its many voices&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Explore new recipes as often as possible when I cook&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Learn to like the taste of tomatoes and cucumbers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Be more at ease around people&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Listen to people and hear what they say&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Play my part&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Look after someone special&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Become a parent&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Share my values with others, help those who need it&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Break up all the negative things inside me&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Know what other people want, help them get it&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When I wake up each morning I would like to remember my dreams&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Understand art more than I do&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lose my fear of creepy crawlies&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Learn to drive&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Learn to write left handed (why not?)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Visit every country in Europe&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Visit the radio telescopes on Mauna Kea in Hawaii&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Let go of unnecessary things&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ditch social networks and the rest of the internet as much as possible&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Learn to appreciate the noise around me&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meditate&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Get over my reliance on sugar to improve my mood&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Get rid of things I don’t need&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grow the garden&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Write people letters&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Learn the differences between species of trees&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Be flexible and adaptable and positive about the future&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Learn how to hang a picture on a wall&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Net Loss</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/net-loss/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/net-loss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I pay to have this blog up and running. That is, I pay for the space where it is stored and I pay for the name. I have to look after all the files and plug-ins, I have to perform all the updates and optimise the database tables. All this is great fun but wouldn’t it be cheaper to slap the mattischro.me address onto a hosted WordPress.com account?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, yes it would. I suppose I just like the independence of having my own little patch of cyberspace, sitting there waiting for all you dear readers to come and visit. Nice ideas don’t make the world go round though and so I need a better reason than that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Painter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-painter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-painter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time there was a man who loved to paint. He studied the art and craft of painting for many years. He chose to invest his time and energy into creating the most realistic portraits that he could paint. For him the joy came not from completing the paintings but the process of recreating the real world with the strokes of his brush.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For many years he continued to study the art of painting. He learned new techniques for abstracting from reality but he always favoured the realism above all else. Meanwhile, his friends and family mocked him and said that he would always be a poor boy who loved to paint but could not make money from it. He had no answer to this criticism, the satisfaction he gained from applying the brush to the canvas was to great to worry about whether his paintings would be finished or not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Amber World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-amber-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-amber-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My earliest memory is waking up in Queen Alexandra hospital in Cosham after an operation on my ears. I must have been about four years old and it was the middle of the night. I was in a room on my own and the door was locked. It had been daylight only seconds before so I got out of the bed and walked to the window to look incredulously out at the amber world that lay beyond.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The News</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-news/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“I read the news today, oh boy”  (The Beatles, &lt;em&gt;A Day In The Life&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes watching the news feels like a series of repeated blows to the face: arbitrary, cruel and unrelenting. It gets draining and upsetting, and leaves you fearful of what might come next.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You won’t need me to tell you about the tragedies that have occurred all over the world in the last few days: drought in East Africa, the gunman running amok in Norway, the death of Amy Winehouse and the horrific train crash in China.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Beta Test Of Everything</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-beta-test-of-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-beta-test-of-everything/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading a few articles about the recent launch of Google+, a few things hit home. Google tends to launch a product that works and not always one that is perfect or finished (like, say, Apple). Sometimes it takes them several iterations to get right. They love the beta tag. In fact, I think it was Google (or possibly Flickr) that made me aware of the concept of beta software.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Along these line I thought about this blog and its one year anniversary. I take a similar approach here to posts on this blog, specifically in pushing out new categories now and then. I have done this in the hope that adding a new subject or thread will lead to me writing more posts. Currently I am averaging ten posts a month, which is not too bad.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maps And Charts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/maps-and-charts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/maps-and-charts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was growing up a framed print of a map hung on the wall in the hallway. It was one of my favourite things, littered with strange latin names and with Vs where Us should have been. The outlines of the continents and countries were all familiar and yet slightly distorted, becoming more recognisable around the shores of western Europe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don’t know the provenance of that map print but at some point it got taken to the charity shop and replaced by Van Gogh’s sunflowers. I guess that means that I shall never be able to work out exactly what map it was and when it was from.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Things To Try When You Can&#39;t Sleep</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/five-things-to-try-when-you-cant-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/five-things-to-try-when-you-cant-sleep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Facebook is wonderful for keeping in touch but I’ve noticed that quite a few of my friends tend to use it to tell the world that they can’t sleep. Here’s some advice for you if you find yourself unable to sleep one night. I’ve often had to try these out myself! Note that these are just things that work for me and your mileage may vary, particularly if you are fortunate enough to have a partner next to you! You may need to appease them if you wriggle around too much.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
