<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Animation on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/animation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Animation on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/animation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Minions: A Short Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/minions-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/minions-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Minions got their own movie, just as I predicted in &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/despicable-me-2-a-short-review/&#34;&gt;my review of Despicable Me 2&lt;/a&gt;. I went to see it this week and I enjoyed it a lot. Here&amp;rsquo;s a short review. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, there are no spoilers here that aren&amp;rsquo;t in the trailer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s very funny. Right from the opening credits you get the minions and their anarchic fun-loving slapstick humour. There&amp;rsquo;s always been something delightful about they way in which they innocently bumble around. Their penchant for evil bosses is inexplicable but incredibly amusing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Despicable Me 2: A Short Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/despicable-me-2-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/despicable-me-2-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s so good that I paid to see it twice! There, that&amp;rsquo;s the review done.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Despicable Me 2&lt;/em&gt; is great for so many reasons. I reckon pretty much anyone aged from 3 to 103 would enjoy both movies&amp;rsquo; warm heartedness and most will love the minions&amp;rsquo; riot of anarchic slapstick. And if they don&amp;rsquo;t, I guess they aren&amp;rsquo;t our kind of people anyway, right?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are a few good reasons for loving &amp;ldquo;Despicable Me 2&amp;rdquo; (and actually most of these reasons apply to the original &amp;ldquo;Despicable Me&amp;rdquo;):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Love The Jungle Book</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-i-love-the-jungle-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-i-love-the-jungle-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just as with the &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;understated classics&lt;/a&gt; I want to set out my stall early on that good movies are good enough. Both &lt;a href=&#34;why-i-love-betty-blue&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Betty Blue&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and today’s choice &lt;em&gt;The Jungle Book&lt;/em&gt; are never going to win any sort of consensus prize for the best movies ever made but they are really good. They also have a personal history attached that makes them worth writing about.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I was younger both my sisters would be given VHS copies of Disney movies at a rate of about two a year, one for Christmas and one at their birthday. It seems strange today to think of that pace of movie acquisition, never mind the clunky VHS cassettes and how they would warp over time. I didn’t really ever get any of the Disney movies myself but I would inevitably find myself watching them with my sisters who would watch them repeatedly. With just four TV channels back then, who could blame us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
