<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Twenty Four on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/twenty-four/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Twenty Four on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/twenty-four/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Orphan Project</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-orphan-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-orphan-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A nice feature I added to this blog in its recent update was a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/tags/&#34;&gt;tags page&lt;/a&gt;. With the help of this &lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io/t/how-to-get-a-tags-page/24213/4&#34;&gt;very useful discourse thread&lt;/a&gt; and some additional CSS tweaks, the resulting page is something that I am very happy with. It lists all of the tags that apply to any post, along with the number of posts with that tag, in alphabetical order. It&amp;rsquo;s mostly intended as a guide for you the reader, to help you see whether your preoccupations match my own.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bob Mortimer, The Satsuma Complex</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/bob-mortimer-the-satsuma-complex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 17:55:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/bob-mortimer-the-satsuma-complex/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A hardback book called &amp;ldquo;The Satsuma Complex&amp;rdquo; is all that remains of a mysterious young lady that young lawyer Gary is chatting up in the pub one night. It&amp;rsquo;s a book that everyone reckons is &amp;ldquo;a bit sh*t&amp;rdquo;. But Gary&amp;rsquo;s moping about after the Satsuma lady doing a runner while he was in the loo will have to be put on hold when his friend turns up dead.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed this book. It&amp;rsquo;s not going to win any prizes for quality of writing but it is both fun and funny. There are a few repetitive phrases and at one point beers magically become lagers in the space of three paragraphs. The writing is very colloquial but there is a point-of-view shift at the start of part two that deploys some writerly skill. (This short-lived though as the new point-of-view soon collapses down into one similar to the main character.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The new look mattischrome</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/new-look-mattischrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 20:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/new-look-mattischrome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the new look for my blog. I&amp;rsquo;ve had my eye on a more minimal look for a while now. Whether this new look is successful or not depends on how often I write new posts. To that end, this theme also supports a separate (or almost separate) stream of photos. Once I&amp;rsquo;ve got back in to the habit of putting photos up, that should be a nice additional stream of content.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sofa So Good</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/sofa-so-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/sofa-so-good/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, a cat named Nerys ripped into the bottom of our sofa to make herself a cozy burrow. This was all well and good, except for the times when she would do it when we were using the sofa too. On these occasions (and presumably on most others) she would proceed to sharpen her claws on what remained of the fabric. (A less charitable reason for this behaviour would be that she was simply widening the whole for her future self after eating more and more kibbles!)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Negativity Casket</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-negativity-casket/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-negativity-casket/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things that people tend to start around this time of year is a diary. They usually get filled for as long as your new year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions last.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing in my current diary for a while. It&amp;rsquo;s a Moleskine extra large ruled Notebook in beautiful Prussian Blue, covered in whatever stickers pass over my desk. (Hint: find my address and send me stickers Internet.) This is much more preferable to a &amp;lsquo;real&amp;rsquo; diary because I can leave a few days and then resume. I can also take breaks and write out a bunch of notes on Org-mode or the Julia programming language if I want to (and yes, I did).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unindexed?</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/unindexed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/unindexed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/c/23998379/google-search-seo-algorithm-webpage-optimization&#34;&gt;an excellent article on The Verge yesterday about how Google is transforming the kinds of sites and blogs that are on the internet&lt;/a&gt;. I also read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fromjason.xyz/p/notebook/where-have-all-the-websites-gone/&#34;&gt;this slightly more personal take by Jason Velasquez&lt;/a&gt;, which is more about how social networks have gobbled up all the time and attention of people who might otherwise be making interesting web sites. This has made me think deeply about what this blog is &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt;, and why I might continue to blog in Twenty Twenty Four.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maara, The Ancient Truth (on vinyl)</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/maara-the-ancient-truth-vinyl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/maara-the-ancient-truth-vinyl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/2023-albums-07-maara-ancient-truth&#34;&gt;I wrote about Maara&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Ancient Truth&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; over Christmas as part of my albums of the year rundown, I mentioned at the end that I would love to find a copy on vinyl to listen to. Well dear reader I managed to! It arrived today from the Netherlands with minimal fuss. It sounds great and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure whether my review did it justice: that&amp;rsquo;s the problem with attempting to (re-)review ten albums in ten days with Christmas and New Year all happening at the same time!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agents of Chaos (2024 edition)</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/agents-of-chaos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 21:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/agents-of-chaos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The cats broke their new resolution not to knock stuff over in my office. Oh, who am I kidding? They never had such a resolution! If you can see a sheet of saturated paper, that was my to do list! Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/2024/cat-chaos-2024.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;A knocked over vase of flowers caused by the cats chasing one another&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The cats were either bounding across my desk to get to the window and look at the snow. Or they were just chasing each other around as usual.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Git Instructions for Future Matt</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/git-instructions-for-future-matt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 21:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/git-instructions-for-future-matt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Future Matt,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Always look up instructions for what you want to do in the Git documentation. It&amp;rsquo;s dry but it&amp;rsquo;s good. In a pinch, look at Stack Overflow. Don&amp;rsquo;t ask Chat-GPT for advice on Git problems!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To reverse mistakes, consult the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ohshitgit.com&#34;&gt;Oh Shit Git&lt;/a&gt; website.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To make things easier, delete the remote to your Github repository and then add it (the remote) back again. This is so much easier than the alternative.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Best wishes,&#xA;Past Matt (with his annual flash of January git confidence).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on 2023</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/reflections-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 22:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/reflections-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;travel&#34;&gt;Travel&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2023, it was Germany or go home.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Went to Cologne in January. Here is photographic evidence:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/2023/cologne-proof.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Photographic evidence of my visit to Cologne&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We took the Eurostar via Brussels. A bit of a long day on the way back but much less stressful compared to flying.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We went to the Isle of Wight in June. It was the first time I&amp;rsquo;d been since I was about 8. This time I didn&amp;rsquo;t get Chicken Pox. Anyway, here is photographic evidence:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums: Honourable Mentions</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/2023-albums-honourable-mentions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 13:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/2023-albums-honourable-mentions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A quick list of ten other albums I considered to be among the best of last year. I either listened to these less, or in the cases of &amp;ldquo;Transmission Three&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Be Opened By The Wonderful&amp;rdquo; considered them to be ineligible as they are compilations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;yves-tumor-praise-a-lord-who-chews-but-which-does-not-consume-or-simply-hot-between-worlds&#34;&gt;Yves Tumor, &amp;ldquo;Praise a Lord Who Chews but Which Does Not Consume; (Or Simply, Hot Between Worlds)&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Great album, recommended to me by Apple Music slinging the first track into my discovery feed back when that featured was added. Lots of earworms and a really good headphone listen. My top 10 was pretty dance heavy and putting this in might have added a few more guitars. Highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
