<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Richard Powers on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/richard-powers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Richard Powers on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/richard-powers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Richard Powers, Orfeo</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/richard-powers-orfeo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/richard-powers-orfeo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The mind may give up its desire to improve on creation and function as a faithful receiver of experience.&amp;rdquo; John Cage&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After enjoying &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/the-overstory/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Overstory&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I wanted to read more of Richard Powers&amp;rsquo; novels. &lt;em&gt;Orfeo&lt;/em&gt;  was also long listed for the Booker prize. Perhaps more of his novels would have been had the prize been opened to American authors earlier.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Orfeo&lt;/em&gt; is about Peter Els, a seventy year old composer who accidentally alerts Homeland Security to the existence of his home laboratory, in which he has been trying to recode the genetic material of a bacterium to include a piece of his music. He ends up on the run, which provides the catalyst for a narrative in which we ponders the past and returns to it. Woven throughout is a history of contemporary classical music, most real and some invented.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Richard Powers, The Overstory</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-overstory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-overstory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Overstory&amp;rdquo; by Richard Powers piqued my interest among the novels shortlisted for the Booker Prize. And &lt;a href=&#34;satin-island-tom-mccarthy-review&#34;&gt;once again&lt;/a&gt; the book that interested me most did not win. One year I will succeed in my prediction!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I found &amp;ldquo;The Overstory&amp;rdquo; an enjoyable read. Its accessibility surprised me. Often people view Booker nominated novels as stuffy or over-intellectual. This novel however is a genuine page turner, full of emotion and heartbreak, not to mention plenty of science and awe of the natural world. Perhaps in another year it may have won.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
