<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Europe on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/europe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Europe on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/europe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spain, New Year 2017/18</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/spain-new-year-201718/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/spain-new-year-201718/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For new year Ingrid and I met up with Ingrid&amp;rsquo;s friend Ros at Barcelona airport. We went from there to Cadaqués on the Costa Brava. A winding drive over steep hills leads you down to a cute bay with the typical white houses and terracotta roofs. All the window frames were painted just the right shade of blue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The surrealist artist Salvador Dalí lived and worked in the area. This meant a trip to Figueres to see his Theatre-Museum and on new year&amp;rsquo;s eve a walk over the hill to Port Lligat to visit his house. Both required timed tickets. We couldn&amp;rsquo;t get into the Port Lligat house on our first day because there were no tickets left. Lucky for us that New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve was so much better weather-wise!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A trip to Iceland. Part 3: Flu∂ir to Vík.</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/a-trip-to-iceland-part-3-even-more-waterfalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/a-trip-to-iceland-part-3-even-more-waterfalls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;iceland-part-two&#34;&gt;We left Gulfoss&lt;/a&gt; and drove through the countryside to Fluðir where our next hotel stay would be. The hotel had cute little cabins arranged around a central square and the room itself was comfy and warm. Our dinner was nice enough, although we had a bit of a Fawlty Towers moment with Ingrid’s chicken salad. First it went back because they didn’t leave the BBQ sauce off. Then it came back &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; tomatoes. And then back again with more BBQ sauce. Fourth time lucky.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A trip to Iceland. Part 2: Reykjavík to Flu∂ir.</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/a-trip-to-iceland-part-2-all-the-waterfalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/a-trip-to-iceland-part-2-all-the-waterfalls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;iceland-part-one&#34;&gt;After a day on foot in Reykjavík&lt;/a&gt;, and with some trepidation, we returned to the car for our drive through Iceland&amp;rsquo;s countryside. We started by heading out on route 1, which is like Iceland&amp;rsquo;s M25 except that it encircles an entire country &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; about thirty times fewer people. We went to house of Nobel Prize winner Halldór Laxness, only to be turned away because it was being renovated and wouldn&amp;rsquo;t open for another month. Undeterred, we pressed on toward &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%C3%9Eingvellir&#34;&gt;Þingvellir&lt;/a&gt;, stopping off on the way to take pictures at a viewpoint. It was just crazy, a flat expanse of undisturbed snow. Just as with the drive from the airport, the territory should have been relentlessly bleak but instead we got a winter wonderland.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A trip to Iceland. Part 1: Reykjavík.</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/a-trip-to-iceland-part-1-reykjavik/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/a-trip-to-iceland-part-1-reykjavik/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We arrived in Reykjavík a few days &lt;a href=&#34;https://weather.com/news/news/reykjavik-iceland-record-snowfall-february&#34;&gt;after a monumental snowstorm&lt;/a&gt;. As such the city was still under at least six inches of snow. We collected the hire car from the airport and drove out of Keflavik. The scenery normally looks like a moonscape, but for us it was a frosty white wonderland.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/iceland/iceland_01.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After about an hour&amp;rsquo;s drive, we arrived at the Hotel Nattura. From the outside it looks like a huge secondary school but as soon as you step inside it&amp;rsquo;s warm and comfortable. This is quite good when you&amp;rsquo;ve just parked next to a snow bank that&amp;rsquo;s two and half metres tall and then bambi&amp;rsquo;d it in over the icy paths with your luggage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A little trip to Italy</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/a-little-trip-to-italy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/a-little-trip-to-italy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We bought a cheap package holiday in the British Airways Black Friday sale. The weekend spanned Ingrid&amp;rsquo;s birthday, so it was ideal. £99 each for flights and a hotel, and we bagged a hire car quite cheaply too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Because our flight was from Heathrow and the trains from Chichester are both expensive and inconvenient for early flights, we spoiled ourselves with a taxi to the airport. It felt very strange to be whisked through the Sussex and Surrey countryside at six am on a Friday morning!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lausanne, Switzerland, March 2016</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/lausanne-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/lausanne-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just before Easter Ingrid and I went to Lausanne in Switzerland for a few days. It was a much-needed break and my first trip out of the UK since I got back from South America.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We caught an early train to Gatwick. It took a strange route along the coast via Worthing and Hove, which was annoying because we could have left later if a more direct train were available at that time of day. At least it wasn&#39;t late, which for Southern is really rare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
