<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eleven on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/eleven/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Eleven on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/eleven/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, December 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-december-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-december-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some rather brief pen pictures of this month’s albums. I’ve been a bit busy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Amber World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-amber-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-amber-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My earliest memory is waking up in Queen Alexandra hospital in Cosham after an operation on my ears. I must have been about four years old and it was the middle of the night. I was in a room on my own and the door was locked. It had been daylight only seconds before so I got out of the bed and walked to the window to look incredulously out at the amber world that lay beyond.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, November 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just three albums this month as I’ve been listening to a lot of Brian Eno records ready for an upcoming understated classic. First up is &lt;em&gt;50 Words For Snow&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;Kate Bush&lt;/strong&gt;, the second album that she has released this year. &lt;a href=&#34;album-digest-may-2011&#34;&gt;Back in May&lt;/a&gt; I wrote about &lt;em&gt;Director’s Cut&lt;/em&gt;, which presented re-recorded and re-mastered versions of songs from her albums &lt;em&gt;The Sensual World&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Red Shoes&lt;/em&gt;. This time around it is an album of brand new material, the first since &lt;em&gt;Aerial&lt;/em&gt; in 2006.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #14: Clear by Bomb The Bass</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think it’s time to discuss your philosophy of drug use as it relates to artistic endeavour…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contagion: A Short Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/contagion-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/contagion-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was much excitement about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1598778/&#34;&gt;Contagion&lt;/a&gt; at work. Finally a movie that explains  as part of the plot! A bunch of us went to see it, mainly to see whether &lt;a href=&#34;http://contagionmovie.warnerbros.com/index.html&#34;&gt;a disaster movie about a global pandemic&lt;/a&gt; could hold up as entertainment and to have a bit of a giggle if it couldn’t.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mark Rowlands, The Philosopher And The Wolf</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-philosopher-and-the-wolf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-philosopher-and-the-wolf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I saw that a friend had ‘liked’ this book on Facebook and reading about it on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Philosopher-Wolf-Lessons-Death-Happiness/dp/1847081029/&#34;&gt;amazon&lt;/a&gt;, I was curious enough to give it a go. It is the autobiography of the philosopher &lt;a href=&#34;http://rowlands.philospot.com/&#34;&gt;Mark Rowlands&lt;/a&gt;, specifically the experiences and lessons learned from raising a wolf, Brenin, from cub to maturity and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, October 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month we have albums by Björk, Coldplay, M83, and Radiohead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hmmm, a rather grey looking selection of covers this month. The albums I have listened to most are:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frank Herbert, Dune</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dune/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dune/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A week or so ago, I finished reading &lt;em&gt;Dune&lt;/em&gt; by Frank Herbert. It tells the story of a revolution within a Galactic Empire that takes place on a harsh and unforgiving desert planet called Arrakis. One central theme is how destinies can be shaped despite being intertwined around many axes. Another is the importance of adaptation in the fight for survival.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #13: U.F.Orb by The Orb</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FUN FACT:&lt;/strong&gt; It was because of the artwork to this album that I obsessively scrawled onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome on my pencil case at school. I also had a very passable u.f.orb logo drawn on it too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I bought a collection of electronic music this month. I mixed them all up in a smart playlist on iTunes, the smart aspect being to limit to tracks that had been played fewer than five then six then seven times etc. This made sure I was still listening to all the tracks equally often, despite the randomness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #12: Look Sharp! by Roxette</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-12/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five lessons from a year of blogging</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/five-lessons-from-a-year-of-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/five-lessons-from-a-year-of-blogging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have now been writing decent length articles on this site for about a year. I have learned a lot in this time, mostly about writing but also how to express your feelings and how to marshal your ideas and passions into action. For this month’s “five on the fifth”, I would like to share  with you some of the things I have learned.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, July 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quite a mixed bag this month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The News</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-news/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“I read the news today, oh boy”  (The Beatles, &lt;em&gt;A Day In The Life&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #11: Second Toughest In The Infants by Underworld</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-11/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Beta Test Of Everything</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-beta-test-of-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-beta-test-of-everything/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading a few articles about the recent launch of Google+, a few things hit home. Google tends to launch a product that works and not always one that is perfect or finished (like, say, Apple). Sometimes it takes them several iterations to get right. They love the beta tag. In fact, I think it was Google (or possibly Flickr) that made me aware of the concept of beta software.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Love The Jungle Book</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-i-love-the-jungle-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-i-love-the-jungle-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just as with the &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;understated classics&lt;/a&gt; I want to set out my stall early on that good movies are good enough. Both &lt;a href=&#34;why-i-love-betty-blue&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Betty Blue&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and today’s choice &lt;em&gt;The Jungle Book&lt;/em&gt; are never going to win any sort of consensus prize for the best movies ever made but they are really good. They also have a personal history attached that makes them worth writing about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maps And Charts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/maps-and-charts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/maps-and-charts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was growing up a framed print of a map hung on the wall in the hallway. It was one of my favourite things, littered with strange latin names and with Vs where Us should have been. The outlines of the continents and countries were all familiar and yet slightly distorted, becoming more recognisable around the shores of western Europe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have had the sort of month that is not conducive to listening to much new music. Therefore this month’s post is only going to consider two new albums and two albums that I have bought behind time. Because of various bits of stress and poor mood, I have ended up going back and taking refuge in some old favourites and not listening to new stuff. At other points I have also gone back to the Fleet Foxes’ album that I wrote about last month, which has grown on me even more since. Sometimes I think that I should writing about these albums on a two month delay. Meanwhile, I even have new music that I haven’t listened to &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt;, namely &lt;strong&gt;Bon Iver&lt;/strong&gt;’s self-titled album. It has received so many good reviews that I have been too intimidated to listen to it. I will try to write about it next month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #10: Tubular Bells II by Mike Oldfield</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was the artwork that got me interested in Tubular Bells II. Rendering Trevor Key&amp;rsquo;s wonderful icon of the twisted tubular bell in yellow and blue made it all the more mysterious. Seeing it one day in Woolworth&amp;rsquo;s in Leigh Park back in 1992 aroused my curiosity. The huge display must have been part of the massive publicity drive for the album. Despite dwindling sales for his albums at that time, a sequel to Tubular Bells represented a huge potential for sales. This is why Oldfield had been lured from his previous home at Virgin records over to Warner Music. At that point Oldfield had not made a good album since his soundtrack to the movie &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0087553/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Killing Fields&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in 1985, the end of a hot streak (perhaps 1980&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;QE2&lt;/em&gt; aside) that had lasted since the original &lt;em&gt;Tubular Bells&lt;/em&gt; back in 1973.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Favourite Numbers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/favourite-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/favourite-numbers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What’s your favourite number?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, Concrete Island</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/concrete-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/concrete-island/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, May 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Four albums this month:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kate Bush &lt;em&gt;Director’s Cut&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Africa Hitech &lt;em&gt;93 Million Miles&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fleet Foxes &lt;em&gt;Helplessness Blues&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;TV On The Radio &lt;em&gt;Nine Types of Light&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #9: Tiger Bay by Saint Etienne</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-9/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Superheroes We Can Live Without</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/five-superheroes-we-can-live-without/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/five-superheroes-we-can-live-without/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The other day while writing some rather self-pitying notes in my blog book (yes, I handwrite all this rubbish before I go to bed at night!) I came up with some useless superheroes, or rather the only superheroes that a washed-up guy in his early thirties could hope to be. Because I haven’t got any ideas for “five things on the fifth” this month, I decided to flesh out a few of these. Last month I began the five on the fifth meme with &lt;a href=&#34;five-things-to-try-when-you-cant-sleep&#34;&gt;five things to try if you can’t sleep&lt;/a&gt; and so this is a rather forced attempt to keep it going. I promise that I will try and think of more interesting posts on these lines for months.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, April 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2011/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Love Betty Blue</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-i-love-betty-blue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-i-love-betty-blue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I saw &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0090563/&#34;&gt;Betty Blue&lt;/a&gt; (original French title &lt;em&gt;37,2 Le Matin&lt;/em&gt;) for the first time in 1996 shortly after having read the book and it remains one of my favourite films to this day. Although there are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.co.uk/images?hl=en&amp;amp;source=hp&amp;amp;biw=1427&amp;amp;bih=1022&amp;amp;q=b%C3%A9atrice+dalle+betty+blue&amp;amp;gbv=2&amp;amp;aq=f&amp;amp;aqi=&amp;amp;oq=&amp;amp;uss=1&#34;&gt;many obvious reasons why&lt;/a&gt; a sixteen year old boy might like it, I think it does stand up to scrutiny beyond the sex and nudity. This post is a brief explanation of some of the obvious and not-so-obvious reasons why this is a film to be loved and cherished. (It was quite interesting to write this defence of a sexy film!)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Things To Try When You Can&#39;t Sleep</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/five-things-to-try-when-you-cant-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/five-things-to-try-when-you-cant-sleep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Facebook is wonderful for keeping in touch but I’ve noticed that quite a few of my friends tend to use it to tell the world that they can’t sleep. Here’s some advice for you if you find yourself unable to sleep one night. I’ve often had to try these out myself! Note that these are just things that work for me and your mileage may vary, particularly if you are fortunate enough to have a partner next to you! You may need to appease them if you wriggle around too much.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Favourite Culture Ship Names</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/favourite-culture-ship-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/favourite-culture-ship-names/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned before &lt;a href=&#34;more-books&#34;&gt;I am re-reading the novels of Iain Banks&lt;/a&gt; and this weekend I managed to finish &lt;em&gt;Consider Phlebas&lt;/em&gt;. A little post about it will be coming up soon. One of my favourite things about the Culture novels is how the ships are named and having found &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_ships_(The_Culture)&#34;&gt;a list on Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;, I thought I would share ten of my favourites with you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, March 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/this-is-not-an-album-digest-march-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/this-is-not-an-album-digest-march-2011/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More Books</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/more-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/more-books/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #8: Second Light by Dreadzone</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;understated classics&lt;/a&gt; series, I try to alternate between pop/rock and electronic albums. Keeping with this trend number eight is the wonderful dub-infused album &lt;em&gt;Second Light&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dreadzone.com&#34;&gt;Dreadzone&lt;/a&gt;. Released in 1996 it was well-received critically and four of its tracks featured on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/radio1/johnpeel/&#34;&gt;John Peel&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s best-of-year list that year. &lt;em&gt;Little Britain&lt;/em&gt; received a lot of radio play, a popular choice for that flag-waving period of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mojo4music.com/13834/the-story-of-britpop-in-60-albums/&#34;&gt;britpop&lt;/a&gt; and assorted other demons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, February 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;February, the shortest month, harbinger of such delights as Groundhog Day and Valentine’s Day. Could it possibly produce any good albums? Well the candidates are the eponymous début album by &lt;strong&gt;James Blake&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Zonoscope&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;Cut/Copy&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Let England Shake&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;PJ Harvey&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Smart Flesh&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;The Low Anthem&lt;/strong&gt;. Furthermore, there was an unexpected bonus when &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.radiohead.com/deadairspace/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Radiohead&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; announced that their new album would be out and available to listen to this month too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Out There Somewhere</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/out-there-somewhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/out-there-somewhere/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hurrah for more exoplanets &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.guardian.co.uk/science/2011/feb/02/new-planets-solar-system&#34;&gt;making the news&lt;/a&gt; this week. This time it is a star with a whole bunch of small planets very close to the star, usually they tend to be single gas giants larger even than &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jupiter&#34;&gt;Jupiter&lt;/a&gt; as this &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_exoplanetary_host_stars&#34;&gt;list of stars with exoplanets&lt;/a&gt; from Wikipedia shows.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Programming an UNO game, part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/programming-an-uno-game-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/programming-an-uno-game-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It turns out that programming the UNO game is not that complicated once you start designing the thing. This post will get the rules and game elements clear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, Crash</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/crash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/crash/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, January 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s to 2011 and the start of a monthly album digest. I want it to be a brief trot through some of the albums I have listened to each month. Sometimes January can bring a few quiet releases by big name bands. This happens if the previous album did not do as well as the record company hoped or if it is the kind of artist who would get lost under the hype of all the Christmas releases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Defence Of Tolerance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-defence-of-tolerance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-defence-of-tolerance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve found twitter to be a bit boring lately but today a perfect storm brew up and once again the Daily Mail and one of its odious columnists was at its centre. Melanie Phillips’ opinion piece was a perfectly constructed piece of trolling that implied that since the repeal of section 28, schools have been flooded with an influx of gay propaganda in subjects like maths, history and geography. Well I’m all for it, Alan Turing &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; a genius brutally mistreated by his country despite turning the second world war in favour of the allies - that story is maths and history is combined. Meanwhile, if you can spice up geography a bit go for it. I am not sure what you would do, discuss routes for pride marches? After all, the subject is hideously out of date now that we all have google maps on our phones.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #7: 100 Broken Windows by Idlewild</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Idewild are a solid band who have released four or five albums that I could consider for this series. I&amp;rsquo;m even in the sleeve credits of one: &lt;em&gt;Post-Electric Blues&lt;/em&gt;, if you&amp;rsquo;re asking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
