<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Album Digest on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/album-digest/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Album Digest on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 17:24:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/album-digest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Maara, The Ancient Truth (on vinyl)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/maara-the-ancient-truth-vinyl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/maara-the-ancient-truth-vinyl/</guid>
      <description>When I wrote about Maara&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Ancient Truth&amp;rdquo; over Christmas as part of my albums of the year rundown, I mentioned at the end that I would love to find a copy on vinyl to listen to. Well dear reader I managed to! It arrived today from the Netherlands with minimal fuss. It sounds great and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure whether my review did it justice: that&amp;rsquo;s the problem with attempting to (re-)review ten albums in ten days with Christmas and New Year all happening at the same time!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums: Honourable Mentions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-honourable-mentions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 13:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-honourable-mentions/</guid>
      <description>A quick list of ten other albums I considered to be among the best of last year. I either listened to these less, or in the cases of &amp;ldquo;Transmission Three&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Be Opened By The Wonderful&amp;rdquo; considered them to be ineligible as they are compilations.&#xA;Yves Tumor, &amp;ldquo;Praise a Lord Who Chews but Which Does Not Consume; (Or Simply, Hot Between Worlds)&amp;rdquo; Great album, recommended to me by Apple Music slinging the first track into my discovery feed back when that featured was added.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #1: Sofia Kourtesis, Madres</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-01-sofia-kourtesis-madres/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-01-sofia-kourtesis-madres/</guid>
      <description>Sofia Kourtesis is a Berlin-based Peruvian dance producer, &amp;ldquo;Madres&amp;rdquo; is her debut album which follows on from a 2021 EP &amp;ldquo;Fresia Magdalena&amp;rdquo;. It was trailed by several singles, including the title track which caught my attention back in May. The album is dedicated to her parents and there are also songs dedicated to the surgeon who performed life-saving surgery on Kourtesis’s mother. The whole album is a heady mix of positivity and dedication to both music and to family.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #2: James Holden, Imagine This is a High Dimensional Space of All Possibilities</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-02-james-holden-imagine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-02-james-holden-imagine/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Cool artwork! No, we don&amp;rsquo;t have it but it&amp;rsquo;s coming in next week.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Cool artwork! We haven&amp;rsquo;t had a copy in but I can order it for you.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Me picking it up a week later: &amp;ldquo;Cool artwork!&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Imagine This is a High Dimensional Space of All Possibilities&amp;rdquo; is definitely album title of the year, made all the more topical with the intrusion of Chat-GPT and the like into the cultural conversation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #3: Barry Can&#39;t Swim, When Will We Land?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-03-barry-cant-swim-when-will-we-land/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-03-barry-cant-swim-when-will-we-land/</guid>
      <description>Some albums you come to one way: a good review on a blog you respect, a track appearing on a playlist by someone whose taste you trust, etc and so on. And sometimes you get directed to something multiple times. This is what happened to me this year with the irrepressible “When Will We Land?” by Barry Can’t Swim. Anyway, tracks by &amp;ldquo;Barry&amp;rdquo; appeared in mixes a lot this year and the album kept popping up in eagerly anticipated lists.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #4: The National, &#34;First Two Pages of Frankenstein&#34; and &#34;Laugh Track&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-04-the-national-frankenstein-laugh-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-04-the-national-frankenstein-laugh-track/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s probably no surprise that as we reach the top four (or five if you like) we also get to the two albums The National released in 2023. The first, “First Two Pages of Frankenstein”, was trailed with a big reveal early on in the year, while the second, “Laugh Track”, was dropped all of a sudden in October. Once I got to know both albums, I swung between liking each one more for a while, hence putting them both at the same point in the list and not considering each separately.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #5: Nation of Language, Strange Disciple</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-05-nation-of-language-strange-disciple/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-05-nation-of-language-strange-disciple/</guid>
      <description>It would be remiss of me to claim that this is a placeholder for any number of (quite different sounding) song based albums that came out this year (Yves Tumor, Wilco to mention two) but it feels that way. This album came high up my list of listens because it&amp;rsquo;s a very good breakfast album, one to listen to while getting the Day started - though there are also some bangers on here too.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #6: Grails, Anches en Maat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-06-grails-anches-en-maat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-06-grails-anches-en-maat/</guid>
      <description>Grails are one of those bands who always get played a lot at my house. There&amp;rsquo;s something about their slow incremental instrumental pieces that my brain just loves to get lost in. Anches en Maat, their first album in six years or so, and the first with the entire band in the studio together since 2008, is their most Grails-y album in a long time.&#xA;On their last album Chalice Hymnal there were a lot of references to various band members&amp;rsquo; side projects like Watter and Lilacs &amp;amp; Champagne, along with continuations of pieces from earlier albums like Deep Politics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #7: Maara, The Ancient Truth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-07-maara-ancient-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-07-maara-ancient-truth/</guid>
      <description>There isn&amp;rsquo;t a great deal I can write about The Ancient Truth without sounding vague and anodyne. While I try to come think about different forms of music and go into some analysis of what makes one album more interesting than another, sometimes you end up just saying &amp;ldquo;this album is great because I like it and I always have a good time listening to it.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;The album has a late nineties early naughties kind of feel, all skittering breakbeats and chilly pads, but it also features a modern chill out vibe perhaps in keeping with recent reappraisals of music by artists like Enya.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #8: Everything But The Girl, Fuse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-08-ebtg-fuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-08-ebtg-fuse/</guid>
      <description>As you get older nostalgia becomes an ever important part of listening to music. It often feels like the business relies on convincing an aging population of fans to part with their money on new versions of old material. It&amp;rsquo;s nostalgia, the feeling of recapturing something you loved in your youth, that often makes this acceptable. Of course it&amp;rsquo;s also nice to get new music from your favourite bands, especially when it&amp;rsquo;s as good as &amp;ldquo;Fuse&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #9: Fever Ray, Radical Romantics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-09-fever-ray-radical-romantics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-09-fever-ray-radical-romantics/</guid>
      <description>Radical Romantics, the third album by Fever Ray was released in April. I bought a copy on red vinyl which is a beautiful sight to behold. I listened to a lot when it was released but eased up a bit until listening to it a couple more times while writing this list. It&amp;rsquo;s a great collection of songs, probably better than their second album &amp;ldquo;Plunge&amp;rdquo;. The cover art is just as scary though.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #10: Wata Igarashi, Agartha</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-10-wata-igarashi-agartha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-10-wata-igarashi-agartha/</guid>
      <description>Agartha is the debut album by Japanese electronic artist Wata Igarashi. I don&amp;rsquo;t really know much about him, but I do know that I enjoy releases on the German record label Kompakt and I have really enjoyed Japanese techno in recent years. Over lockdown I discovered Haruomi Hosono&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Polyharmony&amp;rdquo; album and re-discovered the work of Shinichi Atobe, particularly their album &amp;ldquo;Love of Plastic&amp;rdquo;. Both of those albums could be future understated classics and while both are by Japanese artists working in electronic music, there the comparison ends.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year Preview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/albums-of-the-year-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/albums-of-the-year-preview/</guid>
      <description>Another year (nearly) over and so starting from tomorrow, I&amp;rsquo;m going to count down my top 10 albums of 2023. The rules are:&#xA;They have to have to have been released in 2023. They need to be albums. I&amp;rsquo;m defining this as either more than 7 tracks or songs, or more than forty minutes in length. To make the top ten, they need to have been played the most times. I admit that I don&amp;rsquo;t have a precise measure of this, as I do still buy vinyl and about four of these albums will have had play counts missed by not being captured through a streaming service.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-2020/</guid>
      <description>I’ve listened to music in slightly different ways to normal in the last nine months, but it’s still been a decent year for music. When I checked out my Spotify Unwrapped and my Last.fm reports, I had listened to more 2020 music than I thought.&#xA;December Album of the month had to be &amp;ldquo;We Will Always Love You&amp;rdquo; by the Avalanches. One of only three albums that I bought physical copies of this year, it combines my favourite musical genres and has a novel take on the spacey-sounding album: like something beamed into space about how great humans are.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About the Album Digest</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/about-the-album-digest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 20:13:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/about-the-album-digest/</guid>
      <description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t written one of my monthly album digests for over a year. The reasons mostly boil down to a lack of time and motivation but other factors include the changing way in which I listen to music. I bought more albums on vinyl and only a small proportion of those were recently released music. Meanwhile, the attractions of Spotify&amp;rsquo;s release radar proved too great to resist: it is a very convenient way to consume new music.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, December 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-december-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-december-2017/</guid>
      <description>Bjork Utopia &amp;ldquo;Utopia&amp;rdquo; is Björk&amp;rsquo;s ninth album. It&amp;rsquo;s a happier album compared to the emotional wreckage of &amp;ldquo;Vulnicura&amp;rdquo;. But while &amp;ldquo;Vulnicura&amp;rdquo; was a compelling if uncomfortable listen, &amp;ldquo;Utopia&amp;rdquo; is more comfortable and, unfortunately, not that compelling. This is old ground retrodden with few glimmers of past glories.&#xA;The brevity, succinctness and sharpness are all gone. Even on the best songs (the first three), there is very little strength in the lyrics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, November 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2017/</guid>
      <description>00110100 01010100 &amp;ldquo;0181&amp;rdquo; This is a reissue of a Four Tet rarity from 2013 that has recently surfaced on Spotify under an alias1. &amp;ldquo;0181&amp;rdquo; collects a series of short experimental pieces from throughout his career, though I&amp;rsquo;m not enough of a nerd to know whether they are in any particular order. Last month&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;proper&amp;rsquo; Four Tet album &amp;ldquo;New Energy&amp;rdquo; has a lot more bounce to it, but &amp;ldquo;0181&amp;rdquo; nevertheless has some interesting moments that raises it above mere curiosity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, October 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2017/</guid>
      <description>Mary Epworth &amp;ldquo;Elytral&amp;rdquo; This album came to my attention because its lead single &amp;ldquo;Me Swimming&amp;rdquo; appeared on my Discover Weekly playlist. I&amp;rsquo;d never heard of Mary before but this album was one of those nice discoveries that one sometimes makes when one tries to broaden what one listens to. The aforementioned &amp;ldquo;Me Swimming&amp;rdquo; is probably the best track, a beautiful slice of summery experimental pop layered over a beat that you can imagine as the kicks of a swimmer compared to the swirling lyric that imitates the pull of the strokes through the water.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2017/</guid>
      <description>Note: Recent months have been very busy, so this album digest combines a review of the new album by The National with a couple of reviews left over from earlier in the year.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve written a few more album reviews in the past months but I&amp;rsquo;m so far behind (February and March have already been published on a considerable lag) that I&amp;rsquo;m just going to pepper forthcoming digests with additional reviews of older albums.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, March 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2017/</guid>
      <description>Blanck Mass World Eater This album is pretty extreme. It&amp;rsquo;s not for everyone and even for the people who can handle it, it&amp;rsquo;s not for all the time. This album is a soul crushing experience at points but there are also points of light. Perhaps this makes “World Eater” more reflective of life as a whole than any other of this month&amp;rsquo;s albums. On balance it&amp;rsquo;s probably less crushing than the last Blanck Mass album “Dumb Flesh”, which I reviewed back in June 2015.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, February 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2017/</guid>
      <description>Grails Chalice Hymnal Some albums are good because a band continues making the music that you love. Some albums are good because a band takes their ideas a step or two further than before. Chalice Hymnalis that rare album that does both of these things.&#xA;The references to past albums include the track Deeper Politics and Deep Snow II, and, as per albums past, these tracks evolve slowly out of languid guitar hooks and smoky atmospherics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, January 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2017/</guid>
      <description>Mike Oldfield Return to Ommadawn With Return to Ommadawn, Mike Oldfield revisits his third album Ommadawn. He has past form for this, having revisited his masterwork Tubular Bells twice (the third revisit and fourth instalment Tubular Bells 4 is due next year). I wrote about Tubular Bells II for my understated classics series. Of course Mike has in fact made many more than three Tubular Bells albums1, and this is not a first &amp;ldquo;return&amp;rdquo; to Ommadawn.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2016/</guid>
      <description>This month&amp;rsquo;s album digest features albums by Wilco, M.I.A., Local Natives, and a collaboration between Kaitlyn Aurelia Smith and Suzanne Ciani.&#xA;Wilco Schmilco Schmilco is the tenth studio album by Wilco, which regular readers will know are one of my favourite bands. There&amp;rsquo;s no need to repeat that anecdote about why this blog has the name that it does. Meanwhile, this album follows on from last year&amp;rsquo;s Star Wars and is probably the third Wilco album to have a jokey meta- kind of title.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2016/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned in yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post, I allowed Spotify to pick some new albums for me this month. It chose some noodly ambient techno, a captivating slice of World Jazz, a moody gothic hallucination, and a concept album about humans being rescued by aliens. All in all a pretty good job! Here is the list:&#xA;Prins Thomas &amp;ldquo;Principe del Norte&amp;rdquo; Sarathy Korwar &amp;ldquo;Day to Day&amp;rdquo; Doomsquad &amp;ldquo;Total Time&amp;rdquo; United Vibrations &amp;ldquo;The Myth of the Golden Ratio&amp;rdquo; Prins Thomas &amp;ldquo;Principe del Norte&amp;rdquo; Prins Thomas recently remixed the Orb&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Alpine EP&amp;rdquo; so I&amp;rsquo;m not surprised that Spotify included one of his tracks on my Discover Weekly playlist.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, July 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2016/</guid>
      <description>Album Digest July 2016 consists of a bumper five albums, mainly because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t work out which one to drop. I think they&amp;rsquo;re all pretty good though it&amp;rsquo;s great to hear new music from The Avalanches after all this time.&#xA;Bat For Lashes &amp;ldquo;The Bride&amp;rdquo; For her fourth album as Bat For Lashes, Natasha Khan applies her considerable songwriting skills to a concept album. She sings from the perspective of a bride whose husband dies on his way to their wedding.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2016/</guid>
      <description>Album Digest June 2016 is a poppy batch of albums. We have the return of my long-time favourites Roxette and the heroes of my South American tour Tegan &amp;amp; Sara. There&amp;rsquo;s some dance music in the form of Flume&amp;rsquo;s album &amp;ldquo;Skin&amp;rdquo;: an Australian presence ahead of the new Avalanches album next month. Finally there is the first of two new albums by Islands - both were released back in May but one gets reviewed this month and the other next month.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, May 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2016/</guid>
      <description>Album Digest May 2016 features the work of four bands or artists that I have reviewed in previous album digests. I also own (or will own) all of these albums on vinyl, so it&amp;rsquo;s handy that I&amp;rsquo;ve recently bought myself a record player!&#xA;Radiohead &amp;ldquo;A Moon Shaped Pool&amp;rdquo; Radiohead released &amp;ldquo;A Moon Shaped Pool&amp;rdquo; online about three weeks ago and a physical version hits the shops later in June. As with all of their recent albums, it is (mostly) a slow burner that rewards multiple listens.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, April 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2016/</guid>
      <description>This month&amp;rsquo;s album digest is a mixture of comparisons. First we compare the fortunes of old hands Underworld to even older hands the Pet Shop Boys. After that I&amp;rsquo;ve found two dance albums, one that I liked and one that I didn&amp;rsquo;t. I find it quite hard to write about dance music and so the comparison is quite useful. Sometimes it helps to work out why you like one thing and not another.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, David Bowie RIP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-special-david-bowie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-special-david-bowie/</guid>
      <description>I thought I&amp;rsquo;d add three of my favourite David Bowie albums to my review of Blackstar to a form an album digest tribute. Also among my favourites but not included here is &amp;ldquo;Outside&amp;rdquo;, which will be included in the understated classics (currently it&amp;rsquo;s number 66) at some point. I thought about bumping &amp;ldquo;Outside&amp;rdquo; up the running order but I&amp;rsquo;d like to be objective about it when its turn comes.&#xA;Station To Station &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not the side effects of the cocaine / I&amp;rsquo;m thinking it must be love&amp;rdquo; sings Bowie on the title track of his tenth studio album &amp;ldquo;Station To Station&amp;rdquo;, released in 1976.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Favourite Albums of 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/favourite-albums-of-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/favourite-albums-of-2015/</guid>
      <description>Given that I gave up on writing album digests for a bit this year, I thought I would at least do a proper top ten list of my favourite albums. There are quite a few albums that I did not have room for and I might try to revisit those later. In the mean time, let&amp;rsquo;s crack on. (To save time, I have in some instances pasted my original review from the appropriate album digest.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everything Everything, Get To Heaven</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/everything-everything-get-to-heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/everything-everything-get-to-heaven/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write honestly about your feelings. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write about your feelings consistently, for a living on a regular basis. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write about your feelings when the world constantly intrudes with inanity, insanity and hatred. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write under those conditions without seeming frayed, without coming loose at the edges.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Get To Heaven&amp;rdquo;, the third album by Everything Everything, was forged under these stresses and pressures.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2015/</guid>
      <description>To reboot this series, Album Digest June 2015 features five fantastic albums from Hot Chip, Jamie xx, Blanck Mass, Holly Herndon, and The Orb. I could pick loads more as I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to a lot of albums since February but I decided to focus on the more electronic material. This means that I have no excuses for not continuing next month with a rockier theme.&#xA;Hot Chip &amp;ldquo;Why Make Sense?&amp;rdquo; Hot Chip seem to be settling in to a pattern with their album releases, alternating between messy experimental affairs and then a state of the art correction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, February 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2015/</guid>
      <description>Aphex Twin &amp;ldquo;Computer Controlled Acoustic Instruments Pt2 EP&amp;rdquo; Aphex Twin follows SYRO (reviewed in Album Digest September 2014 here) with this 27 minute EP of music that, if we take the title literally, features computers playing acoustic musical instruments. It&amp;rsquo;s a very different sound to SYRO and sounds acoustic for the most part. It&amp;rsquo;s an important experiment about the role of the musician, one that is already blurred in the creation of electronic music.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, January 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2015/</guid>
      <description>Album Digest January 2015 rounds up a few albums from the tail end of 2014 that I didn&amp;rsquo;t get much time to write about. The only one of these six to be released this month is the excellent &amp;ldquo;No Cities To Love&amp;rdquo; by Sleater-Kinney.&#xA;Sleater-Kinney &amp;ldquo;No Cities To Love&amp;rdquo; I had heard of Sleater-Kinney before their boxed set “Start Together” was released in 2014. I was quite impressed that they curated their own Spotify playlist with the contents of the box.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2014/</guid>
      <description>Album Digest September 2014 contains four amazing albums, including the long-awaited return from the Aphex Twin, and an album from Cymbals Eat Guitars released about a week after I wondered what had happened to them. Spooky. Rounding out the selection this month are a cool punky-disco album by The Juan Maclean and a truly remarkable offering by Vessel.&#xA;Aphex Twin SYRO SYRO is the sixth album by Aphex Twin and his first official Aphex Twin release since Drukqs in 2001.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2014/</guid>
      <description>The album digest returns with five albums by four artists.&#xA;Karl Hyde &amp;amp; Brian Eno Someday World &amp;amp; HIGH-LIFE Lone Reality Testing FKA twigs LP1 Mogwai Come On Die Young: Appendix Karl Hyde &amp;amp; Brian Eno Someday World &amp;amp; HIGH-LIFE I’m a big fan of both Karl Hyde’s work with Underworld and of Brian Eno’s stuff so Someday World seemed like a dream collaboration to me when it was released last May.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2014/</guid>
      <description>Watter are a &amp;ldquo;supergroup&amp;rdquo; composed from various members of Grails, Slint, and other bands. I did not know anything about Hundred Waters before this month: &amp;ldquo;The Moon Rang Like A Bell&amp;rdquo; is their second album. In fact second albums by bands I know nothing about are a something of theme because &amp;ldquo;Sunbathing Animal&amp;rdquo; is Parquet Courts&amp;rsquo; sophomore effort and I don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about them either. Meanwhile, I&amp;rsquo;ve meant to write about &amp;ldquo;The Four Seasons Recomposed&amp;rdquo; since April.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, May 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2014/</guid>
      <description>This month was strange. I didn’t listen to much new music and after last month’s bumper digest there’s probably a reason for that. Not to mention that Spotify gives you more reasons to look backwards than forwards. Nevertheless, this brief post features new albums by Little Dragon and Coldplay, along with the mini-album collaboration between Röyskopp and Robyn.&#xA;Little Dragon “Nabuma Rubberband” I discovered Little Dragon, like most people, I imagine, via Gorillaz’ “Plastic Beach” album.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, March 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2014/</guid>
      <description>I’m back in the UK so it’s back to posts about albums each month. This one is a bit different because I didn’t listen to very much new stuff while I was away so not all of the albums are up to date. I had to write about the new album by Liars though because it&amp;rsquo;s awesome and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait to discuss it! Here’s the list of albums:&#xA;Tegan and Sarah Heartthrob Fanfarlo Let&amp;rsquo;s Go Extinct Liars Mess London Grammar If You Wait Tegan and Sarah Heartthrob I would argue, as I have throughout my sequence of understated classics posts, that a great album is one that changes you as a person.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, October 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2013/</guid>
      <description>Four great albums this month for the last album digest in a while.&#xA;CHVRCHES &amp;ldquo;The Bones Of What You Believe&amp;rdquo; I first got into CHVRCHES on Record Store Day, one of my purchases was an Irn Bru coloured 12&amp;quot; of the Recover EP that, according to eBay, tripled in value over night. Judging by this, their full debut, my see-through orange slab of happiness may hold its value, because it&amp;rsquo;s clear that CHVRCHES should be around for the long haul.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2013/</guid>
      <description>A nice diverse selection of albums this month:&#xA;Arctic Monkeys &amp;ldquo;AM&amp;rdquo; BT &amp;ldquo;A Song Across Wires&amp;rdquo; Goldfrapp &amp;ldquo;Tales of Us&amp;rdquo; Janelle Monáe &amp;ldquo;Electric Lady&amp;rdquo; Arctic Monkeys &amp;ldquo;AM&amp;rdquo; This whole review is basically me catching up with the rest of the world and realising that the Arctic Monkeys are ace. To be fair, I did notice how awesome they were at the opening ceremony of the Olympics last year, and I have liked the odd one or two of their singles, but up until now I haven&amp;rsquo;t really wanted to listen to any of their albums.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2013/</guid>
      <description>For reasons that will become apparent, there will be a short period soon where I will not be writing album digests. Until then, I&amp;rsquo;m clearing a backlog of some albums that I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to but haven&amp;rsquo;t had enough time or motivation to write about. Only one of this month&amp;rsquo;s albums was released this month, something that&amp;rsquo;s not that uncommon at this time of the year as it is not the best time to release things.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, July 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2013/</guid>
      <description>Another four albums for you this month. Sometimes the problem is not finding albums to listen to but actually finding time to listen to them! Often it is not because I don&amp;rsquo;t have time but because I have already found some great albums this month and I am busy listening to those instead. As a result, a couple of these albums are ones that I have only listened to for a week or so, but they are interesting enough to write about.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2013/</guid>
      <description>Just two albums this month as I am still enjoying last month&amp;rsquo;s albums so much (and I spent loads of time getting reacquainted with Boards Of Canada at the start of the month). I listened to a few more albums but not often enough to write loads about them so there is an &amp;ldquo;honourable mention&amp;rdquo; section at the end of the post that briefly discusses a few more albums.&#xA;Without further ado, the two albums are:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, May 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2013/</guid>
      <description>Lilacs &amp;amp; Champagne Danish &amp;amp; Blue You might remember that last year I reviewed the first Lilacs &amp;amp; Champagne album and I liked it a lot. This album sees them back with more of the same: taking the approach that if it ain&amp;rsquo;t broke, don&amp;rsquo;t fix it. There are very few changes to the formula apart from the fact that the spoken word samples are not quite as good this time and there&amp;rsquo;s a bit more Grails-like guitar solo action.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, April 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2013/</guid>
      <description>Some great albums this month!&#xA;The Flaming Lips The Terror Wire Change Becomes Us James Blake Overgrown The Knife Shaking The Habitual The Flaming Lips The Terror How you view The Terror pretty much depends on how much you have kept up with The Flips output since their last official album, the clanking double behemoth in Merkin packaging that was Embryonic. The irony being that I used Embryonic to deal with a break-up and The Terror is pretty much about&amp;hellip; a break-up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, March 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2013/</guid>
      <description>Just the David Bowie album this month as it’s pretty much the only new music that I’ve listened to.&#xA;I must admit that I had no idea what to expect of “The Next Day”. It comes almost exactly ten years after “Reality”, an album that I have never really got into despite it having some pretty decent fun tracks like “New Killer Star” and a nice cover of “Pablo Picasso” that has never sent me in search of Jonathan Richman’s original.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, February 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2013/</guid>
      <description>Most Februaries are quite quiet when it comes to albums (though this was not the case back in 2011) and although only the Foals album is a major release, I was quite surprised to find myself with four decent albums to write about. They are:&#xA;Darkstar &amp;ldquo;News From Nowhere&amp;rdquo; Foals &amp;ldquo;Holy Fire&amp;rdquo; Daniel Hope &amp;ldquo;Spheres&amp;rdquo; Apparat &amp;ldquo;Krieg und Frieden (Music For Theatre)&amp;rdquo; Darkstar &amp;ldquo;News From Nowhere&amp;rdquo; I don&amp;rsquo;t need to give too much biographical background for the Darkstar album as I don&amp;rsquo;t know too much about who the are.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, January 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2013/</guid>
      <description>Only one of this month three albums was actually released this month. Nelly Furtado&amp;rsquo;s Mi plan was actually released over three years ago - I only discovered it last year when I wrote the September album digest following the release of &amp;ldquo;The Spirit Indestructible&amp;rdquo;, or it might have been when I wrote about &amp;ldquo;Folklore&amp;rdquo; at around the same time.&#xA;Anyway, I guess these are albums that I bought with my Christmas gift vouchers!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, December 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-december-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-december-2012/</guid>
      <description>Three albums (one very Christmassey one!) and an EP this month.&#xA;Tracey Thorn “Tinsel and Lights” Woob “Have Landed” Tim Hecker and Daniel Lopatin “Instrumental Tourist” Burial “Truant / Rough Sleeper Tracey Thorn “Tinsel and Lights” “Tinsel and Lights” is that rarest of records, a Christmas record that is perfectly suited to the season and is not in any way overbearing or irritating. Most albums that are Christmas themed are usually centred on lots of covers that are taken from a small subset of well worn classics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, November 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2012/</guid>
      <description>Pretty much a sliding scale between songs and electronic wibble on this month’s albums and a particularly damp, chilly feeling to proceedings too.&#xA;Bat For Lashes “The Haunted Man” Ital “Hive Mind” and “Dream On” Björk “Bastards” Brian Eno “Lux” Bat For Lashes “The Haunted Man” When it comes to Bat For Lashes, I prefer her first album “Fur And Gold” to her second “Two Suns” because when I listen to the latter I don’t feel connected to any of the songs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, October 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2012/</guid>
      <description>It has been a strange month and I found that I didn’t listen to a lot of new music. I have been a bit down and when that’s the case I tend to take refuge in music that I know well, stuff that cheers me up. I have listened to last month’s fave a lot, Nelly Furtado’s “The Spirit Indestructible”. I said a lot of nice things about it but it probably didn’t come over in my writing just how much I really liked it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2012/</guid>
      <description>I had a bit more time to listen to this month’s albums because I was on holiday for two weeks. I didn’t manage to write about them while on holiday though! In fact I bought and listened to a few more, but I will save them for next month. The albums I will discuss now (in order bought) are:&#xA;Four Tet “Pink” The xx “Coexist” Nelly Furtado “The Spirit Indestructible” Grizzly Bear “Shields” It’s quite a diverse collection and, Four Tet apart, quite song based.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2012/</guid>
      <description>Album Digest August 2012 is also from the stack of albums that I mentioned last month. I chose this selection (along with the Passion Pit album) because the colours looked good together in the mosaic of covers that I make each month. Last month’s digest was about the right amount of detail so this will be another briefer digest. These are all good albums but not ones that will change your life, they&amp;rsquo;ll just happily sit alongside it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, July 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2012/</guid>
      <description>Just a short album digest this month. I bought a stack of CDs and am parcelling them out over the next few months (together with important additional releases as they crop up). This is in the hope that I can write more considered pieces about each one. This month I’ve grouped together albums with monochrome covers and a BT album from June that I found out about recently. These albums are not just linked by their artwork, they also form a cohesive whole.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2012/</guid>
      <description>Three fantastic albums for Album Digest June 2012:&#xA;Saint Etienne Words and Music by Saint Etienne Liars WIXIW Hot Chip In Our Heads This month is a curious selection in that the albums are all by bands that I already own a few records by. When there is so much other directly related material that you can write about, it makes focussing on the album in hand quite difficult. I am always thinking up rankings and comparisons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, May 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2012/</guid>
      <description>Four albums for Album Digest May 2012:&#xA;Jack White Blunderbuss One Little Plane Into The Trees Beach House Bloom Oxia Tides Of Mind The April album digest was rather short on songs, so this month I decided to look for albums that were more based around songs not tracks. Electronic music is relatively easy to write about: the music is often simple (but not always), there are recognisable structures and genres (but not always), and there are conventions that are adhered to (but not always).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, April 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2012/</guid>
      <description>A mostly instrumental month with a comeback from Orbital, an excellent remix collection from Battles, an amazing movie documenting a live performance by the Chemical Brothers and Austin Wintory’s soundtrack to the game Journey.&#xA;Orbital Wonky Battles Dross Glop The Chemical Brothers Don’t Think Austin Wintory Journey (Original Soundtrack) Orbital Wonky I am quite keen on Orbital, though perhaps not as keen as I am on the similarly named Orb. I think I have got all the Orbital albums, mostly bought on eBay after the fact.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, March 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-march-2012/</guid>
      <description>Five albums for Album Digest March 2012&#xA;Fanfarlo Rooms Filled With Light The Shins Port Of Morrow Grails Deep Politics New Build Yesterday Was Lived And Lost Scuba Personality A nice collection of albums this month - things usually pick up in March after a slow period after Christmas. One of these is a “catch-up” (the album by Grails) but apart from that one, everything else was released in the last five weeks or so… I should probably have included the album by Racehorses that I bought on my birthday but I will have to leave that for next month as I haven’t listened to it that much.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, February 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2012/</guid>
      <description>One EP and three albums for Album Digest February 2012:&#xA;Burial Kindred EP John Talabot fIN Lilacs &amp;amp; Champagne Lilacs &amp;amp; Champagne The 2 Bears Be Strong Last February was a pretty good month for song based albums, although the likes of Radiohead and James Blake provided plenty of electronic noodling in and around their song structures. (Interestingly, out of the two out-and-out song based albums, one was one of the worst albums of the year and the other one of the best).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, January 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2012/</guid>
      <description>Five albums to see in the new year:&#xA;FOE “Bad Dream Hotline” Leila “U &amp;amp; I” Diagrams “Black Light” Pyramids &amp;amp; Horseback “A Throne Without A King” FabricLive 61 mixed by Pinch FOE Bad Dream Hotline I listened to “Bad Dream Hotline” about four times thinking “who does her voice remind me of?”. In the end I realised it was Sophie Ellis-Bextor, though in parts she sounds like KT Tunstall too.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, December 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-december-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-december-2011/</guid>
      <description>Some rather brief pen pictures of this month’s albums. I’ve been a bit busy!&#xA;Radio Slave - Collected Remixes Thud thud thud. This is pretty much how all Radio Slave remixes go. I really liked his fabric mix and borrowed a few tracks for a playlist I made called &amp;ldquo;Dancing In Space&amp;rdquo;. Anyway, back to the thudding: it’s no bad thing, the remixes have a nice formula that works well for discovering new tracks like UNKLE’s Burn My Shadow (Ian Astbury’s vocal is given plenty of room to shine) and K3’s Play To Win.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, November 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2011/</guid>
      <description>Just three albums this month as I’ve been listening to a lot of Brian Eno records ready for an upcoming understated classic. First up is 50 Words For Snow by Kate Bush, the second album that she has released this year. Back in May I wrote about Director’s Cut, which presented re-recorded and re-mastered versions of songs from her albums The Sensual World and The Red Shoes. This time around it is an album of brand new material, the first since Aerial in 2006.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, October 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2011/</guid>
      <description>This month we have albums by Björk, Coldplay, M83, and Radiohead.&#xA;Album Digest October 2011 - Intro I listened to Wilco’s The Whole Love again the other day. I happened to be walking past the venue in Portsmouth where I went to see them live back in 2004 and it seemed the right fit. I really enjoyed the album after a period of not having listened to it and I found that being familiar with the songs allowed me to better appreciate the production of the album.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2011/</guid>
      <description>Hmmm, a rather grey looking selection of covers this month. The albums I have listened to most are:&#xA;John Beltran Ambient Selections FabricLive 59 mixed by Four Tet The Rapture In The Grace Of Your Love Wilco The Whole Love I have actually only had the Wilco album since Monday of this week (the 26th) but it has inveigled its way into my consciousness quite quickly. As I have said before, this blog owes its name to a Wilco song and they are quite an important band to me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2011/</guid>
      <description>I bought a collection of electronic music this month. I mixed them all up in a smart playlist on iTunes, the smart aspect being to limit to tracks that had been played fewer than five then six then seven times etc. This made sure I was still listening to all the tracks equally often, despite the randomness.&#xA;Biosphere N-plants Ford &amp;amp; Lopatin Channel Pressure Gus Gus Arabian Horse Instra:Mental Resolution 653 Jon Tejada Parabolas Biosphere N-Plants I think this album makes Biosphere the most reviewed musician on this blog at the moment but I don’t mind too much, he makes some great stuff.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, July 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2011/</guid>
      <description>Quite a mixed bag this month.&#xA;SBTRKT SBTRKT Zomby Dedication Brian Eno Drums Between The Bells Bon Iver Bon Iver Washed Out Within and Without This month’s collection of albums is a rather mellow bunch. The SBTRKT album (self-titled) is probably the most frenetic of the five though even that does not exactly pound four to the floor. Most of it is pretty calm, though the occasional burst of pop to spice things up: sometimes it is as downtempo as the rest (Right Thing To Do and Trials Of The Past) but at other times things spark into life, as on Pharaohs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2011/</guid>
      <description>I have had the sort of month that is not conducive to listening to much new music. Therefore this month’s post is only going to consider two new albums and two albums that I have bought behind time. Because of various bits of stress and poor mood, I have ended up going back and taking refuge in some old favourites and not listening to new stuff. At other points I have also gone back to the Fleet Foxes’ album that I wrote about last month, which has grown on me even more since.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, May 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-may-2011/</guid>
      <description>Four albums this month:&#xA;Kate Bush Director’s Cut Africa Hitech 93 Million Miles Fleet Foxes Helplessness Blues TV On The Radio Nine Types of Light There is a pleasing red hue to all the covers this month. I had time to write four full reviews of the major albums I listened to. Like last month I have included a video at the foot of each review. Enjoy!&#xA;Kate Bush Director’s Cut Director’s Cut is not a new album from Kate Bush but a collection of re-visits to old songs, four from The Sensual World (1989) and seven from [The Red Shoes](http://en.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, April 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-april-2011/</guid>
      <description>Album of the month: Mirrorwriting by Jamie Woon Jamie Woon was brought to my attention late last year by Pitchfork who wrote an article about the video for lead single Night Air. I’ve put that video down below because I think that it is very good, a simple well executed and the tune itself is brilliant, probably my favourite individual track of 2010. It’s a downtempo tune full of dark spaces and empty beats, full of nocturnal promise and mystery.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, March 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/this-is-not-an-album-digest-march-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/this-is-not-an-album-digest-march-2011/</guid>
      <description>This is not an Album Digest March 2011 Well as I said at the end of last month’s album digest post, I took a bit of a break from pursuing new music quite as closely as I have been. As promised, I sidestepped the new R.E.M. and Elbow albums - although I had been promised the latter as a birthday present it is yet to show up, maybe I will look at in April.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, February 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2011/</guid>
      <description>February, the shortest month, harbinger of such delights as Groundhog Day and Valentine’s Day. Could it possibly produce any good albums? Well the candidates are the eponymous début album by James Blake, Zonoscope by Cut/Copy, Let England Shake by PJ Harvey and Smart Flesh by The Low Anthem. Furthermore, there was an unexpected bonus when Radiohead announced that their new album would be out and available to listen to this month too.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, January 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2011/</guid>
      <description>Here’s to 2011 and the start of a monthly album digest. I want it to be a brief trot through some of the albums I have listened to each month. Sometimes January can bring a few quiet releases by big name bands. This happens if the previous album did not do as well as the record company hoped or if it is the kind of artist who would get lost under the hype of all the Christmas releases.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
