<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Understated Classics on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/understated-classics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Understated Classics on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/understated-classics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #39: Lifeforms by Future Sound of London</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-39/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-39/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lifeforms&lt;/strong&gt; is the 1994 album from the Future Sound of London. A double album (just), it also features the talents of Robert Fripp, Ozric Tentacles, Talvin Singh, Toni Halliday, and Liz Frazer. It reached number 6 on the UK album chart and went silver.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have wanted to write about the &lt;strong&gt;Lifeforms&lt;/strong&gt; album for a long time. In 2012, I even tried learning how to tell the tracks apart from one another. It was not a success. Ten years later, I know some of them but not all. I know all the music, of course, but the album as a whole resists my trainspotter-like urge to identify the margins and components of every track.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics Or Not?</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-or-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-or-not/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the new year, thoughts and spare time for writing point me toward writing some new posts for my understated classics series. Expect some new ones soon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I also reflected on my previous choices and thought a bit about how my music tastes have changed recently. Some of this has to do with streaming and the frustrations I wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/a-pox-on-both-their-houses&#34;&gt;in my last post&lt;/a&gt;. Some of it is just down to getting older: I have less time to listen to new music, and much of the &amp;rsquo;new&amp;rsquo; stuff I listen to is me investigating the stuff I missed first time around. Who knew Art of Noise were so good? Not me, but I do now!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #38: Trance Nation (Various Artists)</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-38/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-38/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, but lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been in need of some music that:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Blots out the outside world&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Helps me to concentrate on my work&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Makes me feel a bit less anxious about the state of the world&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, allow me to submit the compilation Trance Nation for your consideration as an understated classic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But Matt I&amp;rsquo;ve heard trance music, I hear you say, and it&amp;rsquo;s one of the least understated forms of music possible. Yes, dear reader, we &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; talking about that borderline obnoxious musical form with the thudding beats and the tinkly high synth lines. Indeed, it is a genre that has grown and eaten itself, and the rest of pop music along with it. The &amp;ldquo;give it a drop or go home&amp;rdquo; mentality that infects modern pop musics originates in Trance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #37: Lost Souls by Doves</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-37/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Doves are a band from Manchester who traded dance music for rock yet never left their former genre behind. Starting out as Sub Sub, they scored a worldwide hit in 1993 with &amp;ldquo;Ain&amp;rsquo;t No Love (Ain&amp;rsquo;t No Use)&amp;rdquo;: a timeless dance tune that immediately owns whatever room it plays in. However, subsequent releases by Sub Sub did not catch on and people started to think of the band as a one-hit wonder.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #36: The Coral by The Coral</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-36/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-36/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Perhaps in today&amp;rsquo;s modern age of streaming and such, &lt;a href=&#34;http://thecoral.co.uk&#34;&gt;The Coral&lt;/a&gt; would be a bigger band and may have survived their eventual burnout. Their work ethic was evident from the start, as rumours swirled &lt;a href=&#34;https://i.ebayimg.com/images/g/YdkAAOSwfl9XBSiR/s-l300.jpg&#34;&gt;in the NME&lt;/a&gt; about a fantastic new band from Liverpool who were going to blow everybody&amp;rsquo;s socks off. I went to see them live in Bristol after they&amp;rsquo;d released three EPs and they were incredible. Their sound, a bit like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0071615/&#34;&gt;the movie &amp;ldquo;Holy Mountain&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; set to pop music, imagined a Merseybeat channelled from an alternative universe in which Lennon and McCartney took their acid in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.desertusa.com/mojave-desert.html&#34;&gt;the Mojave desert&lt;/a&gt; rather than in the English suburbs. Yes, it was derivative but somehow it also managed to be utterly new and compelling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #35: Snivilisation by Orbital</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-35/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I came late to Orbital&amp;rsquo;s work. I knew of them through a few remixes and because as a mad Orb fan, they could not have avoided my notice could they? Apart from that, one of my college friends tried to get me into &amp;ldquo;In Sides&amp;rdquo; just after its release in 1996. The same friend got me into &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/understated-classics-11/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Second Toughest In The Infants&amp;rdquo; by Underworld&lt;/a&gt;. I cannot now understand the reason, but &amp;ldquo;In Sides&amp;rdquo; just left me cold.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #34: Stray by Aztec Camera</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-34/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next instalment in my understated classics series is &amp;quot;Stray&amp;quot; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://killermontstreet.net&#34;&gt;Aztec Camera&lt;/a&gt;. Released in 1990, it features two hit singles and the cover is my favourite colour: green.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My angle for writing about “Stray” was that it was an album that I &amp;quot;caught&amp;quot; from my parents. I soon realised that I wrote about some of those already, for example “The Circle and the Square&amp;quot; by Red Box. Besides, I’m not sure that my parents liked this album that much.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #33: Embrya by Maxwell</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-33/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I give the impression of planning these posts but to be honest I came across an article about Maxwell a few weeks ago and fondly remembered my cassette copy of this album. The joy of Spotify is that it&amp;rsquo;s easy to dig up old favourites. The recent warm weather makes for a good opportunity to enjoy the sultry embrace of &amp;ldquo;Embrya&amp;rdquo; once more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Gestation: Mythos&amp;rdquo; burbles along for two and a half minutes, overlaying spoken word samples, string phrases and weird underwater noises, before the bass line of &amp;ldquo;Everwanting: To Want You To Want&amp;rdquo; brings things to life. Over a sinuous and aquatic background, Maxwell delivers a smooth and soulful vocal. As you might guess from the title, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely one for your late nights and warm evenings playlist. I love the way that the song takes its time: it knows where it needs to go, it knows how to get there, and damned if it isn&amp;rsquo;t going to enjoy itself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #32: They Were Wrong So We Drowned by Liars</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-32/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As it is Halloween, I&amp;rsquo;m writing about a spooky understated classic. Liars&amp;rsquo; second album &amp;ldquo;They Were Wrong, So We Drowned&amp;rdquo; is a concept album about witches. It was the first of their albums that I owned having heard their name mentioned among those in the New York Post-punk revival scene at the start of the 00s.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I imagine that to most ears a first listen to &amp;ldquo;They Were Wrong, So We Drowned&amp;rdquo; sounds dreadful. I certainly thought so. It&amp;rsquo;s a short album and if you plough through it there are one or two nuggets that would sound great on most albums - but a lot of it initially seems to be noise and chanting and screaming. If anyone wants to make the argument that Liars are not worth the trouble, not worth the effort to like or understand, then &amp;ldquo;They Were Wrong, So We Drowned&amp;rdquo; is the album they will use as ammunition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #31: The White Room by The KLF</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-31/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This little masterpiece was released in 1991. I got my copy on cassette for Christmas that year, but by May in 1992 they&amp;rsquo;d already &amp;ldquo;retired&amp;rdquo; and split up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The KLF were a band in the right place at the right time with the right idea. Taking advantage of synthesizers and the idea of fusing rock and pop music with the emerging sound of house music, they laid the ground for many of the most successful electronic acts that followed them. They were also master showmen, taking a whole host of crazy conspiracy theories and smooshing them together in one stadium-sized package.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #30: Our Aim Is to Satisfy by Red Snapper</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The thirtieth understated classic is by a band named after a fish. There isn&amp;rsquo;t a great deal for me to say about &amp;ldquo;Our Aim Is To Satisfy&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; apart from the usual insistence that it is quite good. There&amp;rsquo;s no overarching theme to write about, and no deep personal story attached. It was bound to happen eventually.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our Aim Is To Satisfy&amp;rdquo; is one of those albums spawned in the late nineties and early naughties at the height of the Electronica boom: dance music that you didn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily have to dance to. It&amp;rsquo;s not quite chill out music but nor is it song-based (for the most part) - it&amp;rsquo;s mainly instrumental electronic music.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #29: Let It Come Down by Spiritualized</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I listened to Let It Come Down by Spiritualized for the first time during a difficult time in my life. I think this will always affect my feelings towards it. For me it&amp;rsquo;s a great big comfort blanket of a record. Coming after one of the all-time best break-up albums (in an artistic sense) in &amp;ldquo;Ladies and Gentlemen We Are Floating in Space&amp;rdquo; perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s not that much of a surprise. Layered in orchestras, horn sections, and gospel choirs, it&amp;rsquo;s not understated at all but hopefully I can persuade you that it is a classic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #28: The Meadowlands by The Wrens</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-28/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the first lines of &amp;ldquo;The House That Guilt Built&amp;rdquo;, the soft cricket-laden lament that opens The Meadowlands by The Wrens, is &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m nowhere near where I thought I&amp;rsquo;d be&amp;rdquo;. The last line of the whole album is &amp;ldquo;this is not what you had planned&amp;rdquo;. These bookending lines set the tone for this shimmering, ramshackle masterpiece - a fatigue and careworn pride in failing to meet impossible standards writ large over its first and last eighty or so seconds. &amp;ldquo;The Meadowlands&amp;rdquo; is probably the best record you&amp;rsquo;ve never heard, and once you have heard it, you will never be the same. Even better, it changes and you change with every single listen. If you&amp;rsquo;re living your life and you really mean it, then this is the record for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #27: A Ghost Is Born by Wilco</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;whatever-happened-to-that-hat&#34;&gt;I have already given some of the personal background to why I love this album&lt;/a&gt; and now it’s time to give a bit of love to the music itself so I’ll stick to giving a track by track account of “A Ghost Is Born”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are familiar with Wilco’s first few albums, you’ll know that A Ghost Is Born is on the line of best fit through Being There, Summerteeth, and Yankee Hotel Foxtrot. It continues its predecessor’s experimentation, but also gets reined in a little. Great songs - some of my favourite Wilco songs - were left off Yankee Hotel Foxtrot (“&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bemydemon.org/songs/venus.htm&#34;&gt;Venus Stopped The Train&lt;/a&gt;”, “&lt;a href=&#34;http://wilcoworld.net/#!/song/a-magazine-called-sunset/&#34;&gt;A Magazine Called Sunset&lt;/a&gt;”) so the follow-up could easily have been more of the same and everyone would have gone home happy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #26: Come On Die Young by Mogwai</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you about punk rock: punk rock is a word used by dilettantes and ah&amp;hellip; and ah&amp;hellip; heartless manipulators about music that takes up the energies and the bodies and the hearts and the souls and the time and the minds of young men who give what they have to it and give everything they have to it and it&amp;rsquo;s a&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s a term that&amp;rsquo;s based on contempt, it&amp;rsquo;s a term that&amp;rsquo;s based on fashion, style, elitism, satanism and everything that&amp;rsquo;s rotten about rock &amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo; roll. I don&amp;rsquo;t know &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/John_Lydon&#34;&gt;Johnny Rotten&lt;/a&gt; but I&amp;rsquo;m sure&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m sure he puts as much blood and sweat into what he does as &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Sigmund_Freud&#34;&gt;Sigmund Freud&lt;/a&gt; did. You see, what sounds to you like a big load of trashy old noise is in fact the brilliant music of a genius, myself . And that music is so powerful that it&amp;rsquo;s quite beyond my control and ah&amp;hellip; when I&amp;rsquo;m in the grips of it I don&amp;rsquo;t feel pleasure and I don&amp;rsquo;t feel pain, either physically or emotionally. Do you understand what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about? Have you ever felt like that? When you just couldn&amp;rsquo;t feel anything and you didn&amp;rsquo;t want to either. You know? Like that? Do you understand what I&amp;rsquo;m saying sir? (Iggy Pop, Canadian TV, March 11th 1977.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #25: Long Gone Before Daylight by The Cardigans</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The single biggest fact of life is that you are always going to be alone, you just might not realise it. Listening to The Cardigans&amp;rsquo; excellent 2003 &amp;ldquo;Long Gone Before Daylight&amp;rdquo; will help you see that all our relationships are essentially screwed &amp;ndash; but at least it sounds great while it does so.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Long Gone Before Daylight&amp;rdquo; (&amp;ldquo;Long Gone Before Daylight&amp;rdquo;) plays the role of &amp;ldquo;The Empire Strikes Back&amp;rdquo; in a trilogy of great albums that The Cardigans released between 1999 (the arguably better and slightly happier &amp;ldquo;Gran Turismo&amp;rdquo;) and 2006 (the unarguably inferior and definitely happier &amp;ldquo;Super Extra Gravity&amp;rdquo;). &amp;ldquo;Long Gone Before Daylight&amp;rdquo; has more of a country sound than &amp;ldquo;Gran Turismo&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Super Extra Gravity&amp;rdquo;, which meant that I ignored it for a long time: until the disintegration and failure of several relationships convinced me of its brilliance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #24: Reservoir by Fanfarlo</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have written a lot in these posts about how music gets indelibly tied up with places, events and feelings. For me this album by Fanfarlo is tied up with all three of these. It makes me happy and sad at the same time in memory of great times that are now gone but are fondly remembered. I am aware that this is the youngest album on the list so far and so it might be a bit early to endow classic status upon it, but &amp;ldquo;Reservoir&amp;rdquo; is a fine album and to my ears it stands up really well. Listening to it again in the course of writing this post I found that I remembered every note and musical phrase, and yet somehow I also managed to delight in hearing new features in the production that I&amp;rsquo;d not noticed before.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #23: Gorgeous by 808 State</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was quite hard to choose an 808 State album for the &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;understated classics series&lt;/a&gt; for two reasons. The first is that I was introduced to 808 State quite late through a friend&amp;rsquo;s sister&amp;rsquo;s cassette copy of The Shamen&amp;rsquo;s En-Tact (the original version recorded from vinyl that had a thirteen minute version of &amp;ldquo;Evil Is Eden&amp;rdquo;) that also had &amp;ndash; to fill out the C90 &amp;ndash; the full length sweary version of &amp;ldquo;What Time Is Love?&amp;rdquo; by The KLF and four tracks: &amp;ldquo;Cubik&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Pacific&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Olympic&amp;rdquo; (I think&amp;hellip;), and &amp;ldquo;In Yer Face&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #22: Walking With Thee by Clinic</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Walking With Thee” is the second album by Liverpool band &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clinic_(band)&#34;&gt;Clinic&lt;/a&gt;. It was released in 2002, which seems like an age ago now. Even longer ago they released the single “The Return of Evil Bill”, which was got me interested in them in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently got back into “Walking With Thee” when I picked “Vulture” in my A-Z of Animals playlist last month. I’d forgotten just how great a song it is, both musically and lyrically. It’s a caution against letting those with more power and wealth lord it over us – viz, “the best that you’ve left here for others / is the best the rest of us know” – and so it’s surely much more a song for these times than back then in 2002. Anyway, I’m going to avoid too much reading into the lyrics for this particular understated classic, as most of the time Clinic are defiantly resistant to that kind of analysis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #21: Woob 2 by Woob</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The second Woob album (AKA “Woob 4495”) is probably the greatest ambient album ever made and is certainly the best one you have never heard of. Originally released in 1995 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.emit.cc&#34;&gt;on the em:t label&lt;/a&gt; it is also a rare record. I don’t have an actual copy but I have seen one! I downloaded it off the internet and even that is quite difficult to do. My friend is an avid collector of all the em:t releases and it is easy to see why: all the albums are titled in a specific way that is very appealing to people who like to collect things and they also have very striking nature photography on the covers. In a strange way, the label was able to create an identity for its releases in a way that many artists would try to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #20: Folklore by Nelly Furtado</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s rather spooky but shortly after deciding to write about Nelly Furtado’s “Folklore” as the next &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;understated classic&lt;/a&gt;, I found out that she has a new album out this week. As a result, I have been listening to a lot of her music while writing this post, and I’ve been enjoying it too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As always with these choices of mine, “Folklore” is a record that I can link to particular events and emotions in my life and so I guess my perception of it is coloured by that. Nevertheless while re-listening to the album I tried to examine whether my feelings for it were &lt;em&gt;entirely&lt;/em&gt; centred on those memories and emotional responses. I think the answer is not a simple one, because in recent weeks I’ve felt very unsettled in many aspects of my life and so I probably have found it difficult to tell.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #19: The Dreaming by Kate Bush</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“I see the people working and see it working for them.” (&lt;em&gt;Sat In Your Lap&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Dreaming by Kate Bush is a strange 1982 album that many believed had destroyed her career. Two weeks before her first ever performance of “Running Up That Hill”, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nme.com/blog/index.php?blog=10&amp;amp;title=on_this_day_kate_bush_releases_hounds_of_1986&amp;amp;more=1&amp;amp;c=1&amp;amp;tb=1&amp;amp;pb=1&#34;&gt;the NME had written an editorial asking whether she had burnt herself out completely&lt;/a&gt;. Obviously “Running Up That Hill” (recently used to great effect in the Olympic Closing Ceremony) and the parent album “The Hounds Of Love” that followed showed that she had plenty more up her sleeve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #18: Fabric 12 mixed by The Amalgamation Of Soundz</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Say what? We’re allowing compilations now?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes. Why not? A good mix is as much an artistic statement as a full-blown single artist album. It takes a lot of skill to get from A to B and keep everything on the boil in between. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fabriclondon.com/store/catalog/product/view/id/30/s/fabric-12/categories/8/&#34;&gt;This Fabric mix by The Amalgamation Of Soundz&lt;/a&gt; is one of my favourites because it is a downtempo (but, crucially, not &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; downtempo) compilation delivered with flair and using what I consider to be unconventional sources (soundtracks, tribute albums, hip-hop) to do it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #17: Nearly God by Nearly God (Tricky)</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sit back and let it happen, / Let us take your time away.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nearly God&lt;/em&gt; is Tricky’s second album, which was released under a different name either because Island rejected it as the follow-up to &lt;em&gt;Maxinequaye&lt;/em&gt; or because it came too quickly after and Tricky just wanted it released. I had this album before &lt;em&gt;Maxinequaye&lt;/em&gt; because back then it wasn’t as easy to go back and catch up with albums that you had missed as it is now. I had bought enough singles to get the postcards through the post that advertised &lt;em&gt;Nearly God&lt;/em&gt; (this, kids, is what we had before e-mail and liking things on Facebook) and when I heard &lt;em&gt;Poems&lt;/em&gt; for the first time on the radio I was incredibly excited.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #16: Ambient 2 / The Plateaux Of Mirror by Howard Budd and Brian Eno</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;among-fields-of-crystal--wind-in-lonely-fences&#34;&gt;Among Fields of Crystal / Wind in Lonely Fences&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have written about a &lt;a href=&#34;uc4&#34;&gt;fair&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;uc6&#34;&gt;number of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;uc13&#34;&gt;ambient&lt;/a&gt; albums in this series (and there are at least two more to come!) but perhaps none are as unobtrusive as this one by Howard Budd and Brian Eno. It’s a subtle collection of music that sits at the margins of your consciousness: for a long time it was the music that I turned to when I could not sleep but I could just as easily imagine it as (ahem!) romantic background music as I could something to work to. I actually bought it in 2006 to listen to on an overnight flight back from the US.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #15: Début by Björk</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got into Début via a cassette from the library, much like I did with &lt;a href=&#34;uc1&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Together Alone&lt;/em&gt; by Crowded House&lt;/a&gt;. I suppose it is less obscure than many of my choices for &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;this strand&lt;/a&gt; but I do think that &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; is more well-known (because of &lt;em&gt;It’s Oh So Quiet&lt;/em&gt;, which we shall mention here only briefly) and that &lt;em&gt;Homogenic&lt;/em&gt; is probably more popular among her fans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I really like about &lt;em&gt;Début&lt;/em&gt; though, as much as the album itself, is the panoply of remixes and alternative versions that surround the release. In this way &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; is at least as strong if not stronger and you might recall that I had similar fun &lt;a href=&#34;uc13&#34;&gt;when writing about the Orb’s album U.F.Orb a while back&lt;/a&gt;. As a result of this, there will be some detours into the remixes and live versions when discussing this album. In particular, I will mention the remix collection &lt;em&gt;the best mixes from the album début for all the people who don’t buy white labels&lt;/em&gt; and the recording of an MTV Unplugged show that is available in the &lt;em&gt;Live Box&lt;/em&gt; box set.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #14: Clear by Bomb The Bass</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think it’s time to discuss your philosophy of drug use as it relates to artistic endeavour…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That quote is from the movie “The Naked Lunch” directed by David Cronenburg (see also &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/crash/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;) and it also opens “Bug Powder Dust” by Bomb The Bass, the five star single that opens “Clear”. A rollicking piece of rock rap dripping with pop culture references that runs for four and half minutes and does not stop until another quote from “The Naked Lunch”, it is probably one of my favourite songs of the 90s. That churning guitar line sends me right back.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #13: U.F.Orb by The Orb</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FUN FACT:&lt;/strong&gt; It was because of the artwork to this album that I obsessively scrawled onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome on my pencil case at school. I also had a very passable u.f.orb logo drawn on it too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-the-blue-room&#34;&gt;In The Blue Room&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had my first “close encounter” with The Orb in 1992 when the single &lt;em&gt;Blue Room&lt;/em&gt; was in the charts. Back then, as I &lt;a href=&#34;uc2&#34;&gt;mentioned previously&lt;/a&gt;, I would listen to the radio a lot and this tune - introduced as the longest single ever to enter the UK chart - struck me as really interesting. The radio edit was a burbling wash of synths and female vocals underpinned by a hefty bass performance from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newstatesman.com/music/2008/06/wobble-life-music-dub-leaving&#34;&gt;Jah Wobble&lt;/a&gt;. Incidentally, the same week that &lt;em&gt;Blue Room&lt;/em&gt; entered the chart, I was actually listening out for &lt;em&gt;Sentinel&lt;/em&gt; by Mike Oldfield and this single (&lt;a href=&#34;uc10&#34;&gt;from Tubular Bells II&lt;/a&gt;) featured two remixes by The Orb.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #12: Look Sharp! by Roxette</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;happy-birthday&#34;&gt;Happy Birthday!&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No matter how intellectual one gets about these things, the primary function of music is to have fun. With this in mind it is a good time to turn to Roxette then, as they are almost always the epitome of fun.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I received &lt;em&gt;Look Sharp!&lt;/em&gt; as a present for my ninth birthday. This was probably a bit young to fully understand all the emotions expressed on the record. It’s just as well that it is also crammed with the kind of pop confections that made &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_Bore_Us,_Get_to_the_Chorus!&#34;&gt;“Don’t bore us, get to the chorus!”&lt;/a&gt; something of a band motto and made for a great introduction to the world of pop for a nine year old boy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #11: Second Toughest In The Infants by Underworld</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-rails-your-fins-your-thin-paper-wings&#34;&gt;Your rails, your fins, your thin paper wings&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Second Toughest in the Infants&lt;/em&gt; (STITI) is the second album by Underworld, released in 1995. This was just ahead of the mania caused by the .NUXX version of Born Slippy appearing on the &lt;em&gt;Trainspotting&lt;/em&gt; soundtrack a little later. &lt;em&gt;Born Slippy&lt;/em&gt; itself, the blippy techno confection released between their début &lt;em&gt;Dubnobasswithmyheadman&lt;/em&gt; and this album. STITI then is very much the calm before the storm and features a band (in the truest sense, which is unusual among electronic acts) in full flow. The sure hands are apparent from the off with the all-in-one trifecta of &lt;em&gt;Juanita&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Kiteless&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;To Dream of Love&lt;/em&gt;: a huge slab of a track that propels, mashes and then glides over various tempos in its sixteen minute run.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #10: Tubular Bells II by Mike Oldfield</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was the artwork that got me interested in Tubular Bells II. Rendering Trevor Key&amp;rsquo;s wonderful icon of the twisted tubular bell in yellow and blue made it all the more mysterious. Seeing it one day in Woolworth&amp;rsquo;s in Leigh Park back in 1992 aroused my curiosity. The huge display must have been part of the massive publicity drive for the album. Despite dwindling sales for his albums at that time, a sequel to Tubular Bells represented a huge potential for sales. This is why Oldfield had been lured from his previous home at Virgin records over to Warner Music. At that point Oldfield had not made a good album since his soundtrack to the movie &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0087553/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Killing Fields&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in 1985, the end of a hot streak (perhaps 1980&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;QE2&lt;/em&gt; aside) that had lasted since the original &lt;em&gt;Tubular Bells&lt;/em&gt; back in 1973.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #9: Tiger Bay by Saint Etienne</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tiger Bay&lt;/em&gt; is Saint Etienne&amp;rsquo;s third album and I think it is among their best. It was released in June 1994 on Heavenly records. I first owned a copy in 1998 when I picked it up while living in halls as an undergraduate. The reason for including this album in the understated classics series is the same as for &lt;a href=&#34;uc8&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Second Light&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Dreadzone: it marries traditional forms to newer electronic music&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Second Light&lt;/em&gt; melds classical music and sea shanties to house and dub reggae to evoke the rolling hills and mystic caves of England. &lt;em&gt;Tiger Bay&lt;/em&gt; grafts folk structures on to Balearic pop songs and electronic experiments in order to visit motorway verges, windswept seashores, and Mediterranean holidays. There is even a ghost story (&lt;em&gt;Boy Scouts of America&lt;/em&gt;) for good measure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #8: Second Light by Dreadzone</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;understated classics&lt;/a&gt; series, I try to alternate between pop/rock and electronic albums. Keeping with this trend number eight is the wonderful dub-infused album &lt;em&gt;Second Light&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dreadzone.com&#34;&gt;Dreadzone&lt;/a&gt;. Released in 1996 it was well-received critically and four of its tracks featured on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/radio1/johnpeel/&#34;&gt;John Peel&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s best-of-year list that year. &lt;em&gt;Little Britain&lt;/em&gt; received a lot of radio play, a popular choice for that flag-waving period of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mojo4music.com/13834/the-story-of-britpop-in-60-albums/&#34;&gt;britpop&lt;/a&gt; and assorted other demons.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The strengths of &lt;em&gt;Second Light&lt;/em&gt; as an album is the anglicana&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; of its first half and the subversion of it in the second half. I often talk of how albums are front-loaded with the best tracks to get you immersed in them. This is probably a hangover from vinyl where you could repeatedly play one side, making it necessary to make cohesive &amp;lsquo;sides&amp;rsquo; of music.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #7: 100 Broken Windows by Idlewild</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Idewild are a solid band who have released four or five albums that I could consider for this series. I&amp;rsquo;m even in the sleeve credits of one: &lt;em&gt;Post-Electric Blues&lt;/em&gt;, if you&amp;rsquo;re asking.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the end I went for &lt;em&gt;100 Broken Windows&lt;/em&gt; because it means a lot to me. It has more of a place in my life than the others. Usually I find that this happens if I can remember where I bought an album. In this case I bought a copy of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-22533522&#34;&gt;cassette&lt;/a&gt; in Bath HMV at Easter 2000. I can remember the first time that I listened to it too, it was as I marched home to Oldfield Park down Bathwick hill from the &lt;a href=&#34;www.bath.ac.uk&#34;&gt;university&lt;/a&gt; that same afternoon. It took exactly the two sides of the tape to get from one door to the other.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #6: Arbor Bona Arbor Mala by The Shamen</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ask anyone into pop music between 1991 and 1993 about The Shamen, and you&amp;rsquo;ll either receive a flood of euphoric good will about excellent tracks like &lt;em&gt;Move Any Mountain&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;LSI&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Phorever People&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;; or they will rant at you about the evils of &lt;em&gt;Ebeneezer Goode&lt;/em&gt;. The Shamen are either one of the pantheon of great acts from early 90&amp;rsquo;s dance and electronic music, or they are a shameless vaudeville novelty act.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #5: A Weekend In The City by Bloc Party</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-weekend-in-the-city-background&#34;&gt;A Weekend In The City: Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the youngest album I have chosen for this series. I try to pick albums that are at least ten years old but every now and then, I will think of an album that matches the sort of things I want to write about. That&amp;rsquo;s the case here. &lt;em&gt;A Weekend in the City&lt;/em&gt; is an unusual album that, in a reversal of the old adage, is “easy to love but hard to admire”. Nevertheless I do love and admire it, and I would like to share my thoughts about it with you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #4: Substrata by Biosphere</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/other/UC4add1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I bought this album in the summer between my two years at college. I remember listening to this music under skies glowering with clouds so 1997 must have been a poor summer. I’d just bought a book of photography too, which placed photos from the north and south poles on opposite pages. I bought it mainly for the penguins that were, of course, on pretty much every other page. The pictures of snow and ice soon became the ideal companions to this album.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #3: The Circle &amp; The Square by Red Box</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-is-understated-not-understated&#34;&gt;When is understated not understated?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The trouble with writing a series of articles all themed somehow is that eventually you might find something that sits naturally in the sequence but at the same time goes against the grain a little. Et voila, I give you “The Circle &amp;amp; The Square” by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.redboxmusic.net/htm/home.htm&#34;&gt;Red Box&lt;/a&gt;. An album that hardly anyone has heard containing two top 10 UK singles that probably everyone has heard. Don’t get me wrong, it is a complete and utter classic - but it is definitely not understated: it is pompous, pretentious, ornate, artistic, all-encompassing, weird and awesome. I could continue but some innate inner law prevents me from using any more adjectives than that in one sentence. It is a chimeral entity standing way apart from its time, timeless and beautiful. The fact that it sold sod-all copies means that holding &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cherryred.co.uk/cherrypop-exd.asp?id=873&#34;&gt;a CD remaster&lt;/a&gt; makes you feel as if you were clutching a cuddly dodo and thinking “if only, if only…”. So this barking, bonkers, beautiful album gets its “&lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/tags#understated-classics/&#34;&gt;understated classic&lt;/a&gt;” status because it just isn’t stated often enough just what an amazing record it is.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #2: Sinking by The Aloof</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-discovered-the-aloof-while-listening-to-the-top-40&#34;&gt;I discovered The Aloof while listening to the Top 40&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I was younger, I used to listen to the Top 40 every Sunday. To begin with, this was partly an endurance thing and partly an obsession with one day seeing Roxette top the charts - alas, they never did, though for one thrilling spring “Joyride” did flirt with the upper reaches of the chart.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Listening to the charts is probably the best way to become a lover of music. Nearly all my musical loves stem from listening to the top 40 chart, either directly from crouching next to my static-y radio on Sunday evening, or as something that evolving beyond those initial tastes later on. I soon realised that listening to music at the lower end of the chart was more rewarding and not just because this was where all &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Church_of_Your_Heart&#34;&gt;the later Roxette singles ended up&lt;/a&gt;. It was where all the oddities washed in, sometimes there one week and never to be heard again - sometimes growing up into something big. I remember first hearing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.prideofmanchester.com/music/ucc.htm&#34;&gt;“The Key The Secret” by the Urban Cookie Collective&lt;/a&gt; entering the chart at number 40, it eventually climbed to number 2. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/nottingham/content/articles/2004/11/20/entertainment_music_local_bands_kws_feature.shtml&#34;&gt;Also “Please Don’t Go” by KWS which crept all the way up to number 1&lt;/a&gt; - these were great dance records that grew by word of mouth at a time when great dance records were weird and new and meant something.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #1: Together Alone by Crowded House</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week Arcade Fire released their hotly anticipated third album &amp;ldquo;The Suburbs&amp;rdquo;.  I loved &amp;ldquo;Neon Bible&amp;rdquo; but critics found it preachy, as overbearing as the religious folk it sought to satirise. I disagree and think it was an impressive continuation from an exciting debut. &amp;ldquo;The Suburbs&amp;rdquo; steps on from their previous two albums, both in subject matter and tone. It&amp;rsquo;s sad, thoughtful, resigned, angry and tetchy - among other things. “The Suburbs” isn&amp;rsquo;t the understated classic that I want to discuss though: with all the praise and plaudits, it may never suit this new thread of posts. I want to write about &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Together_Alone&#34;&gt;Together Alone by Crowded House&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
