<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Iain M. Banks on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/iain-m.-banks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Iain M. Banks on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/iain-m.-banks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Iain M. Banks, Feersum Endjinn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/feersum-endjinn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/feersum-endjinn/</guid>
      <description>Feersum Endjinn is one of Iain Banks&amp;rsquo; few non-Culture sci-fi novels. Like the Culture novels, an existential crisis drives the plot: in this case the action takes place on Earth in the far future and the sun has aged to a point where it will grow and swallow the earth. This is referred to as the Encroachment. The characters are divided between the good guys who seek to find a solution for the greater good and bad guys who use the Encroachment to consolidate their power and influence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iain M. Banks, Consider Phlebas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/consider-phlebas-a-picaresque-in-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/consider-phlebas-a-picaresque-in-space/</guid>
      <description>A while back, I decided I was going to write about the Iain M. Banks sci-fi-novels (mainly as a respite from having to read and write about J. G. Ballard novels, but I only got as fas as writing about the excellent “Against A Dark Barkground” and re-reading the first of the Culture novels “Consider Phlebas”. WARNING: Some plot spoilers follow (but not too many).&#xA;I’m not sure why it has taken almost two years to write about this novel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Favourite Culture Ship Names</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/favourite-culture-ship-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/favourite-culture-ship-names/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned before I am re-reading the novels of Iain Banks and this weekend I managed to finish Consider Phlebas. A little post about it will be coming up soon. One of my favourite things about the Culture novels is how the ships are named and having found a list on Wikipedia, I thought I would share ten of my favourites with you!&#xA;You’ll Clean That Up Before You Leave Ravished By The Sheer Implausibility Of That Last Statement All Through With This Niceness And Negotiation Stuff Prosthetic Conscience Of Course I Still Love You Size Isn’t Everything Hand Me The Gun And Ask Me Again Dramatic Exit, Or, Thank you And Goodnight We Haven’t Met But You’re A Great Fan Of Mine Anticipation Of A New Lover’s Arrival, The Great names all I am sure you would agree.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
