<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Iain M. Banks on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/iain-m.-banks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Iain M. Banks on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/iain-m.-banks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Iain M. Banks, Feersum Endjinn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/feersum-endjinn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/feersum-endjinn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Feersum Endjinn is one of Iain Banks&amp;rsquo; few non-Culture sci-fi novels. Like the Culture novels, an existential crisis drives the plot: in this case the action takes place on Earth in the far future and the sun has aged to a point where it will grow and swallow the earth. This is referred to as the Encroachment. The characters are divided between the good guys who seek to find a solution for the greater good and bad guys who use the Encroachment to consolidate their power and influence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iain M. Banks, Consider Phlebas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/consider-phlebas-a-picaresque-in-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/consider-phlebas-a-picaresque-in-space/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A while back, I decided I was going to write about the Iain M. Banks sci-fi-novels (mainly as a respite from having to read and write about &lt;a href=&#34;j-g-ballard&#34;&gt;J. G. Ballard novels&lt;/a&gt;, but I only got as fas as writing about the excellent “Against A Dark Barkground” and re-reading the first of the Culture novels “Consider Phlebas”. WARNING: Some plot spoilers follow (but not too many).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Favourite Culture Ship Names</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/favourite-culture-ship-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/favourite-culture-ship-names/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned before &lt;a href=&#34;more-books&#34;&gt;I am re-reading the novels of Iain Banks&lt;/a&gt; and this weekend I managed to finish &lt;em&gt;Consider Phlebas&lt;/em&gt;. A little post about it will be coming up soon. One of my favourite things about the Culture novels is how the ships are named and having found &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_ships_(The_Culture)&#34;&gt;a list on Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;, I thought I would share ten of my favourites with you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
