<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>J. G. Ballard on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/j.-g.-ballard/</link>
    <description>Recent content in J. G. Ballard on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/j.-g.-ballard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, Hello America</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-america/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had low expectations for &amp;ldquo;Hello America&amp;rdquo;, the next in &lt;a href=&#34;j-g-ballard&#34;&gt;the series of Ballard novels&lt;/a&gt; that I started reading over seven years ago. However, it turned out to be a hoot. A couple of years ago, this novel would have been a wig-out bit of standard Ballard weirdness (a bit like &lt;a href=&#34;the-drowned-world&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Drowned World&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;the-crystal-world&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Crystal World&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;) but given recent events &amp;ldquo;Hello America&amp;rdquo; is starting to take on an eerie prescience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hello America&amp;rdquo; (1981) is set a hundred years from now in an alternate time-line where oil production peaked in the late sixties. Without a viable energy supply the North American continent depopulates and the Russians dam the Bering strait in order to turn Siberia into farmland to feed the American refugees. Meanwhile, the continental United States turns into a desert wasteland due to the resulting climate change. The 44th president (President Brown) was the last before America depopulated entirely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Unlimited Dream Company</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-unlimited-dream-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-unlimited-dream-company/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/high-rise/&#34;&gt;I last wrote about a JG Ballard novel nearly three years ago&lt;/a&gt;. That one - &amp;ldquo;High-Rise&amp;rdquo; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/film/2016/mar/20/high-rise-review-ben-wheatley-jg-ballard-tom-hiddleston&#34;&gt;has since been made into a film&lt;/a&gt;. The subject of this post is &amp;ldquo;The Unlimited Dream Company&amp;rdquo;, my favourite among his novels: a silly romp through suburban sexual repression that glitters with sinister wit. Even after many read-throughs I still can&amp;rsquo;t work out whether it is a crazy masterpiece or something light that we&amp;rsquo;re meant to throw away after reading.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, High-Rise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/high-rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/high-rise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a few false starts I managed to finish &amp;ldquo;High-Rise&amp;rdquo;, the next in &lt;a href=&#34;j-g-ballard&#34;&gt;my collection of JG Ballard novels&lt;/a&gt;. For a book that I had trouble getting into, it turned out to be a pretty good read - even if it was also a pretty unpleasant one. Published in 1975, &amp;ldquo;High-Rise&amp;rdquo; is perhaps ahead of its time in exploring the effects of social breakdown in stylised and artificial situations where people are in close contact. You might think the plot, about a luxury high-rise that goes to hell, is in some way political or sociological but it really isn&amp;rsquo;t. It&amp;rsquo;s just a big playground in which Ballard throws around some of his most twisted ideas, all the while remarking on the very artifice of the situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Never Mind The Ballards</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/never-mind-the-ballards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/never-mind-the-ballards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;j-g-ballard&#34;&gt;Ages ago&lt;/a&gt; I set out to write a post for each of JG Ballard’s novels. In fact it is the oldest post on this blog. Most of the novels (I don’t have the two autobiographical novels &lt;em&gt;Empire Of The Sun&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;The Kindness Of Women&lt;/em&gt; and the late period novel &lt;em&gt;Milennium People&lt;/em&gt;) are sat in a row on top of my broken bookshelf, part of the weight there that bowed outer frame of the unit and made the inner shelves collapse. Had I known that it would be a task unfinished nearly eighteen months later and destroy a piece a furniture that I did not yet own, I may have been less ambitious.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, Concrete Island</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/concrete-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/concrete-island/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;no-man-is-an-island-not-any-more&#34;&gt;No man is an island (not any more)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You are tracked pretty much everywhere you go. CCTV, the GPS on your phone or the signals sent by your more primitive model to the masts to keep in touch with the network. Your cash withdrawals, your purchases in Tesco and your journeys on public transport all add to the picture of where you are. If you drive, your sat nav will hold clues to where you have been and, if you disappear, where you might have gone to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, Crash</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/crash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/crash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;form-and-function-deformation-and-dysfunction&#34;&gt;Form and function, deformation and dysfunction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think we should get one thing out of the way first. For me, there is nothing erotic about a car or a motorway. The place in popular culture of the car in particular as sexual icon has always bemused me. In fact, I’m really rather ambivalent about cars. This matters when discussing &lt;em&gt;Crash&lt;/em&gt;, the 1973 novel by JG Ballard that resumes this strand of posts about his novels. (You can read about &lt;em&gt;The Drowned World&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/the-drowned-world/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Drought&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/the-drought/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Crystal World&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/the-crystal-world/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Crystal World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-crystal-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-crystal-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;crystallising-the-world-the-body-or-the-mind&#34;&gt;Crystallising the world, the body, or the mind?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At last, Ballard in full flow. The Crystal World (TCW) is definitely the most enjoyable of the early trio of apocalyptic novels. It takes the successful elements of the first two and embellishes them with new details and ideas. At time of writing, TCW is definitely the best Ballard novel that I have read in its entirety.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The book begins with a steamer travelling up a river in Cameroon carrying the novel’s main protagonist Edward Sanders, a doctor at a hospital for lepers. He is hoping to meet some friends, Max and Suzanne Clair, who are also doctors and run another leprosy hospital in a town named Mount Royal (also the name of the main city in “The Drought”). His motives are not entirely clear and we are given introspection into his doubts about the reasons he is making the journey. The inference is that he had an affair with Suzanne Clair and may well still be in love with her.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Drought</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-drought/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-drought/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-world-created-by-nature-versus-the-world-constructed-by-humans&#34;&gt;The world created by nature versus the world constructed by humans&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On to The Drought by J. G. Ballard in &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/j-g-ballard/&#34;&gt;my ongoing quest to read and review all of his novels&lt;/a&gt;. This is his second novel, if we assume his convention of never acknowledging “The Wind From Nowhere” as being his first novel. “The Drought” itself was renamed from “The Burning World” and additional content added later on. This was quite common practice in SF in the 50s and 60s where novels were serialised in magazines like &lt;a href=&#34;http://philsp.com/mags/amazing_stories.html&#34;&gt;Amazing SF&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://ttapress.com/interzone/about/&#34;&gt;Interzone&lt;/a&gt;. It is evidence though of Ballard finding his voice as he wrote and from The Drought it is easy to see that he is iterating his thought processes and subject matter with each novel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Drowned World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-drowned-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-drowned-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;does-science-fiction-have-to-be-believable-to-be-meaningful&#34;&gt;Does Science Fiction have to be believable to be meaningful?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Should science fiction have predictive power? In plotting the vast unknowns of the future, should authors aim for prescience? Will people be able to say of the best SF novels in five hundred years time that some novels were right about some things and that these novels are better than the ones that didn’t?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I would say no, otherwise we would be remarkably unfair on an awful lot of good writing. That said, I doubt that SF is read for the futurology. As with all literature, SF is at it is best when it has something to say about the world around us now, no matter when it may be set. And if SF has any kind of predictive record, it does better when the psychological issues arising from continued technological development are considered over the mere technology of that advancement. In the long run, a fictional account of space dog Laika (does one exist?) that rings true emotionally will probably endure longer than a pulp novel entitled “Dogs In Space!” (though that is a great title!).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/j-g-ballard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/j-g-ballard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading &amp;ldquo;Crash&amp;rdquo; at 17 left me in a state of numb shock. It got me hooked and left me with &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/J._G._Ballard&#34;&gt;J. G. Ballard&lt;/a&gt; as one of my favourite authors. I then devoured a short story collection called &amp;ldquo;Myths of the Near Future&amp;rdquo; around the same time. You may recognise it because the Klaxons appropriated the title for their debut album. Those stories captured my imagination, in particular the eponymous story of a world gone to run amid &amp;ldquo;space sickness&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
