<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Goldfrapp on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/goldfrapp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Goldfrapp on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/goldfrapp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Goldfrapp - Black Cherry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/goldfrapp-black-cherry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/goldfrapp-black-cherry/</guid>
      <description>This is the first in an unplanned series of album revisits, I will write a post explaining the process soon.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Black Cherry&amp;rdquo; is the second album by Goldfrapp, released in 2003. I bought the lead single Train while I lived in York and also the single of the title track because by then I&amp;rsquo;d discovered M83 and they&amp;rsquo;d done a remix of it.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Black Cherry&amp;rdquo; finds the band faced with following their successful and chilled out debut album &amp;ldquo;Felt Mountain&amp;rdquo;, which back in 2000 had sounded notably weird.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2017/</guid>
      <description>Note: Recent months have been very busy, so this album digest combines a review of the new album by The National with a couple of reviews left over from earlier in the year.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve written a few more album reviews in the past months but I&amp;rsquo;m so far behind (February and March have already been published on a considerable lag) that I&amp;rsquo;m just going to pepper forthcoming digests with additional reviews of older albums.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2013/</guid>
      <description>A nice diverse selection of albums this month:&#xA;Arctic Monkeys &amp;ldquo;AM&amp;rdquo; BT &amp;ldquo;A Song Across Wires&amp;rdquo; Goldfrapp &amp;ldquo;Tales of Us&amp;rdquo; Janelle Monáe &amp;ldquo;Electric Lady&amp;rdquo; Arctic Monkeys &amp;ldquo;AM&amp;rdquo; This whole review is basically me catching up with the rest of the world and realising that the Arctic Monkeys are ace. To be fair, I did notice how awesome they were at the opening ceremony of the Olympics last year, and I have liked the odd one or two of their singles, but up until now I haven&amp;rsquo;t really wanted to listen to any of their albums.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
