<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Self Improvement on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/self-improvement/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Self Improvement on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/self-improvement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Things to Remember</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/things-to-remember/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/things-to-remember/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These are some things I jotted down one day last week, I&amp;rsquo;ll refine them a bit more later on. Think of it as an aide-memoire of things that work for me, your milage may vary.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about things that haven&amp;rsquo;t happened.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t turn whatever has happened and/or is bothering you into a catastrophe, especially if no one else is telling you that it is one. Seek out someone you trust and ask them &amp;ldquo;is this a catastrophe?&amp;rdquo; Not only will they say no about 99.9% of the time, they will often tell you why it isn&amp;rsquo;t a catastrophe.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The people who are important to you will not use your personal characteristics as a laundry list of personal failings in the same way that you do. In fact they won&amp;rsquo;t do it all. What you perceive as your own obvious and innate failings, others will often struggle to even see. Self awareness and hyper-awareness are two different things.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There will be people who don&amp;rsquo;t like you, people who don&amp;rsquo;t think you&amp;rsquo;re good enough, and people who won&amp;rsquo;t give you a chance. They most likely intersect, meaning there are fewer of them than you might think. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to satisfy these people, only those who like you and support you. Most of all, you have to be good enough for you.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Everybody has different needs and wants in life. Even though your needs and wants will often intersect with those of others, there is still no reason to use other people as the measure for what you should be getting out of life.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A person has more depth and dimensions than are measurable. If you focus solely on a single metric when you measure yourself against some standard or goal, you will be wrong in some way or another. A qualified and multi-dimensional validation of your progress will give you a more nuanced and more supportive sense of where you are heading and how to correct yourself.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Always focus on your capability. Regard potential as something to be shaped into capability.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Take time to think about things in many different ways, employing both proven mental models and lateral thinking.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Often problems are easier to tackle once you have been for a walk in the countryside.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Any sugar?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/some-sugar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/some-sugar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not being much of a drinker, I&amp;rsquo;ve never felt the need to do &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nhs.uk/Livewell/alcohol/Pages/dry-january-helped-me-take-back-control-of-my-drinking.aspx&#34;&gt;dry January&lt;/a&gt;. Also Ingrid and I sat in a restaurant in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/spain-new-year-201718/&#34;&gt;Barcelona&lt;/a&gt; on January 2nd drinking for the third night in row. We hadn&amp;rsquo;t got off to that great a start. Well today marks the completion of a dry month: dry January with a two day lag.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Light, Last Light</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/first-light-last-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/first-light-last-light/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I often ponder whether the joys of waking up early are greater than those of staying up late. Empirical evidence seems to bear this out: all those people who get to work before you do, super-eager to get everything done. But then all the people walking under your windows late at night, drunk and laughing, they sound like they&amp;rsquo;re having a whale of a time too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Writing As It Happens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/writing-as-it-happens/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/writing-as-it-happens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m pretty close to a round number. To date I have written 298,500 words for this blog, not counting posts that I have discarded or deleted. This will be the 505th post currently on the blog, which makes for an average of just under 600 words per post. Some posts are just a picture or a video or a gallery though, so that distorts the average a bit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>October and November 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/october-november-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/october-november-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently started a new job and moved in to a new flat. This means I&amp;rsquo;m too busy to write any long blog posts at the moment. Also I&amp;rsquo;m still not quite at home there, so I tend to spend my evenings tidying up or setting up new things. It&amp;rsquo;s a shame because I have plenty of things to write about (even without observations on moving, starting a new job, etc) but I guess the writing will happen eventually&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grumble Grumble</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/grumble-grumble/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/grumble-grumble/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a bit behind in my posts about the trip and this post interrupts the sequence of events somewhat, just because I&amp;rsquo;ve not felt that well and that has dominated my thoughts about what to write. Basically for a week or two I&amp;rsquo;ve had varying degrees of bellyache and it&amp;rsquo;s not been fun. Instead of feeling the gratitude and excitement I&amp;rsquo;ve felt since being here, I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a lot of time wanting to curl up in the corner and just be&amp;hellip; well&amp;hellip; somewhere else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Reset Button</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-reset-button/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-reset-button/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ambitions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ambitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ambitions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, when I am feeling a bit down, I like to write down some of my ambitions. As you can see from this list they are mostly pretty humble but they are also a bit cheesy and embarassing, so I have put them after the fold!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Helen Fisher, Some Lessons In Love</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/some-lessons-in-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/some-lessons-in-love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As indicated by my &lt;a href=&#34;articles/reading-list-mid-april-2012&#34;&gt;reading list&lt;/a&gt; posted a couple of months ago (which has since been added to &lt;a href=&#34;articles/another-reading-list&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), I’ve started to try to read more about the things that I felt that I did not understand so well. Most notably perhaps is this book “on love” by Helen Fisher. Lest there is any innuendo it is not a book about technique nor does it attempt to explain love to those who have never known it, instead it assumes that we have all been there. In fact, the book attempts to explain the neurological mechanisms of love (specifically romantic love) and describes how science has helped reveal these mechanisms to us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dreams Of A Life: A Short Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dreams-of-a-life-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dreams-of-a-life-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dreams Of A Life&lt;/em&gt; is a documentary about Joyce Vincent, a woman who was found in her flat three years after her death surrounded by wrapped christmas presents and with the TV still on. £2400 in arrears on her rent, she was discovered by bailiffs who forced the door down. The film attempts to work out happened to Joyce by interviewing people who knew her. In two other strands that unfold in parallel, various events from her life are re-enacted along with the clearing of her flat by forensics officers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Beta Test Of Everything</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-beta-test-of-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-beta-test-of-everything/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading a few articles about the recent launch of Google+, a few things hit home. Google tends to launch a product that works and not always one that is perfect or finished (like, say, Apple). Sometimes it takes them several iterations to get right. They love the beta tag. In fact, I think it was Google (or possibly Flickr) that made me aware of the concept of beta software.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Things To Try When You Can&#39;t Sleep</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/five-things-to-try-when-you-cant-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/five-things-to-try-when-you-cant-sleep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Facebook is wonderful for keeping in touch but I’ve noticed that quite a few of my friends tend to use it to tell the world that they can’t sleep. Here’s some advice for you if you find yourself unable to sleep one night. I’ve often had to try these out myself! Note that these are just things that work for me and your mileage may vary, particularly if you are fortunate enough to have a partner next to you! You may need to appease them if you wriggle around too much.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Setback</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-setback/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-setback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the run there has been a bit of a hiatus in this blog. I wrote about how running was making me feel better. In fact, I should have said more. I recently stopped taking the antidepressants that I had been taking for eighteen months. This has been my longest period taking such medication but the running made me feel sufficiently good to decide that I could stop taking them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Movember 10K</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/movember-10k/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/movember-10k/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, Saturday. Finally. The big day. Would I a) be able to get to Greenwich in time for the registration? and b) be able to make it all the way around the course without collapsing and crying?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
