<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>May on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/may/</link>
    <description>Recent content in May on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/may/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, May 2016</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-may-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-may-2016/</guid>
      <description>Album Digest May 2016 features the work of four bands or artists that I have reviewed in previous album digests. I also own (or will own) all of these albums on vinyl, so it&amp;rsquo;s handy that I&amp;rsquo;ve recently bought myself a record player!&#xA;Radiohead &amp;ldquo;A Moon Shaped Pool&amp;rdquo; Radiohead released &amp;ldquo;A Moon Shaped Pool&amp;rdquo; online about three weeks ago and a physical version hits the shops later in June. As with all of their recent albums, it is (mostly) a slow burner that rewards multiple listens.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, May 2014</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-may-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-may-2014/</guid>
      <description>This month was strange. I didn’t listen to much new music and after last month’s bumper digest there’s probably a reason for that. Not to mention that Spotify gives you more reasons to look backwards than forwards. Nevertheless, this brief post features new albums by Little Dragon and Coldplay, along with the mini-album collaboration between Röyskopp and Robyn.&#xA;Little Dragon “Nabuma Rubberband” I discovered Little Dragon, like most people, I imagine, via Gorillaz’ “Plastic Beach” album.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, May 2013</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-may-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-may-2013/</guid>
      <description>Lilacs &amp;amp; Champagne Danish &amp;amp; Blue You might remember that last year I reviewed the first Lilacs &amp;amp; Champagne album and I liked it a lot. This album sees them back with more of the same: taking the approach that if it ain&amp;rsquo;t broke, don&amp;rsquo;t fix it. There are very few changes to the formula apart from the fact that the spoken word samples are not quite as good this time and there&amp;rsquo;s a bit more Grails-like guitar solo action.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, May 2012</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-may-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-may-2012/</guid>
      <description>Four albums for Album Digest May 2012:&#xA;Jack White Blunderbuss One Little Plane Into The Trees Beach House Bloom Oxia Tides Of Mind The April album digest was rather short on songs, so this month I decided to look for albums that were more based around songs not tracks. Electronic music is relatively easy to write about: the music is often simple (but not always), there are recognisable structures and genres (but not always), and there are conventions that are adhered to (but not always).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, May 2011</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-may-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-may-2011/</guid>
      <description>Four albums this month:&#xA;Kate Bush Director’s Cut Africa Hitech 93 Million Miles Fleet Foxes Helplessness Blues TV On The Radio Nine Types of Light There is a pleasing red hue to all the covers this month. I had time to write four full reviews of the major albums I listened to. Like last month I have included a video at the foot of each review. Enjoy!&#xA;Kate Bush Director’s Cut Director’s Cut is not a new album from Kate Bush but a collection of re-visits to old songs, four from The Sensual World (1989) and seven from [The Red Shoes](http://en.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
