<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Shins on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/the-shins/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Shins on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/the-shins/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, March 2017</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-march-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-march-2017/</guid>
      <description>Blanck Mass World Eater This album is pretty extreme. It&amp;rsquo;s not for everyone and even for the people who can handle it, it&amp;rsquo;s not for all the time. This album is a soul crushing experience at points but there are also points of light. Perhaps this makes “World Eater” more reflective of life as a whole than any other of this month&amp;rsquo;s albums. On balance it&amp;rsquo;s probably less crushing than the last Blanck Mass album “Dumb Flesh”, which I reviewed back in June 2015.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, March 2012</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-march-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-march-2012/</guid>
      <description>Five albums for Album Digest March 2012&#xA;Fanfarlo Rooms Filled With Light The Shins Port Of Morrow Grails Deep Politics New Build Yesterday Was Lived And Lost Scuba Personality A nice collection of albums this month - things usually pick up in March after a slow period after Christmas. One of these is a “catch-up” (the album by Grails) but apart from that one, everything else was released in the last five weeks or so… I should probably have included the album by Racehorses that I bought on my birthday but I will have to leave that for next month as I haven’t listened to it that much.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
