<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Orb on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/the-orb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Orb on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/the-orb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>In Praise of Pomme Fritz</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-pomme-fritz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-praise-of-pomme-fritz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The release of Pomme Fritz by The Orb in 1994 was a moment of genuine excitement for me as it was the first new material they released after I&amp;rsquo;d become aware of them. Not only that, but thanks to my hard work riding around Emsworth on my BMX at unsafe speeds belting out Green Day&amp;rsquo;s Dookie as out-of-tune-ly as is humanly possible, I&amp;rsquo;d managed to secure the funds to buy the album for myself. My excitement had been mounting from the moment the promotional postcard arrived a few weeks beforehand. I took my £4.99 to Our Price in Portsmouth Cascades on Saturday afternoon and bought myself a copy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And boy, I pretty much hated it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Orb, Live at Brighton Concord 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-orb---brighton-concord-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-orb---brighton-concord-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Went with my friend Nick to see The Orb at Concord 2 last night. The last time I&amp;rsquo;d seen the Orb was back in 2004, at the start of their relatively dry spell. That night, they&amp;rsquo;d been a bit lacklustre despite playing (some of) the hits and a relatively decent album in &amp;ldquo;Bicycles and Tricycles&amp;rdquo;. I left feeling that I&amp;rsquo;d seen the past rather than the future, something that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t glimpse again in their records until 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Orb - Alpine EP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/orb-alpine-ep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/orb-alpine-ep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Orb return with a new EP on the &lt;a href=&#34;www.kompakt.fm&#34;&gt;Kompakt label&lt;/a&gt; called &amp;ldquo;Alpine&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Alpine&amp;rdquo; is split in to three tracks &amp;ldquo;Morning&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Evening&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Dawn&amp;rdquo;. The third of these was included on the 2016 edition of Kompakt&amp;rsquo;s annual &amp;ldquo;Pop Ambient&amp;rdquo; compilation, a gently drifting track with plenty of bells and yodels. A diversion from the sounds of &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/album-digest-june-2015/&#34;&gt;Moonbuilding 2703 AD&lt;/a&gt; (and its presumably ongoing remixed companion EPs), but it sat nicely with the other tracks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To reboot this series, Album Digest June 2015 features five fantastic albums from Hot Chip, Jamie xx, Blanck Mass, Holly Herndon, and The Orb. I could pick loads more as I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to a lot of albums since &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/album-digest-february-2015/&#34;&gt;February&lt;/a&gt; but I decided to focus on the more electronic material. This means that I have no excuses for not continuing next month with a rockier theme.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;hot-chip-why-make-sense&#34;&gt;Hot Chip &amp;ldquo;Why Make Sense?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hot Chip seem to be settling in to a pattern with their album releases, alternating between messy experimental affairs and then a state of the art correction. Witness how &amp;ldquo;The Warning&amp;rdquo; smartened up the all-over-the-place &amp;ldquo;Coming On Strong&amp;rdquo; and how &amp;ldquo;One Life Stand&amp;rdquo; moulded and matured the lovestruck meandering of &amp;ldquo;Made In The Dark&amp;rdquo; into a lithe ten song set. &amp;ldquo;Why Make Sense?&amp;rdquo; takes the earnest song-based approach of &amp;ldquo;In Our Heads&amp;rdquo; and casts it into a funky fun-filled fifty minutes. It&amp;rsquo;s as concise as they&amp;rsquo;ve been since &amp;ldquo;One Life Stand&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, February 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;aphex-twin-computer-controlled-acoustic-instruments-pt2-ep&#34;&gt;Aphex Twin &amp;ldquo;Computer Controlled Acoustic Instruments Pt2 EP&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aphex Twin follows SYRO (reviewed in &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/album-digest-september-2014/&#34;&gt;Album Digest September 2014 here&lt;/a&gt;) with this 27 minute EP of music that, if we take the title literally, features computers playing acoustic musical instruments. It&amp;rsquo;s a very different sound to SYRO and sounds acoustic for the most part. It&amp;rsquo;s an important experiment about the role of the musician, one that is already blurred in the creation of electronic music.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Amazing Subversive Revolutionary Adolescence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-amazing-subversive-revolutionary-adolescence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-amazing-subversive-revolutionary-adolescence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;or-at-least-its-subversive-soundtrack&#34;&gt;Or at least its subversive soundtrack…&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I listened to The Orb’s amazing live album “Live ’93” the other day (after discovering the insipid “History Of The Future” collection on Spotify) and I was amazed at how countercultural and subversive it was. I was listening to this stuff at the age of 14 and now that I’m old enough to be a parent, that makes me a bit uncomfortable. Actually it does nothing of the sort, because it&amp;rsquo;s frigging awesome.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #13: U.F.Orb by The Orb</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FUN FACT:&lt;/strong&gt; It was because of the artwork to this album that I obsessively scrawled onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome on my pencil case at school. I also had a very passable u.f.orb logo drawn on it too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-the-blue-room&#34;&gt;In The Blue Room&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had my first “close encounter” with The Orb in 1992 when the single &lt;em&gt;Blue Room&lt;/em&gt; was in the charts. Back then, as I &lt;a href=&#34;uc2&#34;&gt;mentioned previously&lt;/a&gt;, I would listen to the radio a lot and this tune - introduced as the longest single ever to enter the UK chart - struck me as really interesting. The radio edit was a burbling wash of synths and female vocals underpinned by a hefty bass performance from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newstatesman.com/music/2008/06/wobble-life-music-dub-leaving&#34;&gt;Jah Wobble&lt;/a&gt;. Incidentally, the same week that &lt;em&gt;Blue Room&lt;/em&gt; entered the chart, I was actually listening out for &lt;em&gt;Sentinel&lt;/em&gt; by Mike Oldfield and this single (&lt;a href=&#34;uc10&#34;&gt;from Tubular Bells II&lt;/a&gt;) featured two remixes by The Orb.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
