<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>August on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/august/</link>
    <description>Recent content in August on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/august/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post, I allowed Spotify to pick some new albums for me this month. It chose some noodly ambient techno, a captivating slice of World Jazz, a moody gothic hallucination, and a concept album about humans being rescued by aliens. All in all a pretty good job! Here is the list:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prins Thomas &amp;ldquo;Principe del Norte&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sarathy Korwar &amp;ldquo;Day to Day&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Doomsquad &amp;ldquo;Total Time&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;United Vibrations &amp;ldquo;The Myth of the Golden Ratio&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;prins-thomas-principe-del-norte&#34;&gt;Prins Thomas &amp;ldquo;Principe del Norte&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/orb-alpine-diskomiks-sin-in-space-pt-2/&#34;&gt;Prins Thomas recently remixed the Orb&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Alpine EP&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; so I&amp;rsquo;m not surprised that Spotify included one of his tracks on my Discover Weekly playlist. The connection was obviously waiting to be made. &amp;ldquo;Principe del Norte&amp;rdquo; was released back in March and features 9 tracks over almost 90 minutes. Each track title is a single letter, save the first two which are labelled A1 and A2. I think it was B that caught my attention, a proper old school ambient tune but one with some teeth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everything Everything, Get To Heaven</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/everything-everything-get-to-heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/everything-everything-get-to-heaven/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write honestly about your feelings. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write about your feelings consistently, for a living on a regular basis. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write about your feelings when the world constantly intrudes with inanity, insanity and hatred. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write under those conditions without seeming frayed, without coming loose at the edges.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Get To Heaven&amp;rdquo;, the third album by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.everything-everything.co.uk&#34;&gt;Everything Everything&lt;/a&gt;, was forged under these stresses and pressures. For most of its running time it sounds like either a bomb ticking down to explode or like a clock inexorably counting up missed opportunities and stolen moments. It sounds for all the world as though it is trapped between fight and flight, paused between action and apathy. Yet it also subjects the listener to the yammerings of a culture that has driven itself mad. Depth and surface, glass and steel, truth and lies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The album digest returns with five albums by four artists.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Karl Hyde &amp;amp; Brian Eno &lt;em&gt;Someday World&lt;/em&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;HIGH-LIFE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lone &lt;em&gt;Reality Testing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;FKA twigs &lt;em&gt;LP1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mogwai &lt;em&gt;Come On Die Young: Appendix&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;karl-hyde--brian-eno-someday-world--high-life&#34;&gt;Karl Hyde &amp;amp; Brian Eno &lt;em&gt;Someday World&lt;/em&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;HIGH-LIFE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m a big fan of both Karl Hyde’s work with Underworld and of Brian Eno’s stuff so Someday World seemed like a dream collaboration to me when it was released last May. I was a bit underwhelmed by it, to the point of overlooking it for &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/album-digest-may-2014/&#34;&gt;May’s album digest&lt;/a&gt;. Last month they released a follow-up called High-Life, which includes some of the more experimental tracks they’d worked on. Together the two albums are greater than the some of their parts, so I’m writing about both of them together this month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For reasons that will become apparent, there will be a short period soon where I will not be writing album digests. Until then, I&amp;rsquo;m clearing a backlog of some albums that I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to but haven&amp;rsquo;t had enough time or motivation to write about. Only one of this month&amp;rsquo;s albums was released this month, something that&amp;rsquo;s not that uncommon at this time of the year as it is not the best time to release things. Here&amp;rsquo;s the list:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Album Digest August 2012 is also from the stack of albums that I &lt;a href=&#34;album-digest-july-2012&#34;&gt;mentioned last month&lt;/a&gt;. I chose this selection (along with the Passion Pit album) because the colours looked good together in the mosaic of covers that I make each month. Last month’s digest was about the right amount of detail so this will be another briefer digest. These are all good albums but not ones that will change your life, they&amp;rsquo;ll just happily sit alongside it. They are:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I bought a collection of electronic music this month. I mixed them all up in a smart playlist on iTunes, the smart aspect being to limit to tracks that had been played fewer than five then six then seven times etc. This made sure I was still listening to all the tracks equally often, despite the randomness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Biosphere &lt;em&gt;N-plants&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ford &amp;amp; Lopatin &lt;em&gt;Channel Pressure&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gus Gus &lt;em&gt;Arabian Horse&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Instra:Mental &lt;em&gt;Resolution 653&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jon Tejada &lt;em&gt;Parabolas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;biosphere-_n-plants_&#34;&gt;Biosphere &lt;em&gt;N-Plants&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think this album makes Biosphere the most reviewed musician on this blog at the moment but I don’t mind too much, he makes some great stuff. &lt;em&gt;N-Plants&lt;/em&gt; is a series of pieces about Japanese nuclear power plants and was ready for release by about February this year, just before the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fukushima_Daiichi_nuclear_disaster&#34;&gt;Fukishima nuclear disaster&lt;/a&gt; in March. It ended up being released in June. I am not sure if this represents a delay or not but as this quote shows, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.touchmusic.org.uk/catalogue/to84_biosphere_nplants.html&#34;&gt;Geir Jenssen is aware of how spooky the timing was&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
