<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>August on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/august/</link>
    <description>Recent content in August on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/august/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2016</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-august-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-august-2016/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned in yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post, I allowed Spotify to pick some new albums for me this month. It chose some noodly ambient techno, a captivating slice of World Jazz, a moody gothic hallucination, and a concept album about humans being rescued by aliens. All in all a pretty good job! Here is the list:&#xA;Prins Thomas &amp;ldquo;Principe del Norte&amp;rdquo; Sarathy Korwar &amp;ldquo;Day to Day&amp;rdquo; Doomsquad &amp;ldquo;Total Time&amp;rdquo; United Vibrations &amp;ldquo;The Myth of the Golden Ratio&amp;rdquo; Prins Thomas &amp;ldquo;Principe del Norte&amp;rdquo; Prins Thomas recently remixed the Orb&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Alpine EP&amp;rdquo; so I&amp;rsquo;m not surprised that Spotify included one of his tracks on my Discover Weekly playlist.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everything Everything, Get To Heaven</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/everything-everything-get-to-heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/everything-everything-get-to-heaven/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write honestly about your feelings. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write about your feelings consistently, for a living on a regular basis. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write about your feelings when the world constantly intrudes with inanity, insanity and hatred. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write under those conditions without seeming frayed, without coming loose at the edges.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Get To Heaven&amp;rdquo;, the third album by Everything Everything, was forged under these stresses and pressures.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2014</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-august-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-august-2014/</guid>
      <description>The album digest returns with five albums by four artists.&#xA;Karl Hyde &amp;amp; Brian Eno Someday World &amp;amp; HIGH-LIFE Lone Reality Testing FKA twigs LP1 Mogwai Come On Die Young: Appendix Karl Hyde &amp;amp; Brian Eno Someday World &amp;amp; HIGH-LIFE I’m a big fan of both Karl Hyde’s work with Underworld and of Brian Eno’s stuff so Someday World seemed like a dream collaboration to me when it was released last May.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2013</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-august-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-august-2013/</guid>
      <description>For reasons that will become apparent, there will be a short period soon where I will not be writing album digests. Until then, I&amp;rsquo;m clearing a backlog of some albums that I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to but haven&amp;rsquo;t had enough time or motivation to write about. Only one of this month&amp;rsquo;s albums was released this month, something that&amp;rsquo;s not that uncommon at this time of the year as it is not the best time to release things.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2012</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-august-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-august-2012/</guid>
      <description>Album Digest August 2012 is also from the stack of albums that I mentioned last month. I chose this selection (along with the Passion Pit album) because the colours looked good together in the mosaic of covers that I make each month. Last month’s digest was about the right amount of detail so this will be another briefer digest. These are all good albums but not ones that will change your life, they&amp;rsquo;ll just happily sit alongside it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2011</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-august-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-august-2011/</guid>
      <description>I bought a collection of electronic music this month. I mixed them all up in a smart playlist on iTunes, the smart aspect being to limit to tracks that had been played fewer than five then six then seven times etc. This made sure I was still listening to all the tracks equally often, despite the randomness.&#xA;Biosphere N-plants Ford &amp;amp; Lopatin Channel Pressure Gus Gus Arabian Horse Instra:Mental Resolution 653 Jon Tejada Parabolas Biosphere N-Plants I think this album makes Biosphere the most reviewed musician on this blog at the moment but I don’t mind too much, he makes some great stuff.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
