<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fifteen on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/fifteen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fifteen on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/fifteen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Favourite Albums of 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/favourite-albums-of-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/favourite-albums-of-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Given that I gave up on writing album digests for a bit this year, I thought I would at least do a proper top ten list of my favourite albums. There are quite a few albums that I did not have room for and I might try to revisit those later. In the mean time, let&amp;rsquo;s crack on. (To save time, I have in some instances pasted my original review from the appropriate album digest.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Long Post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-long-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-long-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am writing a long post that I will either publish as one long post (about five or six thousand words) or as about seven smaller ones each closer to the average post length of about eight hundred words. I have to get it out-of-the-way soon as my mind needs to focus on my health economics essay.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is hard to write short posts to a timetable, let alone churn out long posts on a regular basis. As a result, this longer post is not likely to become the norm. It&amp;rsquo;s an idea I had that bloomed into something ever bigger and this time I decided to have a crack at it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Underworld, Second Toughest in the Infants (Superdeluxe edition)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/second-toughest-in-the-infants-superdeluxe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/second-toughest-in-the-infants-superdeluxe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week Underworld reissued their excellent second album “Second Toughest In The Infants” in various formats including a four disc super deluxe edition. I wrote about this album in my understated classics series and I want to share some thoughts on the reissue. I love this album so I was excited to hear the remaster and the additional material.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I can’t comment on the physical version of the release as I can’t afford it at the moment. I also had to wait to buy the gorgeous yellow reissue of “Dubnobasswithmyheadman” but the “Second Toughest In The Infants” box is on the list. Underworld do a really good job on the boxes with interesting artwork to accompany the large volume of material. If the “Dubnobasswithmyheadman” box is anything to go by, the new one will be pretty hefty on the coffee table.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Satin Island by Tom McCarthy: Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/satin-island-tom-mccarthy-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/satin-island-tom-mccarthy-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As much as I wanted it to, Satin Island by Tom McCarthy did not win the Booker Prize. Having read it all I realise it was a long shot. However it is an interesting book that deserved consideration, even if it does have some flaws.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Normally I promise that there will be no spoilers. Not this time. There are some spoilers here. Because it took me so long to work out what I thought Satin Island was actually about, I want to use this post to explore those ideas. I promise to keep the amount of plot exposed to a minimum. Given that at first glance the novel appears plotless, I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have too much trouble. &lt;strong&gt;However, please read the novel before you read this review, unless you don&amp;rsquo;t intend to read it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #32: They Were Wrong So We Drowned by Liars</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-32/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As it is Halloween, I&amp;rsquo;m writing about a spooky understated classic. Liars&amp;rsquo; second album &amp;ldquo;They Were Wrong, So We Drowned&amp;rdquo; is a concept album about witches. It was the first of their albums that I owned having heard their name mentioned among those in the New York Post-punk revival scene at the start of the 00s.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I imagine that to most ears a first listen to &amp;ldquo;They Were Wrong, So We Drowned&amp;rdquo; sounds dreadful. I certainly thought so. It&amp;rsquo;s a short album and if you plough through it there are one or two nuggets that would sound great on most albums - but a lot of it initially seems to be noise and chanting and screaming. If anyone wants to make the argument that Liars are not worth the trouble, not worth the effort to like or understand, then &amp;ldquo;They Were Wrong, So We Drowned&amp;rdquo; is the album they will use as ammunition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Martian: A Short Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-martian-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-martian-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/the-martian-by-andy-weir/&#34;&gt;In my review of the book&lt;/a&gt; I mentioned that a film adaptation of The Martian was on the way. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why but it got released earlier than any of the dates that I&amp;rsquo;d seen and so on Saturday I found myself watching The Martian on the big screen. Could the film version deliver the same level of entertainment as the novel? Could Mark Watney (Matt Damon) get off Mars alive?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Booker Prize Pick 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/booker-prize-pick-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/booker-prize-pick-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theatlantic.com/entertainment/archive/2015/10/man-booker-shortlist-2015-satin-island/408784/&#34;&gt;Satin Island&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; is my pick for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://themanbookerprize.com/man-booker-prize-2015&#34;&gt;Man Booker prize&lt;/a&gt;, announced tomorrow. I&amp;rsquo;ve not managed to read all of it yet. Also, I&amp;rsquo;ve only glanced at the others on &lt;a href=&#34;http://themanbookerprize.com/news/man-booker-prize-fiction-2015-shortlist-revealed&#34;&gt;the shortlist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My prediction record on selecting the winner of the Booker from the shortlist is pretty good, though all I&amp;rsquo;m ever doing is guess the outcome of a 1 in 6 chance, like the roll of a die. Often it&amp;rsquo;s a book that I really hope will win rather than one I know will (except &amp;ldquo;Wolf Hall&amp;rdquo; and its sequel). I still think the world is a worse place for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/culture/books/fictionreviews/3665324/Man-Booker-2007-Prize-Darkmans.html&#34;&gt;Nicola Barker&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Darkmans&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; not winning the prize back in 2007. I was delighted when &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/uk/2006/oct/11/books.bookerprize2006&#34;&gt;Kiran Desai&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Inheritance of Loss&amp;rdquo; won the previous year&lt;/a&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s part of my affection for &amp;ldquo;Satin Island&amp;rdquo;, it&amp;rsquo;s a book that will make people go &amp;ldquo;huh?&amp;rdquo; if they&amp;rsquo;re driven to reading it via a prize win.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ben Elton, Time and Time Again</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/time-and-time-again-by-ben-elton/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/time-and-time-again-by-ben-elton/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Time and Time Again is a ridiculously stupid novel by Ben Elton. A shadowy sect (established by Isaac Newton no less!) recruits a soldier to go back in time and prevent Franz Ferdinand&amp;rsquo;s assassination in Sarajevo in August 1914. I wonder if it all goes to plan and everyone lives happily ever after with no weird timey-wimey after-effects?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Needless to say &lt;strong&gt;this novel makes me wish that time travel were a real thing so that I could travel back in time and slap myself in the face while in the queue to buy this tripe.&lt;/strong&gt; I usually try to see the best in the books, albums and movies that I write about, but the most fun you can have with this novel is to rip it to shreds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South America, Part 11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-trip-part-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/south-america-trip-part-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;la-paz-to-potosi&#34;&gt;La Paz to Potosi&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/south_america/part_11/01.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We left La Paz, this time ascending the rim of steep hills around the city in a slightly less clunky &amp;ldquo;Death Bus&amp;rdquo;. Perhaps it was because we were travelling uphill or because it was daylight, but it didn&amp;rsquo;t seem so bad.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/south_america/part_11/02.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/south_america/part_11/03.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We set off to Potosi through strange towns with weird monuments (see the pictures) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lonelyplanet.com/bolivia/the-southwest/oruro/travel-tips-and-articles/76305&#34;&gt;Oruro where great festivals happen around Ash Wednesday each year&lt;/a&gt; that are famous throughout the continent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eric Schlosser, Gods of Metal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gods-of-metal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gods-of-metal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Y-12 is the United States&amp;rsquo; most secure weapons-grade Uranium storage facility. It is known as the &amp;ldquo;Fort Knox of Uranium&amp;rdquo;. In 2012 it was infiltrated by three elderly peace protesters, sparking a major scandal about the safety of US nuclear sites. &amp;ldquo;Gods of Metal&amp;rdquo; by Eric Schlosser tells the story of that break-in alongside a history of both the anti-nuclear movement (in particular &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plowshares_Movement&#34;&gt;the Plowshares movement&lt;/a&gt;) and nuclear security in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everything Everything, Get To Heaven</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/everything-everything-get-to-heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/everything-everything-get-to-heaven/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write honestly about your feelings. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write about your feelings consistently, for a living on a regular basis. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write about your feelings when the world constantly intrudes with inanity, insanity and hatred. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to write under those conditions without seeming frayed, without coming loose at the edges.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Get To Heaven&amp;rdquo;, the third album by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.everything-everything.co.uk&#34;&gt;Everything Everything&lt;/a&gt;, was forged under these stresses and pressures. For most of its running time it sounds like either a bomb ticking down to explode or like a clock inexorably counting up missed opportunities and stolen moments. It sounds for all the world as though it is trapped between fight and flight, paused between action and apathy. Yet it also subjects the listener to the yammerings of a culture that has driven itself mad. Depth and surface, glass and steel, truth and lies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inherent Vice: A Short Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/inherent-vice-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/inherent-vice-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tonight I finally caught up with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inherent_Vice_(film)&#34;&gt;Inherent Vice&lt;/a&gt;, Paul Thomas Anderson&amp;rsquo;s adaptation of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Inherent-Vice-Thomas-Pynchon/dp/0099542161/ref=sr_1_4?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1437860132&amp;amp;sr=8-4&amp;amp;keywords=inherent+vice&#34;&gt;Thomas Pynchon&amp;rsquo;s novel&lt;/a&gt;. It stars &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0001618/&#34;&gt;Joaquin Phoenix&lt;/a&gt; as Larry &amp;lsquo;Doc&amp;rsquo; Sportello who&amp;rsquo;s put on to a case of possible kidnapping by his &amp;ldquo;ex-old lady&amp;rdquo; Shasta, played by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/film/2015/jun/16/katherine-waterston-jk-rowlings-fantastic-beasts-harry-potter&#34;&gt;Katherine Waterston&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no point attempting to tell much more you of the plot of Inherent Vice: it&amp;rsquo;s rather convoluted and self-digesting. At least this means there&amp;rsquo;s very little chance of stumbling into inadvertent spoilers. However, most of the plot strands do fall into place by the end, much more than I&amp;rsquo;d imagined they would half way through.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #31: The White Room by The KLF</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-31/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This little masterpiece was released in 1991. I got my copy on cassette for Christmas that year, but by May in 1992 they&amp;rsquo;d already &amp;ldquo;retired&amp;rdquo; and split up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The KLF were a band in the right place at the right time with the right idea. Taking advantage of synthesizers and the idea of fusing rock and pop music with the emerging sound of house music, they laid the ground for many of the most successful electronic acts that followed them. They were also master showmen, taking a whole host of crazy conspiracy theories and smooshing them together in one stadium-sized package.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/untitled-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/untitled-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months ago &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/jackson-x/&#34;&gt;I wrote about an idea for a novel that I&amp;rsquo;d abandoned&lt;/a&gt;. I mentioned in that post that I&amp;rsquo;d abandoned it because there was another idea that I wanted to pursue. The working title for it is &amp;ldquo;Untitled 2&amp;rdquo;. (It isn&amp;rsquo;t really, I have an actual working title that would give things away or would at least make me feel like the idea was out in the world.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Light, Last Light</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/first-light-last-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/first-light-last-light/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I often ponder whether the joys of waking up early are greater than those of staying up late. Empirical evidence seems to bear this out: all those people who get to work before you do, super-eager to get everything done. But then all the people walking under your windows late at night, drunk and laughing, they sound like they&amp;rsquo;re having a whale of a time too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I oscillate between the two extremes, though I tend to sleep better if I stay up late. My natural sleep hours are 1am to 8am, though I am usually human if I can get up just after 7. Whenever I try to stick to getting up early, to do masochistic things like running or being organised, I often find it harder to get to sleep or I wake up at 3 rather than 6. I end up second guessing my alarm clock.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minions: A Short Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/minions-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/minions-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Minions got their own movie, just as I predicted in &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/despicable-me-2-a-short-review/&#34;&gt;my review of Despicable Me 2&lt;/a&gt;. I went to see it this week and I enjoyed it a lot. Here&amp;rsquo;s a short review. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, there are no spoilers here that aren&amp;rsquo;t in the trailer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s very funny. Right from the opening credits you get the minions and their anarchic fun-loving slapstick humour. There&amp;rsquo;s always been something delightful about they way in which they innocently bumble around. Their penchant for evil bosses is inexplicable but incredibly amusing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Initial Comparison of Apple Music and Spotify</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/an-initial-comparison-of-apple-music-and-spotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/an-initial-comparison-of-apple-music-and-spotify/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/why-apple-music-feels-like-a-fail/&#34;&gt;previous post about Apple Music&lt;/a&gt; was more a response to how it was presented at the WWDC Keynote rather than to the idea of Apple Music itself. I should have known better than to use that clickbait title. I knew I wasn&amp;rsquo;t writing about the product, more the flatness of its introduction (despite the names on show).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After a few days of living with it I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write about it and Spotify, so that it&amp;rsquo;s not just my snarky comments about the keynote that are on record here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To reboot this series, Album Digest June 2015 features five fantastic albums from Hot Chip, Jamie xx, Blanck Mass, Holly Herndon, and The Orb. I could pick loads more as I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to a lot of albums since &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/album-digest-february-2015/&#34;&gt;February&lt;/a&gt; but I decided to focus on the more electronic material. This means that I have no excuses for not continuing next month with a rockier theme.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;hot-chip-why-make-sense&#34;&gt;Hot Chip &amp;ldquo;Why Make Sense?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hot Chip seem to be settling in to a pattern with their album releases, alternating between messy experimental affairs and then a state of the art correction. Witness how &amp;ldquo;The Warning&amp;rdquo; smartened up the all-over-the-place &amp;ldquo;Coming On Strong&amp;rdquo; and how &amp;ldquo;One Life Stand&amp;rdquo; moulded and matured the lovestruck meandering of &amp;ldquo;Made In The Dark&amp;rdquo; into a lithe ten song set. &amp;ldquo;Why Make Sense?&amp;rdquo; takes the earnest song-based approach of &amp;ldquo;In Our Heads&amp;rdquo; and casts it into a funky fun-filled fifty minutes. It&amp;rsquo;s as concise as they&amp;rsquo;ve been since &amp;ldquo;One Life Stand&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time Is Time and That Is That</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/time-is-time-and-that-is-that/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/time-is-time-and-that-is-that/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A brief rant about Facebook: I hate the fact that the news feed defaults to “Top Stories” even though I change it back to “Most Recent” every time I log in. It’s a horrible pattern of user abuse that needs to stop. Time is time and that is that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So why does Facebook feel the need to jiggle things about into a random order? Well most of you have that mobile phone app of theirs that sucks your battery and your data allowance like crazy (mainly by auto-playing videos like a dick). They know you’re checking your Facebook on the loo at work and that that limits your interaction time. During this precious interlude they want you to see the stuff that they think interests you and the things that other people paid for you to see. You’re going to see some hick’s new tattoo, at least one photo of someone else’s child and an advert telling you to vote Conservative - whether you like it or not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn X in Y Minutes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/learn-x-in-y-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/learn-x-in-y-minutes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found &amp;ldquo;Learn X in Y minutes&amp;rdquo; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://learnxinyminutes.com&#34;&gt;www.learnxinyminutes.com&lt;/a&gt;) while researching the programming languages needed for a new project. The site aims to help people who know at least one programming language to learn others by proving a quick run through of the main language features. It&amp;rsquo;s not quite enough to get you up and running. After all, having sample code doesn&amp;rsquo;t get you the compiler. However, it&amp;rsquo;s a nice start that shows you how similar (and different) language X is compared to the one(s) you already know.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jim&#39;s Conservatory</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/jims-conservatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/jims-conservatory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s assume that Jim has just had a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2008_United_Kingdom_bank_rescue_package&#34;&gt;sudden unexpected expenditure&lt;/a&gt;: a neighbour released a bull into his back garden and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/business/2007/nov/01/creditcrunch.subprimecrisis&#34;&gt;it destroyed his conservatory&lt;/a&gt;. Let&amp;rsquo;s assume that the conservatory is essential to Jim&amp;rsquo;s wellbeing, so it has to be fixed immediately. As a result Jim&amp;rsquo;s debts, which &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/business/2015/may/03/senior-tory-financial-crash-was-purely-a-banking-crisis-not-labour-overspend&#34;&gt;were previously small and well-managed&lt;/a&gt;, have now increased somewhat.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Obviously Jim can&amp;rsquo;t keep that debt hanging over him forever. What does he do?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for Jim, the circumstances of his borrowing aren&amp;rsquo;t so different before and after the event. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/finance/personalfinance/interest-rates/9922941/Interest-rates-predictions-Four-more-years-of-0.5.html&#34;&gt;Interest rates are low and are predicted to stay low&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-21554311&#34;&gt;terms of his credit haven&amp;rsquo;t changed a great deal despite his increased borrowing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Like a Rhino Voting for Poaching</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/like-a-rhino-voting-for-poaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/like-a-rhino-voting-for-poaching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a reason I cannot and will not vote Conservative, and like most people&amp;rsquo;s apparent motive for voting tory it is also a selfish one. As someone employed in the public sector, working to ensure the greater good, I&amp;rsquo;m a member of an increasingly endangered species.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ah Matthew, I hear you say, you&amp;rsquo;re trotting out the old &amp;ldquo;the turkeys have voted for Christmas&amp;rdquo; line. Well no, like I said, this is purely selfish. When you mark that X in the box, you tend to think about yourself only. Never mind the turkeys (for now).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #30: Our Aim Is to Satisfy by Red Snapper</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The thirtieth understated classic is by a band named after a fish. There isn&amp;rsquo;t a great deal for me to say about &amp;ldquo;Our Aim Is To Satisfy&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; apart from the usual insistence that it is quite good. There&amp;rsquo;s no overarching theme to write about, and no deep personal story attached. It was bound to happen eventually.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our Aim Is To Satisfy&amp;rdquo; is one of those albums spawned in the late nineties and early naughties at the height of the Electronica boom: dance music that you didn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily have to dance to. It&amp;rsquo;s not quite chill out music but nor is it song-based (for the most part) - it&amp;rsquo;s mainly instrumental electronic music.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Consider the Donut</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/consider-the-donut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/consider-the-donut/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;or-from-there-to-here-with-the-simpsons&#34;&gt;Or, From There to Here With the Simpsons&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Old episodes of The Simpsons are great. The other night “Bart After Dark” was on and I really enjoyed seeing it again. It’s from season eight, the one where Bart ends up working in the Maison Derriére. I thought it was older; mind you, this makes it nineteen years old. When I thought about the episode later on that evening, I realised how the story anarchically set out in multiple directions before settling into its main storyline. This still happens in newer Simpsons episodes, though the show is rarely as joyfully chaotic now as it was back then.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Andy Weir, The Martian</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-martian-by-andy-weir/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-martian-by-andy-weir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I received a copy of The Martian by Andy Weir for Christmas. This week during some annual leave I managed to finish it. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those novels that just flies by once it gets going. I&amp;rsquo;ve stayed up incredibly late to read it as it is full of those &amp;ldquo;just one more page&amp;rdquo; moments. It’s a readable and enjoyable story of an astronaut trapped on Mars.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mark Watney is believed to be dead following an accident during an emergency evacuation in a dust storm. With his life support readings at zero and unable to locate his body to be certain, his crew reluctantly abandon him on the red planet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jodorowsky&#39;s Dune</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/jodorowskys-dune/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/jodorowskys-dune/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1935156/?ref_=fn_al_tt_1&#34;&gt;Jodorowsky&amp;rsquo;s Dune&lt;/a&gt; is a documentary about outlandish Chilean director &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alejandro_Jodorowsky&#34;&gt;Alejandro Jodorosky&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; attempt at a film adaptation of &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dune/&#34;&gt;Frank Herbert&amp;rsquo;s Dune&lt;/a&gt; in the 1970s. As a big fan of the novel and of science fiction in general, I was very interested in this film. It does not disappoint. It gives a great insight into the mind of a little known (if slightly batty) director and shows even an artistic failure can lead to shock waves that can be felt in later work by others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Little Bit Intimidating Really</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-little-bit-intimidating-really/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-little-bit-intimidating-really/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is so much good writing out there. All you have to do is fire up &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/uk/&#34;&gt;the guardian website&lt;/a&gt;, or download the &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/m/app&#34;&gt;medium app to your smartphone&lt;/a&gt;, or visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://xianity.me/&#34;&gt;my friend Barrie&amp;rsquo;s site&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://narami.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Lee&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;, and so on and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When it comes to my little whisper into this great choir, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to feel a bit intimidated. How do I add my voice? How do I feel distinct? How do I do it as well as all these other wonderful writers?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Fireworks Work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-fireworks-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-fireworks-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night an impromptu firework display occurred. I watched it from my bathroom window. Very pretty and somewhat extravagant, given that there’s no reason for one on the calendar. I could have filmed it on meerkat but it would have diminished the spectacle. However, it did at least motivate me to write this piece that I have put off for a while (since about November I guess?). One where I find out (i.e. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fireworks&#34;&gt;look up on Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;) how fireworks work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ned Beauman, Glow</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/glow-by-ned-beauman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/glow-by-ned-beauman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Glow is about a guy called Raf, a Londoner whose life is going nowhere in particular; a state of affairs not helped by “Non-24 Hour Sleep/Wake Syndrome”. One night while experimenting with a new ecstacy-like drug that’s apparently derived from a social anxiety medication for dogs, Raf meets a beautiful girl and then loses her to the crowd in a blink-and-you-miss-it moment. From there a conspiracy evolves involving the titular dog-medication-derived drug, Burmese dissidents, corporate espionage, pirate radio stations, and urban foxes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Can’t Just Switch Off Free</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-cant-just-switch-off-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-cant-just-switch-off-free/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2015/mar/11/ministry-of-sound-streaming-switch-off-free&#34;&gt;Ministry of Sound boss Lohan Presencer does the cry baby act in today&amp;rsquo;s Guardian&lt;/a&gt;, complaining that Spotify&amp;rsquo;s freemium model doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow him to bathe in a Scrooge McDuck style swimming pool of golden coins any more. The cat is out of the bag for streaming music now, and no matter how much music companies cry foul they can&amp;rsquo;t stop Spotify and their ilk, and there wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be pots of gold waiting for them even if they could.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, February 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;aphex-twin-computer-controlled-acoustic-instruments-pt2-ep&#34;&gt;Aphex Twin &amp;ldquo;Computer Controlled Acoustic Instruments Pt2 EP&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aphex Twin follows SYRO (reviewed in &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/album-digest-september-2014/&#34;&gt;Album Digest September 2014 here&lt;/a&gt;) with this 27 minute EP of music that, if we take the title literally, features computers playing acoustic musical instruments. It&amp;rsquo;s a very different sound to SYRO and sounds acoustic for the most part. It&amp;rsquo;s an important experiment about the role of the musician, one that is already blurred in the creation of electronic music.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #29: Let It Come Down by Spiritualized</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I listened to Let It Come Down by Spiritualized for the first time during a difficult time in my life. I think this will always affect my feelings towards it. For me it&amp;rsquo;s a great big comfort blanket of a record. Coming after one of the all-time best break-up albums (in an artistic sense) in &amp;ldquo;Ladies and Gentlemen We Are Floating in Space&amp;rdquo; perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s not that much of a surprise. Layered in orchestras, horn sections, and gospel choirs, it&amp;rsquo;s not understated at all but hopefully I can persuade you that it is a classic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Writing As It Happens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/writing-as-it-happens/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/writing-as-it-happens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m pretty close to a round number. To date I have written 298,500 words for this blog, not counting posts that I have discarded or deleted. This will be the 505th post currently on the blog, which makes for an average of just under 600 words per post. Some posts are just a picture or a video or a gallery though, so that distorts the average a bit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don’t think I can write the 1500 words I need to hit 300,000 in this post. It’s quite hard to write on demand and I often feel like my bright ideas are unassailable when I sit down to type them up. I’m conscious that I have to keep turning up to type but I’m not sure that it’s worthwhile to write posts like this simply to keep up a streak. A blog should be like an iceberg: the heft below the water line will make everything above it more beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On The Humble Cheese Grater</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/humble-cheese-grater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/humble-cheese-grater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t beat a good cheese grater. Cheese just tastes better in a sandwich once it has been grated. It&amp;rsquo;s been proven by ACTUAL SCIENCE that this is the case: something about the increased surface area making it taste more zingy (NB. QI is not actually a peer-reviewed scientific journal). Of course the cheese we are grating here is a nice mature cheddar, you can&amp;rsquo;t grate Camembert or Stilton (well &lt;em&gt;technically&lt;/em&gt; you can, but why would you?). There are even cheeses that can be grated but don&amp;rsquo;t deserve it, take Red Leicester for example: the ear wax of the cheese world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Jackson X</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/jackson-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/jackson-x/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I set myself the task of writing about a fictional character for this blog post, so this post is about Jackson X. His surname isn’t really X, it’s just one of the details about him that I haven’t fleshed out yet. This is because Jackson X is the one of the protagonists of the novel I’m (not) writing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The name of the novel is “The Summer of the Giant Space Whale”. I’m quite happy to discuss its plot and structure here. I don’t need to worry about anyone stealing the idea because it is already a rip-off of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/112537.Rendezvous_with_Rama&#34;&gt;Arthur C. Clarke’s “Rendezvous With Rama”&lt;/a&gt; (or, less charitably, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0092007/?ref_=nv_sr_1&#34;&gt;“Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home”&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Voting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-voting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We hear a lot about our rights but these are given to us in return for fulfilling our responsibilities. One of these is engagement in the democratic process, and in particular voting. You should register to vote, that’s a no brainer. You should take an interest in what politics means for you locally, nationally, and internationally. On the day you to get to the polling station and cast your vote. Then you need to hold you representative accountable afterwards, even if he or she isn’t the person you voted for.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, January 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-january-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Album Digest January 2015 rounds up a few albums from the tail end of 2014 that I didn&amp;rsquo;t get much time to write about. The only one of these six to be released this month is the excellent &amp;ldquo;No Cities To Love&amp;rdquo; by Sleater-Kinney.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;sleater-kinney-no-cities-to-love&#34;&gt;Sleater-Kinney &amp;ldquo;No Cities To Love&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had heard of Sleater-Kinney before their boxed set “Start Together” was released in 2014. I was quite impressed that they curated their own Spotify playlist with the contents of the box. I added it and even downloaded the songs for offline listening but didn’t get around to much more than a cursory play of a few tracks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #28: The Meadowlands by The Wrens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-28/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the first lines of &amp;ldquo;The House That Guilt Built&amp;rdquo;, the soft cricket-laden lament that opens The Meadowlands by The Wrens, is &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m nowhere near where I thought I&amp;rsquo;d be&amp;rdquo;. The last line of the whole album is &amp;ldquo;this is not what you had planned&amp;rdquo;. These bookending lines set the tone for this shimmering, ramshackle masterpiece - a fatigue and careworn pride in failing to meet impossible standards writ large over its first and last eighty or so seconds. &amp;ldquo;The Meadowlands&amp;rdquo; is probably the best record you&amp;rsquo;ve never heard, and once you have heard it, you will never be the same. Even better, it changes and you change with every single listen. If you&amp;rsquo;re living your life and you really mean it, then this is the record for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iain M. Banks, Feersum Endjinn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/feersum-endjinn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/feersum-endjinn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Feersum Endjinn is one of Iain Banks&amp;rsquo; few non-Culture sci-fi novels. Like the Culture novels, an existential crisis drives the plot: in this case the action takes place on Earth in the far future and the sun has aged to a point where it will grow and swallow the earth. This is referred to as the Encroachment. The characters are divided between the good guys who seek to find a solution for the greater good and bad guys who use the Encroachment to consolidate their power and influence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year 2015!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/happy-new-year-for-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/happy-new-year-for-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a brief message to wish everyone a happy new year. Getting my flat connected to the internet continues to be a trial so it&amp;rsquo;s still not as easy to post as I would like. However, I have some workarounds now and I hope to write (and post) more often from now on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like everyone I make resolutions at this time of year, though as the years pass I realise that the best resolutions are to apopt a new way of being rather than a new way of doing. I find it quite difficult to &amp;ldquo;change&amp;rdquo; myself by willpower alone. I think this is true of most people. Travelling taught me that it&amp;rsquo;s better to evolve. I just do one little thing differently and then try to notice the benefits as they accrue. As you become are of how you are changing it gets easier and you can shift your focus to doing another little thing a bit differently, a bit better. At least that&amp;rsquo;s the theory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
