<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Electronic on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/electronic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Electronic on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/electronic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Underworld, Strawberrry Hotel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/underworld-strawberrry-hotel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/underworld-strawberrry-hotel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An album that arrived a bit too late to be considered in the best of the year list, &lt;em&gt;Strawberry Hotel&lt;/em&gt; by Underworld is a solid effort. Their 11th album, it remarks their return to the format after five years after the &lt;em&gt;Drift&lt;/em&gt; series in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Albums of the Year #1: Bolis Pupul, Letter To Yu</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-01-bolis-pupul-letter-to-yu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-01-bolis-pupul-letter-to-yu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bolispupul.bandcamp.com&#34;&gt;Bolis Pupul&lt;/a&gt; (the stage name of Boris Zeebroek) is an artist on &lt;a href=&#34;https://deew.ee/catalogue&#34;&gt;Soulwax&amp;rsquo;s Deewee label&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://deew.ee/catalogue/074&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Letter to Yu&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is his debut album, inspired by a trip to Hong Kong to investigate his family history. It investigates themes of place, family, and identity. We are exposed to everywhere all at once but we&amp;rsquo;re also all &lt;em&gt;from&lt;/em&gt; somewhere, even if it&amp;rsquo;s somewhere we might not recommend or understand.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Albums of the Year #3: Acopia, Acopia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-03-acopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-03-acopia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Acopia are a band from Melbourne Australia with that time honoured line up of one girl and two guys. This eponymous album is their second and it&amp;rsquo;s full of slinky electronic ballads that echo classic 90s trip hop. It&amp;rsquo;s got that same downtempo downbeat vibe, the sorts of songs that revel in sadness but also the joy of a killer bass line.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Albums of the Year #5: Il Quadro di Troisi, La Commedia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-05-il-quadro-di-troisi-la-commedia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-05-il-quadro-di-troisi-la-commedia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting that an album sung entirely in Italian ended up being one of my favourites of the year, but perhaps not surprising given well written and arranged these songs are. They&amp;rsquo;re just the right side of electro-pop but also with an air of sophistication.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Albums of the Year #6: Total Blue, Total Blue</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-06-total-blue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-06-total-blue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What do you think of when you think of the colour blue? The sea? Perhaps the sky? Maybe it makes you think of blue stones like sapphires, or flowers such as forget-me-nots? Maybe the colour blue is the glow of a phone screen on someone&amp;rsquo;s face (maybe yours) in the dark? Blue gathers at the edges of the harsh white LED light that has come to dominate our night time existence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maara, The Ancient Truth (on vinyl)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/maara-the-ancient-truth-vinyl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/maara-the-ancient-truth-vinyl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/2023-albums-07-maara-ancient-truth&#34;&gt;I wrote about Maara&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Ancient Truth&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; over Christmas as part of my albums of the year rundown, I mentioned at the end that I would love to find a copy on vinyl to listen to. Well dear reader I managed to! It arrived today from the Netherlands with minimal fuss. It sounds great and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure whether my review did it justice: that&amp;rsquo;s the problem with attempting to (re-)review ten albums in ten days with Christmas and New Year all happening at the same time!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #1: Sofia Kourtesis, Madres</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-01-sofia-kourtesis-madres/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-01-sofia-kourtesis-madres/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sofia Kourtesis is a Berlin-based Peruvian dance producer, &amp;ldquo;Madres&amp;rdquo; is her debut album which follows on from a 2021 EP &amp;ldquo;Fresia Magdalena&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;&lt;span class=&#34;marginfigure&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/sofia-kourtesis-madres.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Madres by Sofia Kourtesis&#34; /&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Cover of &lt;em&gt;Madres&lt;/em&gt; by Sofia Kourtesis&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;It was trailed by several singles, including the title track which caught my attention back in May. The album is dedicated to her parents and there are also songs dedicated to the surgeon who performed life-saving surgery on Kourtesis’s mother. The whole album is a heady mix of positivity and dedication to both music and to family.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For me, ten years on from my trip to South America, I think my response to this album has been to its fusion of European and South American dance music, perhaps reminding me that it is possible to incorporate the experiences one has in other places into our viewpoint on the world. It seems to be that we are in a point in history that rather than acknowledging that we are interconnected and responsible for and to one another, that we have instead lurched into a protectionist and selfish mode of thinking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #2: James Holden, Imagine This is a High Dimensional Space of All Possibilities</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-02-james-holden-imagine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-02-james-holden-imagine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cool artwork! No, we don&amp;rsquo;t have it but it&amp;rsquo;s coming in next week.&amp;ldquo;&lt;span class=&#34;marginfigure&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/james-holden-imagine.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Imagine This is a High Dimensional Space of All Possibilities by James Holden&#34; /&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Cover of &lt;em&gt;Imagine This is a High Dimensional Space of All Possibilities&lt;/em&gt; by James Holden&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cool artwork! We haven&amp;rsquo;t had a copy in but I can order it for you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Me picking it up a week later: &amp;ldquo;Cool artwork!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Imagine This is a High Dimensional Space of All Possibilities&amp;rdquo; is definitely album title of the year, made all the more topical with the intrusion of Chat-GPT and the like into the cultural conversation. Large Language Models (LLMs) like Chat-GPT work by absorbing large amounts of textual data (i.e. this blog, helping to make all those instant album reviews you can write now just a tiny bit more shit) and breaking them down into tokens, with each token having a meaning and a grammatical role and so on. These meanings and roles form higher dimensional spaces in which the tokens are vectors, where the rules of the LLMs help determine which tokens live near to one another and which pairs are likely to sit together in &amp;lsquo;meaningful&amp;rsquo; sentences etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #3: Barry Can&#39;t Swim, When Will We Land?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-03-barry-cant-swim-when-will-we-land/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-03-barry-cant-swim-when-will-we-land/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some albums you come to one way: a good review on a blog you respect,&#xA;&lt;span class=&#34;marginfigure&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/barry-cant-swim-when-will-we-land.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of _When Will We Land_ by Barry Can&amp;#39;t Swim&#34; /&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Cover of &lt;em&gt;When Will We Land&lt;/em&gt; by Barry Can&amp;rsquo;t Swim&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;a track appearing on a playlist by someone whose taste you trust, etc and so on. And sometimes you get directed to something multiple times. This is what happened to me this year with the irrepressible “When Will We Land?” by Barry Can’t Swim. Anyway, tracks by &amp;ldquo;Barry&amp;rdquo; appeared in mixes a lot this year and the album kept popping up in eagerly anticipated lists.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to this album a lot but I still have questions. Like is &amp;ldquo;can&amp;rsquo;t swim&amp;rdquo; his last name? Was he not made to learn in detention at lunchtime in the school&amp;rsquo;s outdoor pool in an English April like yours truly?!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The album starts with the title track, a nice minimalist piece that is nearly “not dance music” in the way that so many opening tracks on dance albums are. It puts me in mind of Steve Reich played by Bonobo. The next track “Deadbeat Gospel” is an impromptu rap by an old school friend while on a night out sampled and cut to fit the beat, it’s pretty cool but I’m glad it’s near the beginning so I can skip over it if I’m not feeling it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #5: Nation of Language, Strange Disciple</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-05-nation-of-language-strange-disciple/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-05-nation-of-language-strange-disciple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It would be remiss of me to claim that this is a placeholder for any number&#xA;&lt;span class=&#34;marginfigure&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/nation-of-language-strange-disciple.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Strange Disciple by Nation of Language&#34; /&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Cover of &lt;em&gt;Strange Disciple&lt;/em&gt; by Nation of Language&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;of (quite different sounding) song based albums that came out this year (Yves Tumor, Wilco to mention two) but it feels that way. This album came high up my list of listens because it&amp;rsquo;s a very good breakfast album, one to listen to while getting the Day started - though there are also some bangers on here too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nation of language are a three piece band from New York. I think one of them is famous for being in a band I&amp;rsquo;ve not heard of (or is that their producer, I must do some fact checking) and two of them are married, even going so far as to have had a gofundme or whatever for the band as a present at a wedding. (That doesn&amp;rsquo;t give off future &amp;ldquo;we are a duo now&amp;rdquo; vibes at all!)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #7: Maara, The Ancient Truth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-07-maara-ancient-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-07-maara-ancient-truth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There isn&amp;rsquo;t a great deal I can write about The Ancient Truth without sounding vague and anodyne.&#xA;&lt;span class=&#34;marginfigure&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/maara-ancient-truth.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of The Ancient Truth by Maara&#34; /&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Cover of &lt;em&gt;The Ancient Truth&lt;/em&gt; by Maara&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;While I try to come think about different forms of music and go into some analysis of what makes one album more interesting than another, sometimes you end up just saying &amp;ldquo;this album is great because I like it and I always have a good time listening to it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #8: Everything But The Girl, Fuse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-08-ebtg-fuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-08-ebtg-fuse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you get older nostalgia becomes an ever important part of listening to music.&#xA;&lt;span class=&#34;marginfigure&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/ebtg-fuse.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Fuse by Everything But The Girl&#34; /&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Cover of &lt;em&gt;Fuse&lt;/em&gt; by Everything But The Girl&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;It often feels like the business relies on convincing an aging population of fans to part with their money on new versions of old material. It&amp;rsquo;s nostalgia, the feeling of recapturing something you loved in your youth, that often makes this acceptable. Of course it&amp;rsquo;s also nice to get &lt;strong&gt;new&lt;/strong&gt; music from your favourite bands, especially when it&amp;rsquo;s as good as &amp;ldquo;Fuse&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #9: Fever Ray, Radical Romantics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-09-fever-ray-radical-romantics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-09-fever-ray-radical-romantics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Radical Romantics, the third album by Fever Ray was released in April. I bought a copy on red vinyl which is a beautiful sight to behold.&lt;span class=&#34;marginfigure&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/fever-ray-radical-romantics.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Radical Romantics by Fever Ray&#34; /&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Cover of &lt;em&gt;Radical Romantics&lt;/em&gt; by Fever Ray&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/span&gt; I listened to a lot when it was released but eased up a bit until listening to it a couple more times while writing this list. It&amp;rsquo;s a great collection of songs, probably better than their second album &amp;ldquo;Plunge&amp;rdquo;. The cover art is just as scary though.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #10: Wata Igarashi, Agartha</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-10-wata-igarashi-agartha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-10-wata-igarashi-agartha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Agartha is the debut album by Japanese electronic artist Wata Igarashi.&lt;span class=&#34;marginfigure&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/wata-igarashi-agartha.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Agartha by Wata Igarashi&#34; /&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Cover of &lt;em&gt;Agartha&lt;/em&gt; by Wata Igarashi&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/span&gt; I don&amp;rsquo;t really know much about him, but I do know that I enjoy releases on the German record label Kompakt and I have really enjoyed Japanese techno in recent years. Over lockdown I discovered Haruomi Hosono&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Polyharmony&amp;rdquo; album and re-discovered the work of Shinichi Atobe, particularly their album &amp;ldquo;Love of Plastic&amp;rdquo;. Both of those albums could be future understated classics and while both are by Japanese artists working in electronic music, there the comparison ends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabric 44 by John Tejada</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fabric-44-by-john-tejada/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fabric-44-by-john-tejada/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is one of my more played Fabric mix CDs so I decided to go for it when my random prompter plumped for this earlier today. One constraint of these posts was to write it in roughly the amount of time it takes to listen to it. You&amp;rsquo;d think that for a mix CD that would be ok. After all, this mix is a full CD and 74 minutes long.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Orb, Live at Brighton Concord 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-orb---brighton-concord-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-orb---brighton-concord-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Went with my friend Nick to see The Orb at Concord 2 last night. The last time I&amp;rsquo;d seen the Orb was back in 2004, at the start of their relatively dry spell. That night, they&amp;rsquo;d been a bit lacklustre despite playing (some of) the hits and a relatively decent album in &amp;ldquo;Bicycles and Tricycles&amp;rdquo;. I left feeling that I&amp;rsquo;d seen the past rather than the future, something that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t glimpse again in their records until 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #39: Lifeforms by Future Sound of London</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-39/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-39/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lifeforms&lt;/strong&gt; is the 1994 album from the Future Sound of London. A double album (just), it also features the talents of Robert Fripp, Ozric Tentacles, Talvin Singh, Toni Halliday, and Liz Frazer. It reached number 6 on the UK album chart and went silver.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics Or Not?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-or-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-or-not/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the new year, thoughts and spare time for writing point me toward writing some new posts for my understated classics series. Expect some new ones soon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #38: Trance Nation (Various Artists)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-38/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-38/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, but lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been in need of some music that:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Will Make Room For You - Four Tet Remix</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/i-will-make-room-for-you---four-tet-remix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/i-will-make-room-for-you---four-tet-remix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a perfect confluence of &lt;a href=&#34;album-digest-october-2011&#34;&gt;last month&amp;rsquo;s album digest&lt;/a&gt;, here&amp;rsquo;s an excellent Four Tet remix of Kaitlyn Aurelia Smith&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;I Will Make Room For You&amp;rdquo; from her album &amp;ldquo;The Kid&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ve put it into a playlist with &amp;ldquo;Lush&amp;rdquo; from Four Tet&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;New Energy&amp;rdquo; album and the original version of &amp;ldquo;I Will Make Room For You.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #35: Snivilisation by Orbital</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-35/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I came late to Orbital&amp;rsquo;s work. I knew of them through a few remixes and because as a mad Orb fan, they could not have avoided my notice could they? Apart from that, one of my college friends tried to get me into &amp;ldquo;In Sides&amp;rdquo; just after its release in 1996. The same friend got me into &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/understated-classics-11/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Second Toughest In The Infants&amp;rdquo; by Underworld&lt;/a&gt;. I cannot now understand the reason, but &amp;ldquo;In Sides&amp;rdquo; just left me cold.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Orb - Alpine EP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/orb-alpine-ep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/orb-alpine-ep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Orb return with a new EP on the &lt;a href=&#34;www.kompakt.fm&#34;&gt;Kompakt label&lt;/a&gt; called &amp;ldquo;Alpine&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Underworld, Second Toughest in the Infants (Superdeluxe edition)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/second-toughest-in-the-infants-superdeluxe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/second-toughest-in-the-infants-superdeluxe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week Underworld reissued their excellent second album “Second Toughest In The Infants” in various formats including a four disc super deluxe edition. I wrote about this album in my understated classics series and I want to share some thoughts on the reissue. I love this album so I was excited to hear the remaster and the additional material.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #31: The White Room by The KLF</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-31/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This little masterpiece was released in 1991. I got my copy on cassette for Christmas that year, but by May in 1992 they&amp;rsquo;d already &amp;ldquo;retired&amp;rdquo; and split up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #30: Our Aim Is to Satisfy by Red Snapper</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The thirtieth understated classic is by a band named after a fish. There isn&amp;rsquo;t a great deal for me to say about &amp;ldquo;Our Aim Is To Satisfy&amp;rdquo;&lt;label for=&#34;sidenote-0d5ce721c6374d08ef5be2ea13137861-0&#34; class=&#34;margin-toggle sidenote-number&#34;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; id=&#34;sidenote-0d5ce721c6374d08ef5be2ea13137861-0&#34; class=&#34;margin-toggle&#34;/&gt;&#xA;&lt;span class=&#34;sidenote&#34;&gt;A note on the title of the album, some sources refer to is as &amp;ldquo;Our Aim Is To Satisfy Red Snapper&amp;rdquo;. Personally I think this is ridiculous.&lt;/span&gt; apart from the usual insistence that it is quite good. There&amp;rsquo;s no overarching theme to write about, and no deep personal story attached. It was bound to happen eventually.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What IS That Noise?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-that-noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-that-noise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently spruced up a post I wrote four years ago about &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-4/&#34;&gt;Biosphere’s wonderful album Substrata&lt;/a&gt;. I added the following footnote about the difference between voice samples and found sound:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Amazing Subversive Revolutionary Adolescence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-amazing-subversive-revolutionary-adolescence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-amazing-subversive-revolutionary-adolescence/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #23: Gorgeous by 808 State</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was quite hard to choose an 808 State album for the &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;understated classics series&lt;/a&gt; for two reasons. The first is that I was introduced to 808 State quite late through a friend&amp;rsquo;s sister&amp;rsquo;s cassette copy of The Shamen&amp;rsquo;s En-Tact (the original version recorded from vinyl that had a thirteen minute version of &amp;ldquo;Evil Is Eden&amp;rdquo;) that also had &amp;ndash; to fill out the C90 &amp;ndash; the full length sweary version of &amp;ldquo;What Time Is Love?&amp;rdquo; by The KLF and four tracks: &amp;ldquo;Cubik&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Pacific&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Olympic&amp;rdquo; (I think&amp;hellip;), and &amp;ldquo;In Yer Face&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Work Of Art At The End Of My Road?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-work-of-art-at-the-end-of-my-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-work-of-art-at-the-end-of-my-road/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have had a lot of ideas for posts swirling around in my head in recent days. This is because I have actually done quite a lot of cool things in that time, and because I have hung out with some great people who make me think, and because I always have a whole load of things bouncing around in there anyway - space junk of the mind. I was thinking about how to put together these thoughts I have been having about art and about stories and yes, about love too. It all kind of got muddled up and then I saw it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #21: Woob 2 by Woob</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The second Woob album (AKA “Woob 4495”) is probably the greatest ambient album ever made and is certainly the best one you have never heard of. Originally released in 1995 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.emit.cc&#34;&gt;on the em:t label&lt;/a&gt; it is also a rare record. I don’t have an actual copy but I have seen one! I downloaded it off the internet and even that is quite difficult to do. My friend is an avid collector of all the em:t releases and it is easy to see why: all the albums are titled in a specific way that is very appealing to people who like to collect things and they also have very striking nature photography on the covers. In a strange way, the label was able to create an identity for its releases in a way that many artists would try to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #19: The Dreaming by Kate Bush</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“I see the people working and see it working for them.” (&lt;em&gt;Sat In Your Lap&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #18: Fabric 12 mixed by The Amalgamation Of Soundz</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Say what? We’re allowing compilations now?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #17: Nearly God by Nearly God (Tricky)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sit back and let it happen, / Let us take your time away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #16: Ambient 2 / The Plateaux Of Mirror by Howard Budd and Brian Eno</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-16/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #15: Début by Björk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got into Début via a cassette from the library, much like I did with &lt;a href=&#34;uc1&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Together Alone&lt;/em&gt; by Crowded House&lt;/a&gt;. I suppose it is less obscure than many of my choices for &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;this strand&lt;/a&gt; but I do think that &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; is more well-known (because of &lt;em&gt;It’s Oh So Quiet&lt;/em&gt;, which we shall mention here only briefly) and that &lt;em&gt;Homogenic&lt;/em&gt; is probably more popular among her fans.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #14: Clear by Bomb The Bass</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think it’s time to discuss your philosophy of drug use as it relates to artistic endeavour…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #13: U.F.Orb by The Orb</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FUN FACT:&lt;/strong&gt; It was because of the artwork to this album that I obsessively scrawled onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome on my pencil case at school. I also had a very passable u.f.orb logo drawn on it too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #11: Second Toughest In The Infants by Underworld</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-11/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #9: Tiger Bay by Saint Etienne</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-9/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #8: Second Light by Dreadzone</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;understated classics&lt;/a&gt; series, I try to alternate between pop/rock and electronic albums. Keeping with this trend number eight is the wonderful dub-infused album &lt;em&gt;Second Light&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dreadzone.com&#34;&gt;Dreadzone&lt;/a&gt;. Released in 1996 it was well-received critically and four of its tracks featured on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/radio1/johnpeel/&#34;&gt;John Peel&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s best-of-year list that year. &lt;em&gt;Little Britain&lt;/em&gt; received a lot of radio play, a popular choice for that flag-waving period of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mojo4music.com/13834/the-story-of-britpop-in-60-albums/&#34;&gt;britpop&lt;/a&gt; and assorted other demons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #6: Arbor Bona Arbor Mala by The Shamen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-6/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #4: Substrata by Biosphere</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I bought this album in the summer between my two years at college. I remember listening to this music under skies glowering with clouds so 1997 must have been a poor summer. I’d just bought a book of photography too, which placed photos from the north and south poles on opposite pages. I bought it mainly for the penguins that were, of course, on pretty much every other page. The pictures of&#xA;snow and ice soon became the ideal companions to this album.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #2: Sinking by The Aloof</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
