<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Electronic on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/electronic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Electronic on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 17:24:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/electronic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Maara, The Ancient Truth (on vinyl)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/maara-the-ancient-truth-vinyl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/maara-the-ancient-truth-vinyl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/2023-albums-07-maara-ancient-truth&#34;&gt;I wrote about Maara&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Ancient Truth&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; over Christmas as part of my albums of the year rundown, I mentioned at the end that I would love to find a copy on vinyl to listen to. Well dear reader I managed to! It arrived today from the Netherlands with minimal fuss. It sounds great and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure whether my review did it justice: that&amp;rsquo;s the problem with attempting to (re-)review ten albums in ten days with Christmas and New Year all happening at the same time!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #1: Sofia Kourtesis, Madres</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-01-sofia-kourtesis-madres/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-01-sofia-kourtesis-madres/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/sofia-kourtesis-madres.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Madres by Sofia Kourtesis&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sofia Kourtesis is a Berlin-based Peruvian dance producer, &amp;ldquo;Madres&amp;rdquo; is her debut album which follows on from a 2021 EP &amp;ldquo;Fresia Magdalena&amp;rdquo;. It was trailed by several singles, including the title track which caught my attention back in May. The album is dedicated to her parents and there are also songs dedicated to the surgeon who performed life-saving surgery on Kourtesis’s mother. The whole album is a heady mix of positivity and dedication to both music and to family.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #2: James Holden, Imagine This is a High Dimensional Space of All Possibilities</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-02-james-holden-imagine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-02-james-holden-imagine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/james-holden-imagine.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Imagine This is a High Dimensional Space of All Possibilities by James Holden&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cool artwork! No, we don&amp;rsquo;t have it but it&amp;rsquo;s coming in next week.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cool artwork! We haven&amp;rsquo;t had a copy in but I can order it for you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Me picking it up a week later: &amp;ldquo;Cool artwork!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Imagine This is a High Dimensional Space of All Possibilities&amp;rdquo; is definitely album title of the year, made all the more topical with the intrusion of Chat-GPT and the like into the cultural conversation. Large Language Models (LLMs) like Chat-GPT work by absorbing large amounts of textual data (i.e. this blog, helping to make all those instant album reviews you can write now just a tiny bit more shit) and breaking them down into tokens, with each token having a meaning and a grammatical role and so on. These meanings and roles form higher dimensional spaces in which the tokens are vectors, where the rules of the LLMs help determine which tokens live near to one another and which pairs are likely to sit together in &amp;lsquo;meaningful&amp;rsquo; sentences etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #3: Barry Can&#39;t Swim, When Will We Land?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-03-barry-cant-swim-when-will-we-land/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-03-barry-cant-swim-when-will-we-land/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/barry-cant-swim-when-will-we-land.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of When Will We Land by Barry Can&amp;rsquo;t Swim&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some albums you come to one way: a good review on a blog you respect, a track appearing on a playlist by someone whose taste you trust, etc and so on. And sometimes you get directed to something multiple times. This is what happened to me this year with the irrepressible “When Will We Land?” by Barry Can’t Swim. Anyway, tracks by &amp;ldquo;Barry&amp;rdquo; appeared in mixes a lot this year and the album kept popping up in eagerly anticipated lists.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #5: Nation of Language, Strange Disciple</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-05-nation-of-language-strange-disciple/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-05-nation-of-language-strange-disciple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/nation-of-language-strange-disciple.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Strange Disciple by Nation of Language&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It would be remiss of me to claim that this is a placeholder for any number of (quite different sounding) song based albums that came out this year (Yves Tumor, Wilco to mention two) but it feels that way. This album came high up my list of listens because it&amp;rsquo;s a very good breakfast album, one to listen to while getting the Day started - though there are also some bangers on here too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #7: Maara, The Ancient Truth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-07-maara-ancient-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-07-maara-ancient-truth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/maara-ancient-truth.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of The Ancient Truth by Maara&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There isn&amp;rsquo;t a great deal I can write about The Ancient Truth without sounding vague and anodyne. While I try to come think about different forms of music and go into some analysis of what makes one album more interesting than another, sometimes you end up just saying &amp;ldquo;this album is great because I like it and I always have a good time listening to it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #8: Everything But The Girl, Fuse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-08-ebtg-fuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-08-ebtg-fuse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/ebtg-fuse.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Fuse by Everything But The Girl&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you get older nostalgia becomes an ever important part of listening to music. It often feels like the business relies on convincing an aging population of fans to part with their money on new versions of old material. It&amp;rsquo;s nostalgia, the feeling of recapturing something you loved in your youth, that often makes this acceptable. Of course it&amp;rsquo;s also nice to get &lt;strong&gt;new&lt;/strong&gt; music from your favourite bands, especially when it&amp;rsquo;s as good as &amp;ldquo;Fuse&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #9: Fever Ray, Radical Romantics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-09-fever-ray-radical-romantics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-09-fever-ray-radical-romantics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/fever-ray-radical-romantics.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Radical Romantics by Fever Ray&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Radical Romantics, the third album by Fever Ray was released in April. I bought a copy on red vinyl which is a beautiful sight to behold. I listened to a lot when it was released but eased up a bit until listening to it a couple more times while writing this list. It&amp;rsquo;s a great collection of songs, probably better than their second album &amp;ldquo;Plunge&amp;rdquo;. The cover art is just as scary though.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #10: Wata Igarashi, Agartha</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-10-wata-igarashi-agartha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-albums-10-wata-igarashi-agartha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/albums-2023/wata-igarashi-agartha.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cover of Agartha by Wata Igarashi&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Agartha is the debut album by Japanese electronic artist Wata Igarashi. I don&amp;rsquo;t really know much about him, but I do know that I enjoy releases on the German record label Kompakt and I have really enjoyed Japanese techno in recent years. Over lockdown I discovered Haruomi Hosono&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Polyharmony&amp;rdquo; album and re-discovered the work of Shinichi Atobe, particularly their album &amp;ldquo;Love of Plastic&amp;rdquo;. Both of those albums could be future understated classics and while both are by Japanese artists working in electronic music, there the comparison ends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabric 44 by John Tejada</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fabric-44-by-john-tejada/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fabric-44-by-john-tejada/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is one of my more played Fabric mix CDs so I decided to go for it when my random prompter plumped for this earlier today. One constraint of these posts was to write it in roughly the amount of time it takes to listen to it. You&amp;rsquo;d think that for a mix CD that would be ok. After all, this mix is a full CD and 74 minutes long.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Orb, Live at Brighton Concord 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-orb---brighton-concord-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-orb---brighton-concord-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Went with my friend Nick to see The Orb at Concord 2 last night. The last time I&amp;rsquo;d seen the Orb was back in 2004, at the start of their relatively dry spell. That night, they&amp;rsquo;d been a bit lacklustre despite playing (some of) the hits and a relatively decent album in &amp;ldquo;Bicycles and Tricycles&amp;rdquo;. I left feeling that I&amp;rsquo;d seen the past rather than the future, something that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t glimpse again in their records until 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #39: Lifeforms by Future Sound of London</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-39/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-39/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lifeforms&lt;/strong&gt; is the 1994 album from the Future Sound of London. A double album (just), it also features the talents of Robert Fripp, Ozric Tentacles, Talvin Singh, Toni Halliday, and Liz Frazer. It reached number 6 on the UK album chart and went silver.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have wanted to write about the &lt;strong&gt;Lifeforms&lt;/strong&gt; album for a long time. In 2012, I even tried learning how to tell the tracks apart from one another. It was not a success. Ten years later, I know some of them but not all. I know all the music, of course, but the album as a whole resists my trainspotter-like urge to identify the margins and components of every track.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics Or Not?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-or-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-or-not/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the new year, thoughts and spare time for writing point me toward writing some new posts for my understated classics series. Expect some new ones soon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I also reflected on my previous choices and thought a bit about how my music tastes have changed recently. Some of this has to do with streaming and the frustrations I wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/a-pox-on-both-their-houses&#34;&gt;in my last post&lt;/a&gt;. Some of it is just down to getting older: I have less time to listen to new music, and much of the &amp;rsquo;new&amp;rsquo; stuff I listen to is me investigating the stuff I missed first time around. Who knew Art of Noise were so good? Not me, but I do now!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #38: Trance Nation (Various Artists)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-38/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-38/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, but lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been in need of some music that:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Blots out the outside world&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Helps me to concentrate on my work&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Makes me feel a bit less anxious about the state of the world&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, allow me to submit the compilation Trance Nation for your consideration as an understated classic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But Matt I&amp;rsquo;ve heard trance music, I hear you say, and it&amp;rsquo;s one of the least understated forms of music possible. Yes, dear reader, we &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; talking about that borderline obnoxious musical form with the thudding beats and the tinkly high synth lines. Indeed, it is a genre that has grown and eaten itself, and the rest of pop music along with it. The &amp;ldquo;give it a drop or go home&amp;rdquo; mentality that infects modern pop musics originates in Trance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Will Make Room For You - Four Tet Remix</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/i-will-make-room-for-you---four-tet-remix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/i-will-make-room-for-you---four-tet-remix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a perfect confluence of &lt;a href=&#34;album-digest-october-2011&#34;&gt;last month&amp;rsquo;s album digest&lt;/a&gt;, here&amp;rsquo;s an excellent Four Tet remix of Kaitlyn Aurelia Smith&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;I Will Make Room For You&amp;rdquo; from her album &amp;ldquo;The Kid&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ve put it into a playlist with &amp;ldquo;Lush&amp;rdquo; from Four Tet&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;New Energy&amp;rdquo; album and the original version of &amp;ldquo;I Will Make Room For You.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #35: Snivilisation by Orbital</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-35/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I came late to Orbital&amp;rsquo;s work. I knew of them through a few remixes and because as a mad Orb fan, they could not have avoided my notice could they? Apart from that, one of my college friends tried to get me into &amp;ldquo;In Sides&amp;rdquo; just after its release in 1996. The same friend got me into &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/understated-classics-11/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Second Toughest In The Infants&amp;rdquo; by Underworld&lt;/a&gt;. I cannot now understand the reason, but &amp;ldquo;In Sides&amp;rdquo; just left me cold.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Orb - Alpine EP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/orb-alpine-ep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/orb-alpine-ep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Orb return with a new EP on the &lt;a href=&#34;www.kompakt.fm&#34;&gt;Kompakt label&lt;/a&gt; called &amp;ldquo;Alpine&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Alpine&amp;rdquo; is split in to three tracks &amp;ldquo;Morning&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Evening&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Dawn&amp;rdquo;. The third of these was included on the 2016 edition of Kompakt&amp;rsquo;s annual &amp;ldquo;Pop Ambient&amp;rdquo; compilation, a gently drifting track with plenty of bells and yodels. A diversion from the sounds of &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/album-digest-june-2015/&#34;&gt;Moonbuilding 2703 AD&lt;/a&gt; (and its presumably ongoing remixed companion EPs), but it sat nicely with the other tracks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Underworld, Second Toughest in the Infants (Superdeluxe edition)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/second-toughest-in-the-infants-superdeluxe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/second-toughest-in-the-infants-superdeluxe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week Underworld reissued their excellent second album “Second Toughest In The Infants” in various formats including a four disc super deluxe edition. I wrote about this album in my understated classics series and I want to share some thoughts on the reissue. I love this album so I was excited to hear the remaster and the additional material.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I can’t comment on the physical version of the release as I can’t afford it at the moment. I also had to wait to buy the gorgeous yellow reissue of “Dubnobasswithmyheadman” but the “Second Toughest In The Infants” box is on the list. Underworld do a really good job on the boxes with interesting artwork to accompany the large volume of material. If the “Dubnobasswithmyheadman” box is anything to go by, the new one will be pretty hefty on the coffee table.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #31: The White Room by The KLF</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-31/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This little masterpiece was released in 1991. I got my copy on cassette for Christmas that year, but by May in 1992 they&amp;rsquo;d already &amp;ldquo;retired&amp;rdquo; and split up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The KLF were a band in the right place at the right time with the right idea. Taking advantage of synthesizers and the idea of fusing rock and pop music with the emerging sound of house music, they laid the ground for many of the most successful electronic acts that followed them. They were also master showmen, taking a whole host of crazy conspiracy theories and smooshing them together in one stadium-sized package.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #30: Our Aim Is to Satisfy by Red Snapper</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The thirtieth understated classic is by a band named after a fish. There isn&amp;rsquo;t a great deal for me to say about &amp;ldquo;Our Aim Is To Satisfy&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; apart from the usual insistence that it is quite good. There&amp;rsquo;s no overarching theme to write about, and no deep personal story attached. It was bound to happen eventually.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our Aim Is To Satisfy&amp;rdquo; is one of those albums spawned in the late nineties and early naughties at the height of the Electronica boom: dance music that you didn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily have to dance to. It&amp;rsquo;s not quite chill out music but nor is it song-based (for the most part) - it&amp;rsquo;s mainly instrumental electronic music.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What IS That Noise?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-that-noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-that-noise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently spruced up a post I wrote four years ago about &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/articles/uc4/&#34;&gt;Biosphere’s wonderful album Substrata&lt;/a&gt;. I added the following footnote about the difference between voice samples and found sound:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I suppose I am distinguishing between found sound and vocal samples here. Perhaps there is very little difference, or that one is the other? When is a vocal snippet something more than found sound? Is it the fact that one has meaning? Isn’t a “meaningless” sample - like the ones here in Russian that I can’t understand - little more than found sound anyway?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Amazing Subversive Revolutionary Adolescence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-amazing-subversive-revolutionary-adolescence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-amazing-subversive-revolutionary-adolescence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;or-at-least-its-subversive-soundtrack&#34;&gt;Or at least its subversive soundtrack…&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I listened to The Orb’s amazing live album “Live ’93” the other day (after discovering the insipid “History Of The Future” collection on Spotify) and I was amazed at how countercultural and subversive it was. I was listening to this stuff at the age of 14 and now that I’m old enough to be a parent, that makes me a bit uncomfortable. Actually it does nothing of the sort, because it&amp;rsquo;s frigging awesome.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #23: Gorgeous by 808 State</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was quite hard to choose an 808 State album for the &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;understated classics series&lt;/a&gt; for two reasons. The first is that I was introduced to 808 State quite late through a friend&amp;rsquo;s sister&amp;rsquo;s cassette copy of The Shamen&amp;rsquo;s En-Tact (the original version recorded from vinyl that had a thirteen minute version of &amp;ldquo;Evil Is Eden&amp;rdquo;) that also had &amp;ndash; to fill out the C90 &amp;ndash; the full length sweary version of &amp;ldquo;What Time Is Love?&amp;rdquo; by The KLF and four tracks: &amp;ldquo;Cubik&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Pacific&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Olympic&amp;rdquo; (I think&amp;hellip;), and &amp;ldquo;In Yer Face&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Work Of Art At The End Of My Road?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-work-of-art-at-the-end-of-my-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-work-of-art-at-the-end-of-my-road/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have had a lot of ideas for posts swirling around in my head in recent days. This is because I have actually done quite a lot of cool things in that time, and because I have hung out with some great people who make me think, and because I always have a whole load of things bouncing around in there anyway - space junk of the mind. I was thinking about how to put together these thoughts I have been having about art and about stories and yes, about love too. It all kind of got muddled up and then I saw it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #21: Woob 2 by Woob</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The second Woob album (AKA “Woob 4495”) is probably the greatest ambient album ever made and is certainly the best one you have never heard of. Originally released in 1995 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.emit.cc&#34;&gt;on the em:t label&lt;/a&gt; it is also a rare record. I don’t have an actual copy but I have seen one! I downloaded it off the internet and even that is quite difficult to do. My friend is an avid collector of all the em:t releases and it is easy to see why: all the albums are titled in a specific way that is very appealing to people who like to collect things and they also have very striking nature photography on the covers. In a strange way, the label was able to create an identity for its releases in a way that many artists would try to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #19: The Dreaming by Kate Bush</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“I see the people working and see it working for them.” (&lt;em&gt;Sat In Your Lap&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Dreaming by Kate Bush is a strange 1982 album that many believed had destroyed her career. Two weeks before her first ever performance of “Running Up That Hill”, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nme.com/blog/index.php?blog=10&amp;amp;title=on_this_day_kate_bush_releases_hounds_of_1986&amp;amp;more=1&amp;amp;c=1&amp;amp;tb=1&amp;amp;pb=1&#34;&gt;the NME had written an editorial asking whether she had burnt herself out completely&lt;/a&gt;. Obviously “Running Up That Hill” (recently used to great effect in the Olympic Closing Ceremony) and the parent album “The Hounds Of Love” that followed showed that she had plenty more up her sleeve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #18: Fabric 12 mixed by The Amalgamation Of Soundz</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Say what? We’re allowing compilations now?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes. Why not? A good mix is as much an artistic statement as a full-blown single artist album. It takes a lot of skill to get from A to B and keep everything on the boil in between. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fabriclondon.com/store/catalog/product/view/id/30/s/fabric-12/categories/8/&#34;&gt;This Fabric mix by The Amalgamation Of Soundz&lt;/a&gt; is one of my favourites because it is a downtempo (but, crucially, not &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; downtempo) compilation delivered with flair and using what I consider to be unconventional sources (soundtracks, tribute albums, hip-hop) to do it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #17: Nearly God by Nearly God (Tricky)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sit back and let it happen, / Let us take your time away.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nearly God&lt;/em&gt; is Tricky’s second album, which was released under a different name either because Island rejected it as the follow-up to &lt;em&gt;Maxinequaye&lt;/em&gt; or because it came too quickly after and Tricky just wanted it released. I had this album before &lt;em&gt;Maxinequaye&lt;/em&gt; because back then it wasn’t as easy to go back and catch up with albums that you had missed as it is now. I had bought enough singles to get the postcards through the post that advertised &lt;em&gt;Nearly God&lt;/em&gt; (this, kids, is what we had before e-mail and liking things on Facebook) and when I heard &lt;em&gt;Poems&lt;/em&gt; for the first time on the radio I was incredibly excited.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #16: Ambient 2 / The Plateaux Of Mirror by Howard Budd and Brian Eno</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;among-fields-of-crystal--wind-in-lonely-fences&#34;&gt;Among Fields of Crystal / Wind in Lonely Fences&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have written about a &lt;a href=&#34;uc4&#34;&gt;fair&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;uc6&#34;&gt;number of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;uc13&#34;&gt;ambient&lt;/a&gt; albums in this series (and there are at least two more to come!) but perhaps none are as unobtrusive as this one by Howard Budd and Brian Eno. It’s a subtle collection of music that sits at the margins of your consciousness: for a long time it was the music that I turned to when I could not sleep but I could just as easily imagine it as (ahem!) romantic background music as I could something to work to. I actually bought it in 2006 to listen to on an overnight flight back from the US.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #15: Début by Björk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got into Début via a cassette from the library, much like I did with &lt;a href=&#34;uc1&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Together Alone&lt;/em&gt; by Crowded House&lt;/a&gt;. I suppose it is less obscure than many of my choices for &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;this strand&lt;/a&gt; but I do think that &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; is more well-known (because of &lt;em&gt;It’s Oh So Quiet&lt;/em&gt;, which we shall mention here only briefly) and that &lt;em&gt;Homogenic&lt;/em&gt; is probably more popular among her fans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I really like about &lt;em&gt;Début&lt;/em&gt; though, as much as the album itself, is the panoply of remixes and alternative versions that surround the release. In this way &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; is at least as strong if not stronger and you might recall that I had similar fun &lt;a href=&#34;uc13&#34;&gt;when writing about the Orb’s album U.F.Orb a while back&lt;/a&gt;. As a result of this, there will be some detours into the remixes and live versions when discussing this album. In particular, I will mention the remix collection &lt;em&gt;the best mixes from the album début for all the people who don’t buy white labels&lt;/em&gt; and the recording of an MTV Unplugged show that is available in the &lt;em&gt;Live Box&lt;/em&gt; box set.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #14: Clear by Bomb The Bass</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think it’s time to discuss your philosophy of drug use as it relates to artistic endeavour…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That quote is from the movie “The Naked Lunch” directed by David Cronenburg (see also &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/crash/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;) and it also opens “Bug Powder Dust” by Bomb The Bass, the five star single that opens “Clear”. A rollicking piece of rock rap dripping with pop culture references that runs for four and half minutes and does not stop until another quote from “The Naked Lunch”, it is probably one of my favourite songs of the 90s. That churning guitar line sends me right back.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #13: U.F.Orb by The Orb</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FUN FACT:&lt;/strong&gt; It was because of the artwork to this album that I obsessively scrawled onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome onourwayhome on my pencil case at school. I also had a very passable u.f.orb logo drawn on it too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-the-blue-room&#34;&gt;In The Blue Room&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had my first “close encounter” with The Orb in 1992 when the single &lt;em&gt;Blue Room&lt;/em&gt; was in the charts. Back then, as I &lt;a href=&#34;uc2&#34;&gt;mentioned previously&lt;/a&gt;, I would listen to the radio a lot and this tune - introduced as the longest single ever to enter the UK chart - struck me as really interesting. The radio edit was a burbling wash of synths and female vocals underpinned by a hefty bass performance from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newstatesman.com/music/2008/06/wobble-life-music-dub-leaving&#34;&gt;Jah Wobble&lt;/a&gt;. Incidentally, the same week that &lt;em&gt;Blue Room&lt;/em&gt; entered the chart, I was actually listening out for &lt;em&gt;Sentinel&lt;/em&gt; by Mike Oldfield and this single (&lt;a href=&#34;uc10&#34;&gt;from Tubular Bells II&lt;/a&gt;) featured two remixes by The Orb.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #11: Second Toughest In The Infants by Underworld</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-rails-your-fins-your-thin-paper-wings&#34;&gt;Your rails, your fins, your thin paper wings&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Second Toughest in the Infants&lt;/em&gt; (STITI) is the second album by Underworld, released in 1995. This was just ahead of the mania caused by the .NUXX version of Born Slippy appearing on the &lt;em&gt;Trainspotting&lt;/em&gt; soundtrack a little later. &lt;em&gt;Born Slippy&lt;/em&gt; itself, the blippy techno confection released between their début &lt;em&gt;Dubnobasswithmyheadman&lt;/em&gt; and this album. STITI then is very much the calm before the storm and features a band (in the truest sense, which is unusual among electronic acts) in full flow. The sure hands are apparent from the off with the all-in-one trifecta of &lt;em&gt;Juanita&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Kiteless&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;To Dream of Love&lt;/em&gt;: a huge slab of a track that propels, mashes and then glides over various tempos in its sixteen minute run.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #9: Tiger Bay by Saint Etienne</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tiger Bay&lt;/em&gt; is Saint Etienne&amp;rsquo;s third album and I think it is among their best. It was released in June 1994 on Heavenly records. I first owned a copy in 1998 when I picked it up while living in halls as an undergraduate. The reason for including this album in the understated classics series is the same as for &lt;a href=&#34;uc8&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Second Light&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Dreadzone: it marries traditional forms to newer electronic music&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Second Light&lt;/em&gt; melds classical music and sea shanties to house and dub reggae to evoke the rolling hills and mystic caves of England. &lt;em&gt;Tiger Bay&lt;/em&gt; grafts folk structures on to Balearic pop songs and electronic experiments in order to visit motorway verges, windswept seashores, and Mediterranean holidays. There is even a ghost story (&lt;em&gt;Boy Scouts of America&lt;/em&gt;) for good measure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #8: Second Light by Dreadzone</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;understated classics&lt;/a&gt; series, I try to alternate between pop/rock and electronic albums. Keeping with this trend number eight is the wonderful dub-infused album &lt;em&gt;Second Light&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dreadzone.com&#34;&gt;Dreadzone&lt;/a&gt;. Released in 1996 it was well-received critically and four of its tracks featured on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/radio1/johnpeel/&#34;&gt;John Peel&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s best-of-year list that year. &lt;em&gt;Little Britain&lt;/em&gt; received a lot of radio play, a popular choice for that flag-waving period of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mojo4music.com/13834/the-story-of-britpop-in-60-albums/&#34;&gt;britpop&lt;/a&gt; and assorted other demons.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The strengths of &lt;em&gt;Second Light&lt;/em&gt; as an album is the anglicana&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; of its first half and the subversion of it in the second half. I often talk of how albums are front-loaded with the best tracks to get you immersed in them. This is probably a hangover from vinyl where you could repeatedly play one side, making it necessary to make cohesive &amp;lsquo;sides&amp;rsquo; of music.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #6: Arbor Bona Arbor Mala by The Shamen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ask anyone into pop music between 1991 and 1993 about The Shamen, and you&amp;rsquo;ll either receive a flood of euphoric good will about excellent tracks like &lt;em&gt;Move Any Mountain&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;LSI&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Phorever People&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;; or they will rant at you about the evils of &lt;em&gt;Ebeneezer Goode&lt;/em&gt;. The Shamen are either one of the pantheon of great acts from early 90&amp;rsquo;s dance and electronic music, or they are a shameless vaudeville novelty act.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #4: Substrata by Biosphere</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/other/UC4add1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I bought this album in the summer between my two years at college. I remember listening to this music under skies glowering with clouds so 1997 must have been a poor summer. I’d just bought a book of photography too, which placed photos from the north and south poles on opposite pages. I bought it mainly for the penguins that were, of course, on pretty much every other page. The pictures of snow and ice soon became the ideal companions to this album.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #2: Sinking by The Aloof</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-discovered-the-aloof-while-listening-to-the-top-40&#34;&gt;I discovered The Aloof while listening to the Top 40&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I was younger, I used to listen to the Top 40 every Sunday. To begin with, this was partly an endurance thing and partly an obsession with one day seeing Roxette top the charts - alas, they never did, though for one thrilling spring “Joyride” did flirt with the upper reaches of the chart.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Listening to the charts is probably the best way to become a lover of music. Nearly all my musical loves stem from listening to the top 40 chart, either directly from crouching next to my static-y radio on Sunday evening, or as something that evolving beyond those initial tastes later on. I soon realised that listening to music at the lower end of the chart was more rewarding and not just because this was where all &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Church_of_Your_Heart&#34;&gt;the later Roxette singles ended up&lt;/a&gt;. It was where all the oddities washed in, sometimes there one week and never to be heard again - sometimes growing up into something big. I remember first hearing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.prideofmanchester.com/music/ucc.htm&#34;&gt;“The Key The Secret” by the Urban Cookie Collective&lt;/a&gt; entering the chart at number 40, it eventually climbed to number 2. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/nottingham/content/articles/2004/11/20/entertainment_music_local_bands_kws_feature.shtml&#34;&gt;Also “Please Don’t Go” by KWS which crept all the way up to number 1&lt;/a&gt; - these were great dance records that grew by word of mouth at a time when great dance records were weird and new and meant something.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
