<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BT on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/bt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in BT on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/bt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A nice diverse selection of albums this month:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Arctic Monkeys &amp;ldquo;AM&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;BT &amp;ldquo;A Song Across Wires&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Goldfrapp &amp;ldquo;Tales of Us&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Janelle Monáe &amp;ldquo;Electric Lady&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;arctic-monkeys-am&#34;&gt;Arctic Monkeys &amp;ldquo;AM&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This whole review is basically me catching up with the rest of the world and realising that the Arctic Monkeys are ace. To be fair, I did notice how awesome they were at the opening ceremony of the Olympics last year, and I have liked the odd one or two of their singles, but up until now I haven&amp;rsquo;t really wanted to listen to any of their albums. In fact before &amp;ldquo;AM&amp;rdquo;, I already had two (ripped from the CDs of friends) but had never bothered to listen to them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, July 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a short album digest this month. I bought a stack of CDs and am parcelling them out over the next few months (together with important additional releases as they crop up). This is in the hope that I can write more considered pieces about each one. This month I’ve grouped together albums with monochrome covers and a BT album from June that I found out about recently. These albums are not just linked by their artwork, they also form a cohesive whole. As a result I dispense with reviewing each album in depth. As usual there is a playlist at the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have had the sort of month that is not conducive to listening to much new music. Therefore this month’s post is only going to consider two new albums and two albums that I have bought behind time. Because of various bits of stress and poor mood, I have ended up going back and taking refuge in some old favourites and not listening to new stuff. At other points I have also gone back to the Fleet Foxes’ album that I wrote about last month, which has grown on me even more since. Sometimes I think that I should writing about these albums on a two month delay. Meanwhile, I even have new music that I haven’t listened to &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt;, namely &lt;strong&gt;Bon Iver&lt;/strong&gt;’s self-titled album. It has received so many good reviews that I have been too intimidated to listen to it. I will try to write about it next month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
