<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Saint Etienne on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/saint-etienne/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Saint Etienne on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/saint-etienne/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-june-2012/</guid>
      <description>Three fantastic albums for Album Digest June 2012:&#xA;Saint Etienne Words and Music by Saint Etienne Liars WIXIW Hot Chip In Our Heads This month is a curious selection in that the albums are all by bands that I already own a few records by. When there is so much other directly related material that you can write about, it makes focussing on the album in hand quite difficult. I am always thinking up rankings and comparisons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #9: Tiger Bay by Saint Etienne</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-9/</guid>
      <description>Background Tiger Bay is Saint Etienne&amp;rsquo;s third album and I think it is among their best. It was released in June 1994 on Heavenly records. I first owned a copy in 1998 when I picked it up while living in halls as an undergraduate. The reason for including this album in the understated classics series is the same as for Second Light by Dreadzone: it marries traditional forms to newer electronic music1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, March 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/this-is-not-an-album-digest-march-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/this-is-not-an-album-digest-march-2011/</guid>
      <description>This is not an Album Digest March 2011 Well as I said at the end of last month’s album digest post, I took a bit of a break from pursuing new music quite as closely as I have been. As promised, I sidestepped the new R.E.M. and Elbow albums - although I had been promised the latter as a birthday present it is yet to show up, maybe I will look at in April.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
