<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>M1 External Monitor Issues</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/m1-external-monitor-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/m1-external-monitor-issues/</guid>
      <description>Since moving to an M1 Mac, I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed some issues with my second screen that I do not experience with my previous Intel Mac or with my current work laptop, which is a Dell Intel PC running Windows 10.&#xA;I get a lot of flickering on the screen, which is intolerable if I have Pro-motion and True Tone turned on. Note that these are options for the main display rather than the external monitor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holiday Tabs</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/holiday-tabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/holiday-tabs/</guid>
      <description>Over the course of a week on holiday, I started reading many interesting articles. In lockdown there isn&amp;rsquo;t much to do but read articles, but I still find myself not that good at finishing them. My phone has lots of tabs open and has become a Rolodex of shame. This post is to confess my sins.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m trying to re-familiarise myself with Python. As with all modern software development, Python now seems atomised and hyper-complicated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should I Drop Dropbox?</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/should-i-drop-dropbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/should-i-drop-dropbox/</guid>
      <description>I am thinking about whether I want to use Dropbox to sync my files anymore. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, I love Dropbox. It came along in beta in just 2008 just as I needed it to manage my PhD thesis. In fact I often jokingly claim to having invented it by asking on the MacRumors forums whether a program like it existed - just a few weeks before its beta rode in to my life like a knight in shining armour.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
