<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bjork on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/bjork/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bjork on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/bjork/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, December 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-december-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-december-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;bjork-utopia&#34;&gt;Bjork &lt;em&gt;Utopia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Utopia&amp;rdquo; is Björk&amp;rsquo;s ninth album. It&amp;rsquo;s a happier album compared to the emotional wreckage of &amp;ldquo;Vulnicura&amp;rdquo;. But while &amp;ldquo;Vulnicura&amp;rdquo; was a compelling if uncomfortable listen, &amp;ldquo;Utopia&amp;rdquo; is more comfortable and, unfortunately, not that compelling. This is old ground retrodden with few glimmers of past glories.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The brevity, succinctness and sharpness are all gone. Even on the best songs (the first three), there is very little strength in the lyrics. The music is all texture and no melody. And while formlessness and adaptability are central to the album&amp;rsquo;s lyrical themes, the songs themselves are ill-served by allowing these same concepts to take hold of their arrangements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, November 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pretty much a sliding scale between songs and electronic wibble on this month’s albums and a particularly damp, chilly feeling to proceedings too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bat For Lashes “The Haunted Man”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ital “Hive Mind” and “Dream On”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Björk “Bastards”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Brian Eno “Lux”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;bat-for-lashes-the-haunted-man&#34;&gt;Bat For Lashes “The Haunted Man”&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When it comes to Bat For Lashes, I prefer her first album “Fur And Gold” to her second “Two Suns” because when I listen to the latter I don’t feel connected to any of the songs. For me, “Fur And Gold” remains a wonderful adventure throughout, it’s a fantastic listen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #15: Début by Björk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got into Début via a cassette from the library, much like I did with &lt;a href=&#34;uc1&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Together Alone&lt;/em&gt; by Crowded House&lt;/a&gt;. I suppose it is less obscure than many of my choices for &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;this strand&lt;/a&gt; but I do think that &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; is more well-known (because of &lt;em&gt;It’s Oh So Quiet&lt;/em&gt;, which we shall mention here only briefly) and that &lt;em&gt;Homogenic&lt;/em&gt; is probably more popular among her fans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I really like about &lt;em&gt;Début&lt;/em&gt; though, as much as the album itself, is the panoply of remixes and alternative versions that surround the release. In this way &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; is at least as strong if not stronger and you might recall that I had similar fun &lt;a href=&#34;uc13&#34;&gt;when writing about the Orb’s album U.F.Orb a while back&lt;/a&gt;. As a result of this, there will be some detours into the remixes and live versions when discussing this album. In particular, I will mention the remix collection &lt;em&gt;the best mixes from the album début for all the people who don’t buy white labels&lt;/em&gt; and the recording of an MTV Unplugged show that is available in the &lt;em&gt;Live Box&lt;/em&gt; box set.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, October 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month we have albums by Björk, Coldplay, M83, and Radiohead.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;album-digest-october-2011---intro&#34;&gt;Album Digest October 2011 - Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I listened to Wilco’s &lt;em&gt;The Whole Love&lt;/em&gt; again the other day. I happened to be walking past the venue in Portsmouth where I went to see them live back in 2004 and it seemed the right fit. I really enjoyed the album after a period of not having listened to it and I found that being familiar with the songs allowed me to better appreciate the production of the album. It really is better than I had said last time when I included it in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/2011/09/album-digest-september-2011/&#34;&gt;September Album Digest&lt;/a&gt;, I suppose that it was the danger in writing about music you have only had with you for a few weeks (or days in the case of &lt;em&gt;The Whole Love&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
