<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bjork on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/bjork/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bjork on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/bjork/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, December 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-december-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-december-2017/</guid>
      <description>Bjork Utopia &amp;ldquo;Utopia&amp;rdquo; is Björk&amp;rsquo;s ninth album. It&amp;rsquo;s a happier album compared to the emotional wreckage of &amp;ldquo;Vulnicura&amp;rdquo;. But while &amp;ldquo;Vulnicura&amp;rdquo; was a compelling if uncomfortable listen, &amp;ldquo;Utopia&amp;rdquo; is more comfortable and, unfortunately, not that compelling. This is old ground retrodden with few glimmers of past glories.&#xA;The brevity, succinctness and sharpness are all gone. Even on the best songs (the first three), there is very little strength in the lyrics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, November 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-november-2012/</guid>
      <description>Pretty much a sliding scale between songs and electronic wibble on this month’s albums and a particularly damp, chilly feeling to proceedings too.&#xA;Bat For Lashes “The Haunted Man” Ital “Hive Mind” and “Dream On” Björk “Bastards” Brian Eno “Lux” Bat For Lashes “The Haunted Man” When it comes to Bat For Lashes, I prefer her first album “Fur And Gold” to her second “Two Suns” because when I listen to the latter I don’t feel connected to any of the songs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #15: Début by Björk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-15/</guid>
      <description>I got into Début via a cassette from the library, much like I did with Together Alone by Crowded House. I suppose it is less obscure than many of my choices for this strand but I do think that Post is more well-known (because of It’s Oh So Quiet, which we shall mention here only briefly) and that Homogenic is probably more popular among her fans.&#xA;What I really like about Début though, as much as the album itself, is the panoply of remixes and alternative versions that surround the release.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, October 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-october-2011/</guid>
      <description>This month we have albums by Björk, Coldplay, M83, and Radiohead.&#xA;Album Digest October 2011 - Intro I listened to Wilco’s The Whole Love again the other day. I happened to be walking past the venue in Portsmouth where I went to see them live back in 2004 and it seemed the right fit. I really enjoyed the album after a period of not having listened to it and I found that being familiar with the songs allowed me to better appreciate the production of the album.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
