<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Depression on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/depression/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Depression on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/depression/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Things to Remember</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/things-to-remember/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/things-to-remember/</guid>
      <description>These are some things I jotted down one day last week, I&amp;rsquo;ll refine them a bit more later on. Think of it as an aide-memoire of things that work for me, your milage may vary.&#xA;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about things that haven&amp;rsquo;t happened. Don&amp;rsquo;t turn whatever has happened and/or is bothering you into a catastrophe, especially if no one else is telling you that it is one. Seek out someone you trust and ask them &amp;ldquo;is this a catastrophe?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Don&#39;t Have a Clue, part 43</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/no-clue-part-43/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/no-clue-part-43/</guid>
      <description>A little man wearing a bow tie, and possibly a fez, scurries into the middle of the frame clutching a clapboard. Breathing heavily he hoists the clapboard up to chest height. He holds the clapper up then brings down while slurring &amp;quot;This is a blog post about not having a clue, take 43&amp;quot;. He exits to the right of the frame.&#xA;My feet are hot. The bed seems too small. Why are my feet always too hot on nights like these?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Setback</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-setback/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-setback/</guid>
      <description>Since the run there has been a bit of a hiatus in this blog. I wrote about how running was making me feel better. In fact, I should have said more. I recently stopped taking the antidepressants that I had been taking for eighteen months. This has been my longest period taking such medication but the running made me feel sufficiently good to decide that I could stop taking them.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
