<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Civ on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/civ/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Civ on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/civ/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Civ Leaders #4: Qin Shi Huang (Mandate of Heaven) of China</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/civ-leaders-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/civ-leaders-4/</guid>
      <description>Well, it&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I wrote my last Civ VI leader post about Amanitore of Nubia and there&amp;rsquo;s been a whole host of new leaders and personas added to the game since then. Among these the number of Chinese leaders has increased from two to five. Therefore it&amp;rsquo;s probably a good time to start writing about one of them, and where better to start than the OG himself, Qin Shi Huang.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Civ Leaders #3: Amanitore of Nubia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/civ-leaders-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/civ-leaders-3/</guid>
      <description>Amanitore of Nubia is available in a base game DLC. She also has her own scenario “The Gifts of the Nile”, which like most scenarios has unique tech and civic trees. You need to assert your dominance over the Nile by building seven temples. The scenario combines faith and military tactics in a satisfying way and you can also play it as Cleopatra for a different perspective.&#xA;Civ ability Ta-Seti +50% Production toward Ranged units.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Civ Leaders #2: Alexander of Macedon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/civ-leaders-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 16:41:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/civ-leaders-2/</guid>
      <description>Alexander of Macedon is available in a base game DLC pack alongside Darius of Persia. He also has his own scenario “The Conquests of Alexander”, which is both fun to play and instructive in how to use the formidable benefits of his bonuses and unique units.&#xA;Civ ability Hellenistic Fusion When capturing a city, receive civic boosts for each holy site and theatre square, and tech boosts for each campus and encampment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Civ Leaders #1: Hojo Tokimune of Japan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/civ-leaders-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 19:14:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/civ-leaders-1/</guid>
      <description>Civ ability Meiji Restoration Districts receive a +1 adjacency bonus for each adjacent district, instead of +0.5.&#xA;Leader bonus: Land units in Coastal tiles and naval units in Coast tiles receive +5 Combat Strength. +50% Production towards Encampment, Holy Site and Theatre Square districts. Units are immune to Hurricane damage. Civilisations at war with Japan receive +100% unit damage from hurricanes while in Japanese territory Unique unit The samurai, a high combat strength unit that does not lose combat strength when damage and gains an extra 10 combat strength against anti-cavalry units.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All the Civs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/all-the-civs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/all-the-civs/</guid>
      <description>Ingrid and I love playing Civ VI. It&amp;rsquo;s a fine game that improves on previous versions, adding many layers and mechanics that mean you can vary your playing style. In fact, with the recent Gathering Storm expansion there&amp;rsquo;s now an incredible variety of ways to play. The 39 leaders to play with both reflect and provide the game&amp;rsquo;s increased complexity. Each leader has a slightly different mechanic that influences how you play the game, and of course the leaders you are up against also affect your game play.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
