<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>James Holden on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/james-holden/</link>
    <description>Recent content in James Holden on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/james-holden/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2023 Albums of the Year #2: James Holden, Imagine This is a High Dimensional Space of All Possibilities</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/2023-albums-02-james-holden-imagine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 18:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/2023-albums-02-james-holden-imagine/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Cool artwork! No, we don&amp;rsquo;t have it but it&amp;rsquo;s coming in next week.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Cool artwork! We haven&amp;rsquo;t had a copy in but I can order it for you.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Me picking it up a week later: &amp;ldquo;Cool artwork!&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Imagine This is a High Dimensional Space of All Possibilities&amp;rdquo; is definitely album title of the year, made all the more topical with the intrusion of Chat-GPT and the like into the cultural conversation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, November 2017</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-november-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-november-2017/</guid>
      <description>00110100 01010100 &amp;ldquo;0181&amp;rdquo; This is a reissue of a Four Tet rarity from 2013 that has recently surfaced on Spotify under an alias1. &amp;ldquo;0181&amp;rdquo; collects a series of short experimental pieces from throughout his career, though I&amp;rsquo;m not enough of a nerd to know whether they are in any particular order. Last month&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;proper&amp;rsquo; Four Tet album &amp;ldquo;New Energy&amp;rdquo; has a lot more bounce to it, but &amp;ldquo;0181&amp;rdquo; nevertheless has some interesting moments that raises it above mere curiosity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, July 2013</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-july-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-july-2013/</guid>
      <description>Another four albums for you this month. Sometimes the problem is not finding albums to listen to but actually finding time to listen to them! Often it is not because I don&amp;rsquo;t have time but because I have already found some great albums this month and I am busy listening to those instead. As a result, a couple of these albums are ones that I have only listened to for a week or so, but they are interesting enough to write about.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
