<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Films on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/films/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Films on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/films/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Three Billboards Outside Ebbing, Missouri</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/three-billboards-outside-ebbing-missouri/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/three-billboards-outside-ebbing-missouri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ingrid and I renewed our Cineworld passes as it is the season to go to the movies and check out the Oscar contenders. You nod along sagely while dreaming up superlatives to show how much you agree with the taste-makers. Or you can call such-and-such movie a pretentious load of crap.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With &amp;ldquo;Three Billboards Outside Ebbing, Missouri&amp;rdquo;, it&amp;rsquo;s more the former. But I don&amp;rsquo;t have to say anything pretentious about the cinematography or its timeliness. Most people will recognise those elements. Instead, I can say it is a &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; film. An enjoyable movie. A flat-out entertaining one in fact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wonder Woman: A Short Review</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/wonder-woman-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/wonder-woman-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed Wonder Woman, which came as a surprise to me given my growing distaste for superhero movies. &lt;a href=&#34;man-of-steel-a-short-review&#34;&gt;I can remember seeing the Superman reboot Man of Steel&lt;/a&gt; with its phallic rockets and its boring boring fight sequences. But almost everything about Wonder Woman exceeded my expectations. It&amp;rsquo;s a well-made superhero movie and better still, it gets to the heart of why these kinds of movies matter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whereas Man of Steel ended up levelling cities and criminally underusing Amy Adams, all while giving us no stake on why Superman even matters as a man or a hero, Wonder Woman focusses tightly on its main character and explains what matters to her, and in turn the movie then explains why she should matter to us. In other words, it&amp;rsquo;s not boring and it&amp;rsquo;s not pointless.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Martian: A Short Review</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-martian-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-martian-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/the-martian-by-andy-weir/&#34;&gt;In my review of the book&lt;/a&gt; I mentioned that a film adaptation of The Martian was on the way. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why but it got released earlier than any of the dates that I&amp;rsquo;d seen and so on Saturday I found myself watching The Martian on the big screen. Could the film version deliver the same level of entertainment as the novel? Could Mark Watney (Matt Damon) get off Mars alive?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inherent Vice: A Short Review</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/inherent-vice-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/inherent-vice-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tonight I finally caught up with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inherent_Vice_(film)&#34;&gt;Inherent Vice&lt;/a&gt;, Paul Thomas Anderson&amp;rsquo;s adaptation of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Inherent-Vice-Thomas-Pynchon/dp/0099542161/ref=sr_1_4?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1437860132&amp;amp;sr=8-4&amp;amp;keywords=inherent+vice&#34;&gt;Thomas Pynchon&amp;rsquo;s novel&lt;/a&gt;. It stars &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0001618/&#34;&gt;Joaquin Phoenix&lt;/a&gt; as Larry &amp;lsquo;Doc&amp;rsquo; Sportello who&amp;rsquo;s put on to a case of possible kidnapping by his &amp;ldquo;ex-old lady&amp;rdquo; Shasta, played by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/film/2015/jun/16/katherine-waterston-jk-rowlings-fantastic-beasts-harry-potter&#34;&gt;Katherine Waterston&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no point attempting to tell much more you of the plot of Inherent Vice: it&amp;rsquo;s rather convoluted and self-digesting. At least this means there&amp;rsquo;s very little chance of stumbling into inadvertent spoilers. However, most of the plot strands do fall into place by the end, much more than I&amp;rsquo;d imagined they would half way through.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minions: A Short Review</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/minions-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/minions-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Minions got their own movie, just as I predicted in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/despicable-me-2-a-short-review/&#34;&gt;my review of Despicable Me 2&lt;/a&gt;. I went to see it this week and I enjoyed it a lot. Here&amp;rsquo;s a short review. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, there are no spoilers here that aren&amp;rsquo;t in the trailer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s very funny. Right from the opening credits you get the minions and their anarchic fun-loving slapstick humour. There&amp;rsquo;s always been something delightful about they way in which they innocently bumble around. Their penchant for evil bosses is inexplicable but incredibly amusing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jodorowsky&#39;s Dune</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/jodorowskys-dune/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/jodorowskys-dune/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1935156/?ref_=fn_al_tt_1&#34;&gt;Jodorowsky&amp;rsquo;s Dune&lt;/a&gt; is a documentary about outlandish Chilean director &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alejandro_Jodorowsky&#34;&gt;Alejandro Jodorosky&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; attempt at a film adaptation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/dune/&#34;&gt;Frank Herbert&amp;rsquo;s Dune&lt;/a&gt; in the 1970s. As a big fan of the novel and of science fiction in general, I was very interested in this film. It does not disappoint. It gives a great insight into the mind of a little known (if slightly batty) director and shows even an artistic failure can lead to shock waves that can be felt in later work by others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guardians of the Galaxy: A Short Review</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/guardians-of-the-galaxy-fifteen-observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/guardians-of-the-galaxy-fifteen-observations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finally&lt;/em&gt; saw Guardians of the Galaxy today. Here are fifteen observations about the film that may or may not constitute a short review.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;At least two Oscars for &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.comicbook.com/uploads1/2014/07/guardians-of-the-galaxy-gamora-101682-101718.jpg&#34;&gt;Best Use Of Body Paint (Green)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://images.radiotimes.com/namedimage/Karen_Gillan_takes_on_Zoe_Saldana_in_extended_Guardians_of_the_Galaxy_trailer.jpg?quality=85&amp;amp;mode=crop&amp;amp;width=620&amp;amp;height=374&amp;amp;404=tv&amp;amp;url=https://mattischrome.com/uploads/images/original/53103.jpg&#34;&gt;Best Use Of Body Paint (Blue)&lt;/a&gt; are sewn up.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chris Pratt basically plays Star Lord as “&lt;a href=&#34;http://parksandrecreation.wikia.com/wiki/Andy_Dwyer&#34;&gt;Andy Dwyer&lt;/a&gt; in space” and this is fine by me.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Best movie to feature &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.etonline.com/movies/148845_bradley_cooper_explains_his_voice_guardians_of_the_galaxy/&#34;&gt;a talking raccoon&lt;/a&gt; in a long time.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://screenrant.com/thor-2-dark-world-mid-post-credits-button-scenes-explained&#34;&gt;Watching the entirety of the end credits of Thor 2&lt;/a&gt; paid off!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;“&lt;em&gt;WE&lt;/em&gt; are &lt;a href=&#34;https://uk.yahoo.com/movies/dancing-baby-groot-clip-guardians-of-the-galaxy-94738291414.html&#34;&gt;Groot&lt;/a&gt;” — aren’t we just?! All of the feels.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It features a dance off as a major event, something that it shares with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Step_Up_(film_series)&#34;&gt;Step Up movies&lt;/a&gt;. Guardians of the Galaxy is a waaaay better movie.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The first words of the credits are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mtv.com/news/1887915/guardians-of-the-galaxy-sequel/&#34;&gt;“The Guardians of the Galaxy will return”&lt;/a&gt;. It is in fact a movie that reviews itself.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The 3D version might have been pretty good. I watched the 2D version but &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cinemablend.com/new/Guardians-Galaxy-Has-Something-Special-Planned-Its-IMAX-3D-43350.html&#34;&gt;the scenes with lots of action &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; be improved with a bit of depth&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/culture/film/film-news/11033572/Guardians-of-the-Galaxy-Awesome-Mix-soundtrack-tops-Billboard-chart.html&#34;&gt;A great soundtrack&lt;/a&gt;, but there is a cheesy “smooth rock wins chicks” bit that’s a little icky half way through.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;That said, the description of the legend of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0087277/&#34;&gt;Footloose&lt;/a&gt; is hilarious. Especially the callback toward the end of the movie.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I especially enjoyed the scene with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slashfilm.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-easter-eggs-quotes/&#34;&gt;the Collector&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Karen Gillen is wasted as Nebula, but &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cinemablend.com/new/Nebula-Return-Guardians-Galaxy-2-66648.html&#34;&gt;hopefully she will be back&lt;/a&gt;. Karen’s also in what may well be &lt;a href=&#34;http://abc.go.com/shows/selfie&#34;&gt;one of the most ill-conceived TV shows of all time&lt;/a&gt; later this autumn.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I thought it was Bruce Willis playing &lt;a href=&#34;http://whatculture.com/wwe/batista-praised-role-guardians-galaxy-movie.php&#34;&gt;Drax the Destroyer&lt;/a&gt; (I’m useless at this guess the actor game). I loved his taking things literally: “Nothing goes over my head. My reflexes are too fast, I would catch it.”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you text me at any point in the next month, I will probably reply with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nerdist.com/2014/08/translate-any-website-into-groot-speak-with-this-nifty-new-button/&#34;&gt;“I am Groot”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;No Raccoons or tree creatures were harmed during the making of this film.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Despicable Me 2: A Short Review</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/despicable-me-2-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/despicable-me-2-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s so good that I paid to see it twice! There, that&amp;rsquo;s the review done.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Despicable Me 2&lt;/em&gt; is great for so many reasons. I reckon pretty much anyone aged from 3 to 103 would enjoy both movies&amp;rsquo; warm heartedness and most will love the minions&amp;rsquo; riot of anarchic slapstick. And if they don&amp;rsquo;t, I guess they aren&amp;rsquo;t our kind of people anyway, right?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are a few good reasons for loving &amp;ldquo;Despicable Me 2&amp;rdquo; (and actually most of these reasons apply to the original &amp;ldquo;Despicable Me&amp;rdquo;):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man of Steel: A Short Review</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/man-of-steel-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/man-of-steel-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I went to see the new Superman reboot &lt;em&gt;Man of Steel&lt;/em&gt; with friends. I really enjoyed it, particularly the more reflective take on the superhero myth. Starting out with the fate of the planet Krypton, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0770828/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Man of Steel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; approximately fuses the events of both the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0078346/?ref_=sr_2&#34;&gt;first&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0081573/&#34;&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; original Superman movies. We get to see Superman&amp;rsquo;s arrival and childhood on earth and then the arrival of Zod, a maniac bent on replacing the earth and everyone on it with a new race of Kryptonians.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Star Trek: Into Darkness - A Short Review</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/star-trek-into-darkness-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/star-trek-into-darkness-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I saw &lt;em&gt;Star Trek: Into Darkness&lt;/em&gt; last night in 3D at the IMAX in Waterloo. I am going to have to separate this into a review into two parts, a review of the film and a review of the viewing experience. I am not completely happy with how the film experience is changed by the 3D and the super big screen and I will try to explain what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Love On The Road</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/why-i-love-on-the-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/why-i-love-on-the-road/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was fifteen when I first read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/70401.On_the_Road&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;On The Road&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jack_Kerouac&#34;&gt;Jack Kerouac&lt;/a&gt; and recently, after twice as much lifetime lived, I was able to watch &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0337692/&#34;&gt;the film version directed by Walter Salles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The only people for me are the mad ones, the ones who are mad to live, mad to talk, mad to be saved, desirous of everything at the same time, the ones who never yawn or say a commonplace thing, but burn, burn, burn like fabulous yellow roman candles exploding like spiders across the stars. (&lt;strong&gt;Jack Kerouac&lt;/strong&gt;, &amp;ldquo;On the Road&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rust And Bone: A Short Review</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/rust-and-bone-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/rust-and-bone-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, two short reviews in a row. I had the day off work and went to see “Rust And Bone” this afternooon. It’s the new film by Jacques Audiard, who directed “A Prophet” – one of my favourite films of the last five years.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Rust And Bone” is a love story about Ali, a sexually feckless security guard who is struggling to look after his young son on his own, and Stéphanie (played by second most beautiful woman in the world, Marion Cotillard), who is injured while working as a co-ordinator of killer whale displays at an ocenarium. Needless to say it is not a minor injury. The film is basically their love story. I don’t feel so much responsibility to hide plot details about this film because, to be frank, I could type out the whole plot here and it wouldn’t convey the reasons why it’s so great.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skyfall: A Short Review</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/skyfall-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/skyfall-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I went to see &amp;ldquo;Skyfall&amp;rdquo; last night and I really enjoyed it. I knew nothing about the plot, mostly because I had avoided all discussion of the plot with people who had already seen it and I even avoided reviews as so many these days seem to just rattle off plot points, instead of discussing what makes the movie any good. With that in mind I will obviously try not to give away any of the plot in this brief review.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Case For Yellow As Your New Favourite Colour</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/a-case-for-yellow-as-your-new-favourite-colour/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/a-case-for-yellow-as-your-new-favourite-colour/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is about the films of Wes Anderson. I am no expert, I’ve just watched them all recently (inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;moonrise-kingdom-a-short-review&#34;&gt;seeing “Moonrise Kingdom”&lt;/a&gt;) and spotted a some similarities and differences between the films and I thought it would be fun to write about them. My appearance on Mastermind with “The Films of Wes Anderson” as my specialist subject will have to wait for now. Feel free to add to the discussion in the comments. In case you don’t know what the films are, here they are in order (with links to their IMDB pages):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moonrise Kingdom: A Short Review</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/moonrise-kingdom-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/moonrise-kingdom-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tonight I avoided the first half of the football along with my friend Albert Jan and we went to watch “Moonrise Kingdom” at the wonderful Everyman cinema in Hampstead. It was a real treat in every sense. To start with, the Everyman is a lovely cinema. It is quite expensive but you do get what you pay for: a comfortable seat in a great theatre and the chance to watch more than just the latest blockbusters (though it shows those too). I think it was the only cinema in my area that was showing &lt;em&gt;Moonrise Kingdom&lt;/em&gt;, though it has been out for a while now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dreams Of A Life: A Short Review</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/dreams-of-a-life-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/dreams-of-a-life-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dreams Of A Life&lt;/em&gt; is a documentary about Joyce Vincent, a woman who was found in her flat three years after her death surrounded by wrapped christmas presents and with the TV still on. £2400 in arrears on her rent, she was discovered by bailiffs who forced the door down. The film attempts to work out happened to Joyce by interviewing people who knew her. In two other strands that unfold in parallel, various events from her life are re-enacted along with the clearing of her flat by forensics officers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contagion: A Short Review</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/contagion-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/contagion-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was much excitement about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1598778/&#34;&gt;Contagion&lt;/a&gt; at work. Finally a movie that explains  as part of the plot! A bunch of us went to see it, mainly to see whether &lt;a href=&#34;http://contagionmovie.warnerbros.com/index.html&#34;&gt;a disaster movie about a global pandemic&lt;/a&gt; could hold up as entertainment and to have a bit of a giggle if it couldn’t.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I liked three things in particular about the film. I liked the cinematography, especially the opening sequences with the index cases staggering around. I liked the soundtrack except for when it intruded a bit too much into proceedings. Finally, I liked Marion Cotillard, who seems to be in every interesting movie at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Love The Jungle Book</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/why-i-love-the-jungle-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/why-i-love-the-jungle-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just as with the &lt;a href=&#34;understated-classics&#34;&gt;understated classics&lt;/a&gt; I want to set out my stall early on that good movies are good enough. Both &lt;a href=&#34;why-i-love-betty-blue&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Betty Blue&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and today’s choice &lt;em&gt;The Jungle Book&lt;/em&gt; are never going to win any sort of consensus prize for the best movies ever made but they are really good. They also have a personal history attached that makes them worth writing about.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I was younger both my sisters would be given VHS copies of Disney movies at a rate of about two a year, one for Christmas and one at their birthday. It seems strange today to think of that pace of movie acquisition, never mind the clunky VHS cassettes and how they would warp over time. I didn’t really ever get any of the Disney movies myself but I would inevitably find myself watching them with my sisters who would watch them repeatedly. With just four TV channels back then, who could blame us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Love Betty Blue</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/why-i-love-betty-blue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/why-i-love-betty-blue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I saw &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0090563/&#34;&gt;Betty Blue&lt;/a&gt; (original French title &lt;em&gt;37,2 Le Matin&lt;/em&gt;) for the first time in 1996 shortly after having read the book and it remains one of my favourite films to this day. Although there are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.co.uk/images?hl=en&amp;amp;source=hp&amp;amp;biw=1427&amp;amp;bih=1022&amp;amp;q=b%C3%A9atrice+dalle+betty+blue&amp;amp;gbv=2&amp;amp;aq=f&amp;amp;aqi=&amp;amp;oq=&amp;amp;uss=1&#34;&gt;many obvious reasons why&lt;/a&gt; a sixteen year old boy might like it, I think it does stand up to scrutiny beyond the sex and nudity. This post is a brief explanation of some of the obvious and not-so-obvious reasons why this is a film to be loved and cherished. (It was quite interesting to write this defence of a sexy film!)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Setback</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-setback/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-setback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the run there has been a bit of a hiatus in this blog. I wrote about how running was making me feel better. In fact, I should have said more. I recently stopped taking the antidepressants that I had been taking for eighteen months. This has been my longest period taking such medication but the running made me feel sufficiently good to decide that I could stop taking them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
