<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kate Bush on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/kate-bush/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kate Bush on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/kate-bush/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>If anything, make it weirder</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/make-it-weird/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/make-it-weird/</guid>
      <description>Today I listened to &amp;lsquo;Cloudbusting&amp;rsquo; by Kate Bush for the first time in a while. What a gloriously strange song it is. Best of all, it&amp;rsquo;s one of those songs that obscures what it is really about. It&amp;rsquo;s not a song about a change in the weather, but about Wilhelm Reich, the orgone accumulator, fluorescent yo-yos, and a son (rather than a sun) coming out.&#xA;&amp;lsquo;Cloudbusting&amp;rsquo; is from &amp;lsquo;Hounds of Love&amp;rsquo;, Kate&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;comeback&amp;rsquo; album following the commercial failure of &amp;lsquo;The Dreaming&amp;rsquo;, an album I wrote about in my understated classics series.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #19: The Dreaming by Kate Bush</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/understated-classics-19/</guid>
      <description>“I see the people working and see it working for them.” (Sat In Your Lap)&#xA;The Dreaming by Kate Bush is a strange 1982 album that many believed had destroyed her career. Two weeks before her first ever performance of “Running Up That Hill”, the NME had written an editorial asking whether she had burnt herself out completely. Obviously “Running Up That Hill” (recently used to great effect in the Olympic Closing Ceremony) and the parent album “The Hounds Of Love” that followed showed that she had plenty more up her sleeve.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, November 2011</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-november-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-november-2011/</guid>
      <description>Just three albums this month as I’ve been listening to a lot of Brian Eno records ready for an upcoming understated classic. First up is 50 Words For Snow by Kate Bush, the second album that she has released this year. Back in May I wrote about Director’s Cut, which presented re-recorded and re-mastered versions of songs from her albums The Sensual World and The Red Shoes. This time around it is an album of brand new material, the first since Aerial in 2006.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, May 2011</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-may-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-may-2011/</guid>
      <description>Four albums this month:&#xA;Kate Bush Director’s Cut Africa Hitech 93 Million Miles Fleet Foxes Helplessness Blues TV On The Radio Nine Types of Light There is a pleasing red hue to all the covers this month. I had time to write four full reviews of the major albums I listened to. Like last month I have included a video at the foot of each review. Enjoy!&#xA;Kate Bush Director’s Cut Director’s Cut is not a new album from Kate Bush but a collection of re-visits to old songs, four from The Sensual World (1989) and seven from [The Red Shoes](http://en.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
