<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science Fiction on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/science-fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science Fiction on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/science-fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tade Thompson, Rosewater</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/tade-thompson-rosewater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/tade-thompson-rosewater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rosewater is an exciting science fiction novel set several decades after first contact with an alien called Wormwood, that has established itself as a large biodome in Nigeria. The novel follows Kaaro, a thief whose extra special abilities are forged from an unlikely connection with the alien. The whole thing is part sci-fi adventure and part spy novel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amal El-Mohtar &amp; Max Gladstone, This Is How You Lose the Time War</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/this-is-how-you-lose-the-time-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/this-is-how-you-lose-the-time-war/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Is How You Lose the Time War is a short novella about two members of opposing factions (Red and Blue) engaged in a &amp;rsquo;time war’: that is they travel in time and attempt to erase each other&amp;rsquo;s existence. Except that one day Red decides to taunt Blue with a letter, and a correspondence emerges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isaac Asimov, Foundation and Empire, Second Foundation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-rest-of-the-foundation-trilogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-rest-of-the-foundation-trilogy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I managed to read all of the foundation novels since I &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/foundation&#34;&gt;wrote about the first one&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, I’ll write about the next two, which covers the original trilogy of ‘novels’ created from the original short stories. I’ve tried to avoid spoilers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isaac Asimov, Foundation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/foundation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For our &lt;a href=&#34;the-same-but-different&#34;&gt;first anniversary&lt;/a&gt; we decided to exhange books. What better way to &lt;a href=&#34;https://ideas.hallmark.com/articles/anniversary-ideas/anniversary-gifts-by-year/&#34;&gt;celebrate a paper anniversary&lt;/a&gt;? Ingrid bought me the entire Foundation saga, most of which were &lt;a href=&#34;https://abcoverd.co.uk/archive/designers/topping-mike&#34;&gt;reissued in fancy new paperback designs by Mike Topping&lt;/a&gt; in 2016. All save for 1993&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/7lueju/asimovs_forward_the_foundation_published_in_2016/&#34;&gt;Forward The Foundation&lt;/a&gt; that is, but Ingrid got me a copy anyway. Hence, here is a new series of blog posts!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alistair Reynolds, Revelation Space</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/revelation-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/revelation-space/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://approachingpavonis.blogspot.co.uk&#34;&gt;Alistair Reynolds&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; 2000 novel &amp;ldquo;Revelation Space&amp;rdquo; has long been in orbit of my science fiction &amp;ldquo;to read&amp;rdquo; list, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until one sleepless night (post &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/command-and-control/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Command and Control&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;) that I came across it in Ingrid&amp;rsquo;s audiobooks. I was instantly drawn in as I listened to the opening scene about an archaeological dig facing evacuation ahead of an imminent &amp;lsquo;razor storm&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, Hello America</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-america/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had low expectations for &amp;ldquo;Hello America&amp;rdquo;, the next in &lt;a href=&#34;j-g-ballard&#34;&gt;the series of Ballard novels&lt;/a&gt; that I started reading over seven years ago. However, it turned out to be a hoot. A couple of years ago, this novel would have been a wig-out bit of standard Ballard weirdness (a bit like &lt;a href=&#34;the-drowned-world&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Drowned World&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;the-crystal-world&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Crystal World&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;) but given recent events &amp;ldquo;Hello America&amp;rdquo; is starting to take on an eerie prescience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wonder Woman: A Short Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/wonder-woman-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/wonder-woman-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed Wonder Woman, which came as a surprise to me given my growing distaste for superhero movies. &lt;a href=&#34;man-of-steel-a-short-review&#34;&gt;I can remember seeing the Superman reboot Man of Steel&lt;/a&gt; with its phallic rockets and its boring boring fight sequences. But almost everything about Wonder Woman exceeded my expectations. It&amp;rsquo;s a well-made superhero movie and better still, it gets to the heart of why these kinds of movies matter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paul McAuley, Something Coming Through</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/something-coming-through-by-paul-mcauley/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/something-coming-through-by-paul-mcauley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Something Coming Through&amp;rdquo; is a science fiction novel set in the near future. A few years after a brief nuclear war known as &amp;ldquo;The Spasm&amp;rdquo;, an alien race known as the Jackaroo introduce themselves to humanity. The novel is funny, thoughtful, and politically charged. I found it to be a good read.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Martian: A Short Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-martian-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-martian-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/the-martian-by-andy-weir/&#34;&gt;In my review of the book&lt;/a&gt; I mentioned that a film adaptation of The Martian was on the way. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why but it got released earlier than any of the dates that I&amp;rsquo;d seen and so on Saturday I found myself watching The Martian on the big screen. Could the film version deliver the same level of entertainment as the novel? Could Mark Watney (Matt Damon) get off Mars alive?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Andy Weir, The Martian</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-martian-by-andy-weir/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-martian-by-andy-weir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I received a copy of The Martian by Andy Weir for Christmas. This week during some annual leave I managed to finish it. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those novels that just flies by once it gets going. I&amp;rsquo;ve stayed up incredibly late to read it as it is full of those &amp;ldquo;just one more page&amp;rdquo; moments. It’s a readable and enjoyable story of an astronaut trapped on Mars.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jodorowsky&#39;s Dune</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/jodorowskys-dune/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/jodorowskys-dune/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1935156/?ref_=fn_al_tt_1&#34;&gt;Jodorowsky&amp;rsquo;s Dune&lt;/a&gt; is a documentary about outlandish Chilean director &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alejandro_Jodorowsky&#34;&gt;Alejandro Jodorosky&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; attempt at a film adaptation of &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dune/&#34;&gt;Frank Herbert&amp;rsquo;s Dune&lt;/a&gt; in the 1970s. As a big fan of the novel and of science fiction in general, I was very interested in this film. It does not disappoint. It gives a great insight into the mind of a little known (if slightly batty) director and shows even an artistic failure can lead to shock waves that can be felt in later work by others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iain M. Banks, Feersum Endjinn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/feersum-endjinn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/feersum-endjinn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Feersum Endjinn is one of Iain Banks&amp;rsquo; few non-Culture sci-fi novels. Like the Culture novels, an existential crisis drives the plot: in this case the action takes place on Earth in the far future and the sun has aged to a point where it will grow and swallow the earth. This is referred to as the Encroachment. The characters are divided between the good guys who seek to find a solution for the greater good and bad guys who use the Encroachment to consolidate their power and influence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guardians of the Galaxy: A Short Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/guardians-of-the-galaxy-fifteen-observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/guardians-of-the-galaxy-fifteen-observations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finally&lt;/em&gt; saw Guardians of the Galaxy today. Here are fifteen observations about the film that may or may not constitute a short review.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, High-Rise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/high-rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/high-rise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a few false starts I managed to finish &amp;ldquo;High-Rise&amp;rdquo;, the next in &lt;a href=&#34;j-g-ballard&#34;&gt;my collection of JG Ballard novels&lt;/a&gt;. For a book that I had trouble getting into, it turned out to be a pretty good read - even if it was also a pretty unpleasant one. Published in 1975, &amp;ldquo;High-Rise&amp;rdquo; is perhaps ahead of its time in exploring the effects of social breakdown in stylised and artificial situations where people are in close contact. You might think the plot, about a luxury high-rise that goes to hell, is in some way political or sociological but it really isn&amp;rsquo;t. It&amp;rsquo;s just a big playground in which Ballard throws around some of his most twisted ideas, all the while remarking on the very artifice of the situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man of Steel: A Short Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/man-of-steel-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/man-of-steel-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I went to see the new Superman reboot &lt;em&gt;Man of Steel&lt;/em&gt; with friends. I really enjoyed it, particularly the more reflective take on the superhero myth. Starting out with the fate of the planet Krypton, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0770828/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Man of Steel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; approximately fuses the events of both the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0078346/?ref_=sr_2&#34;&gt;first&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0081573/&#34;&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; original Superman movies. We get to see Superman&amp;rsquo;s arrival and childhood on earth and then the arrival of Zod, a maniac bent on replacing the earth and everyone on it with a new race of Kryptonians.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Star Trek: Into Darkness - A Short Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/star-trek-into-darkness-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/star-trek-into-darkness-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I saw &lt;em&gt;Star Trek: Into Darkness&lt;/em&gt; last night in 3D at the IMAX in Waterloo. I am going to have to separate this into a review into two parts, a review of the film and a review of the viewing experience. I am not completely happy with how the film experience is changed by the 3D and the super big screen and I will try to explain what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iain M. Banks, Consider Phlebas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/consider-phlebas-a-picaresque-in-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/consider-phlebas-a-picaresque-in-space/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A while back, I decided I was going to write about the Iain M. Banks sci-fi-novels (mainly as a respite from having to read and write about &lt;a href=&#34;j-g-ballard&#34;&gt;J. G. Ballard novels&lt;/a&gt;, but I only got as fas as writing about the excellent “Against A Dark Barkground” and re-reading the first of the Culture novels “Consider Phlebas”. WARNING: Some plot spoilers follow (but not too many).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nick Harkaway, The Gone-Away World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-gone-away-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-gone-away-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Gone-Away World” is a novel by Nick Harkaway. It’s about a world slightly askew to our own in which the powers-that-be have deigned to unleash a weapon that simply wipes the enemy out of existence. Unfortunately the enemies also have the same weapon and there are terrible consequences to the extent that the very fabric of reality is threatened. If you don’t already know what reification means, you will by the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contagion: A Short Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/contagion-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/contagion-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was much excitement about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1598778/&#34;&gt;Contagion&lt;/a&gt; at work. Finally a movie that explains  as part of the plot! A bunch of us went to see it, mainly to see whether &lt;a href=&#34;http://contagionmovie.warnerbros.com/index.html&#34;&gt;a disaster movie about a global pandemic&lt;/a&gt; could hold up as entertainment and to have a bit of a giggle if it couldn’t.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frank Herbert, Dune</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dune/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dune/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A week or so ago, I finished reading &lt;em&gt;Dune&lt;/em&gt; by Frank Herbert. It tells the story of a revolution within a Galactic Empire that takes place on a harsh and unforgiving desert planet called Arrakis. One central theme is how destinies can be shaped despite being intertwined around many axes. Another is the importance of adaptation in the fight for survival.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, Concrete Island</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/concrete-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/concrete-island/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Favourite Culture Ship Names</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/favourite-culture-ship-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/favourite-culture-ship-names/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned before &lt;a href=&#34;more-books&#34;&gt;I am re-reading the novels of Iain Banks&lt;/a&gt; and this weekend I managed to finish &lt;em&gt;Consider Phlebas&lt;/em&gt;. A little post about it will be coming up soon. One of my favourite things about the Culture novels is how the ships are named and having found &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_ships_(The_Culture)&#34;&gt;a list on Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;, I thought I would share ten of my favourites with you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Crystal World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-crystal-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-crystal-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At last, Ballard in full flow. The Crystal World (TCW) is definitely the most enjoyable of the early trio of apocalyptic novels. It takes the successful elements of the first two and embellishes them with new details and ideas. At time of writing, TCW is definitely the best Ballard novel that I have read in its entirety.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Drought</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-drought/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-drought/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On to The Drought by J. G. Ballard in &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/j-g-ballard/&#34;&gt;my ongoing quest to read and review all of his novels&lt;/a&gt;. This is his second novel, if we assume his convention of never acknowledging “The Wind From Nowhere” as being his first novel. “The Drought” itself was renamed from “The Burning World” and additional content added later on. This was quite common practice in SF in the 50s and 60s where novels were serialised in magazines like &lt;a href=&#34;http://philsp.com/mags/amazing_stories.html&#34;&gt;Amazing SF&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://ttapress.com/interzone/about/&#34;&gt;Interzone&lt;/a&gt;. It is evidence though of Ballard finding his voice as he wrote and from The Drought it is easy to see that he is iterating his thought processes and subject matter with each novel.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“The Drought” is marvellous in a way that “The Drowned World” is not. Here Ballard has cut away much of the ropy science of that novel and left us with a much more realistic scenario of global drought without having to worry about all the outré trappings of giant iguanas and dragonflies the size of your head. Instead, all the magnetic and mesmerising elements of Ballard’s work are beginning to take form: the eccentric recluse with possible sinister intent, the confused and detached protagonist, the ambivalently regarded woman of standing, the encroachment of nature and the human tendency to defile pretty much all it touches, including all that it has constructed and lived alongside.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Drowned World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-drowned-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-drowned-world/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/j-g-ballard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/j-g-ballard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading &amp;ldquo;Crash&amp;rdquo; at 17 left me in a state of numb shock. It got me hooked and left me with &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/J._G._Ballard&#34;&gt;J. G. Ballard&lt;/a&gt; as one of my favourite authors. I then devoured a short story collection called &amp;ldquo;Myths of the Near Future&amp;rdquo; around the same time. You may recognise it because the Klaxons appropriated the title for their debut album. Those stories captured my imagination, in particular the eponymous story of a world gone to run amid &amp;ldquo;space sickness&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
