<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science Fiction on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/science-fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science Fiction on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/science-fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tade Thompson, Rosewater</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/tade-thompson-rosewater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/tade-thompson-rosewater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rosewater is an exciting science fiction novel set several decades after first contact with an alien called Wormwood, that has established itself as a large biodome in Nigeria. The novel follows Kaaro, a thief whose extra special abilities are forged from an unlikely connection with the alien. The whole thing is part sci-fi adventure and part spy novel.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The novel is set in multiple timelines with whole sections of the story told in flashback. This gives a sense of hopping through Kaaro’s memories and helps us explore this strange futuristic vision of Nigeria. It also really helps with pace, first by throwing us into the story and then helping to explain the relationships between the characters we are introduced to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amal El-Mohtar &amp; Max Gladstone, This Is How You Lose the Time War</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/this-is-how-you-lose-the-time-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/this-is-how-you-lose-the-time-war/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Is How You Lose the Time War is a short novella about two members of opposing factions (Red and Blue) engaged in a &amp;rsquo;time war’: that is they travel in time and attempt to erase each other&amp;rsquo;s existence. Except that one day Red decides to taunt Blue with a letter, and a correspondence emerges.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The book is entertaining by virtue of wit and brevity. However, the elements that are skipped over that end up being more interesting to reflect on later. Clearly these are two talented writers bouncing ideas off one another, but you get a  sense that this whole fictional universe might have developed into something more. I was more interested in individual episodes than in the correspondence and its results. Perhaps the writers have ended up constrained by their witty idea.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isaac Asimov, Foundation and Empire, Second Foundation</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-rest-of-the-foundation-trilogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 21:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-rest-of-the-foundation-trilogy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I managed to read all of the foundation novels since I &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/foundation&#34;&gt;wrote about the first one&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, I’ll write about the next two, which covers the original trilogy of ‘novels’ created from the original short stories. I’ve tried to avoid spoilers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;foundation-and-empire&#34;&gt;Foundation and Empire&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Foundation and Empire comprises two novella length stories. The first story (“The General”) picks up from shortly after where the last of the five short stories in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/foundation&#34;&gt;Foundation&lt;/a&gt; left off. While the Foundation has expanded its influence by using its monopoly on technology to control trade, the once great Empire begins to notice. One particular person who notices is a brilliant young General who is determined to crush the Foundation and restore the former power of the Empire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isaac Asimov, Foundation</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/foundation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For our &lt;a href=&#34;the-same-but-different&#34;&gt;first anniversary&lt;/a&gt; we decided to exhange books. What better way to &lt;a href=&#34;https://ideas.hallmark.com/articles/anniversary-ideas/anniversary-gifts-by-year/&#34;&gt;celebrate a paper anniversary&lt;/a&gt;? Ingrid bought me the entire Foundation saga, most of which were &lt;a href=&#34;https://abcoverd.co.uk/archive/designers/topping-mike&#34;&gt;reissued in fancy new paperback designs by Mike Topping&lt;/a&gt; in 2016. All save for 1993&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/7lueju/asimovs_forward_the_foundation_published_in_2016/&#34;&gt;Forward The Foundation&lt;/a&gt; that is, but Ingrid got me a copy anyway. Hence, here is a new series of blog posts!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Foundation novels detail a galactic empire in decline. A mathematician named Hari Seldon, using a novel science called psychohistory, realises that this is happening and formulates a plan for humanity, one that will reduce the time between empires. This, he reasons, will minimise human suffering and prevent an extended period of barbarism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alistair Reynolds, Revelation Space</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/revelation-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/revelation-space/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://approachingpavonis.blogspot.co.uk&#34;&gt;Alistair Reynolds&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; 2000 novel &amp;ldquo;Revelation Space&amp;rdquo; has long been in orbit of my science fiction &amp;ldquo;to read&amp;rdquo; list, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until one sleepless night (post &lt;a href=&#34;command-and-control&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Command and Control&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;) that I came across it in Ingrid&amp;rsquo;s audiobooks. I was instantly drawn in as I listened to the opening scene about an archaeological dig facing evacuation ahead of an imminent &amp;lsquo;razor storm&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Revelation Space&amp;rdquo; is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sf-encyclopedia.com/entry/hard_sf&#34;&gt;hard sci-fi&lt;/a&gt; set in a universe where the speed of light cannot be exceeded. Most of the action takes place in the 26th century, with the narrative also recounting earlier events as the story progresses. Humanity has expanded to five or six systems beyond our current solar system, using huge colony ships that travel at 99.9% of the speed of light. This means that &lt;a href=&#34;http://science.howstuffworks.com/science-vs-myth/everyday-myths/relativity10.htm&#34;&gt;relativistic effects&lt;/a&gt; play an important role in the narrative. A lot is made of the difference between sleeping away the decades between star systems and subjectively experiencing them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, Hello America</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/hello-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/hello-america/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had low expectations for &amp;ldquo;Hello America&amp;rdquo;, the next in &lt;a href=&#34;j-g-ballard&#34;&gt;the series of Ballard novels&lt;/a&gt; that I started reading over seven years ago. However, it turned out to be a hoot. A couple of years ago, this novel would have been a wig-out bit of standard Ballard weirdness (a bit like &lt;a href=&#34;the-drowned-world&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Drowned World&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;the-crystal-world&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Crystal World&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;) but given recent events &amp;ldquo;Hello America&amp;rdquo; is starting to take on an eerie prescience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hello America&amp;rdquo; (1981) is set a hundred years from now in an alternate time-line where oil production peaked in the late sixties. Without a viable energy supply the North American continent depopulates and the Russians dam the Bering strait in order to turn Siberia into farmland to feed the American refugees. Meanwhile, the continental United States turns into a desert wasteland due to the resulting climate change. The 44th president (President Brown) was the last before America depopulated entirely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wonder Woman: A Short Review</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/wonder-woman-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/wonder-woman-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed Wonder Woman, which came as a surprise to me given my growing distaste for superhero movies. &lt;a href=&#34;man-of-steel-a-short-review&#34;&gt;I can remember seeing the Superman reboot Man of Steel&lt;/a&gt; with its phallic rockets and its boring boring fight sequences. But almost everything about Wonder Woman exceeded my expectations. It&amp;rsquo;s a well-made superhero movie and better still, it gets to the heart of why these kinds of movies matter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whereas Man of Steel ended up levelling cities and criminally underusing Amy Adams, all while giving us no stake on why Superman even matters as a man or a hero, Wonder Woman focusses tightly on its main character and explains what matters to her, and in turn the movie then explains why she should matter to us. In other words, it&amp;rsquo;s not boring and it&amp;rsquo;s not pointless.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paul McAuley, Something Coming Through</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/something-coming-through-by-paul-mcauley/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/something-coming-through-by-paul-mcauley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Something Coming Through&amp;rdquo; is a science fiction novel set in the near future. A few years after a brief nuclear war known as &amp;ldquo;The Spasm&amp;rdquo;, an alien race known as the Jackaroo introduce themselves to humanity. The novel is funny, thoughtful, and politically charged. I found it to be a good read.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The aliens have given humanity fifteen &amp;ldquo;gift&amp;rdquo; worlds and an automated way to access them. Think of the Docklands Light Railway but with space shuttles. These worlds contain artefacts and remnants from their previous occupants. Movement between the worlds has also changed the Earth: it suffers from incursions by invasive species brought back from the other worlds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Martian: A Short Review</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-martian-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-martian-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/the-martian-by-andy-weir/&#34;&gt;In my review of the book&lt;/a&gt; I mentioned that a film adaptation of The Martian was on the way. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why but it got released earlier than any of the dates that I&amp;rsquo;d seen and so on Saturday I found myself watching The Martian on the big screen. Could the film version deliver the same level of entertainment as the novel? Could Mark Watney (Matt Damon) get off Mars alive?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Andy Weir, The Martian</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-martian-by-andy-weir/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-martian-by-andy-weir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I received a copy of The Martian by Andy Weir for Christmas. This week during some annual leave I managed to finish it. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those novels that just flies by once it gets going. I&amp;rsquo;ve stayed up incredibly late to read it as it is full of those &amp;ldquo;just one more page&amp;rdquo; moments. It’s a readable and enjoyable story of an astronaut trapped on Mars.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mark Watney is believed to be dead following an accident during an emergency evacuation in a dust storm. With his life support readings at zero and unable to locate his body to be certain, his crew reluctantly abandon him on the red planet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jodorowsky&#39;s Dune</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/jodorowskys-dune/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/jodorowskys-dune/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1935156/?ref_=fn_al_tt_1&#34;&gt;Jodorowsky&amp;rsquo;s Dune&lt;/a&gt; is a documentary about outlandish Chilean director &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alejandro_Jodorowsky&#34;&gt;Alejandro Jodorosky&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; attempt at a film adaptation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/dune/&#34;&gt;Frank Herbert&amp;rsquo;s Dune&lt;/a&gt; in the 1970s. As a big fan of the novel and of science fiction in general, I was very interested in this film. It does not disappoint. It gives a great insight into the mind of a little known (if slightly batty) director and shows even an artistic failure can lead to shock waves that can be felt in later work by others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iain M. Banks, Feersum Endjinn</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/feersum-endjinn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/feersum-endjinn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Feersum Endjinn is one of Iain Banks&amp;rsquo; few non-Culture sci-fi novels. Like the Culture novels, an existential crisis drives the plot: in this case the action takes place on Earth in the far future and the sun has aged to a point where it will grow and swallow the earth. This is referred to as the Encroachment. The characters are divided between the good guys who seek to find a solution for the greater good and bad guys who use the Encroachment to consolidate their power and influence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guardians of the Galaxy: A Short Review</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/guardians-of-the-galaxy-fifteen-observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/guardians-of-the-galaxy-fifteen-observations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finally&lt;/em&gt; saw Guardians of the Galaxy today. Here are fifteen observations about the film that may or may not constitute a short review.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;At least two Oscars for &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.comicbook.com/uploads1/2014/07/guardians-of-the-galaxy-gamora-101682-101718.jpg&#34;&gt;Best Use Of Body Paint (Green)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://images.radiotimes.com/namedimage/Karen_Gillan_takes_on_Zoe_Saldana_in_extended_Guardians_of_the_Galaxy_trailer.jpg?quality=85&amp;amp;mode=crop&amp;amp;width=620&amp;amp;height=374&amp;amp;404=tv&amp;amp;url=https://mattischrome.com/uploads/images/original/53103.jpg&#34;&gt;Best Use Of Body Paint (Blue)&lt;/a&gt; are sewn up.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chris Pratt basically plays Star Lord as “&lt;a href=&#34;http://parksandrecreation.wikia.com/wiki/Andy_Dwyer&#34;&gt;Andy Dwyer&lt;/a&gt; in space” and this is fine by me.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Best movie to feature &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.etonline.com/movies/148845_bradley_cooper_explains_his_voice_guardians_of_the_galaxy/&#34;&gt;a talking raccoon&lt;/a&gt; in a long time.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://screenrant.com/thor-2-dark-world-mid-post-credits-button-scenes-explained&#34;&gt;Watching the entirety of the end credits of Thor 2&lt;/a&gt; paid off!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;“&lt;em&gt;WE&lt;/em&gt; are &lt;a href=&#34;https://uk.yahoo.com/movies/dancing-baby-groot-clip-guardians-of-the-galaxy-94738291414.html&#34;&gt;Groot&lt;/a&gt;” — aren’t we just?! All of the feels.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It features a dance off as a major event, something that it shares with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Step_Up_(film_series)&#34;&gt;Step Up movies&lt;/a&gt;. Guardians of the Galaxy is a waaaay better movie.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The first words of the credits are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mtv.com/news/1887915/guardians-of-the-galaxy-sequel/&#34;&gt;“The Guardians of the Galaxy will return”&lt;/a&gt;. It is in fact a movie that reviews itself.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The 3D version might have been pretty good. I watched the 2D version but &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cinemablend.com/new/Guardians-Galaxy-Has-Something-Special-Planned-Its-IMAX-3D-43350.html&#34;&gt;the scenes with lots of action &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; be improved with a bit of depth&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/culture/film/film-news/11033572/Guardians-of-the-Galaxy-Awesome-Mix-soundtrack-tops-Billboard-chart.html&#34;&gt;A great soundtrack&lt;/a&gt;, but there is a cheesy “smooth rock wins chicks” bit that’s a little icky half way through.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;That said, the description of the legend of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0087277/&#34;&gt;Footloose&lt;/a&gt; is hilarious. Especially the callback toward the end of the movie.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I especially enjoyed the scene with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slashfilm.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-easter-eggs-quotes/&#34;&gt;the Collector&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Karen Gillen is wasted as Nebula, but &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cinemablend.com/new/Nebula-Return-Guardians-Galaxy-2-66648.html&#34;&gt;hopefully she will be back&lt;/a&gt;. Karen’s also in what may well be &lt;a href=&#34;http://abc.go.com/shows/selfie&#34;&gt;one of the most ill-conceived TV shows of all time&lt;/a&gt; later this autumn.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I thought it was Bruce Willis playing &lt;a href=&#34;http://whatculture.com/wwe/batista-praised-role-guardians-galaxy-movie.php&#34;&gt;Drax the Destroyer&lt;/a&gt; (I’m useless at this guess the actor game). I loved his taking things literally: “Nothing goes over my head. My reflexes are too fast, I would catch it.”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you text me at any point in the next month, I will probably reply with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nerdist.com/2014/08/translate-any-website-into-groot-speak-with-this-nifty-new-button/&#34;&gt;“I am Groot”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;No Raccoons or tree creatures were harmed during the making of this film.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, High-Rise</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/high-rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/high-rise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a few false starts I managed to finish &amp;ldquo;High-Rise&amp;rdquo;, the next in &lt;a href=&#34;j-g-ballard&#34;&gt;my collection of JG Ballard novels&lt;/a&gt;. For a book that I had trouble getting into, it turned out to be a pretty good read - even if it was also a pretty unpleasant one. Published in 1975, &amp;ldquo;High-Rise&amp;rdquo; is perhaps ahead of its time in exploring the effects of social breakdown in stylised and artificial situations where people are in close contact. You might think the plot, about a luxury high-rise that goes to hell, is in some way political or sociological but it really isn&amp;rsquo;t. It&amp;rsquo;s just a big playground in which Ballard throws around some of his most twisted ideas, all the while remarking on the very artifice of the situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man of Steel: A Short Review</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/man-of-steel-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/man-of-steel-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I went to see the new Superman reboot &lt;em&gt;Man of Steel&lt;/em&gt; with friends. I really enjoyed it, particularly the more reflective take on the superhero myth. Starting out with the fate of the planet Krypton, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0770828/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Man of Steel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; approximately fuses the events of both the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0078346/?ref_=sr_2&#34;&gt;first&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0081573/&#34;&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; original Superman movies. We get to see Superman&amp;rsquo;s arrival and childhood on earth and then the arrival of Zod, a maniac bent on replacing the earth and everyone on it with a new race of Kryptonians.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Star Trek: Into Darkness - A Short Review</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/star-trek-into-darkness-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/star-trek-into-darkness-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I saw &lt;em&gt;Star Trek: Into Darkness&lt;/em&gt; last night in 3D at the IMAX in Waterloo. I am going to have to separate this into a review into two parts, a review of the film and a review of the viewing experience. I am not completely happy with how the film experience is changed by the 3D and the super big screen and I will try to explain what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iain M. Banks, Consider Phlebas</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/consider-phlebas-a-picaresque-in-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/consider-phlebas-a-picaresque-in-space/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A while back, I decided I was going to write about the Iain M. Banks sci-fi-novels (mainly as a respite from having to read and write about &lt;a href=&#34;j-g-ballard&#34;&gt;J. G. Ballard novels&lt;/a&gt;, but I only got as fas as writing about the excellent “Against A Dark Barkground” and re-reading the first of the Culture novels “Consider Phlebas”. WARNING: Some plot spoilers follow (but not too many).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure why it has taken almost two years to write about this novel. Perhaps it is because I couldn’t find myself a proper explanation for the title. The following is my own theory, feel free to add your own in the comments. The book takes its name from the epigraph, an extract from T.S. Elliot’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bartleby.com/201/1.html&#34;&gt;“The Waste Land”&lt;/a&gt; (which is also on my “to read” list):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nick Harkaway, The Gone-Away World</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-gone-away-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-gone-away-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Gone-Away World” is a novel by Nick Harkaway. It’s about a world slightly askew to our own in which the powers-that-be have deigned to unleash a weapon that simply wipes the enemy out of existence. Unfortunately the enemies also have the same weapon and there are terrible consequences to the extent that the very fabric of reality is threatened. If you don’t already know what reification means, you will by the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contagion: A Short Review</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/contagion-a-short-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/contagion-a-short-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was much excitement about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1598778/&#34;&gt;Contagion&lt;/a&gt; at work. Finally a movie that explains  as part of the plot! A bunch of us went to see it, mainly to see whether &lt;a href=&#34;http://contagionmovie.warnerbros.com/index.html&#34;&gt;a disaster movie about a global pandemic&lt;/a&gt; could hold up as entertainment and to have a bit of a giggle if it couldn’t.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I liked three things in particular about the film. I liked the cinematography, especially the opening sequences with the index cases staggering around. I liked the soundtrack except for when it intruded a bit too much into proceedings. Finally, I liked Marion Cotillard, who seems to be in every interesting movie at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frank Herbert, Dune</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/dune/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/dune/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A week or so ago, I finished reading &lt;em&gt;Dune&lt;/em&gt; by Frank Herbert. It tells the story of a revolution within a Galactic Empire that takes place on a harsh and unforgiving desert planet called Arrakis. One central theme is how destinies can be shaped despite being intertwined around many axes. Another is the importance of adaptation in the fight for survival.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I came to &lt;em&gt;Dune&lt;/em&gt; via the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0087182/&#34;&gt;David Lynch film&lt;/a&gt; and then &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frank_Herbert%27s_Dune&#34;&gt;the Sci-Fi Channel’s mini-series&lt;/a&gt;, which I was able to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lovefilm.com/film/Dune-Part-1/161663/&#34;&gt;stream through LoveFilm&lt;/a&gt;. Of the two filmed versions, I found the latter to be more enjoyable and this is almost certainly because it runs to nearly six hours. The 1984 film runs to over 3 hours and yet still feels rather rushed. The Lynch version is to be praised though as in my opinion it develops a unique aesthetic for the Dune universe that I did not detect so much in the book.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, Concrete Island</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/concrete-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/concrete-island/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;no-man-is-an-island-not-any-more&#34;&gt;No man is an island (not any more)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You are tracked pretty much everywhere you go. CCTV, the GPS on your phone or the signals sent by your more primitive model to the masts to keep in touch with the network. Your cash withdrawals, your purchases in Tesco and your journeys on public transport all add to the picture of where you are. If you drive, your sat nav will hold clues to where you have been and, if you disappear, where you might have gone to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Favourite Culture Ship Names</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/favourite-culture-ship-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/favourite-culture-ship-names/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned before &lt;a href=&#34;more-books&#34;&gt;I am re-reading the novels of Iain Banks&lt;/a&gt; and this weekend I managed to finish &lt;em&gt;Consider Phlebas&lt;/em&gt;. A little post about it will be coming up soon. One of my favourite things about the Culture novels is how the ships are named and having found &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_ships_(The_Culture)&#34;&gt;a list on Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;, I thought I would share ten of my favourites with you!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;You’ll Clean That Up Before You Leave&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ravished By The Sheer Implausibility Of That Last Statement&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;All Through With This Niceness And Negotiation Stuff&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prosthetic Conscience&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Of Course I Still Love You&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Size Isn’t Everything&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hand Me The Gun And Ask Me Again&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dramatic Exit, Or, Thank you And Goodnight&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;We Haven’t Met But You’re A Great Fan Of Mine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Anticipation Of A New Lover’s Arrival, The&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Great names all I am sure you would agree. Not all of them appear as fully developed characters. In fact (and I will mention this again later) the ships don’t get nearly enough time as characters in the novels apart from &lt;em&gt;Excession&lt;/em&gt;, which is almost entirely devoted to them. In that novel, one ship is central to the story and is probably my favourite, an eccentric GCU (General Contact Unit) called &lt;em&gt;Grey Area&lt;/em&gt; that has been shunned by the other machines for “non-consensual mind reading”. It turns out the ship is somewhat morbid and likes to confront the perpetrators of genocides with their crimes. It is known by the other ships as “the meatf***er” and is totally badass.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Crystal World</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-crystal-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-crystal-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;crystallising-the-world-the-body-or-the-mind&#34;&gt;Crystallising the world, the body, or the mind?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At last, Ballard in full flow. The Crystal World (TCW) is definitely the most enjoyable of the early trio of apocalyptic novels. It takes the successful elements of the first two and embellishes them with new details and ideas. At time of writing, TCW is definitely the best Ballard novel that I have read in its entirety.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The book begins with a steamer travelling up a river in Cameroon carrying the novel’s main protagonist Edward Sanders, a doctor at a hospital for lepers. He is hoping to meet some friends, Max and Suzanne Clair, who are also doctors and run another leprosy hospital in a town named Mount Royal (also the name of the main city in “The Drought”). His motives are not entirely clear and we are given introspection into his doubts about the reasons he is making the journey. The inference is that he had an affair with Suzanne Clair and may well still be in love with her.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Drought</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-drought/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-drought/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-world-created-by-nature-versus-the-world-constructed-by-humans&#34;&gt;The world created by nature versus the world constructed by humans&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On to The Drought by J. G. Ballard in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/j-g-ballard/&#34;&gt;my ongoing quest to read and review all of his novels&lt;/a&gt;. This is his second novel, if we assume his convention of never acknowledging “The Wind From Nowhere” as being his first novel. “The Drought” itself was renamed from “The Burning World” and additional content added later on. This was quite common practice in SF in the 50s and 60s where novels were serialised in magazines like &lt;a href=&#34;http://philsp.com/mags/amazing_stories.html&#34;&gt;Amazing SF&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://ttapress.com/interzone/about/&#34;&gt;Interzone&lt;/a&gt;. It is evidence though of Ballard finding his voice as he wrote and from The Drought it is easy to see that he is iterating his thought processes and subject matter with each novel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard, The Drowned World</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-drowned-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/the-drowned-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;does-science-fiction-have-to-be-believable-to-be-meaningful&#34;&gt;Does Science Fiction have to be believable to be meaningful?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Should science fiction have predictive power? In plotting the vast unknowns of the future, should authors aim for prescience? Will people be able to say of the best SF novels in five hundred years time that some novels were right about some things and that these novels are better than the ones that didn’t?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I would say no, otherwise we would be remarkably unfair on an awful lot of good writing. That said, I doubt that SF is read for the futurology. As with all literature, SF is at it is best when it has something to say about the world around us now, no matter when it may be set. And if SF has any kind of predictive record, it does better when the psychological issues arising from continued technological development are considered over the mere technology of that advancement. In the long run, a fictional account of space dog Laika (does one exist?) that rings true emotionally will probably endure longer than a pulp novel entitled “Dogs In Space!” (though that is a great title!).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. G. Ballard</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/j-g-ballard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/j-g-ballard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading &amp;ldquo;Crash&amp;rdquo; at 17 left me in a state of numb shock. It got me hooked and left me with &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/J._G._Ballard&#34;&gt;J. G. Ballard&lt;/a&gt; as one of my favourite authors. I then devoured a short story collection called &amp;ldquo;Myths of the Near Future&amp;rdquo; around the same time. You may recognise it because the Klaxons appropriated the title for their debut album. Those stories captured my imagination, in particular the eponymous story of a world gone to run amid &amp;ldquo;space sickness&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
