<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tate Britain on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/tate-britain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tate Britain on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/tate-britain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>LS Lowry At Tate Britain</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/ls-lowry-at-tate-britain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/ls-lowry-at-tate-britain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have mixed feelings about this show. On the one hand, I like that there are depictions of working class Britain on display and I feel that it is right that these paintings are considered part of the British cultural canon. I also like that a lot of these paintings represent large gatherings of people, which are absent from a lot of what we might call the mainstream of art.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Art Under Attack at Tate Britain</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/art-under-attack-at-tate-britain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/art-under-attack-at-tate-britain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I went with a friend to see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tate.org.uk/whats-on/tate-britain/exhibition/art-under-attack-histories-british-iconoclasm&#34;&gt;Tate Britain&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Art Under Attack&amp;rdquo; show&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting, if uneven, affair that entertains but doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite succeed in everything it attempts to do. The big word that you learn is iconoclasm: the act of attacking an object believed to represent particular beliefs. The show splits into two parts: ideological acts of iconoclasm committed against works of art in Britain and the work of British artists who embrace iconoclasm as a means for making art. The first half (comprising more than half of the show - because I lump together two of the shows sections &amp;ldquo;Religion&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Politics&amp;rdquo; into this half) is more interesting and successful than the second (&amp;ldquo;Aesthetics&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
