<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hot Chip on mattischrome</title>
    <link>https://mattischrome.com/tags/hot-chip/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hot Chip on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mattischrome.com/tags/hot-chip/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2015</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-june-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-june-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To reboot this series, Album Digest June 2015 features five fantastic albums from Hot Chip, Jamie xx, Blanck Mass, Holly Herndon, and The Orb. I could pick loads more as I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to a lot of albums since &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/album-digest-february-2015/&#34;&gt;February&lt;/a&gt; but I decided to focus on the more electronic material. This means that I have no excuses for not continuing next month with a rockier theme.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;hot-chip-why-make-sense&#34;&gt;Hot Chip &amp;ldquo;Why Make Sense?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hot Chip seem to be settling in to a pattern with their album releases, alternating between messy experimental affairs and then a state of the art correction. Witness how &amp;ldquo;The Warning&amp;rdquo; smartened up the all-over-the-place &amp;ldquo;Coming On Strong&amp;rdquo; and how &amp;ldquo;One Life Stand&amp;rdquo; moulded and matured the lovestruck meandering of &amp;ldquo;Made In The Dark&amp;rdquo; into a lithe ten song set. &amp;ldquo;Why Make Sense?&amp;rdquo; takes the earnest song-based approach of &amp;ldquo;In Our Heads&amp;rdquo; and casts it into a funky fun-filled fifty minutes. It&amp;rsquo;s as concise as they&amp;rsquo;ve been since &amp;ldquo;One Life Stand&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, June 2012</title>
      <link>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-june-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattischrome.com/posts/album-digest-june-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three fantastic albums for Album Digest June 2012:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Saint Etienne &lt;em&gt;Words and Music by Saint Etienne&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Liars &lt;em&gt;WIXIW&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hot Chip &lt;em&gt;In Our Heads&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This month is a curious selection in that the albums are all by bands that I already own a few records by. When there is so much other directly related material that you can write about, it makes focussing on the album in hand quite difficult. I am always thinking up rankings and comparisons. Where does this new album fit in with the rest of them? Will I like it as much when the novelty wears off? What would it sound like if they had done Y or Z like they did back on album X?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
