<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dance on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/dance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dance on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/dance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2024 Albums of the Year #8: Pet Shop Boys Nonetheless</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-08-pet-shop-boys-nonetheless/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-albums-08-pet-shop-boys-nonetheless/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless is the fifteenth album by the Pet Shop Boys. As seems to be a common theme with this top 10 so far, it&amp;rsquo;s an album that initially underwhelmed me. Well, perhaps &amp;ldquo;underwhelmed&amp;rdquo; is a little unfair, it was more that it didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to have much to it to distinguish it from their previous albums, and there have been some palpable duds in the previous fourteen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, this album is definitely a grower. As I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten to know some of the songs, I&amp;rsquo;ve come to appreciate the little details strewn throughout. For example, the lovely little rave riff that breaks into the bridge on &amp;ldquo;Loneliness&amp;rdquo;, something that turns a potentially stern song into something a lot more fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goldfrapp - Black Cherry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/goldfrapp-black-cherry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/goldfrapp-black-cherry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the first in an unplanned series of &lt;strong&gt;album revisits&lt;/strong&gt;, I will write a post explaining the process soon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Cherry_(Goldfrapp_album)&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Black Cherry&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is the second album by Goldfrapp, released in 2003. I bought the lead single Train while I lived in York and also the single of the title track because by then I&amp;rsquo;d discovered M83 and they&amp;rsquo;d done a remix of it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Black Cherry&amp;rdquo; finds the band faced with following their successful and chilled out debut album &amp;ldquo;Felt Mountain&amp;rdquo;, which back in 2000 had sounded notably weird. But nobody wants to sound like a kook forever, sometimes people want to let their hair down and just dance. That&amp;rsquo;s very much what the first two tracks anyway, especially the pulsating &amp;ldquo;Train&amp;rdquo;. To my ears, I was definitely pleased when I first played the single - I love that relentless synth riff that sounds like it&amp;rsquo;s being fed through about seventy FX pedals. I vaguely remember the single&amp;rsquo;s B-side &amp;ldquo;Big Black Cloud, Little White Lie&amp;rdquo; and the Village Hall Remix being pretty ace too. Fortunately they&amp;rsquo;re also on streaming, so I was able to check. I think I liked the B-side because it sounded very much like a &amp;ldquo;Felt Mountain&amp;rdquo; outtake - twenty years ago I likely appreciated the familiarity but today it serves a reminder that while &amp;ldquo;Felt Mountain 2&amp;rdquo; would have been nice, &amp;ldquo;Black Cherry&amp;rdquo; definitely benefitted from changing things up a bit. The Remix is mostly instrumental and adds even more Glitter beat stomp to Train, pleasant enough I guess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics Or Not?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-or-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-or-not/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the new year, thoughts and spare time for writing point me toward writing some new posts for my understated classics series. Expect some new ones soon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I also reflected on my previous choices and thought a bit about how my music tastes have changed recently. Some of this has to do with streaming and the frustrations I wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattischrome.com/a-pox-on-both-their-houses&#34;&gt;in my last post&lt;/a&gt;. Some of it is just down to getting older: I have less time to listen to new music, and much of the &amp;rsquo;new&amp;rsquo; stuff I listen to is me investigating the stuff I missed first time around. Who knew Art of Noise were so good? Not me, but I do now!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
