<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Biosphere on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/biosphere/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Biosphere on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/biosphere/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What IS That Noise?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-that-noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-that-noise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently spruced up a post I wrote four years ago about &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/articles/uc4/&#34;&gt;Biosphere’s wonderful album Substrata&lt;/a&gt;. I added the following footnote about the difference between voice samples and found sound:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I suppose I am distinguishing between found sound and vocal samples here. Perhaps there is very little difference, or that one is the other? When is a vocal snippet something more than found sound? Is it the fact that one has meaning? Isn’t a “meaningless” sample - like the ones here in Russian that I can’t understand - little more than found sound anyway?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, August 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-august-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I bought a collection of electronic music this month. I mixed them all up in a smart playlist on iTunes, the smart aspect being to limit to tracks that had been played fewer than five then six then seven times etc. This made sure I was still listening to all the tracks equally often, despite the randomness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Biosphere &lt;em&gt;N-plants&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ford &amp;amp; Lopatin &lt;em&gt;Channel Pressure&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gus Gus &lt;em&gt;Arabian Horse&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Instra:Mental &lt;em&gt;Resolution 653&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jon Tejada &lt;em&gt;Parabolas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;biosphere-_n-plants_&#34;&gt;Biosphere &lt;em&gt;N-Plants&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think this album makes Biosphere the most reviewed musician on this blog at the moment but I don’t mind too much, he makes some great stuff. &lt;em&gt;N-Plants&lt;/em&gt; is a series of pieces about Japanese nuclear power plants and was ready for release by about February this year, just before the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fukushima_Daiichi_nuclear_disaster&#34;&gt;Fukishima nuclear disaster&lt;/a&gt; in March. It ended up being released in June. I am not sure if this represents a delay or not but as this quote shows, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.touchmusic.org.uk/catalogue/to84_biosphere_nplants.html&#34;&gt;Geir Jenssen is aware of how spooky the timing was&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understated Classics #4: Substrata by Biosphere</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understated-classics-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../assets/images/other/UC4add1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I bought this album in the summer between my two years at college. I remember listening to this music under skies glowering with clouds so 1997 must have been a poor summer. I’d just bought a book of photography too, which placed photos from the north and south poles on opposite pages. I bought it mainly for the penguins that were, of course, on pretty much every other page. The pictures of snow and ice soon became the ideal companions to this album.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
