<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aphex Twin on mattischrome</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/aphex-twin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aphex Twin on mattischrome</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/aphex-twin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, July 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-july-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Album Digest July 2016 consists of a bumper five albums, mainly because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t work out which one to drop. I think they&amp;rsquo;re all pretty good though it&amp;rsquo;s great to hear new music from The Avalanches after all this time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;bat-for-lashes-the-bride&#34;&gt;Bat For Lashes &amp;ldquo;The Bride&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For her fourth album as Bat For Lashes, Natasha Khan applies her considerable songwriting skills to a concept album. She sings from the perspective of a bride whose husband dies on his way to their wedding. Almost all artists would deliver this subject matter in a melodramatic way, but Khan focusses on the sadness and delivers a beautiful suite of songs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, February 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-february-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;aphex-twin-computer-controlled-acoustic-instruments-pt2-ep&#34;&gt;Aphex Twin &amp;ldquo;Computer Controlled Acoustic Instruments Pt2 EP&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aphex Twin follows SYRO (reviewed in &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/album-digest-september-2014/&#34;&gt;Album Digest September 2014 here&lt;/a&gt;) with this 27 minute EP of music that, if we take the title literally, features computers playing acoustic musical instruments. It&amp;rsquo;s a very different sound to SYRO and sounds acoustic for the most part. It&amp;rsquo;s an important experiment about the role of the musician, one that is already blurred in the creation of electronic music.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Album Digest, September 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/album-digest-september-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Album Digest September 2014 contains four amazing albums, including the long-awaited return from the Aphex Twin, and an album from Cymbals Eat Guitars released about a week after I wondered what had happened to them. Spooky. Rounding out the selection this month are a cool punky-disco album by The Juan Maclean and a truly remarkable offering by Vessel.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;aphex-twin-syro&#34;&gt;Aphex Twin &lt;em&gt;SYRO&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SYRO&lt;/em&gt; is the sixth album by Aphex Twin and his first official Aphex Twin release since Drukqs in 2001. Announced with a typically cryptic track listing at a month&amp;rsquo;s notice via the dark web, along with artwork that resembles a tax receipt for the costs of releasing the album, his anarchic streak appears intact. Therefore the most suprising thing about SYRO is just how conventional it sounds on first listen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
